SUBS: LFBS
Miss Fanny?
- Miss Fanny?
- Down here, Emma. Third row.
I came in early to tidy up,
and the doorman said you were in.
What you doing out there?
The one place in the theatre
I've never sat.
Maybe things look different from here.
This is the day, isn't it?
Yeah.
Any word yet?
No. The wire just said tonight.
You nervous?
Nervous, happy, scared, excited...
I'm going to make a fresh pot
of coffee. You coming?
I think I'll just sit here
for a while, okay?
Well, I'll be in
the dressing room if you want me.
Mr. Ziegfeld wants to see you.
When you feel like it, he says.
He'll be waiting in his office.
Thanks, Em.
Did you hear that, Mrs. Strakosh?
Ziegfeld is waiting for me.
For me.
See, you were wrong, Mrs. Strakosh.
No, Fanny, darling, I'm not wrong.
For a girl, for average,
you're a pleasure.
But when people pay good money
in the theatre...
...especially the male element,
they want something extra to look at.
But if a girl isn't...
If a girl isn't what?
Don't worry, Mrs Strakosh, they'll look at me.
The whole world will
look at me and be stunned.
It was all right when you were
a child and made funny faces.
- Then, you were cute.
- My condolences, darling, you're no longer cute.
Hey, wait a minute.
No, it's all right. I'm one of the 8 Beautiful Girls 8.
Well, the makeup helps a lot.
Really.
Sell it, sell it.
Get in there, Fanny.
Knees high. High! Way up there.
Go.
Hold it, Eddie.
Hold it!
You, with the skinny legs.
You. Yes, you, with the bloomers!
Yeah?
- You're fired.
- What?
You call that a replacement?
What's the matter, Ed? Did you owe somebody a favour?
- It seemed like a funny idea.
- What's funny about it?
- What do I say?
- Everybody back at 4.
But listen, you're making a mistake.
I got a lot of experience, honest.
I've been on the stage since I was 10.
Amateur contests,
Gottlieb's Southern Repertory...
...professional companies. Lassie...
I doubled six parts.
I played a daughter and her father.
A 60-year-old Indian chief.
Listen, girlie...
- Hau.
Please, you've got to face facts.
You don't look like the other girls.
- I know, but...
- You got skinny legs, you stick out.
And you are out!
I'm just trying to tell you something...
- Sorry, kid.
- Why don't you give me a chance?
Look! I do a terrific time step! Watch!
Out! Out!
Look Mr. Keeney. Suppose all you ever had for breakfast
was onion rolls.
Now, all of a sudden, one morning in walks a bagel.
So, I mean, you take a look at it and say,
"What is that?"...
...until you tried it.
That's my trouble.
What's your trouble?
I'm a bagel on a plate full of onion rolls!
Nobody recognizes me. Listen:
No autographs, please.
Hau? What did she say?
You think beautiful girls are gonna stay stars forever?
I should say not. Any minute now thye're gonna be out.
You're no chorus girl.
You're a singer.
And a comic.
With skinny legs.
So why did you try out for the chorus?
'Cause that's what you were looking for.
If you'd been looking for a juggler, I would have been a juggler.
I just gotta get on a stage somehow.
How come you hired me?
Because you wanted it so much.
Are you sure you're tough enough for business?
Maybe not.
- Say, can you roller skate?
- Why, you had a sudden urge to go skating?
No, I'm trying out a novelty number tomorrow.
If you can skate, be here at noon.
Yeah, but what about Keeney?
- He won't be in till night. By then the number'll be in the show.
But he'll kill you. He might even fire you.
Not if you're good.
Are you sure you can roller skate?
Can I roller skate?
- I thought you said you could skate.
- I didn't know I couldn't.
Nora.  Sandra.
Cherry.  Wilma.
Ruthie. Polly.
Fanny.
Go. Get out there.
Thanks, mister, I really...
Hey, you!
- Lady, back inside.
- What are you doing?
Fanny, they liked you. Go back out
there, Fan. Go ahead, honey.
- You, stay back.
- It's my show!
No, you don't.
Her. On her. Over there!
Smile.
Eddie, they liked it!
Did you hear that...?
- Mr. Keeney...
- Get the next act on.
What do you think I'm paying you for?
So they shouldn't like it?
I didn't know you were paying me.
I don't know what you pay me,
but I bet it isn't enough.
Listen girlie, when I get around to thinking
about you, I'll let you know.
Well, if it isn't Miss Roller Skates.
- Listen, I'm really sorry, girls.
- Oh, sure you are.
We heard the applause.
I'm sorry I loused up the number,
but I couldn't help it.
As long as I did, I'm glad it was a hit.
Who do you think will see you in this dump?
Florenz Ziegfeld?
Why not? You think the word can't spread?
I'll spread it myself.
I know a lady who knows the lady
who makes his shirts.
He's gonna hear about me.
Go ahead and laugh.
I'm telling you something.
One night, you'll be sitting around here laughing
and kidding, just like that...
...and there's gonna be a knock on the door.
You see? And there
he'll be: Ziegfeld!
Sorry to disappoint you,
but the name's Arnstein.
- Did you want to see someone?
- Yes.
You.
Gorgeous.
- I beg your pardon?
- Oh, I mean, your shirt.
It's absolutely the most gorgeous
thing I've ever seen in my life.
What's it made out of?
French handkerchief linen.
It goes very limp, though.
Yeah. I can see.
Except, it's really beautiful.
All the tailcoats I've seen,
I mean...
...well, they were rented, you know...
...they all got these stiff shirts.
Well, this one's just for fun.
You've probably heard this so often that it's boring...
...but I had to come back to tell you how much I enjoyed what you did.
It's not so boring. You'd be
surprised how boring it isn't.
You're going to be a big star some day, Miss...
Brice. Fanny Brice.
Fanny Brice.
I'll look for it in lights.
- What did you say your name was?
- Nick Arnstein.
- Come around thinking about me, Mr. Keeney?
- It's you. Hello, Arnstein.
I'll give you $25 a week.
Take it or leave it.
- I'll take it.
- Leave it.
I'm offering 35.
What do you mean you're offering? Since when are you...?
In show business? I'm not.
But one of your competitors authorized me to deal for him...
...whenever I ran across a talent I considered really unique.
So...
...$35 a week?
- 40.
- 45.
50.
Well, I wasn't authorized to go over 50.
She's yours for $50 a week.
Congratulations.
Yeah.
$50 a week?
$50 a week? I'm almost a millionaire!
- Hey, who's the competitor?
- There's no competitor.
What do you mean, you were bluffing?
Like in a poker game?
- What if Keeney had stopped first?
- You'd have lost.
- I would've lost a job.
- I was willing to take a chance.
With my job?
Hey, Nicky.
- Come on. We're waiting. Hurry up.
I'll be with you in a minute.
Wow. Are those yours?
I'm just minding them for a friend.
Look, we're going to Delmonico's for supper.
Won't you join us?
We'd be happy to wait while you change.
I'd have to change too much. Nobody could wait that long.
I'd have a much better time and a lot more laughs.
Well...
...thanks anyway...
...but I'm meeting some people in my mother's saloon.
Honest.
You want a few jokes to take with you?
I'll wait till the next time we meet, which will be soon, I hope.
Hey!
Whoever washes your shirt, tell them to put a little starch in the last rinse.
That way, it won't go so limp.
Oh.
A little starch...
...in the last rinse.
Thank you. I won't forget.
It's a telegram! There's a telegram for Mrs. Brice!
A telegram for the Brices!
The Western Union man.
That's life for you. Somebody's dead.
Come on, telegram!
- What do you think of my new song?
- I like the old one better.
Yeah, but I'm tired of it.
I've been singing it for six months.
- So?
What?
What's that?
- Oh, look, here's Fanny now.
- Let her mama tell her.
Rosie.
Who is it, Mama?
Auntie Blanche or Lou?
Ziegfeld.
He died?
"Dear Miss Brice. Stop.
Please meet me
at the New Amsterdam Theatre...
...on Thursday at 11:00 a.m. Stop.
Florence Ziegfeld."
See? By heart, like the Pledge of Allegiance.
Mazel tov, Fanny, darling. Mazel tov.
- I knew you'd do it.
- My stomach aches.
I wonder how a mother could call a boy Florence.
It's "Florenzzzzz."
I wonder how a mother could call a boy Florenzzzzz.
You think it's a job or an audition?
A job.
You know what I think?
Somebody talked to him about me.
See, I met this guy backstage
one night with a ruffled shirt on.
Just the kind you figure to know Ziegfeld.
I bet you he said a word.
That's what must have happened.
Oh, my head aches.
Nothing aches. You're built like a horse.
I have nothing to wear.
What's she been walking around in
all this time? Towels?
It's coming too easy.
That's what's got me scared.
Where's all the suffering you're supposed to do  before you click?
And the hard knocks, the setbacks
you're supposed to learn from?
This is too quick.
I haven't suffered enough yet.
You haven't goy the job yet either.
Who says if you get it in a week you can't lose it?
Cheer up. Maybe you'll suffer later.
I guarantee you if you're as bossy with Ziegfeld as you are with...
I am not bossy with you or anyone.
And even if I was...
...Ziegfeld isn't just anyone.
And believe me... ...whatever Mr Ziegfeld tells me to do,
that's what I'm gonna do.
Bravo, Miss Brice! Perfectly charming,
and I'm delighted.
John, will you get the bride music for Miss Brice, please?
- Yes, sir.
- You mean I'm hired?
Uh-Huh.
- I'm a Ziegfeld Girl?
- That's exactly what you are.
I'm a Ziegfeld Girl.
Miss Brice, you will do "Second Hand Rose" in the first act...
...and you will sing this new number in the finale.
Alright?
Anything you say, Mr Ziegfeld.
And just go along with Tony, and he'll teach it to you.
OK.
John, I want to see the second act opening right from the top.
I'll watch it from the balcony.
Turn on the rails.
Bill, will you turn on the rails for Mr. Ziegfeld, please?
We'll do the second act opening, kids.
This way, miss.
Hey!
Paul. Paul?
Mr. Ziegfeld? Mr. Ziegfeld?
Yoo-hoo, Mr. Ziegfeld?
Mr. Ziegfeld?
Georgia, you're late.
Sorry, Flo.
- Where is he?
- He's up above. Like God.
Mr. Ziegfeld?
Mr. Ziegfeld? Mr. Ziegfeld?
Yes, Miss Brice?
I don't want to be in the finale.
What was that you said?
Well, I just...
I can't sing words like: "I am the beautiful reflection
of my love's affection." I mean...
Why not?
Well, it's embarrassing.
Listen, why don't I just do my first act number ...and we'll call it a night, okay?
- No, it's not okay.
- Why not?
Miss Brice, may I remind you that you're in my theatre?
So nobody argues with the landlord?
Just wait right there. I'm coming down.
Take five. Take five, everybody.
Just take...
...five.
Is that bad, he's coming down?
Only if you want to stay in the show.
Look, what's your name?
Fanny Brice.
Georgia James.
Hi.
Tell him you were wrong.
But I'm not.
In that case, it was nice to have met you.
Miss Brice?
Now what is all this?
Not two minutes ago you said: "Anything you say, Mr. Ziegfeld." Remember?
Yes, and I'm very sorry.
But if I come out opening night...
...telling the audience how beautiful I am,
I'll be back at Keeney's before the curtain comes down.
I assure you that won't happen.
But I need a strong voice in the finale.
But please take me out of it, Mr Ziegfeld.
Miss Brice, if I take you out of the finale
l'll also take you out of the Follies.... It's just that simple.
Okay, you win.
Thank you.
You don't win fair, but you win.
John, forget the second act opening.
I want to see the bride number right from the top with Miss Brice.
She can walk through it.
Right, sir.
All right kids, this'll be the bride number.
Mr. Ziegfeld?
Mr. Ziegfeld!
Now what?
Listen, can I hum it?
You will sing the words exactly as written.
And that, Miss Brice,
is the end of this discussion.
Yes, Mr. Ziegfeld.
Whatever you say, Mr. Ziegfeld.
I'm sorry.
The winter bride is typified...
by Christmas, frost and fairies...
And though the weather's changeable...
Her virtue never varies.
The springtime bride is stary-eyed
And poets often say...
No other bride would dare to dream the dreams that April...
May.
The summer bride is glorified by Merlin's magic touch...
A lucky man receives the love of...
June
July
And such.
The autumn bride is prude and wise at sweet sixteen or twenty...
And as a wife in future life...
She'll hold the horn of plenty.
And now a singing bride who vocally encompasses
the happiness and harmony
that marriage truly promises.
My friend the showstopper.
- Listen, you could have told me about it.
- I didn't know about it...
...until a minute before when I was in my dressing room,
and I saw...
I had to do something.
Ladies and gentlemen, thank you very much.
It went beautifully.
You were all very good...
...and I am proud of you.
Congratulations, Flo.
Thank you.
Wonderful, Flo.
That finale topped everything.
Mr. Ziegfeld, l...
Be quiet.
The bride number was wonderful, Mr Ziegfeld.
Yes, that was fun, wasn't it?
All right, Miss Brice.
I'm waiting.
Mr Ziegfeld, I don't blame you for being mad.
But I didn't do it out of spite, honest.
I didn't plan it.
I was just sitting here and... uhhh
"Oh, look. What do you know?"
I couldn't do it straight as if I thought I was like one of those other girls.
They would have laughed.
And they did.
Yes, but it was my joke. You see?
They laughed with me, not at me.
Because I wanted them to laugh.
But, I mean...
You know what I mean.
No, explain it to me.
Miss Brice can't see anyone.
Oh, not even her mama?
Mama...
Darling, everybody's talking.
You were wonderful.
You know, we're so proud of you,
we're ready to bust.
Proud, yes. But surprised, no.
Mr. Ziegfeld, this is my mother.
Oh, the big boss.
Oh, Mr Ziegfeld.
You have a hit on your hands.
Especially with my daughter Fanny.
This is Mrs. Strakosh,
our neighbour.
And this is Eddie Ryan. He's my friend.
Oh, Mr Ziegfeld. How do you do?
Mr. Ziegfeld, you're a genius.
To put a beautiful wedding gown on a girl that's in the family way.
Who would think of such a thing?
Only one person I know.
We'd better go. Mrs. Brice is expecting half the neighbourhood.
Half? All.
Free beer. You come, huh?
Beer?
Mama, I'll come home soon as soon as I can.
Take your time. I'm gonna be so busy showing off.
How many mothers on Henry Street are the mother of a Ziegfeld star?
Bye.
I'll see you later.
Well, you have a charming mother, and I have a problem.
I ought to fire you. But I love talent.
And it's hard to quarrel with five curtain calls.
Six.
There you are. That's my problem.
So I guess I'll have to give you another chance.
Oh, Mr. Ziegfeld!
Did he fire you?
Not yet.
But I'll ring the curtain
down on you...
...if you ever disobey an order of mine again.
I won't. I won't. Never, ever.
I'll do it straight tomorrow night.
I mean...
...without the pillow.
You'll do it exactly as you did tonight and that's an order.
- You mean you liked it?
No! But the audience did. That's why I'm going to give you another number.
I'll choose a new song for you.
Thank you, Mr. Ziegfeld!
The only thing is, about that song.
A song, you know, it's a very, very intimate thing.
I mean, it's really between me and the audience.
So?
So uhhh...
one of the things I really feel definite about is choosing my own.
Choosing your own what?
Songs. Songs.
Good evening. And congratulations. Both of you.
Hello, Nick.
It's you, my first ruffled shirt.
Good to see you. How're they running?
Ahead, Flo, just like you and this little girl.
First time I saw her, I had a hunch you two belonged together.
I have the same hunch. And it's aging me...
...fast.
I knew it. I was sure it was you who told him about me.
- I'm afraid not. I wish I had.
- I don't believe you.
Have it your own way.
And you had it your own way on that stage tonight, didn't you?
Six curtain calls.
Only five.
But you stopped the show.
I did! I stopped the Ziegfeld Follies!
I knew you would. I wrote the card
with your flowers before the curtain went up.
What?
The yellow roses.
I didn't even have a chance to look!
Oh, they're beautiful.
"Dear Star, I told you so."
Don't forget, I saw you work out.
Where would you like to go?
Luchow's? Delmonico's? A party? Two parties?
I can't. I gotta meet a gang of people...
" At my mother's saloon ".
Not again. Can't you skip it?
No, it wouldn't be nice and...
It's sort of a party for me.
You want to come?
I'd love to.
- You mean it?
- Of course.
You'd better think it over. I mean, it's a neighbourhood thing.
It might waste the whole evening for you.
I'll be with you, won't I?
Go ahead, get dressed.
Candidly, Mrs. Brice,
that's a good-looking fellow.
Gorgeous. He reminds me of
Fanny's papa, my ex, also gorgeous.
Wherever he is, he should only stay there, huh?
What do you do anyway?
I mean, between my opening nights?
Live.
Everybody does that.
Hardly anyone does. But I do. And on the side, I gamble.
You just gamble?
Yes. Like you did tonight.
You married?
No, Mrs. Strakosh, I'm not married.
So you're Mrs. Strakosh's married daughter, Sadie.
To a dentist.
Mr. Arnstein, could I interest you
in a friendly little game of poker?
Three-cent limit.
I was hoping you'd ask me.
Oh, good.
Deuces, 10s and jokers wild.
What?
We're out for blood.
Would you care to deal?
All right.
Oh, look!
That's marvellous.
I think he's played a game of poker before, that Mr. Arnstein.
The way he looks to home.
He's a gentleman.
A gentleman fits in any place.
A sponge fits in any place.
To me, when a person's a stranger, they should act a little strange.
Oh, Mom...
I bet.
I call.
I'm afraid you're too good for me.
I see. I got two pair.
It's yours.
Oh, I win, I win, I win!
How much do I owe?
I think 27 cents.
Fine bunch of crooks I introduced you to.
We had a little more practice, that's all.
Oh, Fanny, darling, I'm so happy for your success.
Only one thing could make me happier.
What?
To dance at your wedding.
Come on, children, sit down.
Talk a little.
Should I murder her now
or wait till the party's over?
Now.
No, I like her.
Besides, I've been waiting all evening
for a chance to be alone with you.
Where does that go?
It's the alley.
Come.
Alone at last.
Fanny, congratulations!
- Thanks, Mrs. Nadler.
I had to get up on account of the baby.
He's a regular midnight fisherman!
He'll outgrow it.
Alone at last.
That's Henry Street. You're never alone.
Everybody worries about everybody.
But it's my home and  I love having people care about me.
But I don't see how anyone could help caring about you.
Why, because I'm funny?
Well, that's part of it.
It's a funny thing. I've imagined you practically all over the world:
Paris, London, the Delaware Water Gap.
Everyplace. Everyplace except Henry Street. And here you are.
You've imagined me?
Well, I mean, I thought about you a lot.
Maybe it was your ruffled shirt.
Anyway, you're like a character in a book to me.
And I hadn't read many books, see?
So that makes you kind of...
- I talk a lot, don't I?
- Yes.
But it's one of the things I like best about you.
Boy, have you got good manners.
- It's your turn. Say something.
- All right.
With all these people who care about
you by the blockfull and theatrefull...
...doesn't it ever narrow down
to just one special person?
You mean, like a boyfriend?
I haven't had time.
But don't get me wrong. I mean, I know a million guys.
- After all, I am in the theatre.
- Oh, yes.
Well, see, I've been very busy and...
How about you?
Hundreds of girls, huh?
Oh, thousands!
All gorgeous.
Well, tonight should be a nice change for you.
It is.
Thousands. Wow!
Well. that way, I don't get too involved.
I like to feel free.
You can get lonesome being that free.
You can get lonesome being that busy.
Now, who would think to look at us that we got the same problem?
Fanny, you're an enchanting girl.
I wish I could get to know you better.
So give me six good reasons why not?
Just one.
I have to catch a train for Kentucky early in the morning.
What's in Kentucky?
A half interest in a little farm. I breed horses.
What's the matter, they can't do it alone?
Hey, you all packed?
So, what are you doing around here?
It's late. It's practically morning. I'll walk you to the car.
I' should go in and say good night.
No, it's all right. I'll say it for you.
You know, if you weren't in a show...
...I think I'd have asked you to come with me.
Too bad, isn't it?
I don't know. What with the Follies and an indecent proposal...
...it's been quite a night.
It was indecent, wasn't it?
Very.
Thank God. At least I can tell Mrs. Strakosh things are looking up.
- May I call you when I come back?
- Sure. When's that?
I don't know exactly. I may go right on to Europe or the Coast...
You see, I never have definite plans.
They make me feel too tied down.
But I'll call you.
Goodbye.
Watch your step.
- You the Ziegfeld Girls? - You can't tell?
All right, dear, line up over here.
Conductor, baby. What time is it, and where are we?
It's 7 a.m., miss, and we're in Baltimore.
Baltimore?
Okay, girls, that's it. Smile pretty. Hold it.
Good. All right, girls. Hold it, hold it.
Now, where's that new star...
...Fanny Brice?
Enter the star.
Miss Brice?
Hold it. Perfect. This'll just take a minute, Miss Brice.
How about a smile, Miss Brice?
So shoot the picture.
Now.
Oh, very good.
- Great. - Yes, wasn't it? I loved it.
Fanny!
How wonderful to see you.
And how wonderful you look.
You look good too. The first time I've seen you in broad daylight.
You haven't changed. And I'm glad.
Do you know how long it's been?
Just a year.
And two weeks.
What are you doing here?
I'm waiting for the train from New York.
My train?
That's right.
Fanny, will you have dinner with me tonight?
Tell me all about Mrs. Strakosh, and about you.
When a fellow gets up at 7 a.m. To meet a girl's train...
I came here to meet another girl, named Elsie.
That's good, because I have plans, so you can have dinner with her.
It'll be very dull.
There she is now.
Thanks, Jack. I'll see you at the stables.
- That's my girl Elsie. - Skinny legs, just like mine.
How about dinner? Will you, Fanny?
You always ask me out, don't you?
Whenever you happen to run into me.
- I've never known anyone so polite.
Fanny, l...
But I still have other plans. And I really must go.
Thanks anyway.
Fanny, I can't give up this easily.
I want to see you too much. We've such a lot to catch up on.
Where are you staying? Majestic?
There's a nice little private dining room downstairs.
I'll reserve it for 8:00. I'm going to hope you'll change your mind.
I'll be waiting.
No law against waiting.
People do it all the time.
"No law against waiting," I said.
"People do it all the time."
You should have heard me. I was a regular Theda Bara.
For once in my life, I didn't say too much, I didn't say too little.
I said just enough, then I walked.
You like these flowers in my hair?
Why should I have dinner with him? I'm not hungry.
You like these earrings?
Even if I was hungry, I don't need him to buy my dinner.
Then why are you going?
- I said, why...? - Who said I was going?
Won't you please come in?
May I take your wrap?
That colour looks wonderful with your eyes.
Just my right eye. I hate what it does to the left.
You planning to make advances?
I wasn't planning it, but it does seem possible.
Before dinner or after dinner?
You look beautiful.
You don't have to make leading lady dialogue for me. I'm a comic.
On-stage.
That's where I live, on-stage.
Then you're missing too much.
You said we had a lot to catch up on.
So let's start. I'm here touring with the Follies.
A week here, then a week in Chicago.
Then we rehearse a new show after that. What about you?
My girl Elsie's running in the Baltimore Handicap next Friday.
After that, I'm not sure because...
You never had definite plans.
I remember.
Somebody laid an egg on your table.
What is it?
A blue marble egg.
I got it in Rome ages ago.
It's one of my favourite things, so I thought you might like to have it.
A blue marble egg, and yellow roses...
You went to a lot of trouble even though you weren't sure I'd show up.
I hoped you would.
Just as I hope you like very dry sherry.
I wouldn't know dry from wet.
What are you so angry about?
Who's angry?
I'm sorry if I'm disappointing you in some way, but what did you expect?
You didn't answer my question.
Why are you so angry?
I am not angry! Why don't you answer a question?
Do you think I should be flattered because this time
your train isn't leaving in the morning?
This time you have a few days to kill.
Well I'm not a kid in Sweeney's. You're not slumming anymore.
I never was and you know it.
Don't holler at me!
I'm not hollering. You are.
That's different.
I'm a natural hollerer. Anyway, I answered your silly question.
Look, why don't we cut through all this and get to the point, which is:
Why didn't I call you when I got back from Kentucky?
You got busy.
You forgot.
There could be a hundred reasons.
Just one.
I wanted to stay away from you.
We were heading to something you couldn't possibly have known how to handle.
What makes you think I do now?
If you don't...
...it's time you learned.
Maybe we should order now?
Yes.
Are you sure you want to stay?
Well...
...might as well have dinner.
Very sensible.
Come in.
Paul, I think we're about ready now.
Madame.
Caviar, to begin with?
No, I don't think so.
Pâté Strasbourg?
Good.
Then we'll have filet de boeuf, sauce bordelaise.
Saignant?
Saignant.
Pommes Soufflées, salade d'indives...
Avec du vinaigre et un peu de moutard dedans?
Very good, Paul. Thank you.
Et comme dessert?
Fraises des bois?
Very good. Thank you.
All right?
I would have ordered roast beef and potatoes.
I did.
What's the matter?
If I can't tell when you're ordering roast beef and potatoes...
...how will I know when you're making advances?
You'll know. I'll be much more direct.
I'm calling you. What have you got?
Ace of diamonds...
...jack of spades, nine of hearts...
...four of clubs and two of diamonds.
Take it. I thought you were bluffing.
What do you hear from Fanny?
This morning she telephoned, long-distance.
Oh, yeah? How did she sound?
Two shows in a row, three months on the road.
How do you think she sounded? She sounded tired.
She didn't sound tired.
Excuse me, I made a mistake.
She sounded silly, she kept laughing.
Maybe something strike her comical.
A mother says, "How are you?" That's so comical?
She breaks out laughing.
Another thing about Fanny. On the road, she lives like a mouse.
All day in the hotel, all night in the theatre, never a drop of fresh air.
But suddenly in Baltimore, MD, she's running...
...up streets, down streets, museums, racetracks, graveyards yet.
- Do you think it could be a fellow?
Think? I know.
Who? Who is it?
The ruffled shirt!
The ruffled shirt.
Lady, if you're game for this one, he's on the house.
Nobody in history ever had three.
Start boiling the water.
I'm proud to think that I'm the man who introduced you to your first lobster....
Among other things.
Behave yourself!
I get so mad when I think of what I missed before I met you.
I played Baltimore before but never realized
it was the most beautiful city in the whole world.
It makes me wish you'd come with us tomorrow.
See what you can do for Chicago.
I was going to, I decided yesterday.
Now I can't.
Yesterday you could now you can't,
What happened between yesterday and now?
You were there. Elsie lost the Baltimore Handicap.
I lost Elsie and my shirt.
But I was watching you. You didn't blink an eye.
You didn't lose your ruffled shirt.
No, darling. I never lose that.
Nor my gambling money. Just about everything else.
So...
...I have to take a train for New York at midnight...
...and the Berengaria for Europe tomorrow night.
Stop boiling the water. I just lost my appetite.
What's in Europe?
It's what's on the boat to Europe.
A lot of bored men who have nothing to do for eight days but play cards.
You are going to Europe so you can play cards on the boat?
Fanny, that's how I live. I told you that on Henry Street
and the first night we were here.
Yes, I know....
I know it by heart.
And...
...you don't have to worry. You're not involved.
But I am involved...
...with a girl who has her own work, is too busy to get lonesome.
So we wave to each other from boats and trains.
I better get to the theatre.
Yes, sir.
Fanny, please don't look sad.
You walk back into my life, change everything and walk right out again.
How should I look? Happy?
But I'll be back in your life again, darling. Very soon.
Like last time.
Not a bit like last time.
So, what's different?
I love you.
Do you mean that?
You're not just trying to be polite?
You do mean it.
What do you know?
It's been the most beautiful week in my whole life.
Fanny, I should hurry if I'm to drop you,
get packed and catch that train for New York.
Pick me up at the theatre at 11...
...and I'll go to the station with you.
Oh, why not? Are you afraid I'll cry?
No. I'm afraid I will.
So where have you been since 6:00 this morning?
Walking.
Just walking.
If you're gonna die whenever you say goodbye to a man...
Calling Miss Brice, Miss Fanny Brice.
Right here.
Miss Brice?
Yeah?
You feel better now?
Yeah. Yeah.
Better.
Thank you.
Wait a minute.
- Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
Ten dollars?
Thank you!
From Fanny? The last of the five-cent tippers?
Yeah, I should have made it 20.
Emma. Emma. Where's Emma?
What is it, Fanny?
I am not going to die. That's all.
And I'm not going to Chicago, either.
Are you out of your mund? What are you gonna tell Ziegfeld?
I don't know. I'd better find out.
Would you please get him on the phone for me, Georgia.
Where's Emma? Have you seen Emma?
Where is she? Em?
Miss Fanny?
Be an angel and help me. Hold these.
I'm only gonna take that bag and that one. I'm not going to Chicago.
What do you mean, you're not going to Chicago?
Where are you going?
Empire Limited departing for New York at 8:30 a.m.
... now boarding at track 14.
Fanny... I told him.
Please talk to her, Miss Georgia.
You can't talk to Fanny about anything.
Once Fanny makes up her mind, she makes up her mind.
But somebody has to talk to her.
- Who is it? - Ziegfeld.
You don't need me in Chicago. You still have four other good names...
...besides the tour is over in two weeks anyway.
You've said a lot of idiotic things.
No, Flo.
That's the most unprofessional thing I've ever heard in my entire life!
Hello?
Flo, will you simmer down before your ulcer starts flaring up.
That's funny coming from you. You gave me that ulcer.
Now, listen, Flo, I love the theatre.
I love to hear an audience applaud,
but you can't take an audience home with you!
I want a personal life too and I'm gonna have it.
Why don't you just wish me luck?
She can't stop in the middle... What did he say?
He hung up.
Let me have that phone.
Ladies of the ensemble, adieu.
- Where are you going? - New York.
- Why?
Because I'm going to Europe with Nick Arnstein.
What?
Fanny, you've got to be kidding!
I told you, when I meet a guy I want, I won't make jokes.
Fanny, did Nick ask you to go with him?
No, but...
...when he sees me, he'll be glad.
I hope.
One ticket on the Empire Limited departing
for New York at 8:30 a.m. now boarding at track 14.
Fanny what's the matter with you? Haven't you any pride?
I love the guy he loves me, I want to be with him. It's that simple.
Fanny, you're making a fool of yourself.
Georgia, when something's right for me I do it and this is right for me.
Have you asked yourself if it's right for Nick?
I'll make it right for him!
Don't stick your neck out this way!
Don't do it! Don't do it!
Don't. You mustn't do it.
Would you like all of these out, sir?
- Oh, no. Just these two, please. - Thank you, sir.
Fanny.
Darling!
If you hadn't looked exactly the way you did...
...this could have been embarrassing.
You crazy girl.
What are you doing here?
I figured that if I waited for you to make your fortune...
...how would you know that I wasn't after you for your money?
I promise I'll never tie you down. I promise.
Will that be all, sir?
Yes, steward. Thank you.
Thank you, sir.
I say, I caught your show the last time I was in port.
You were simply marvelous.
- Oh, thank you. - Thank you.
Ring if you need me, Mr. Brice.
Thank you.
Courvoisier, Mr. Arnstein?
Yes, perfect. And a...
...crème de menthe frappé. - Yes, sir.
All right?
Oui, oui, mon chérie.
I like that beard on that captain. Makes him look so trustworthy.
He wants me to bring you to his cabin tomorrow for cocktails.
You're a great success, Fanny, and that's off-stage.
I'm with you, that's all.
I don't know how I ever thought of going without you.
Me neither.
- Nick... - Yes?
Go on, say it.
You went to good schools. I went to practically no schools.
You're Park Avenue, I'm Lower East Side.
Now, now. Don't be a snob..
No, no. What I am trying to say is...
And you don't have to... I mean, I'm all yours anyway, but...
Well, where I come from on Henry Street...
...when two people sort of love each other...
Oh, never mind, never mind.
Well, what do they do when they sort of love each other?
One of them says, "Why don't we get married?"
Is that so?
And sometimes it's even the man.
Really?
Forget the whole thing. Just forget I mentioned it. Wipe it out.
All right.
Thank you.
You know...
...it's pretty much the same where I come from.
Well, why don't you stop making jokes and say it so that I can say...
...I have to think it over, or ask my mother, or turn you down.
I've got a better idea.
What's that?
Have your drink.
Have my drink.
Look, why don't we get married?
When? Here? Tonight? When?
The captain looks like a rabbi.
How? When? tonight? Right now?
When I make a bankroll.
No, I don't care about that.
I do.
I intend to be the head of this family.
You will. You're smarter.
It'll be the way I say or not at all.
Could you win what you need in that poker game tonight?
It's possible.
Well what are you doing here? Go ahead, go play cards.
Wait.
I want to be a Sadie.
A what?
You met Mrs. Strakosh's married daughter, Sadie.
That's a married lady.
I see.
Can I come and watch with you?
Look, my whole future depends on it. Please!
Can you watch with no expression at all?
Whatever happens?
Can I watch with no expression?
I pass.
I'll call.
- I'll call. - I pass.
Call.
I'll call.
Cards?
Just one, please. Thank you.
Three here.
Three.
- Two. - Two.
The dealer takes three.
Up to the opener.
Opener checks.
I'll bet a thousand.
I'm out.
All right.
One thousand and...
...two thousand more.
I'm out.
Well, I think you are bluffing, Mr. Arnstein.
So I'll see you.
Well, I've got three kings here.
I thought you were bluffing.
In this distinguished and expert company?
I wouldn't dare.
I'm afraid this is getting rather dull for you, darling.
Excuse me. I'll be right back.
Good night.
Quit, quit, quit!
It's against my religion to break a winning streak.
Goodbye, Sadie.
Sorry, gentlemen.
Your deal.
What happened?
It's a beautiful night.
I had a stroll around the deck. Did me a lot of good.
Nick!
It's terribly late, Sadie.
You should have been in bed ages ago.
How could I go to bed?
I've been sitting here waiting, hour after hour.
Did you say "Sadie"?
Honey, if this is a hotel, I don't think they're ready for us.
Oh, Nick. Oh, Nick.
It must have cost a fortune.
I made a fortune on the Epsom Derby, didn't I?
I expect to make another with this Florida deal.
So there's nothing to worry about, is there?
So who's worried? Anyway, it's the perfect house for a millionaire.
Nice baby. Open your eyes, look at your daddy.
Baby.
I bought her something. Sort of an add-a-pearl necklace.
An add-a-tooth necklace would be...
Nick, you are absolutely crazy.
She won't be able to wear this until she's grown up.
But she'll know she has it. It'll give her confidence.
Besides, if you play your cards right...
...she might loan it to you until then.
You bet she will. Won't you?
- Fifteen. One more. - Oh, please!
Sixteen.
Look at me. I'm breathing like a whale.
The way that baby slowed me down, I ought to sue her.
She's pretty, isn't she, Eddy?
Frances? She's the cutest little thing I ever saw.
Alive, alert...
But she's pretty.
Yes, Fan, she's pretty. Very pretty. Come on.
Ziegfeld made no mistake hiring you.
Heard from Nick lately?
Yeah, he calls me every night.
From Oklahoma?
Sure. With the phone bills we're getting, he better strike oil.
Come on, let's try this.
Let's go.
One, two, three. One, two, three. One, two, three, four.
Nick!
I can't believe it.
There you are.
Thank you very much.
Is that ghastly sound coming from my daughter?
What is it, honey? What is it, sweetheart? Are you wet?
Welcome home, Mr. Arnstein.
It's good to see you.
What happened? What happened to the baby?
Look who's here, honey.
Frances, that isn't very attractive, dear.
I wish you'd stop.
Thank you, sweetheart.
You've stayed blond, you clever girl.
I hate to say it, Miss Fanny, but we're going to be late for rehearsal.
Just a few more minutes.
Em, would you take the baby up to Hilda for me?
Sure.
Goodbye, my love.
Say bye-bye.
You know what?
This time I think you lost your ruffled shirt.
We struck sand and rock and water.
I think we even struck champagne.
The one thing we didn't strike was oil.
You'll think of something bigger and better
while lying in a hammock at your beautiful country house.
It is beautiful, isn't it?
Nick, it's been absolutely murder dragging myself
back and forth to that theatre every day....
You guessed it.
We better start looking for an apartment in town...
...on 5th Avenue. - Even on 6th. I wouldn't be insulted.
You know what bothers me more than losing the house?
It's the fact that I seem to have lost my poker face.
Just to me, honey. Come on.
Nick.
Tom.
The place looks wonderful.
As you say, a church can look cute, but a gambling house has to look honest.
And be honest.
Come on in here.
Joe, a Scotch and water for Mr. Arnstein.
When did you get back?
A couple of weeks ago.
It's good to see you, Tom.
Well, what took you so long to drop in if it's so good to see me?
We've been moving into a new apartment in town.
I've been helping with the legwork.
My wife has a show opening tonight.
Say, Nick, I'm sorry to hear about those oil wells.
Is it all over town, Tom?
Even made the papers.
But that doesn't mean anything.
It's funny, though.
I once dropped 20,000 on Monday, picked up 30 on Tuesday all in absolute privacy....
The news travels much faster these days.
That big spotlight on your wife lights you up too.
Any action in the backroom?
Now? Yeah, there's a game, but...
Nick.
Just by way of limbering up. Besides, I've got an hour to kill.
I hear they haven't been running too well.
It'll change.
He's not in his seat. I looked down during the number. He's not in his seat.
So maybe the guy's late, ran into an old friend or his watch stopped.
You're getting yourself excited over nothing.
Nothing? People get run over, don't they!
I mean, they have accidents, don't they?
Emma, go call the hospitals. Every one of them.
He could be lying in a street someplace.
Where's my eyeliner? Have you seen my eyeliner?
Hurry up and get dressed, will you?
I'll call 300.
500. Bettor.
No, not for me.
Have a bite, gentlemen. Keep your strength up. Food and liquor right over there.
Nick, it's after 9:00.
Why don't you get out?
No, Tom. Thank you. I'll watch it.
Telephone for you, Mr. Arnstein, in the bar.
It's your wife's maid at the theatre.
Look, tell her I've been detained.
I'll be there in time for the second act. Thank you.
What are you going to do? Shoot the swans?
These lovelies?
My swan girls? What are you, dumb?
Prince!
Was that necessary?
You couldn't walk over here like a person?
Where was I? Oh... I was here.
I'm sorry, darling.
How did it go?
Good reviews?
Wow!
"All any show needs is Fanny Brice."
"New York audiences continue their love affair with Fanny."
Darling, I'm so happy for you.
How was the party?
There was no party.
The guests didn't think the hostess was in the mood for a party.
Not without the host.
Look, let's not fight about this.
Why not?
Isn't just spoiling my opening night worth fighting about?
How do you think I felt out there trying to be funny?
I'm trying to make them laugh.
My own husband not caring enough to be there!
You didn't let your audience suffer because of me.
You're damn right I didn't!
How do you think I felt afterwards in my dressing room,
with people asking me where you were?
How could I say to them that a lousy poker game
was more important than my opening night?
To hell with your opening night!
Why shouldn't the poker game be just as important to me as your opening night?
It's my work, and I haven't had a smash hit for a long time.
But tonight I was winning.
I wouldn't have left that game for anything...
...because I thought maybe, finally, at last my luck had changed.
Only it hadn't.
So it'll change tomorrow.
The way it has a hundred other times.
Everyone has a run of bad luck now and then. It doesn't mean anything.
How would you know, darling?
You never lose.
That was my crazy husband on the phone.
A guy with a deal for me offered Nick a thousand to put in a word.
He took the money......
...and gave it to a waiter he never saw before in his life.
And he just put in a word.
You want to play? Get a deck.
Fanny, I never butted in your life, did I?
Sure, when I was a kid, you made me wear long underwear to school.
Some day when your children grow up and you want to talk serious...
...I hope they make jokes.
I'm sorry, mom.
I thought you were gonna start in on Nick.
Where would I come to criticize Nick? It's you I'm surprised at.
Why?
Because when you look at him, you only see what you want to see.
I see him as he is. I love him as he is.
Fanny, love him a little less.
Help him a little more.
Mama, he doesn't need any help. He's not a child.
The man is drowning. He owes money everywhere.
He doesn't know which way to turn.
What?
How do you know that?
Everybody knows. Only you don't know.
Fanny, are you so wrapped up in the show you can't see anything else?
Why wouldn't he tell me? He knows he can have anything I've got.
That's not what he needs.
Darling, you are his wife.
You've gotta sit down with him, talk to him...
...think together what he should do.
Some of that for me, Nick?
Won't make a dent in what I owe you, Peterson. But if you can't wait...
I could wait. I could even forget it.
In return for what?
I need a front man, someone like you...
...who can talk, for a bond deal I'm putting together.
It's a big one, Nick. You could make yourself a mint.
Thanks, but I don't think so.
I guess when you have Fanny Brice for a meal ticket...
...you don't get very hungry. Nick!
I'm sorry, Peterson.
Meal tickets... ...that's my joke.
Sure.
Is Mr. Branca here yet?
Not yet, Mr. Arnstein.
I expect him any minute.
This yelled through the window from FAO Schwarz:
"Take me home to Frances," it said. So I did.
Will you give it to her for me, please?
Yes, Mr. Arnstein.
Thank you.
Oh, Hilda. You and the cook have been very patient...
...but it's high time I paid your salaries.
I owe you for two months, I believe.
Miss Brice paid us, sir. All that was owed and three months in advance.
I mean, Mrs. Arnstein paid us.
Miss Brice paid you.
I'll get it, thank you.
There you are.
Am I late?
No, I just beat you in. Let's go in here.
I'll mix us a drink. You can tell me what you have in mind.
Hey, nice place, Nick.
It's comfortable and very convenient.
Water or soda, Tom?
Straight. Look, Nick, I haven't got much time.
The place is getting crowded earlier and earlier these days.
When you do that well, it's called good trouble.
That's what I want to talk to you about.
Nick, I didn't know you were home.
Hello, darling.
Mr. Branca, I haven't seen you for ages.
I've been dying to see your show, Mrs Arnstein, but I've been so busy.
I just dropped by to make Nick a little proposition.
If it's some new way of marking cards, Nick, don't listen.
Aside from that, I'll leave you. Although I'm dying of curiosity.
Come back, silly. Get yourself a drink and sit down.
- All right with you, Tom?
Of course. It's all in the family.
Sit down and start propositioning.
All right.
Well, as I told you, the place... No, thanks.
The place is doing awfully well.
So well in fact that a couple of money men approached me
about opening another one on the East Side.
You know, it's getting very fashionable.
I'd like to, Nick. I think it would go.
But I can't possibly run two places single-handed.
And those people don't know the first thing about this business.
So I told them about you.
The long and short of it is, we want you as a partner.
With an extra cut for running the place. How's it strike you?
Pleasantly. I'm flattered, naturally.
And it's no secret there's no place I'd rather be than a gambling club....
Except the theatre on opening night.
Anyway it does sound like something you'd be awfully good at.
I've always had a little yen to run a club. And lots of ideas for it.
Well, then, great. Then it's a deal.
Wait, wait a minute.
It would have to depend on how much
I'd have to put up for the partnership, because...
Nick, we don't need your money. We need you.
Well how much are you and the others putting in?
Fifty thousand.
And for me it's free?
Tom, I can't let you put up my share.
I'm not. I swear I'm not.
Look, our thinking is that with your know-how and your...
...well, class is the only word I can use...
...you'll draw all the right people. We'll make our money back in no time.
A full partnership for nothing? Oh, except my "class."
Plus a cut for running the place.
That's a very generous offer.
Too generous.
Fanny...
How much were you going to put in?
Fifty thousand.
Tom, I'm sorry your time's been wasted.
Nick, it is a good idea.
Was a good idea.
Please don't blame Tom. I talked him into it.
Thanks for everything.
Nick, I was just trying to help.
I don't want that kind of help!
I don't want anyone going around behind my back...
...sinking money into me to make me look good.
Fanny, l...
I just wish you hadn't done it.
You'd better go. You'll be late for the theatre.
I can't go. Not like this.
Darling, listen. Please.
Once I saw how unhappy you are...
...I knew I had to do something.
I guess I did it wrong. You know how dumb I can be.
You don't have to tell me that everything you did you did it out of love.
Believe me, I know that.
Murray Hill 4119.
Peterson?
Arnstein.
Something wrong?
It's Nick.
He's hurt?
No, no. He's in trouble.
He's gotten himself mixed up in a phony bond deal.
So...
...what do I do? I call a lawyer or...?
He's got a lawyer.
Branca got him Bill Fallon.
And Fallon's the best criminal attorney in New York City.
Criminal?
Fanny, embezzlement is a criminal charge.
Now Fallon advised him to give himself up, and he did. A few hours ago.
He gave himself up?
You mean he's in jail?
Uh-huh.
I've got to see him.
You can't, honey. They won't let you.
I just gotta.
Look...
Miss Fanny, is there something I can do?
Fanny, Fanny look.
He doesn't want to see you.
It's understandable, dear. The man's humiliated, ashamed...
Ashamed of what? This is Nick Arnstein, not some hood!
If these bonds were phony, you don't think he knew it, do you?
That's the line Fallon is going to use, that he was a victim, an innocent dupe.
- Fallon is going to call you in a little while at home.
I'd better go.
There are a whole bunch of reporters out there backstage...
Come on to my office and go out through the front of the house.
Why? There's nothing to hide.
You want me to go with you, Fan?
No.
Will you answer some questions, Miss Brice?
Sure, but I don't talk very good yet.
Hold it that pose.
! Did you know Nick was gonna give himself up?
That man will do anything to keep him from coming home for dinner.
Peterson says Nick masterminded the whole swindle, what do you say?
He couldn't mastermind an electrical light bulb out of a socket!
What about these stocks?
Stock? The only stock I know about is summer stock.
What's your husband's story?
There is no story.
My dope was an innocent dupe! Or, my dupe was an innocent dope?
Did he try to sell you any of the bonds?
That much of a dope he ain't.
You realise he might go to prison for this?
At least I'll know where he is nights.
You still love him, Miss Brice?
The name is Arnstein.
Mrs. Arnstein.
Mrs. Arnstein, do you still love him?
Next case.
"The People vs. Arnstein. The grand jury has returned an indictment charging the defendant...
...with embezzlement, according to statute 119, Section A of the penal code."
The defendent has heard the charge. How does he plead?
Your Honour, I move for a postponement of the arraignment.
Why, Mr. Fallon?
My client's been in custody only 24 hours. I've seen him only once.
I've been unable to acquaint him fully with the charges.
Therefore I submit he's unable to enter a plea without full understanding...
Your honour...
Nick, please.
Sorry, Bill.
Your honour, there's no need for a postponement. I understand the charge.
I knew exactly what I was doing.
Nick.
So I wish to plead guilty.
I'll see the deputy D.A. And Mr. Fallon in my chambers.
I'm sorry.
You have only a few minutes.
Thank you.
What happened in there?
The minimum sentence, two years.
With luck, I'll be out in 18 months.
With luck.
Why, Nick?
You had a chance.
All you had to do was say that Peterson tricked you.
I couldn't say that.
Why not?
Because he didn't.
I want you to divorce me.
What are you saying?
We're just no good for each other, that's all. Everybody knows that.
Look, my darling, I may not be good for you...
...but nobody has the right to say what's good for me.
Not even you.
Look, you think I don't know that everything that went wrong was my fault?
I know that.
It's no use, Fanny.
Look, I've tried to tell myself I'll catch up with you.
It'll be all right.
But there's no way I can catch up with you.
I don't want to run anymore. Not in a race I can't win.
Let me go, Fanny. Let me be myself again.
I can't.
I can't just let you go off to prison and say that's that.
Why not? Wouldn't the publicity be good?
I'll be with you in a minute.
I'm sorry, darling. That's what I've turned into.
Nick, you think you mean this, and maybe you do.
But maybe it's just because of all that's happened.
So why don't we just leave it for now...
...and if you still feel the same way when you come home...
...I won't fight you.
Okay?
Okay.
Listen, you take care of yourself.
Go out, see people, do things, enjoy yourself.
I don't worry about you.
The moment you're out there on that stage, nothing bothers you.
Nothing.
The strongest woman in the whole world, that's what you are.
Did you know that?
Yeah, sure.
Everybody knows that.
So long, funny girl.
It cleaned up fine.
You been sitting in that theatre all this time?
Uh-huh
You all right?
Then would you see Mr. Ziegfeld? He's waiting outside.
Yeah.
Flo, come on in.
I'll get your props for you.
Any word from Nick?
No, not yet.
I've been worried about you, Fanny.
I'm sorry you've been worried.
Flo, I don't even know if Nick wants us to go on...
...but if he does...
...I don't want to make the same mistakes.
So if it means giving up the theatre, I hope you'll be a sport about it.
Well, I won't be.
But I won't worry about it until it happens.
- Fifteen minutes, Miss Brice. - Thank you.
I'll let you get dressed.
Be happy, dear
Hello, Fanny.
You must be that fella I met at Keeney's one night.
You must be that girl from Henry Street.
I feel like a kid on a blind date.
Did you see the baby, darling?
No. I came straight here.
She's gorgeous.
Getting to look just like you.
Who says I'm not lucky?
Fanny, l...
I've had 18 months to think about us.
You want to hear something funny?
I've had the same 18 months, and I never thought about us.
I mean, I simmered, I stewed...
...I cried my eyes out...
...but I never really thought.
Not until today.
Then I saw that you were right.
You did a lot for me, Nick.
That's what I'm going to remember.
What did I ever do for you, darling?
What did I ever give you that you couldn't have gotten for yourself?
A blue marble egg.
No one would have given me that but you.
And you...
You made me feel sort of...
...beautiful, you know...
...for a very long time.
You are beautiful.
Five minutes.
There are lots of people waiting for you.
Goodbye, Fanny.
Goodbye, Nick.
SUBS: LFBS