Are you a doctor?
Yes. Yes.
He's an actor.
Oh, an actor.
We're very popular
with actors.
Have l, uh,
seen you in anything?
Let's see. I did Hamlet a while back,
didn't l, Liz?
And then we did, the, uh,
The Sand piper.
He's joking.
He was in Luther
and Nobody Loves An Albatross
and a lot of television
plays and commercials.
Well, that's where the money is,
isn't it? Commercials.
And the artistic thrills, too.
7, Diego.
Originally,
the smallest apartment was in 9.
They've been broken up
into four, fives, and sixes.
Now, 7-E is a four,
originally the back
part of a 10.
It has the original dining room
for its living room,
another bedroom
for the bedroom,
and two servants' rooms
thrown together
for a dining room
or a second bedroom.
Do you have children?
Uh, we plan to.
We must oil that gate,
Diego.
This way, please.
The previous tenant,
Mrs. Gardenia,
passed away
just a few days ago,
so nothing
has been moved yet.
Her son asked me to say
that some of the furniture
could be picked up
practically for the asking.
Did she die
in the apartment?
Not that it makes
any difference.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
In a hospital.
She'd been in a coma
for weeks.
After you, please.
Thank you.
She was very old
and passed away
without ever waking.
I'd be grateful to go that way myself
when the time comes.
Oh, no, no, no, not
in the apartment, no.
She was chipper
right to the end,
Been one of the first women
lawyers in New York state.
Did a little gardening on
the side, too.
She was quite a woman.
Oh, closet.
Oh, plenty of closets.
Oh, nice view of the park.
Oh, very nice view.
"I can no longer associate myself"
Now, this room, for instance,
it would make
a lovely nursery.
Yes. Yellow and white wallpaper
would brighten it
tremendously.
What are all
these things here?
Herbs, mostly.
A nice large bathroom.
Mmm. Mint, basil.
Yeah. No marijuana?
The, uh, master bedroom.
Oh, yes.
Here we are,
back at the hallway again.
There.
Oh...
Oh, Guy!
Yeah.
Ohh!
The fireplace works,
Of course.
Great.
Oh!
Oh, it's a wonderful apartment.
I love it!
See what she's trying
to do?
She's trying to get you
to lower the rent, see?
Yes. Well, we'd raise it
if we were allowed.
Apartments with
this kind of charm--
Why, that's odd.
There's a closet
behind that secretary.
I'm su--
I'm sure there is.
Yeah. Oh, I think you're right.
She moved it.
It used to be there.
Give me
a hand, will you?
I see now why she
went into a coma!
She couldn't have lifted it by herself.
She was 89!
Should we open it?
Maybe her son should.
I'm authorized
to show the apartment.
Well!
Whatever she locked in
got out.
Well, perhaps she didn't need
five closets.
Why would she cover up
her vacuum cleaner and her towels?
I don't suppose
we'll ever know.
Maybe she was becoming
senile after all.
Is there anything else?
Yes, please.
What about the laundry facilities?
It's bigger
than the other one.
Yeah. It's more expensive, too,
you know?
It's better located.
Yeah, well, God knows,
I could walk to all
the theaters from here.
Oh, Guy, let's take it,
please?
That living room
could be--
Oh, please,
let's take it.
O.K., darling,
we get out of the other lease, O.K.
I was tempted
to write the management
that you were drug addicts
and litterbugs.
Instead, I decided to lie
and tell them you
were wonderful tenants.
Oh, you're great, Hutch.
Wish I could talk
you out of it, though.
He's pulling
your leg, Ro, honey.
Indeed I'm not.
Now, that looks great.
That is--
Are you aware
that the Bramford
had rather an unpleasant reputation
around the turn of the century?
It's where
the Trench sisters
conducted their little
dietary experiments,
and Keith Kennedy
held his parties.
Adrian Marcato lived there, too.
So did Pearl Ames.
- Who was Adrian Marcato?
- Who were the Trench sisters?
The Trench sisters were two proper
Victorian ladies.
They cooked and ate several
young children, including a niece.
Oh, lovely.
Adrian Marcato
practiced witchcraft.
He made quite a splash
in the nineties
by announcing that he'd
conjured up the living devil.
Apparently,
people believed him,
so they attacked
and nearly killed him
in the lobby
of the Bramford.
You're joking?
Later, the Keith Kennedy
business began,
and by the twenties,
the house was half empty.
I knew about
Keith Kennedy.
I didn't know that Marcato
lived there.
And those sisters.
World War Il filled
the house up again.
Terrific.
What? The house?
The lamb.
Oh.
They called it
Black Bramford.
But, Hutch, awful things happen
in every apartment house.
Ah, but this house has a high incidence
of unpleasant happenings.
In '59, a dead infant was found,
wrapped in newspaper
in the basement.
Mmm! You really
rouse my appetite.
Have some more wine.
Roman!
Bring me in some root beer
when you come!
Hey, these are shelves.
Hey...
Iet's make love.
Shh!
I think I hear
the Trench sisters chewing.
Oh!
Straight up
to the left.
Here in Daytona, Florida,
it's the 250-CC
100-Mile Classic
with Yamaha leading
the pack on the final lap...
and winning it, as Yamaha takes 7
of the top 10 places.
It's the third straight year for Yamaha,
a clean sweep.
Yamaha is race bred
from champions,
and, as you can see,
we have a model for
every kind of riding.
You know,you really should
Discover the swingin' world of Yamaha.
Why don't you get on,
have a ride?
Come on. Get on.
O.K., come on.
Let'sgo.
Look.
It's great.
I'm sorry. I thought
you were Victoria Vetri, the actress.
I'm sorry.
That's all right.
A lot of people
think I'm Victoria.
I don't see
any resemblance.
Do you know her?
No.
My name's
Terry Gionoffrio.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Rosemary Woodhouse.
Uh, we--we're
new tenants here.
I'm staying with the Castavets,
seventh floor.
I'm their guest, sort of,
Since June.
Our apartment used to be
the back part of yours.
Oh, for goodness sakes.
You took the old lady's apartment.
Mrs., uh...
Yeah, um, Miss, uh...
Gard--Gardenia.
Gardenia. Yeah.
She was a good friend
of the Castavets.
She used to grow all kinds of herbs
and things for her to cook with.
I saw those plants.
Yeah. Well, now,
she grows her own things.
Excuse me a moment.
I have to put the softener in.
What does
your husband do?
He's an actor.
No kidding?
What's his name?
Guy Woodhouse.
He was in Luther
and Nobody Loves an Albatross,
and he does a lot
of television and radio.
Gee, I watch TV
all day long.
I bet I've seen him.
Wow!
Ooh!
I hate this basement.
Yeah, me, too.
It gives me the creeps.
Listen, why don't we come down here
regular together
and do our laundry?
O.K., that would be great.
I have a good luck charm.
It might work
for both of us.
Oh, that's beautiful.
Isn't it?
Mrs. Castavet
gave it to me.
It's good luck.
Anyway, it's supposed to be.
It's got some
stuff inside.
I'm not mad about
the smell either.
I hope it works.
It's a beautiful charm, though.
I've never seen
anything like it.
European.
The Castavets are the most wonderful
people in the world,
bar none.
You know, they picked me up
Off the sidewalk, literally?
You were sick?
I was starving and on dope
and doing a lot
of other things.
They're childless, though.
I'm like the daughter
they never had.
At first, I thought they
wanted me for some kind of sex thing,
but they've turned out to be
like real grandparents.
It's nice to know
there are people like that
when you hear
so much about apathy
and people who are afraid
of getting involved.
I'd be dead now
if it wasn't for them.
That's an absolute fact,
dead or in jail.
You don't have any family
that could have helped you?
A brother in the Navy.
Why, it's impossible
to be 100% sure!
If you want my opinion,
we shouldn't tell her at all!
That's my opinion!
That must be
the partition.
That's the back part
of the original 10 with a dining room,
and there's--
there's a closet over here,
and then there's
a closet over here.
Stay back, huh, lady?
Get back now,
will you, please?
Get back.
There's nothing to see.
Get back,
will you, please?
Jesus.
Get back!
We know her.
What's her name?
Terry.
Terry what?
Ro?
What was her name again?
Terry what?
I don't remember.
An ltalian name.
She was staying with some people
named Castavet,
7-E.
Yeah. We got that already.
Short and sweet.
She stuck it to the window sill
with a band-aid.
Come on. Get back.
Theresa Gionoffrio.
Move on!
You knew her?
Only slightly.
Come on, Ro baby.
Let's go.
Oh! Here they come.
You folks the Castavets
on the seventh floor?
We are.
You have a young woman named
Theresa Gionoffrio living with you?
We do. What's wrong?
Has there been an accident?
You'd better brace yourself
for some bad news.
She's dead.
Jumped out
of the window.
That's not possible!
It's a mistake!
Artie, you want to let these folks
take a look, please?
I knew this would happen.
She got deeply depressed
every three weeks or so.
I told my wife about it,
but she pooh-poohed me.
Well, that--that doesn't
mean she killed herself.
She was a very happy girl
with no reason
for self-destruction.
She must have been cleaning
the windows or something.
She wasn't cleaning
windows at midnight.
Why not? Maybe she was!
Is that her handwriting?
Yeah.
Definitely.
Absolutely.
Thank you.
I'll see this gets back
to you when we're done with it.
I don't believe it.
I just don't believe it.
She was so happy.
Who's the next-of-kin?
She's all alone.
She didn't have anybody,
only us.
Didn't she
have a brother?
Did she?
She said she did.
In the Navy.
News to me.
Do you know where he's stationed?
No, I don't.
She mentioned him to me
in the laundry room.
I'm Rosemary Woodhouse.
Uh, we're in,
uh, 7-E.
I feel just the way you do,
Mrs. Castavet.
She seemed so happy
and full of--
She said wonderful things about you
and your husband,
how grateful she was.
Thank you.
You know anything else
about this brother
except he's
in the Navy?
No, I don't.
It should be easy
to find him.
I'm so stunned.
I'm so sorry.
It's such a pity.
Well, thank you.
Sometimes I wonder how come
you're the leader of anything.
Please don't tell me
what Laura-Louise said
because I'm not interested.
If you'd listened to me,
we wouldn't have
had to do this!
We'd have been
all set to go now
instead of having to start
all over from scratch!
I told you not to
tell her in advance!
I told you she wouldn't
be open-minded!
I told Sister Veronica
about the windows,
and she withdrew the school
from the competition.
Otherwise, we would--
Hello. How are you?
Fine. May I come in a minute?
Yes, of course. Please do.
I just come over
to thank you
for saying those nice things to us
the other night.
Oh, no, please.
There's--
Poor Terry. We thought
maybe we'd failed her some way,
although her note made it crystal clear
we hadn't.
You'll never know
how helpful it was
in such a shock moment.
So I do thank you.
Roman does, too.
Roman's my hubby.
You're welcome.
I'm glad I could help.
Yeah. Well, she was cremated yesterday.
Now we got to forget and go on.
It won't be easy.
We don't have any children of our own.
You have any?
No, we don't.
Oh, well,
there you have it.
Ohh! Oh...
that's a nice--
Look how you put the table!
Now, isn't that interesting?
I saw it in a magazine.
Oh, my. Nice paintjob.
I know.
Ahh...well.
That's nice. What is that?
That's the TV room?
Yeah, well,
only temporarily.
It's going
to be a nursery.
Oh, you're pregnant?
No, not yet.
I hope to be as soon
as we're settled.
Wonderful.
Well, you're young and healthy.
You ought to have
lots ofchildren.
We plan to have three.
I'm dying to see what you did
to this apartment.
The woman who had it before
was a dear friend of mine.
I know.
Terry told me.
Well, did she?
You two had some long talks together
in the laundry room.
Only one.
Oh! Oh, my goodness!
Ah ha ha!
It looks so much brighter.
What do you pay
for a chair like that?
Um, I'm not sure, really.
I think about $200.
What does your hubby do?
He's an actor.
I knew it!
I said it to Roman yesterday.
He's so good-looking.
What movies was he in?
No movies.
He was in two plays
called Luther
and Nobody Loves an Albatross
and a lot of television
and radio.
Listen, Rosemary...
I got a 2-inch thick
sirloin steak
sitting defrosting
right this minute.
Why don't you and Guy come over,
have supper with us tonight?
What do you say?
Oh, no. We couldn't.
Why not?
No, really, that's very kind of you.
Listen--
It would be a real help to us.
Oh...
first night we'll be alone since...
Oh, are you sure it wouldn't be
too much trouble for you?
Oh, honey, if it was trouble,
I wouldn't ask you.
All right.
You go ahead and count on us.
I'll have to check with Guy,
though.
Listen, you tell him
I won't take no for an answer!
Oh! Here's your mail!
Oh! Ads!
Thank you.
Yoo-hoo!
Hey.
Mmm!
Donald Baumgart
got that part.
It's a bad play anyway.
Yeah. Even if it folds out of town,
it's the kind of part
that gets noticed.
Mrs. Castavet was here
to thank me for what
I said about Terry.
She is the nosiest
person I've ever seen.
You know she actually
asked the prices of things?
No kidding.
She invited us to have dinner
with them tonight.
I told her I'd have
to check with you,
but that it would
probably be O.K.
Oh, Jesus! We don't have to do that,
do we, honey?
I think they're lonely.
We get friendly with
an old couple like that,
and we'll never
get rid of them.
They're right
across the wall.
I told her she
could count on us.
You don't have
to sulk about it.
I'm not sulking.
I see exactly
what you mean.
Hell, we'll go.
No, no. What for?
We'll go!
No. We don't have to
if you don't want to.
That sounds so phony,
but I really mean it, really, I do.
Be my good deed
for the day.
O.K., but only if you want to.
We'll make it clear that it's just
for this one night
and not the beginning
of anything, all right?
Oh! Perfect timing!
Come on in.
Roman's fixing us
some vodka blushes.
My, I'm glad you could come, Guy.
I'm fixing to tell everybody
that I knew you when.
Look, dinner isn't ready
just yet,
but sit down there
anywhere.
Take a seat
on the couch.
You'll find yourself
very comfortable.
I seem to have
overfilled the glasses.
No, no, no.
Don't get up.
Generally, I pour these out precisely
as a bartender, don't l, Minnie?
Just watch
the carpet.
But this evening I made
a little too much,
and rather I'm afr--
Oh, there we are.
No, no, no.
Sit down, please.
Now, Mrs. Woodhouse...
Uh, Mr. Woodhouse,
uh, vodka blush?
Yes, thanks.
Have you ever
tasted one?
No, no.
I haven't.
It looks delicious.
Minnie. They're very
popular in Australia.
Now, to our guests--
welcome to our home.
Hear, hear.
Cheers.
Mmm.
The carpet.
Oh, dear.
Brand-new carpet.
This man
is so clumsy!
Do you come
from Australia?
Oh, no, no. I'm from
right here in New York city.
I've been there, though.
I've been everywhere,
literally.
You name a place,
and I've been there.
Go ahead. Name a place.
Fairbanks, Alaska!
I've been there,
been all over Alaska--
Yes--Fairbanks, Juneau, Anchorage,
Nome, Sitka, Seward.
I spent four months
there in '38--
Where are
you folks from?
Well--Well, l--
I'm from Omaha.
Guy's from Baltimore.
Omaha's a good city.
Baltimore is, too.
Do you travel
for business?
Well, business
and pleasure both.
I'm 79, and I've been going one place
or another since I was 10.
You name a place,
I've been there.
Ah! Steak's ready.
Don't rush your drinks, now.
Roman, take your pill!
No Pope ever visits a city where
the newspapers are on strike.
I heard he's going to postpone
and wait till it's over.
Well, that's show biz.
That's exactly what it is.
All the costumes
are rituals,
all religions.
Oh, I think we're offending Rosemary.
No, no.
No, you're not religious,
my dear, are you?
Well, l--I was brought up a Catholic.
Now I don't know.
You looked
uncomfortable.
Well, he is the Pope.
Now, you don't need
to have respect for him
because he pretends
that he's holy.
Now, that's a good point.
When I think what they spend
on robes and jewels!
A good picture of the hypocrisy
behind organized religion
was given, I thought,
in Luther.
Did you ever get to play
that leading part, Guy?
Me? No.
Weren't you Albert Finney's
understudy?
No.
Well, that's strange.
I remember being struck
by a gesture you made
and checking in the program
to see who you were.
Um, what gesture
was that?
Well, I'm not sure now.
It was a reaction--
Oh, I did a thing with my arms
when Luther was having a fit.
It was a kind of
involuntary reach.
That's it! That's it.
It had a wonderful authenticity to it.
Oh, come on.
-No, no. I mean it!
My father was
a theatrical producer,
and my early years
were spent in the company
of Mrs. Fiske, Forbes-Robertson,
Modjeska.
Guy?
Oh, yes, please.
You have a most interesting
inner quality, Guy.
It appears in your
television work, too.
It should take you
a long way, indeed,
provided, of course,
that you get those initial breaks.
Are you preparing
for a show now?
Um, well,
I'm up for a couple parts.
Well, I can't believe
that you won't get them.
Well, I can.
I'd like to have
a spice garden someday.
I guess I'm a country girl
at heart.
You come from a big family?
Three brothers
and two sisters.
Your sisters married?
They have children?
One has two,
the other has four.
There's a chance you'll have
lots of children, too.
We're fertile, all right.
I've got 16
nieces and nephews.
Oh, my goodness!
Would you like me to wash
and you can wipe for a while?
Oh, no.
That's fine, dear.
Now, Roman, will you stop
bending Guy's ears
with your Modjeska stories?
He's only listening
'cause he's polite.
No, no, no, no.
It's very interesting, Mrs. Castavet.
Minnie!
I'm Minnie, he's Roman, O.K.?
O.K.?
O.K.
O.K.!
Terrific.
Just terrific.
Goodbye, darling.
Goodbye.
Thank you
for having us.
Yeah, it was lovely.
Oh, bless you.
Minnie!
Minnie, ya good kid, ya.
Ooh!
About that steak, huh?
Oh, my God!
And the cake.
How did you eat two pieces?
It was weird.
Out of politeness.
That's how I ate two pieces.
Only three dinner plates
that matched.
Shh!
And all that beautiful,
beautiful silver.
We'll be nice.
Maybe they'll will it to us.
Oh!
Yeah.
Guess what they have
in their bathroom.
A bidet.
Jokes for the John.
No.
A book on a hook
right next to the toilet.
Roman's stories are pretty damned
interesting, though.
Yeah?
Never even heard
of Forbes-Robertson before.
I'm going to go over there
again tomorrow night
and hear some more.
You are?
Yeah. He asked me.
Here. Do this damn thing for me,
will you?
I thought we were going to do something
With Joan and Dick Jellico.
- Was that definite?
- Well, it wasn't definite.
We'll see them next week.
You don't have to come along
If you don't want to.
You can stay here.
Yeah, I think I will stay here.
He knew Henry lrving, too.
I mean,
really interesting, you know?
Why did they take
their pictures down?
What do you mean?
Their pictures.
They took them down.
The hooks in the wall
and clean spaces
and the one picture
that is there doesn't fit.
I didn't notice that.
Hi, dear.
We're not bothering you, are we?
This is my dear friend
Laura-Louise McBurney,
Lives up on 12.
Laura-Louise,
this is Guy's wife Rosemary.
Hello, Rosemary.
Welcome to the Bram!
Laura-Louise just met Guy.
She wanted to meet you, too.
Could we come in?
Uh, of course. Please do.
There you are.
Go ahead.
Oh, look what you got.
There's a light.
Oh, gosh!
Isn't that beautiful!
It came this morning.
Are you all right, dear?
You look worn.
Oh, no. I'm fine.
It's the first day of my period.
And you're up and around?
On my first day,
I experienced such pain,
I couldn't move, eat,
or anything.
Dan used to give me gin
through a straw to kill the pain.
Girls today take things
much more in their stride.
They're much healthier
than we were,
Thanks to vitamins, better medical care.
What are those things over there,
seat covers?
Um, cushions for the window seats.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, before I forget.
This is for you
from Roman and me.
For me?
It's just a little present is all.
For moving in.
There's no reason--
It's real old.
It's over 300 years.
It's lovely.
Yeah. The green inside
is called tannis root.
That's for good luck.
It's lovely, but l--
I can't accept it.
You already have.
Put it on.
-Yeah.
Ah, you'll get used to the smell
before you know it.
Yeah, go on.
Ohh, yes.
Well, were his stories
as interesting as last night?
Yes. Did you have a good time?
All right.
I got a present.
It was Terry's.
No kidding?
Kind of pretty, though.
Aren't you going to wear it?
It smells.
There's stuff in it
called tannis root
from her greenhouse.
Not too bad, though.
Tannis, anyone?
Well, if you took it,
you ought to wear it.
Hello.
Yes.
This is he.
Oh, God, no.
Oh, the poor guy.
And, uh...
They don't have any idea
what's causing it?
Oh, my God.
That's awful.
That's just awful.
Yes, I would.
I mean, yes, I am.
I hate to get it
that way, but...
Well, you'd have
to speak to my agent
about that end of it.
Alan Stone.
I'm sure there won't be any problem,
Mr. Weiss,
not as far as
we're concerned.
Thank you, Mr. Weiss.
Guy?
What is it?
Donald Baumgart--
he's gone blind.
He woke up yesterday
and he can't see.
Oh, no.
Oh, I've got the part.
It's a hell of a way
to get it.
Listen, uh...
I have to get out
and walk around.
I understand.
Go ahead.
Baumgart--
Donald Baumgart.
It's a fascinating part.
He'll really
be noticed this time.
He also has an offer
for a lead
in a television
series, Miami Beach.
He's suddenly very hot.
Mm-hmm. I understand
why you're so overjoyed.
Well, it's a difficult
period in his life.
A challenge.
I see.
You know how actors are.
They're all a bit
self-centered.
I'll bet even
Laurence Olivier
is vain
and self-centered.
It's a difficult part.
He's got to work
with crutches
and, naturally,
he's preoccupied.
And he...
well, preoccupied.
I see you had another suicide
up there at happy house.
Oh, didn't I tell you?
No, you didn't.
It was that girl
I told you about,
the drug-addict who was rehabilitated
by this old couple, the Castavets.
I'm sure I told you that.
They didn't rehabilitate her
very successfully,
it seems.
I've been a creep.
It's from worrying if Baumgart
would regain his sight,
rat that I am.
Oh, it's natural.
You're bound to feel
two ways about it.
Even if I'm Mr. Yamaha
for the rest of my days,
I'm going to stop giving you
the short end of the stick.
You haven't been.
Yes, I have.
I've been tearing my hair out
over my career.
Let's have a baby.
All right?
Let's have three babies, one at a time,
all right?
A baby. You know.
Mama, dada, poo-poo.
you know?
You mean it?
Sure, I mean it.
I mean, I even figured out
the right time to start,
Look.
You mean it, really?
No, I'm kidding.
Sure, I mean it.
Oh, Ro, honey, for God's sake,
don't cry.
I won't. I won't.
Here goes nothing.
Mmm-unh! The paint!
The paint!
Good grief.
Nobody, but nobody
has a fire tonight.
Isn't it gorgeous?
I hope we have
the coldest winter ever.
Oh, shit!
Hi, Guy! How are ya?
No, don't let her in.
Not tonight.
Oh, that's very kind of you.
Oh, are you sure
you don't want to come in?
No! I don't want
to bother you.
Good.
Who says
there's nothing to ESP?
Madame and monsieur shall
have ze dessert after all!
Mousse au chocolat.
Or as Minnie calls it--
chocolate mouse.
I was afraid she'd stay
all evening.
She just wanted us
to try it.
Seein' it's one of her specialities.
It was sweet of her, really.
We shouldn't
make fun of her.
Yeah, you're right,
you're right, you're right.
Mmm! It's good.
Has an undertaste.
A chalky undertaste.
I don't get it.
That's silly, honey.
There is no undertaste.
There is.
Come on. The old bat slaved all day.
Now eat it.
-I don't like it.
-It's delicious.
Here. You can have mine.
All right. Don't eat it.
There's always something wrong.
Oh, if it's going to turn
into a big thing--
Look, if you really
can't stand it,
just don't eat it.
Mmm! It's delicious!
No undertaste at all.
Would you turn
the record over, please?
There, Daddy,
do I get a gold star?
You get two of them.
I'm sorry
if I was stuffy.
You were.
...is making a full circle
of the ball park...
It's the Pope
at Yankee Stadium!
...to his specially built
canopy at second base.
Put him out!
Listen to that crowd roar.
Everywhere the Pope
Has been today,
he's received this type
of reception.
As one man put it
This afternoon,
"Perhaps we are being
undignified,
but this is
a special day. "
And a special day
it has been.
That's a great spot
for my Yamaha commercial.
I'd like to give you
a brief summary
of today's
historic happening.
Pope Paul VI arrived
at 9.:27A.M.
What is it?
Dizzy.
Hey.
No wonder.
All that booze.
You didn't eat anything
all day before dinner, huh?
Hey.
Nice.
Sleep is what you need.
A good night's sleep.
We have to make a baby.
Oh, we'll...
we'll do it.
Tomorrow.
There's plenty of time.
Just a nap.
Why are you
taking them off?
To make you
more comfortable.
I am more comfortable.
Sleep, Ro.
Isn't Hutch
coming with us?
Catholics only,
I wish we weren't bound by these
prejudices,
but, unfortunately...
Easy, easy.
You got her too high.
Typhoon!
It killed 55 people
in London
and it's heading this way!
You better
go down below, Miss.
She's awake.
She sees.
She don't see.
As long as
she ate the mouse,
She can't hear.
She's like dead. Now sing.
I'm sorry to hear
you aren't feeling well.
It's only the mouse bite.
You'd better have
your legs tied down
in case of convulsions.
Yes, I suppose so.
There's always a chance
it was rabid.
lf the music bothers you,
Iet me know,
and I'll have it stopped.
Oh, no, no, no.
Please don't change
the program on my account.
Try to sleep.
We'll be waiting up on deck.
This is no dream!
This is really happening!
They tell me you have
been bitten by a mouse.
Yes. That's why I couldn't come
to see you.
That's all right.
We wouldn't want you
To jeopardize your health.
Am I forgiven, father?
Oh, absolutely.
Hey, it's after 9:00.
Uhm.
Five minutes.
I have to be at Alan's
at 10:00.
Eat out.
Like hell I will.
What time is it?
It's 10 after 9:00.
What time did I go to sleep?
You didn't go to sleep.
You passed out.
From now on you get
cocktails or wine,
Not cocktails and wine, hmm?
The dreams I had.
Don't yell.
I already filed them down.
I didn't want to
miss baby night.
A couple of my nails were ragged.
-While I was out?
And it was kind of fun,
in a necrophile sort of way.
I dreamed
someone was raping me.
I don't know,
someone inhuman.
Thanks a lot!
What's the matter?
-Nothing.
I didn't want
to miss the night.
We could've done it
this morning or tonight.
Last night wasn't
the only split second.
I was a little bit loaded myself,
you know?
Oh! Hello there.
Did ya like it?
Oh, yeah.
I think I put a little too much
cream de cocoa in it.
No, no.
It was delicious.
You'll have to give me
the recipe.
Yeah, love to.
Oh, listen, you going shopping?
Do me a teeny favor,
will ya?
Get me six eggs, a small instant Sanka.
I'll pay you later.
Right. Bye-bye.
Don't you think we ought
to talk about it?
About what?
The way you haven't
been looking at me.
What are you talking about?
I've been looking at you.
You haven't.
Why, sure, I have.
Now, what is it?
What's the matter?
Nothing. Never mind.
No, no. Don't say that.
What is it?
Nothing.
Look, honey, l--
I know I've been preoccupied
with the part and all,
but it is important.
That doesn't mean
I don't love you.
It was due on Friday.
It was?
It'll probably come
tonight or tomorrow.
- Wanna bet?
- Yeah.
- A quarter.
- O.K.
You're going to lose.
Shut up, will you?
You're getting me
all jumpy.
It's only been two days.
When will I know?
I'll call you just as soon as I
get the results.
I like to do
a general examination
just to know
something more...
It was Elise Dunstan who recommended
you to me, Doctor.
Oh, yes.
How is she?
She's fine. And the boys are great.
Did you deliver all of them?
No, just the last.
Universal hemoglobin.
Yes, Doctor.
We went to see
The Fantasticks.
-Did you?
-Mmm.
Did you enjoy it?
-Yeah.
Good.
Hello?
Mrs. Woodhouse?
Dr. Hill?
Congratulations.
-Really?
-Really.
Are you there?
Uh, yes, um,
what happens now?
You come see me
next month.
You get those Natalin pills.
One a day.
I'll mail you forms
for the hospital.
Uh, when will it be?
It works out
to be June 28th.
-That sounds so far away!
-It is.
One more thing,
Mrs. Woodhouse,
we'd like another
blood sample.
Oh, yes, of course.
What for?
The nurse didn't take enough,
so would you
drop by and see her?
But I am pregnant,
aren't l?
Oh, yes, it's just for blood samp--
Blood sugar and so forth.
But you're pregnant.
Don't worry.
All right.
Well, I'll come in on Monday.
Don't forget the pills.
No, I won't.
-Goodbye, Mrs. Woodhouse.
-Goodbye, Dr. Hill.
Blood sugar?
What's that?
Oh!
That's great.
That's just great.
Father.
Mother.
Guy, Guy, listen.
Let's, uh, make this
a new beginning, O.K.?
A new openness in
talking to each other,
because we haven't been open.
That's true.
I've been so goddamned self-centered.
That's what
the whole trouble is.
You know I love you,
don't you, Ro?
I do. I swear to God
I'm going to be
as open and--
It's my fault
as much as yours.
No, bull, it's mine.
Now you bear with me.
I'll try and do better,
you hear?
Oh, Guy.
What?
It's...
a fine way for parents
to be carrying on.
Hey...
know what I'd love to do?
What?
Tell Minnie and Roman.
Oh, I know, I know.
It's, uh...
it's, uh, supposed to be
a deep, dark secret,
but I already told them
that we were trying.
They were so pleased.
Tell them.
Back in two minutes?
You're pregnant.
Another blood sample.
Ta-da!
Now, that's what
I call good news.
Aw, honey,
congratulations.
Thank you.
-Best wishes, Rosemary.
-Thank you very much.
We are more pleased
than we can say.
We didn't have any
champagne on hand,
but this will do
just as nicely.
When are you due, dear?
June 28th.
Oh, it's going
to be so exciting.
Listen, dear,
you got a good doctor?
Oh, yes,
a very good one.
One of the top
obstetricians
is a dear friend of ours,
Abe Sapirstein.
Delivers all
the society babies.
Abe Sapirstein?
One of the finest obstetricians
in the country.
Wasn't he on Open End
a couple of years ago?
That's right.
Ro?
Uh...
well, what about Dr. Hill?
Don't worry about Hill.
I'll tell him something.
You know me.
Listen, I won't let you
go to no Dr. Hill
nobody ever heard of.
The best is what you're going to have,
young lady.
Where's your telephone, huh?
It's in the bedroom.
He's a brilliant man.
Very sensitive.
Ro, sit down, sit down.
No, I'm fine.
Abe, Minnie. Fine.
Listen, Abe,
a dear friend of ours
just found out today
she's pregnant.
Yeah, isn't it?
I'm in her apartment right now.
We told her you'd be glad
to take care of her.
You wouldn't charge her none of
your fancy society prices neither.
Well, just wait a minute.
Rosemary, tomorrow morning at 11:00?
All right.
Yeah, 11:00's fine, Abe.
Uh-huh.
Yeah, well, you, too.
No, no, no, no,
not at all.
All right.
Well, let's hope so.
Goodbye.
Well, there you are.
Thanks a million, Minnie.
I don't know how to thank you.
Both of you.
Just have a fine,
healthy baby, that's all.
My, I can't wait to tell
Laura-Louise.
Oh...
uh, please don't tell anyone else,
not right away.
No, she's right.
There's plenty of time.
Now, to a fine, healthy baby.
-Hear, hear.
-Hear!
Andy.
or Susan.
Susan.
Please don't read books.
No pregnancy was ever exactly
like the ones described in the books.
And don't listen
to your friends, either.
No two pregnancies
are ever alike.
Dr. Hill prescribed vitamin pills.
-No pills.
Minnie Castavet
has a herbarium.
I'm going to have her
make a daily drink for you
that'll be fresher, safer,
and more vitamin-rich
than any pills
on the market.
Any questions you have,
call me night or day.
Call me, not your Aunt Fanny.
That's what I'm here for.
-Here.
-What's in it?
Snips and snails
and puppy dogs' tails.
That's fine,
but what if we want a girl?
Do you?
It would be nice if the first one
were a boy.
Well, there you are.
No, really, what is in it?
A raw egg, gelatin, herbs.
Tannis root?
Some of that along
with some other things.
Don't be so violent, Harry.
If you want to be stupid,
be nonviolent stupid,
I'm in love with no one.
Especially not
your fat wife.
I'm a hopeless cripple...
What's that?
I-I've been
to Vidal Sassoon.
Don't tell me
you paid for that.
Guy,
I have a pain.
Where?
Here.
Just now?
Since Monday.
A sharp pain.
Did you see Sapirstein?
I'm seeing him
on Wednesday.
This is ridiculous.
Why don't you see Sapirstein?
Why didn't you say anything?
I see him Wednesday
regular.
An entirely natural
expansion of the pelvis.
You can fight it
with ordinary aspirin.
I was afraid it might be
an ectopic pregnancy.
Ectopic?
I thought you weren't
going to read books, Rosemary.
-It was staring at me in the drugstore.
-All it did was worry you.
Will you go home
and throw it away, please?
The pains will
be gone in two days.
Ectopic pregnancy!
I look awful.
What are you talking about?
You look great!
It's that haircut
that looks awful.
You want the truth, honey,
that's the worst mistake
you ever made.
My God!
It's Vidal Sassoon.
It's very in.
What's wrong with you?
Do I look that bad?
Terrible!
You're not on one
Of those Zen diets, are you?
No.
Then what is it?
Have you seen a doctor?
Hutch, I might
as well tell you.
I'm pregnant.
Oh, rubbish.
Pregnant women gain weight.
They don't lose it.
I don't sleep well.
I have stiff joints or something,
so I get a pain.
Nothing serious.
Well, congratulations.
You must be very happy.
Oh, I am.
We both are.
Who's your obstetrician?
Abraham Sapirstein.
Oh! He delivered two
of my daughter's babies.
He's one of the best
in the city.
When did you
see him last?
Um, yesterday.
And?
And he says
it's fairly common.
How much weight
have you lost?
Uh, 3 pounds.
Nonsense. You've lost
far more than that.
It's perfectly normal
to lose a little at first.
Later on, I'll be gaining.
Well...
we must assume Dr. Sapirstein
knows where of he speaks.
He should.
He charges enough.
We're getting
bargain rates.
Our neighbors are
close friends of his.
I'll go.
Stay where you are.
It hurts less
when I move around.
Oh, I was just
talking about you.
Favorably, I hope.
Do you need anything
from outside?
No. Thank you for asking.
Is Guy home already?
He won't be home till 6:00.
Oh.
A friend of ours is here.
Would you--
would you like to meet him?
If I won't
be intruding.
No. Please come in.
Hutch, this is Roman Castavet.
Edward Hutchins.
How do you do?
Oh, how are you, sir?
I was just telling Hutch
that it was you and Minnie
who sent me
to Dr. Sapirstein.
Oh, so Rosemary has told you
the good news.
Yes, she has.
We must see that
she gets plenty of rest.
I was a bit alarmed
by her appearance.
Well, she has lost
some weight,
but that's quite normal
for the early months.
Later on, she'll gain,
probably far too much.
So I gather.
Please sit down.
Mrs. Castavet makes
a vitamin drink for me every day
from fresh herbs
she grows.
Yes, all according to Dr. Sapirstein's
directions, of course.
He's inclined
to be suspicious
of commercially prepared
vitamin pills.
Indeed?
But surely they're manufactured
under every imaginable
safeguard.
That's quite true,
but commercial pills
can sit for months
on a druggist's shelf
and lose a great deal
of their original potency.
I hadn't thought of that.
I like the idea of having everything
fresh and natural.
I'll bet expectant mothers
chewed bits of tannis root
when nobody'd even heard
of vitamin pills.
Tannis root?
It's one of the herbs
she puts in the drink.
Or is it an herb?
Can a root be an herb?
You sure you don't mean anise
or orris root?
No, tannis.
Look.
It's good luck, too.
Ish!
Doesn't look like,
uh, root matter,
more like mold or fungus
of some kind.
Is it ever called
by any other name?
Not to my knowledge, no.
Tannis. I must look it up
in the encyclopedia.
What a pretty holder
or charm or whatever it is.
The Castavets gave it to me.
You and your wife
seem to be taking better care
of Rosemary
than her own parents.
We're very fond of her.
And of Guy, too.
Now if you'll excuse me,
I'll have to go.
My wife is waiting for me.
It's a pleasure
to have met you.
Oh, don't bother, Rosemary.
We'll meet again, I'm sure.
I just noticed
he has pierced ears.
Pierced ears
and piercing eyes.
What's she like?
Nosy.
Funny.
Guy's gotten
very close to them.
I suppose they've become
sort of parent figures for him.
And you?
I--I don't know.
Sometimes I think they're too friendly
and helpful.
Hey, what a surprise.
How are you, Hutch?
Good to see you.
You're the surprise.
What happened?
They stopped for a rewrite,
those dumb bastards.
Ah, stay where you are.
Nobody move.
Would you like some coffee?
Love some!
Loot!
Seems congratulations
are in order.
Yeah, it's wonderful,
isn't it?
When's the baby due?
June 28th.
Did you know
that Dr. Sapirstein
delivered two of
Hutch's grandchildren?
-Really?
-Mmm.
I met your neighbor.
Roman Castavet.
Oh, did you?
Funny old duck,
isn't he?
Did you ever notice
he has pierced ears?
-You're kidding.
-No, I'm not. I saw.
It's a shame we haven't
seen more of you lately,
but with me being so busy
and Ro being the way she is,
we really haven't
seen anyone.
Perhaps we can have dinner
together soon.
You're not going,
are you?
Thanks for the coffee, my dear.
Thank you for coming,
my dear.
This isn't mine.
It must be yours, right?
Right you are.
Have you thought about names,
or is it too soon?
Andrew or Douglas
if it's a boy,
Melinda or Sarah
if it's a girl.
Sarah? What happened to Susan?
Say, is there another
of these around?
Oh.
I don't see it, Hutch.
No, it's not here.
I probably left it
at the City Center.
I'll stop back there.
Let's really have that dinner,
shall we?
Definitely.
Next week.
Bye.
Goodbye.
- Bye.
It was a nice surprise.
Guess what he said.
What?
I look terrible.
Good old Hutch.
He's spreading cheer
wherever he goes.
I'm going to get a paper,
honey.
He's a professional crepehanger.
He's not a professional
crepehanger.
Then he's one of the top-ranking
amateurs.
Hello.
Oh, uh, she's not
feeling too well.
Well, I think she's asleep.
All right.
Oh, she could be, yeah.
All right,
can you hold on a minute?
It's Hutch.
He wants to speak to you.
Oh.
I told him you were resting,
but he said he couldn't wait.
Hutch?
Tell me, dear,
do you go out at all?
Well, I--I haven't been going out,
why?
Can you meet me
tomorrow morning at 11:00
in front of
the Time-Life building?
Yes, if you want me to.
What is it?
Can't you tell me now?
I'd rather not.
We can have an early lunch
if you like.
That would be nice.
Good. 11:00 then?
O.K.
Oh, did you find your glove?
No, they didn't have it.
Good night, Rosemary.
Sleep well.
You, too.
Good night.
What was that?
He wants to talk to me.
What about?
I don't know.
He wouldn't say.
I think those
boys' adventure stories
are going to his head.
Where are you meeting him?
Uh, Time and Life building
tomorrow at 11:00.
This is ridiculous.
You're pregnant,
I've got the yens.
I'm getting an ice-cream cone.
You want one?
Yeah, I'd love one.
Vanilla?
O.K.
Hi.
Minnie, I'm going out now,
so I won't have
my drink at 11:00.
That's fine, dear.
Take it later.
Buzz me when you get back,
huh?
Pain, be gone.
I will have no more of thee.
Yes?
Is this Edward Hutchins'
apartment?
Yes. Who is this, please?
My name is
Rosemary Woodhouse.
I had an appointment
with Mr. Hutchins.
Is he there?
Hello?
He was taken ill
this morning.
-Taken ill?
-Yes.
He's in a deep coma at St. Vincent's
hospital.
That's awful.
I--I--I just spoke to him
last night about 10:30.
I spoke to him
at 11:00.
Who is this?
You don't know me,
Rosemary.
I'm Grace Cardiff,
Hutch's friend.
Um, do they know
what's causing it?
No, they don't know yet.
At the moment, he's
totally unresponsive.
Oh, I'm going
to the hospital now.
Is there anything
I can do?
Not really.
All right, um,
thank you.
No!
This is what I call
the long arm of coincidence!
I said to myself,
as long as Rosemary's going out,
I might as well go out and do
a little bit of Christmas shopping.
Now here you are, here I am.
Isn't that something?
Aw, darling,
what's the matter?
You feel all right?
Aw...
aw, you poor thing.
You know
what I think?
I think we better
be going home now.
What do you say?
No, no, you have
your shopping to do.
Ah, shoot,
there's two more weeks.
It'll stop any day now.
It's like a wire inside me
getting tighter and tighter.
Usually older women
with less flexible joints
have this sort of trouble.
I'm not going out anymore.
You don't have to.
One minute to go!
Rosemary,
I want you to meet Dr. Shand.
He used to be
a famous dentist.
He made the chain
For your charm.
Oh, how do you do?
Come on, sweetie.
Put this wonderful hat on.
Doctor, come over here.
Minnie, Minnie.
Happy New Year.
Have a good year.
To 1966!
The Year 1 !
What the hell are you doing?
Planning the menu.
We're having a party
a week from Saturday.
It's for our old--
I mean, our young friends.
Minnie and Roman
are not invited.
Neither is Laura-Louise.
Nor is Dr. Sapirstein.
It's going to be
a very special party.
You have to be
under 60 to get in.
Well.
For a minute there,
I didn't think
I was going to make it.
You'll make it,
all right.
You can be bartender.
Oh, swell.
Do you really think
it's such a good idea?
I think it's the best idea
I've had in months.
Don't you think you ought to check
with Dr. Sapirstein first?
What for?
I'm just giving a party.
I'm not going to swim
the English Channel.
What about the pain?
Oh, haven't you heard?
It'll go away
in a day or two.
That looks interesting.
What's it for?
We're having some people
over on Saturday.
Oh, you feel up
to entertaining?
Yes, I do.
These are old friends
I haven't seen
in a long time.
They don't even know yet
that I'm pregnant.
I'll give you a hand
if you like.
I'll help you
dish things out.
No, thank you, Minnie,
but I can manage.
It's going
to be a buffet,
and we're getting
a bartender, so...
I'll help you
take the coats.
No, really,
you do too much for me as it is.
Well, let me know
if you change your mind.
Drink your drink now.
I'd rather not.
Not right this minute.
I'll drink it
in a little while.
It don't do
to let it stand.
No, I won't wait too long.
You go on back, and I'll bring
the glass back to you later.
I'll wait.
I'll save you the walk.
You'll do no such thing.
It makes me very nervous
when people
watch me cook.
Now, scoot.
Don't let it
stand too long.
It's going to lose its vitamins.
You dirty, stinking secret-keeper.
Congratulations!
-Congratulations.
-Thank you.
-Hey, Rosie.
-Yeah?
Bob and Leo got stuck
at another party, dear,
but they'll be over
right away.
Oh, fine.
Oh Rosie, you're so lucky.
It's a fantastic house.
Hi.
It's been so long!
You look like
a piece of chalk!
You make him
feed you, luv.
-Adrian Marcato lived here.
- Yeah, and the Trench sisters.
-Trent sisters?
-Trench. They ate little children.
He doesn't just mean
they ate them.
He means
I made their first one strong
to get them happy,
then I go light
and conserve, eh?
Rosie, do you feel O.K.?
You look a little tired.
Thanks for the understatement.
How do you like C.C. Hill?
Isn't he a dream boy?
Mm-hmm, but I--I--
I'm not going to him.
You're not?
I've got another doctor
named Sapirstein, an older man.
Oh, congratulations, Papa.
Thanks. Weren't nothing to it.
Ro, I'm going to take
that dip inside.
Oh, yeah, please.
See my flowers?
Yeah.
Elise, will you give me a hand?
Oh, yeah, sure.
Hey, whatever happened
to the other guy?
-Is he still blind?
-Donald Baumgart?
Well, you know who he is.
He's the boy that Zoe Piper
lives with.
He's writing a play.
-Is he still blind?
-Excuse me.
Yeah. He's going through hell
trying to make
the adjustment.
He dictates
and Zoe writes.
Are you all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
I just had a cramp
for a minute.
Don't cry.
It's all right. It's good for her.
Let her cry it out.
It's all right, darling.
It's all right.
Sit down, sit down.
-Hey, let me in.
-Sorry, girls only.
-I want to talk to Rosemary.
-You can't. She's busy.
I have to wash these--
Use the bathroom.
It hurts so much!
I'm so afraid
the baby's gonna die.
When did the pain start?
Um...
in, uh, November.
November?
What?
You have been in pain
since November,
and he's not doing anything
to help you?
He says it's gonna stop.
Why don't you go
to see another doctor?
No, he's very good.
He was on Open End.
He sounds like
a sadistic nut.
Rosemary,
pain like that
is a warning that
something isn't right.
Go see Dr. Hill.
Go see anybody
besides that...that...
That nut.
You can't go on
suffering like this.
I won't have
an abortion.
Nobody's telling you
to have an abortion.
Just go to see another doctor,
that's all.
The thing to do now
is move.
Guy?
Yeah?
I'm going to Dr. Hill
Monday morning.
Dr. Sapirstein is either lying,
or he's...
I don't know,
out of his mind.
Pain like this is a warning
something's wrong.
Rosemary...
and I'm not drinking
Minnie's drink anymore.
I want vitamins and pills
like everyone else.
I haven't drunk it
for the last three days.
I've thrown it away.
You've what?
I've made
my own drink.
Is that what those bitches
were giving you in there?
And is that
their hint for today?
They're my friends--
They're a bunch of
not very bright bitches
who ought to mind
their own goddamn business!
All they said was
get a second opinion.
Rosemary, you got the best doctor
in New York.
You know
who Dr. Hill is?
He's a Charlie Nobody.
That's who he is!
I'm tired of hearing
how great Dr. Sapirstein is.
Well, we'll have to pay Sapirstein,
we'll have to pay Hill.
It's out of
the question.
No, I'm not changing.
I just wanna go to Dr. Hill
and get a second opinion.
I won't let you do it, Ro.
I mean,
because it's, uh...
it's not fair
to Sapirstein.
Not fair to...
What are you
talking about?
What about
what's fair to me?
You want
a second opinion?
You tell Sapirstein
and let him decide who gives it.
No! I want Dr. Hill!
At least have
that much courtesy--
If you won't pay,
then I'll...
Ro?
Rosemary?
What is it?
It stopped.
What?
The pain stopped
just like that.
Stopped?
-Stopped.
What was in
that drink you made?
Uh...
eggs, milk, sug--
sugar.
What else?
Come on, Rosemary, for Christ's sake,
what else was in that drink?
It's alive!
Guy, it's moving!
It's all right!
Feel.
Oh, yeah, I felt it.
Don't be scared.
It won't bite you.
It's wonderful.
It really is.
I feel it kicking.
It's alive!
It's moving!
I'll, uh, clean up
some of this mess.
Watch the walls.
Thanks, boys.
Have one on the baby.
Thank you very much.
What's that for?
This is
my hospital suitcase.
Honey,
you got three weeks.
Yes?
Hello, Mrs. Cardiff.
No.
Oh, my God.
Yes, of course I will.
Hutch is dead.
I feel awful.
All this time,
I didn't even think of him.
Doris, we'll see you later.
I beg your pardon.
I'm Mrs. Woodhouse.
I knew your father.
Oh, so you're Rosemary.
I'm terribly sorry.
Thank you.
This is my sister Edna.
How do you do?
And my husband.
I'm sorry to be late.
Excuse me.
Yes?
I'm Grace Cardiff.
I was hoping to meet you.
Thank you for calling me.
I was going to mail this,
but then I thought you
were going to be here.
What is it?
-A book.
Hutch regained consciousness
at the end,
and he thought it was
the next morning.
You know,
when you had the appointment.
Oh, yes.
I wasn't there,
but he told the doctor
to make sure you got the book
that was on his desk.
Thank you.
Oh, and I'm to tell you
the name is an anagram.
The name of the book?
Apparently.
He was delirious,
so it's hard to be sure.
I heard you come in.
It certainly
wasn't very long.
I was late.
I couldn't get a taxi.
Oh, what a shame.
Oh, you got mail already?
Somebody gave it to me.
Here. I'll hold it.
Book.
Oh, I know that house.
The Gilmores used to live there.
Oh?
-Yeah.
I've been there
lots of times.
Grace-- That's one
of my favorite names.
Yes.
You need anything?
Nothing, thank you.
Take a nap,
why don't you?
I'm going to.
Yeah. Goodbye.
"Born in Glasgow in 1846,
He was soon after
brought to New York.
He resided for several years
in the United St--
He was attacked by a mob
outside the Bram..."
Outside, not in the lobby.
There are no witches.
Not really.
The name is an anagram.
Now, that really makes sense.
Poor Hutch.
Ro?
What's with the chain?
What's the matter?
You all right?
-I'm fine.
Oh.
Oh, why, thank you.
How was the funeral?
O.K.
Got the shirt
that was in the New Yorker.
I got that shirt
That's nice.
Do you know
who Roman really is?
What do you mean,
honey?
He's Adrian Marcato's son.
What?
Come here.
I want to show you something.
Roman Castavet
is Steven Marcato rearranged.
It's from Hutch.
Look.
And look here.
There he is when he was 13.
See the eyes?
Coincidence.
In the same house?
And look. Look here.
"Soon after that
in August, 1886,
his son Steven
was born."
1886. Got it?
That makes him 79 now.
No coincidence.
No, I guess not.
He's Steven Marcato,
all right.
Poor old geezer.
With a crazy father
like that,
no wonder he switched
his name around.
You don't think
he's the same?
What do you mean,
a witch?
Ro, are you kidding?
Oh, Ro, honey.
His father was a martyr to it.
Do you know how he died?
Honey, it's 1966.
This was published
in 1933.
There were covens
in Europe.
That's what they're called--
the congregation.
Covens in Europe, in America,
and in Australia,
and they have one right here,
that whole bunch.
The parties with the singing
and the flute and the chanting,
those are esbats or sabbaths
or whatever they're called.
Honey, don't get excited.
Read what they do, Guy.
They use blood
in their rituals.
The blood that has the most power
is baby's blood.
And they don't just use the blood,
they use the flesh, too.
Rosemary,
for God's sakes!
They're not setting foot
in this apartment ever again.
They're not coming within 50 feet
of the baby.
They're old people.
They have a bunch
of old friends.
Dr. Shand happens
to play the recorder.
I'm not taking any chances
with the baby's safety.
We're gonna sublet
and move out.
We are not.
-Oh, yes we are!
We'll talk about it later.
I don't think you ought
to read any more of that.
-Just this last chapter.
-Not today, honey.
Look. Your hands are shaking.
Come on. Give it to me.
Read it tomorrow.
-Guy!
I mean it, now.
Give it to me.
Fantastic.
Absolutely fantastic.
What'd you say the name was,
"Marchado"?
Marcato.
He told me his father
was a coffee importer.
He told Guy
he was a producer.
I understand
how disturbed you must be
to have him for
a close neighbor.
I don't want anything more
to do with him or Minnie.
I can't take even the slightest chance
for the baby's sake.
Absolutely.
Any mother'd feel the same way.
Is there
any chance at all
that maybe Minnie put something
harmful in those drinks
or in those
little cakes?
No, Rosemary, I'd have seen evidence
of it long ago.
I won't take anything else
from them.
You won't have to.
I can give you some pills
that'll be adequate
these last few weeks.
In a way,
this may be the answer
to Minnie's and
Roman's problem, too.
What do you mean?
Roman's very ill.
In fact, confidentially, he has
no more than a month or two left.
I had no idea.
He wanted to pay a last visit
to a few of his favorite cities.
They didn't want
to offend you
by leaving before
the baby's birth.
I'm sorry to hear
that Roman isn't well.
He'd be
extremely embarrassed
if he knew
what you found out.
Suppose we do this.
I'll tell him
to leave on Sunday.
I'll say I spoke to you
and you understand.
Are you sure they'll
leave on Sunday?
I'll see to it.
No matter
where we are,
our thoughts are gonna be with you
every minute
till you're all
happy and thin again.
Your sweet little boy or girl
laying safely in your arms.
Thank you.
Thank you for everything.
Yeah. You make Guy
send us lots of pictures, ya hear?
Yes, I will.
Now, I'm not going
to wish you good luck
because you
won't need it.
You're going to have
a happy, happy life.
Have a good trip
and come back safely.
Perhaps. But I may stay in Dubrovnik
or Pescara
or maybe Majorca.
We shall see,
we shall see.
Come back.
Bye, Minnie.
Yeah, goodbye.
Goodbye, Roman.
Bye-bye.
Take care now.
Kennedy Airport,
Pan Am Building.
Bye!
Bye, Roman.
Oh, boy.
Guy?
Hmm?
Where's my book?
Oh, I put it
in the garbage.
What?
I didn't want you
upsetting yourself anymore.
Guy, Hutch gave me that book.
He left it to me.
I wasn't thinking
about that.
That's a terrible thing to do.
I'm sorry.
I wasn't thinking about Hutch.
Hey, watch out, lady!
"Some cultures believed that a personal
possession of the victim is necessary
and spells cannot be cast
without one of the victim's
belongings."
Yeah?
Is this Donald Baumgart?
That's right.
This is Rosemary Woodhouse,
Guy Woodhouse's wife.
Oh, yes.
I want to know--
You must be
a happy little lady,
living in the Bram,
rows of uniformed lackeys.
I wanted to know
how you are,
if there's been
any improvement.
Well, bless your heart.
Guy Woodhouse's wife, huh?
Well, I'm splendid.
I only broke
six glasses today.
Guy and I
are both very unhappy
that he got his break
because of your misfortune.
Aw, what the hell.
That's the way it goes, right?
I'm sorry I didn't come along that day
he came to visit you.
V-Visit?
Oh, you mean the day
we met for drinks?
Yes, that's what I meant.
By the way,
he has something of yours, you know.
What do you mean?
Don't you know?
No.
Didn't you miss anything
that day?
You don't mean my tie,
do you?
Yes.
Oh, well, he's got mine,
and I've got his.
He can have it back.
I'm sorry.
Doesn't matter to me now
what color tie I'm wearing.
I didn't understand.
I thought he'd only borrowed it.
Oh, no.
It was a trade.
Or...
do you think
he stole it?
I have to hang up now.
I just wanted to know if there'd been
any improvement.
No, no, there isn't.
It was nice of you to call. Bye.
You aren't in labor,
are you?
No, but I have
to see the doctor.
It's very important.
But he has to leave
at 5:00,
and there is Mrs. Byron.
I'm sure he'll see you.
Just sit down.
Thank you.
How is it out there?
Oh, awful. 94.
Ugh!
See you next week.
Make an appointment.
Yes, I will.
You're due any day now,
aren't you?
Tuesday.
You're smart to get it over with
before August.
Mrs. Byron.
He'll see you right after.
Well, let's see, um...
July the 10th?
What time?
4:00?
Fine.
All right.
See you then.
Thank you.
-Bye-bye.
Good luck.
Thank you.
Mmm! That smells nice.
What is it?
Oh, my--
It's called detchema.
Well, it's a big improvement
on your regular,
if you don't mind
my saying.
That wasn't a perfume.
That was a good luck charm.
I threw it away.
Good.
Maybe the doctor will follow
your example.
Dr. Sapirstein?
Yes. The aftershave.
Well, it isn't, is it?
I don't think he has
a good luck charm.
Anyway, he has the same smell
once in a while.
When he does--
Oh, boy.
Haven't you ever noticed?
No.
Well, maybe you thought it was your own
you were smelling.
What is it,
a chemical thing?
Will you excuse me a moment,
please?
My husband
is waiting outside.
I have to go
and tell him something.
I'll be back in a minute.
Dr. Hill's office.
Dr. Hill, please.
This is his
answering service.
Would you like
to leave a message?
Um, yes.
My name is Rosemary Woodhouse.
Woodhouse.
And would you ask him to call me back
right away, please?
Uh, my number is
475-2598.
It's an emergency.
I'm in a phone booth.
All right.
Quickly, please,
Dr. Hill, call me.
Oh, oh, really?
Did he really say that?
Oh, he didn't say that.
What else was it
that he said?
Oh, that's wonderful.
That's wonder--
That's marvelous.
Yes. Dr. Hill?
Did I get the name right?
Is it Rosemary Woodhouse?
Yes.
Are you Dr. Hill's patient?
No.
Um, yes, I mean,
well, I've seen him once.
Um, please, please tell him
he has to speak to me.
It's important.
Tell him to call me, hmm?
-All right.
-Thank you.
All of them.
All in it together.
All of them witches.
Don't you worry,
little Andy or Jenny,
I'll kill them before
I let them touch you.
Yes. Dr...
Mrs. Woodhouse?
Yes!
Oh, thank you,
Thank you for calling me.
Thought you were
in California.
No. No, I've been
to another doctor,
and he isn't good,
Dr. Hill.
He's been lying to me
and giving me unusual kinds
of drinks and capsules.
The baby's due
on Tuesday.
Remember you told me
June 28th?
Well, I want you
to deliver it.
Mrs. Woodhouse...
Please let me
talk to you.
Let me come and explain
what's been going on.
I can't stay too long here.
They'll be coming,
looking for me.
Dr. Hill?
Dr. Hill,
there's a plot--
I know that sounds crazy.
You're probably thinking,
"My God, this poor girl
has really flipped,"
but I haven't flipped,
Dr. Hill, I swear.
By all the saints,
I haven't.
There are plots against people,
aren't there?
Yes, I suppose there are.
Well, then there's one against me
and my baby.
Come to my office
tomorrow after 5:00.
No!
Right now.
Mrs. Woodhouse,
I'm not at my office now.
I'm home. I've been up
since yesterday morning.
I beg you.
I can't stay here.
My office at 8:00.
-Yes, thank you.
Oh, wait! Dr. Hill?
Yes?
My husband may call you,
asking--
I'm not gonna speak to anyone.
I'm gonna take a nap.
Thank you.
Keep the change.
Uh, driver, please,
could you wait and watch until--
until I'm inside the door?
He lied to you.
He said we were
going to Hollywood.
The worst thing of all,
he's involved
with them as well.
He sleeps in pajamas now.
He never used to before.
He's probably
hiding a mark.
You know they give you marks
when you join--
All sorts of rituals.
They hold sabbaths there.
You could hear them singing
through the wall.
Guy, my husband Guy
said it was Dr. Shand,
one of these people
playing a recorder.
Now, how did he know
it was Dr. Shand
unless he was there
with them?
Um, they're very clever people.
They planned everything right
from the beginning.
They probably made
some sort of deal with Guy.
They gave him success,
and he promised them our baby
to use in their rituals.
I know
this sounds crazy,
but I've--I've got books here.
Look.
There was another actor like him,
Donald Baumgart,
and they put
a spell on him.
They cast a spell on him
and made him blind
so that Guy
could get his part.
Look, here.
I had this friend
Edward Hutchins.
Maybe you heard of him,
a writer.
He wrote stories
for boys.
Anyway, he was my good friend
since I first came
to New York.
May I keep this?
Yes, please,
and, look, anyway,
once Mr. Hutchins
came to visit me--
Came to visit me. It was the time
I was having this pain, Doctor.
I was suffering so-- You can't
imagine how much I was suffering,
and they wouldn't help me.
Nobody would.
They were giving me a drink
with tannis root in it.
Also witches' stuff,
tannis root.
Hutch came, and he immediately saw
something was wrong.
He--He knew about witches,
you see.
Suddenly, Guy rushed in with his makeup
still on,
which he never did.
They probably
called him to come home
and steal one of
Hutch's belongings,
which he did.
Took his glove,
and they put a spell
on him, too.
Put him in a coma.
Three months later, he died.
Now, maybe all of this
is coincidence,
but one thing
is for sure.
They have a coven
and they want my baby.
Certainly seems that way.
I was afraid you
wouldn't believe me.
I don't believe
in witchcraft,
but there are plenty of maniacs
and crazy people in this city.
The doctor's name is Shand,
you say?
N-No, Dr. Shand is
one of these people.
The doctor's name
is Sapirstein.
Abraham Sapirstein?
Yeah.
Do you know him?
I've met him once or twice.
To look at him,
you'd never think he--
No, you wouldn't.
Not in a million years.
Would you like to go
into Mount Sinai right now,
this evening?
Yeah, I would love to.
Would that be possible?
It's difficult,
but we'll try.
I want you to lie down
and get some rest.
Yes.
Anything they've got,
even a broom closet'd be fine.
I hope we can
do better than that.
I'll see what I can do,
then I'll check you over.
Oh, should I undress now?
No. It'll take me about
a half-hour on the telephone.
You just lie down, rest.
O.K.?
O.K.
God bless Dr. Hill.
Everything's going to be O.K. now,
Andy or Jenny.
We're going to be in a nice,
clean hospital
with no visitors.
Oh.
Monsters.
Unspeakable.
I was sleeping.
Come with us quietly,
Rosemary.
Don't argue or make a scene
because if you say anything more about
witches or witchcraft,
we're going to be forced to take you
to a mental hospital.
You don't want that,
do you?
So put your shoes on.
Wejust want
to take you home.
No one's going
to hurt you.
Or the baby.
Put your shoes on.
She's fine now.
We're going to go home and rest.
That's all it takes.
Thank you for your trouble,
Doctor.
Glad I could be of help, sir.
It's a shame you had to come in here.
Good evening,
Mrs. Woodhouse.
Mrs. Woodhouse!
Uhh!
Ro!
Ro, baby, Ro!
Come on, open up, Ro.
Go to hell!
Come on, honey.
No one's going to hurt you.
You promised them the baby,
get out!
No, I didn't promise
them anything.
What are you talking about?
Promised who?
Rosemary, you're--
You, too! Get away!
Hello.
Elise?
Mrs. Dunstan is out.
-Who is this?
-The babysitter.
Do you know
where she went?
They went
to the movies.
This is Rosemary.
Please ask her to call Rosemary
the second
she gets home.
It's terribly urgent.
Don't-- Don't forget.
Don't worry.
I'll tell her.
Thank you.
We don't want
to hurt you, Ro.
We're your friends,
Rosemary.
There's nothing to be afraid of,
Honest and truly there isn't.
This is nothing but a mild sedative
to calm you down.
You know I wouldn't
let any--
Ro.
Aah!
Ro, Ro!
Help me!
Oh, Ro, baby.
Somebody help me!
Aah!
Wait a minute.
Wait a minute now.
We happen to be
in labor here.
Here?
Here.
You're all right, baby.
You're going to be
perfectly all right.
I swear to God you will.
There were supposed
to be doctors, hospitals!
Doctors, hospitals!
Everything--
Everything's clean and sterile!
No, she isn't here, Elise.
I'll have her
call you back.
Oh, Andy...
Andy or Jenny...
I--I'm sorry,
my little darling.
Forgive me.
Hi.
Is it all right?
Yes, it's fine.
What is it?
A boy.
Really?
A boy?
And it's all right?
Yes.
Where is it?
Ohh!
Oh, my goodness.
Oh, gee, what a start you gave me.
My goodness.
The baby, where is it?
Oh, uh, you wait
here one minute.
Where's my baby?
Uh, I'll go find Dr. Abe.
Ju-Just wait.
Where's the baby?
Where is it?
Honey...
There were complications,
Rosemary,
but nothing that will affect
future births.
It's...
Dead.
It was in
the wrong position.
In the hospital
I might have been able
to do something about it,
but you wouldn't listen.
Honey, we can have others
as soon as you're better. I promise you.
Absolutely. You can start on another
in a very few months.
As soon as
you're better.
No.
I don't believe you.
You're both lying.
You're lying!
It didn't die!
You took it!
You're lying!
You're witches!
Abe says it's called
pre-partum.
I don't know.
It's some kind of a hysteria.
Boy, you were really kapow,
out of your mind.
Uh, I know where you got the idea
that Minnie and Roman were witches,
but, um, how come you thought
that Abe and I joined the party?
Um, let's face it, darling.
You had the pre-partum crazies.
Now you're going to rest,
and you're going to get over them.
I know this is the worst thing
that ever happened to you,
but from now on,
everything's going to be roses.
Paramount's within an inch
of where we want them,
and suddenly Universal's
interested, too,
and we're going
to blow this town,
and we're going to be
in the beautiful Hills of Beverly
with a pool, a spice garden,
the whole schmeer,
and the kids, too, Ro.
Scout's honor.
You heard what Abe said.
Now, I got to run now
and get famous.
Let me see your shoulder.
Are you kidding?
Your left shoulder.
All right.
Anything you say.
I generally prefer
doing this to music.
Left shoulder.
Right shoulder.
And that's as far as I go
without a blue light.
The high pressure area
that we see here
has been causing this
extreme heat and humidity.
And unfortunately
will be staying with us city dwellers
through the rest of the week.
It will be hot and over cast
upstate New York as well
with the possibility of thunder showers
tonight and tomorrow
withg radual clearing
by tomorrow night.
All you people leaving the city this
upcoming weekend should find it hot.
Do you hear a baby crying?
Why, no, I don't, dear.
Now, you come
and get into your bed now.
It's time for you
to take your pill.
Did you turn the air
conditioner off?
Mm-hmm.
Well, you mustn't do that, dear.
Why, people are actually dying,
it's so hot.
What do you do
with the milk?
Why, uh,
throw it away.
Your pill, Rosemary.
Hello, girls.
Whew. 95 out.
Some new people
moved on in up in 8.
Do they have a baby?
How'd you know that?
I heard it crying.
Oh, wait a minute.
Oh, no.
Don't do that.
Why not?
Uh, a little messy, that's all.
Easy, easy.
Got her too high.
Not if he's still waiting
for a plane, he isn't.
Oh, hell, now, Hayato.
You're just
making fun of me.
You're pulling my leg,
like we say.
Aah!
Rosemary,
go back to bed.
You know you're not supposed
to be up and around.
Is the mother?
Uh, Rosemary--
Shut up. You're in Dubrovnik.
I don't hear you.
What have you
done to it?
What have you done
to its eyes?
He has his
father's eyes.
What are you talking about?
Guy's eyes are normal.
What have you done to him,
you maniacs?
Satan is his father,
not Guy.
He came up from hell and begat a son
of mortal woman.
Hail, Satan.
Satan is his father,
and his name is Adrian.
He shall overthrow the mighty
and lay waste their temples.
He shall redeem the despised
and wreak vengeance
in the name of the burned
and the tortured!
Hail, Adrian!
Hail, Satan!
He chose you
out of all the world.
Out of all the women
in the whole world, he chose you.
He arranged things
because he wanted you
to be the mother
of his only living son.
His power is stronger
than stronger!
His might shall last
longer than longer!
Hail, Satan!
No!
It can't be!
Go look at his hands.
And his feet.
Oh, God!
God is dead!
Satan lives!
The year is one!
- Hail, Satan!
The year is one,
and God is done!
Oh, God!
The year is one!
Hail, Adrian!
Hail, Satan!
Why don't you help us out,
Rosemary?
Be a real mother to Adrian.
You don't have to join
If you don't want to.
Just be a mother
to your baby.
Minnie and Laura-Louise
are too old.
It's not right.
Think about it, Rosemary.
Oh, God!
Oh, shut up with your oh, Gods,
or we'll kill you,
milk or no milk.
You shut up.
Rosemary's his mother,
so you show some respect.
Come, my friend.
Come see him.
Come see the child.
What would you
like to drink?
They, uh, promised
me you wouldn't be hurt,
and you haven't
been, really.
I mean, supposing you had the baby
and you lost it.
Wouldn't that
be the same?
And we're getting so much
in return, Ro.
Oh, Guy, let me introduce
you to Argyron Stavropoulos.
How proud you must be.
Is this the mother?
Why in the name of--
Here, drink this.
You'll feel a little better.
What's in it?
Tannis root?
Nothing's in it.
Just plain,
ordinary Lipton's tea.
You drink it.
Get away from here.
Roman.
You're rocking him too fast.
Sit down.
Get her out of here.
Put her where she belongs.
You're rocking him too fast.
That's why he's crying.
Oh, mind your own business.
Let Rosemary rock him.
Go on, sit down with the others.
Well, she's liable to--
Sit down with the others,
Laura-Louise.
Rock him.
You're trying to get me
to be his mother.
Aren't you his mother?
END