Hey, this area's restricted.
Hi. Yeah, I know. They called me down here.
Some of this wiring got screwed up.
Nobody called it down to me.
I'm gonna have to see a work order.
Yeah. Just a second.
There you are.
Nothing personal.
Well, I guess that wraps it up.
Good work, everybody.
Marty, I couldn't be happier
with the way this worked out.
Congratulations.
- Hold that.
- Whoa.
Gee, thanks.
Thanks for pushing that, Bob. The light's on,
but you never know, it might be broken.
Shut up.
Remember, honey...
Jesus. Bob, what button did you push?
Mr Bagwell, make sure these other elevators
remain locked down and empty.
There's no doors, no other way in or out,
except through access panels, correct?
What we have here are 13 passengers
in an express elevator below floor 30.
Bomb's taken out cables. Bomber wants
$3 million or he blows the brakes.
- What's our clock?
- He gave one hour.
That leaves us 23 minutes exactly.
- Anything to keep this elevator from falling?
- The basement.
We'd like to avoid that, Traven.
- We can't unload the passengers?
- This is an express elevator.
The only way in is through access panels.
The bomber's wired the hatch,
which seats him
in the "crazy but not stupid" section.
Sir, Harry volunteers to examine the device.
- Yeah, right.
- Fine. The two of you check it out.
The nearest access panel's
on the 32nd floor in the lobby.
I want reports only. We're in a holding
pattern. Worthy, Briggs, secure the base area.
Everyone else,
I want you to affirm building evac. Move!
Looks like we're walkin'.
- Hurry, but watch your step!
- 29.
All the way down to the lobby! Let's go, folks!
30.
31.
32.
Hello?
- Come on! Get us outta here!
- Hello! Hello!
Help! Please, get us out of here!
Please!
Please! Get us out of here!
Who's up there?
Who's up there? What's going on?
Ladies and gentlemen, this is the LAPD.
- Thank God.
- What are you doing up there?
There's been
an elevator malfunction, so just relax.
Hey, come on!
What are you guys waiting for?
We'll have you out of there
as soon as possible.
Am I lying?
How come they sent cops here?
Shouldn't they send repair guys?
What do you think?
- You're the expert. I just work here.
- Looks pretty solid.
- Anyone we know?
- I don't recognise the work, but he's a pro.
- He's cutting it close.
- I don't like it.
Well, what's to like?
Mac said we hold, so we hold.
All right, pop quiz.
The airport. Gunman with one hostage.
He's using her for cover.
He's almost to a plane.
You're 100 feet away.
Jack.
Shoot the hostage.
- What?
- Take her out of the equation.
Go for the good wound and he can't
get to the plane with her. Clear shot.
You're deeply nuts, you know that?
"Shoot the hostage."
Harry, this is wrong.
He's gonna blow it anyway.
- Why?
- I don't know. Gut feeling.
Right now Mac outranks your gut, so we sit.
This is taking way too long.
How much d'you think that elevator weighs?
Jack, come on.
Maybe we can do something
about those hostages.
We're not gonna shoot 'em, right?
Hey, where you going?
What's going on?
Don't go! Don't leave us here!
No, we just take them out of the equation.
- Are you sure it'll hold?
- It'll hold.
Six minutes.
I can't get any more time. He's not talking!
I need the goddamn money now.
Tell me again, Harry. Why did I take this job?
Oh, come on. 30 more years of this, you get
a tiny pension and a cheap gold watch.
Cool.
Ho!
- God, it's hot in here.
- There's no air.
- Can't they just pry the doors open?
- I can't breathe.
Don't fuck with Daddy.
Usually they fall down now.
He's early. The son of a bitch is early!
Mac, we need more help up here now!
Oh, please! I don't wanna die!
Please save us!
Open the door!
Open the door, please!
- Please help me!
- We'll get you out!
- Give me your hands! It's OK.
- Pull me through.
Watch your head. Watch your head.
- OK, I've got you.
- Take it easy.
- You're fine. You're fine.
- Thank you.
- Take her.
- Who's next?
Thank you.
We've got you, ma'am.
- What the hell is all this?
- Help us! Hurry!
Hurry, hurry! Let's go! Go! Go!
Come on. Come on.
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
- Help me out! Please, help me out.
- Watch your head.
- Come on, lady!
- No.
Come on, lady! Come on! Grab my hand!
- Come on! Let's go! It's going to fall!
- No!
No, I can't!
Just take one step, reach out
and take my hand.
Come on! Come on!
- Oh, God! Don't let go of me!
- You're OK.
My shoe!
Was it good for you?
It was great for me.
How was it for you, honey?
- Elevator dropped.
- Good. That's good to know.
- Is your watch slow?
- No. He jumped the gun.
- We had three minutes left.
- Why does he do that?
He's losing his $3 million.
Maybe he couldn't hold his wad long enough.
It's a common problem among
middle-aged men. So I'm told.
- He's here.
- He could've blown that thing from Pacoima.
No. He knew we were up to something.
He's close by.
He's not gonna corner himself in a building
we evacuated anyway. Come on.
He'd... he'd wanna be here,
but he'd wanna stay mobile, right?
The elevators.
Passenger cars were stopped.
They checked 'em out.
What about the freight elevators?
- Will the mystery guest please sign in?
- What?
Jack!
Damn it.
Get to the side!
Shit! Shit! Shit!
Up! Get your ass up!
I don't suppose anybody'll give me
three million just for you.
Hold it!
Pop quiz, hotshot.
Terrorist holding a police hostage.
Got enough dynamite strapped to his chest to
blow a building in half. Now what do you do?
There's gonna be 50 cops
waiting for you in the basement.
Standard flanking deployment, right?
Maybe we'll get off on the third floor, huh?
At least that's what they'll think.
I want location on those goddamn shots!
Briggs! Where's Jack and Harry?
Lieutenant, we've got movement
on the freight elevator.
It's on three. Let's move!
End of the line. This day has been
real disappointing, I don't mind saying.
Because you didn't kill everyone?
There will come a time, boy,
when you'll wish you'd never met me.
Mister, I'm already there.
I'm in charge here. I drop this stick
and they pick your friend up with a sponge.
- Are you ready to die, friend?
- Fuck you.
In 200 years, we've come from "I regret
but I have one life to give for my country"
to "fuck you"?
- Go ahead. Drop the stick. Do it.
- Shut up, Harry.
We've got all the balls
in the world right here, man.
Give it up. You got nowhere to go!
Shoot the hostage.
Say goodbye, Harry.
You fuck!
Freeze!
Give it up! You're out of options!
Through dedication and bravery,
these next two officers effected the rescue
of 13 citizens of this city.
And, thanks to them, the only life taken
by the terrorist's bomb was his own.
You shot me. I can't believe it.
They're giving you a medal
for shooting me, you little prick.
Harry, you told me to.
...the Los Angeles Police Department.
Officer Harry Temple.
Officer Jack Traven.
Way to go, Jack. Way to go.
- There we go.
- Harry, my man.
Beautiful. A toast to me.
Make me feel good about myself.
Hey, Sandy! Here we go!
OK, so how we doing? Whoa, whoa.
Shit. I need a bib!
- Here we go. All right.
- You can't take me anywhere.
And here is to Harry,
for his quick thinking,
for his grace under pressure
and for his brave and selfless act.
Hear! Hear!
And to Jack, for shooting Harry.
Something we've all wanted to do
for a very long time.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
OK, no, no. Here it is.
Here's to you guys for doing yourjob
and for not getting dead.
Mazel tov.
We are the two luckiest guys in the world.
We got the bad guy
and we didn't lose any civilians.
- We're good.
- No. You were lucky.
No, we were lucky. You'd better understand it.
We were dealing with a total psycho.
This guy could've blown us up at any time.
And I got a bullet in me.
Six inches off the mark,
and they're giving the medal to my wife.
Harry, come on, man.
I mean, we won. We got him.
Do you listen? Do you ever?
Because I am not gonna be around
to back you up, so you better start thinking.
Guts'll get you so far,
and then they'll get you killed.
Luck runs out sooner or later. Right, Chief?
That's right.
Ho!
I'm all right. I'm all right.
I'm gonna go home, have some sex.
- Harry, you're gonna go home and puke.
- Yeah, well, that'll be fun, too.
Come on, you gimp.
- Hey, Jack, saw you on TV. Congratulations.
- Thanks, Bob.
- You looked fat.
- Take it easy on him, Bob.
- The boy was up late last night partying.
- Wild party, huh?
I don't remember that well.
Couldn't have been too great. Woke up alone.
Yeah? The last time I partied like that,
I woke up married, huh, Vinnie?
Hey, Jack, you forgot your muffins.
- Have a good one, Bob.
- Thanks, Jack. Take care.
Thanks.
See you tomorrow.
What do you think, Jack?
You think if you pick up all the bus driver's
teeth, they'll give you another medal?
Jesus!
You think I wouldn't have been prepared?
Two years I spent setting up that elevatorjob.
Two years I invested myself in it.
You couldn't understand
the kind of commitment that I have.
You ruined a man's life's work
and you think you can walk away?
You got blinders on to the world,
but I got your attention now, didn't I, Jack?
- Why didn't you just come after me?
- This is about me. This is about my money.
This is about money due me,
which I will collect.
$3.7 million.
It's my nest egg, Jack.
At my age, you gotta think ahead.
- When I find you...
- Pop quiz, hotshot.
There's a bomb on a bus.
Once the bus goes 50 miles an hour,
the bomb is armed.
If it drops below 50, it blows up.
What do you do? What do you do?
- I'd wanna know what bus it was.
- You think I'm gonna tell you that?
- Yes.
- Very good.
There are rules, Jack,
and I want you to get this right.
No one goes off the bus.
You try to take any passengers off the bus,
I will detonate it.
I want my money by 11am.
- We can't pull that kind of money in time.
- Focus, Jack!
Your concern is the bus.
And don't try to call. The radio's down.
Now, the number of the bus is 2525.
It's running downtown from Venice.
It is at the corner of Ocean Park and Main.
Sam!
Annie.
Sam! Tell him to stop!
Shit. Excuse me. Coming through! Sam!
- Sam!
- This ain't no bus stop.
- Come on.
- Get rid of your butt, Annie.
OK, it's gone, it's gone.
You are a good, kind man. One day
people are gonna write songs about you.
- Hi.
- First time in LA.
- Oh, no. I live here.
No, I mean mine. Oh, that's just funny.
- You heard me wrong. I'm sightseeing.
- Oh, really?
Yeah. I hate to use the word "tourist",
but it's not like I can hide it.
Not really.
Aw, jeez. You know, it took me three hours
just to get here from the airport. I got so lost.
LA is one large place. Course, you live here.
You probably don't notice.
I'm such a yokel. There. I said it.
You know what? I got gum on my seat.
Gum.
Excuse me.
- Morning.
- Hi.
I just couldn't handle the freeways any more.
I got so tense.
This way, I can just relax all the way to work.
Yeah, well, I love my car. I miss my car.
Oh, God. Look at that.
- Hey, Sam!
- Shit.
- Sam!
- What?
- Why don't you just drive over these people?
- Don't spit on my bus, Annie.
Such a mess.
Stop!
- Open up!
- Get off the door. This ain't no bus stop.
- That guy really wants to get on the bus.
- Open up! Stop!
- Don't, Sam! Don't let him on!
- LAPD!
- I can't hear you!
- Stop this bus!
What?
LAPD! Stop the bus!
LAPD!
Stop! Stop!
- Stop! LAPD! Get out of the car.
- Jesus, not again.
This is my car. I own this car. It's not stolen.
- It is now. Move over.
- Fuck!
Man, you scratch this puppy, and me and you
are gonna have words, you understand?
OK, look, man, we don't have to go so fast.
Just slow down a little bit.
Oh, shit. Come on, man.
Just... just don't tear up my car, all right?
OK, OK. Just slow down just a bit, all right?
We don't have to go so fast, do we?
We don't have to go so...
That was a nice move, man.
Whoo!
Shit, shit, shit, shit!
The least you could do is slow down.
Come on.
Oh, shit.
Oh, shit!
Move! Move!
Is that that guy?
Man sure has a hard-on for this bus.
Hey! I'm a cop!
What?
I'm a cop!
LAPD! There's a bomb on your bus!
- What?
- There's a bomb on your bus!
There's a... What? Fuck!
- Watch the road!
Grab that. I want you to write on it.
I want you to write on the back:
"Bomb on bus."
Write it, write it, write it!
Watch the road. Oh, shit.
Oh, shit!
No!
Don't slow down!
No! No, no, no, no, no!
Speed up!
Op...
Open your door!
Open the doors!
50! Stay above 50!
All right?
4708000. Ask for Detective Harry Temple.
Harry.
Harry, it's Jack.
You better not be calling in sick,
cos I dragged my ass...
- Harry, he's alive.
- What?
The bomber. He's back.
He hit one in Venice already.
There's nothing left.
We got a ransom demand from your
dead terrorist. Says he's rigged a bus.
- Where's Jack?
- Where do you think?
- I gotta get on that bus.
- You gotta get...
Yeah, yeah. You get on the bus.
Drive straight!
Stay in this lane!
Watch the road.
Wait a minute. What are you doin'?
- Are you insured?
- Yeah! Why?
No! No!
You broke my... my door.
- Sir, I need to take your phone.
- Take the phone.
- Take the wheel.
- What are you... What?
Oh, shit. Oh, shit.
Drive straight.
Oh, shit!
Whoa! Shit!
This guy's out of his mind.
OK, listen, you gotta stay above 50.
- Excuse me, are you out of your mind?
- Whatever it takes.
Everybody, I'm Jack Traven, LAPD.
We have a slight situation on the bus.
If you'll please sit down.
- You're scaring the shit out of these people.
- Ma'am, please!
If everybody will stay in your seats
and remain calm,
we should be able to defuse the problem...
Get away from me!
I don't know you, man.
I'm not here for you. Let's not do this.
- Stop the bus!
- He can't.
Shut up! Stop the bus! Stop it!
Listen!
Look, I'm putting my gun away, OK?
OK?
Now, listen. I don't care about your crime.
Whatever you did, I'm sure that you're sorry,
so it's cool now. It's over.
And I'm not a cop right now.
See? We're just two cool guys,
just hanging out...
Sam!
I've got the wheel! I've got it!
Sam! Oh God, Sam!
You've gotta move your legs.
Can somebody move his legs?
Sam, get your foot...
Sam, get your foot off the pedal!
- I gotta stop this thing!
- No! Don't! Stay above 50!
- Sam's been shot! We gotta get him off!
- You slow down and this bus'll explode!
There is a bomb on this bus.
If we slow down, it'll blow.
If anyone tries to get off, it'll explode.
Bullshit! Yeah, there's a bomb.
- Some funny joke, man.
- Are we gonna have a problem now?
He's bleeding so much.
I don't know what to do.
Put pressure front and back, keep
his legs up and put this under his head.
- Hold on, man.
- Sam, lift your head.
- Can you handle this bus?
- Sure. It's like driving a really big Pinto.
- I need to know! Can you handle it?
- I'm fine. Just tell me what the plan is.
- Is there a plan?
- For you to drive. We're OK for now.
- Just keep us above 50.
- Good plan.
- So, you're a cop, right?
- That's right.
Well, I should probably tell you that
I had my driver's licence revoked.
- What for?
- Speeding.
Harry, we're on our way to the chopper.
If anything changes, let us know.
Anything we haven't seen
should be in here.
... wrong with the driver,
but at least one car, a Jaguar,
has been driven off the road
by the speeding bus.
The bus came onto the freeway
at the Lincoln onramp.
It began picking up speed, swerving,
and hasn't slowed down since.
Minutes ago a police officer boarded the bus
by jumping onto it from a moving car.
Would that be you, Jack?
- Where do we start?
- The speedometer.
Has it been fucked with or loosened?
See any wires or anything?
Excuse me, ma'am.
No, it's clean.
Then it's gonna be under the bus.
Probably rigged to one of the axles.
I can't get under the bus right now.
It's kind of in motion.
Excuse me! Excuse me!
Hold on.
Access panel... in the floor.
Underneath you, man.
All right, Harry. We're in. Passenger relay.
Sir, take this. I want you to tell him what I see.
OK.
We got a wad! Pretty big!
- There's a pretty big wad.
- Brass fittings!
- Brass fittings.
- I think I can reach the circuit wire.
- He can reach the circuit wire.
- No, don't. That's a decoy. Classic.
- Classic decoy.
- What else?
- Hold on.
Hold on.
Fuck me!
Oh, darn.
Harry, there's enough C4 on this thing
to put a hole in the world.
OK, all right. Just stay calm. What else?
Three triggers - one on the axle
I can't really see, a cellular remote
and a timer running off a wristwatch.
- A watch? What kind of watch?
- Gold.
Gold band. Fairly cheesy.
Officer!
- Officer!
- What's on your mind, Harry?
Shit. What do I do? Officer!
- What do I do?
- Oh, shit.
- Which way? Which way?!
- Get on the shoulder.
OK.
Watch it!
Stay on or get off? Stay on or get off?
Off! Off! Hold on!
Oh, God.
- Keep going.
- It's red!
Go! Go!
This is much better.
... city streets. The bus is on Western,
heading in a southbound direction.
Now, where the bus did exit here,
it had a couple of close calls.
Yeah! Yeah! All right!
We don't know what authorities plan to do.
I don't get it.
The watch is a shitty timer.
Why use it? What's he saying?
- Lots of people have watches, Harry.
- This guy has no MO.
A bomber falls in love with one kind
of bomb and they're very monogamous.
This guy uses C4, dynamite, different trigger
every time, and now he throws in this watch.
He's an encyclopaedia of bombs.
He knows every kind.
Yeah, and everything we do to dismantle it.
Wait a minute.
I wanna look at the files for the last 10 years.
- We did the mug shots. It's not gonna help.
- No. I wanna look at cops.
Come on. Let's go.
Yeah. Mac, where have you been?
I had to bail on the freeway.
We're in the city.
I can see you. Just keep going straight.
I'm gonna try to clear the roads for you.
Just stay on line.
Shit! Oh, Jesus! God! No!
Go left!
- Sorry.
- Oh, my God!
Oh, jeez!
People, stay out of my way!
Stay out of my way!
- Ma'am, up to the right.
- OK, OK, OK. I see it, I see it.
Mac! Mac, you've gotta get me outta here!
A few more blocks,
you're gonna come up to a soft turn. Right.
Then hold straight. I've got
some units waiting for you there.
They're gonna lead you to the 105 freeway.
It's not in use. It'll be empty.
- You'll be totally clear.
- Got it.
In a few blocks,
we take the soft turn to the right.
OK. Wait a minute. Escort to where?
Where do we get an escort to?
Look out!
Oh, God!
Son of a bitch!
Oh, Jesus! Oh, God!
- Oh, God! I just hit the baby!
- Cans!
- There was no baby. It was full of cans.
- Are you sure?
Oh, jeez. No! No! No!
- Why aren't they at school?
- Mac, we're boned.
I'll get you out, Jack.
All right, listen.
You got an entrance coming up, Jack.
It's gonna be a real ugly turn, though.
- How ugly?
- What's ugly?
We got a hard right coming up
at the construction site.
- This should be it.
- That is a dead end.
- I can't make that turn.
- You can make it. Keep left. Make it wide.
Oh, God. We're gonna tip over.
We're gonna tip over.
You're right. We're gonna tip over.
Everyone on this side of the bus now!
On this side of the bus!
As far as you can, please.
Hold on!
Over here. Over here. As far as you can! Now!
Mac, you better clear this site out.
- Everybody hold on!
- This side of the bus!
Hold on!
Hold on! Oh, God! Here we go! Here we go!
Here we go!
Whoo!
Oh, my God! Oh, God! Is everybody all right?
- Yes!
- Oh, my God.
Take me to that interchange at the 105.
Oh, my God. We might've died. I can't think.
It's OK. If you need to,
you go right ahead and vomit.
Frank, get rid of that scaffolding
and replace it with webbing.
Norwood, I want aerial units up ahead.
No obstructions in the freeway.
We have a window here.
I wanna make sure it stays open.
Shoot.
Could you do me a favour
and hold the wheel for me for a second?
Hold the wheel? Thank you.
Ma'am, you did very well. Actually, you were
incredible. I've never seen driving like that.
- Annie.
- What?
It's my name. Annie.
- Annie.
- As opposed to "ma'am".
OK.
So, why is all this happening?
I mean, what did we do?
Bomb the guy's country or something?
No. It's just a guy who wants money.
I don't buy that.
It's not a very good way to make money.
So, um... what is this guy's deal?
A while back,
he held some people for ransom.
It went sour,
and now he's a little pissed at me.
- What does that have to do with us?
- Nothing. It's a game.
If he gets the money, he wins.
If the bus blows up, he wins.
- What if you win?
- Tomorrow we'll play another one.
But I'm not available
to drive tomorrow. Busy.
We got no match for that description.
No one's lost a thumb
for at least the last 10 years.
- He could be from anywhere.
- I can't access all that.
Forget the files.
Start going through the pension fund.
This guy's drawing disability. He may not
be LAPD, but he's living here now.
I want pictures! I've seen this asshole.
- Hey! Let's get these passengers off the bus!
- We can't do it, sir!
There's no time for any stunts.
We gotta get these people out of harm's way.
I got orders. We move these people, he'll see.
Remember: Crazy, not stupid.
Harry's trying to find out who this guy is.
We think maybe he's a cop.
Lieutenant, it's him.
- He wants to talk to Jack.
- He's on the line for you.
- OK, give him the number.
- Give him the number.
- How's he doing?
- The bleeding is less, but...
- Are they going to help us?
- Sure they are. They're the police.
Hey, your taxes are paying their salary.
If we die, they gotta take a pay cut.
I mean, you know.
Yeah.
I think we have trust, but it looks on TV
like you're trying to get those passengers off.
- Look, you've gotta let me have one.
- We went over the rules.
As an act of faith. We have
an injured man here. The driver's been shot.
Tell me you haven't
been shooting the passengers.
I thought it was customary
for a police officer to shoot the bad guys.
- This man has no time.
- No one gets off.
It'll grease the wheels with the money men.
There's still gonna be plenty of us to kill.
OK, son, you can try and unload the driver.
You tell that wildcat behind the wheel
not to slow down, though,
or he won't even get a chance
to bleed to death. And, Jack, don't slip.
- He's letting us unload the driver.
- Norwood! Get us closer!
- We're gonna get the driver off.
- Just him?
- For now. Gigantor.
- Ortiz.
Ortiz, we're gonna need your help.
I need you to pass him to me.
Keep him straight, or the wound'll tear.
- What about the rest of us?
- Hey, hey, hey! Lady!
I can't stay!
- How are you feeling?
- Like I've been shot.
- Take care, Sam.
- OK, Annie.
Drive straight!
- Get as close as you can, OK?
- All right.
Closer. A little closer, Annie.
- Annie, a little closer.
- OK.
OK, how's this?
Sorry. Sorry.
OK, Annie. No problem.
Let's try it one more time.
A little more!
OK! OK! Right there! Steady! Hold it steady!
You got him? You got him?
I'm all right. Thanks.
- Oh, my God.
- Yes!
He's gonna be OK.
Come on! Come on, lady. Give me your hand.
- I have to, Annie.
- No, Helen!
- No, Helen, no!
- Come on!
Helen, no! No!
I'm here at the 105 Freeway, where the police
have successfully led the runaway bus...
No, Helen!
Goddamn it, Mac!
Get those fucking choppers outta here!
... was driving the bus.
Well, I couldn't tell how old...
An explosion. Some kind of an explosion.
The bus hasn't exploded, but... Oh, my God.
A woman caught in the blast fell. She was
pulled under the wheels. This is terrible.
Interactive TV, Jack. Wave of the future, huh?
I can't be here.
I can't, you know...
This is the wrong bus.
I mean, for me to...
I can't die here.
Hey, shut up, man.
- I got a wife.
- Oh, you do?
Hey! So if you have a wife and I don't,
does that mean I'm expendable?
What are you talking about, man?
The guy's just talking crazy.
He gets on my nerves.
He gets on everybody's nerves.
- I think I have the right to be a little upset.
- What are you staring at, anyway?
Why don't you let us all die in peace,
if it has to happen?
Oh, so you're a really tough guy, huh?
Why don't we just step outside?
Hey!
How are you doing? You all right?
What can I do?
When that bomb went off...
I know.
I thought that was it.
I thought that was the bomb, and I was dead.
And then when I saw her body fall
under the bus, it was like...
You were glad you were still alive.
- I'm so sorry.
- Don't be.
You should be glad. We all are.
- It doesn't mean you don't care.
- I know, but she was so scared.
She was a nice lady
who didn't deserve to get killed,
but if she'd gotten off,
it would have killed us all.
He's the asshole, Annie. The guy
who put us here. Remember that, OK?
Big asshole.
OK.
Are you sure?
Well, how far?
Sir, we have a serious problem.
What?
- This freeway isn't finished.
- What are you talking about?
The aerial unit caught it. About three miles
ahead there's a section missing.
A section missing?
But it's on the map.
It's finished on the goddamn map!
I guess they fell behind.
Fuck! You're fired. Everybody's fucking fired!
Get me closer!
Hey, get closer. Watch him in the mirror.
Jack!
- How big is the section?
- 50 feet... at least.
There's a gap in the road up ahead. It's big.
- You're kidding. How big?
- 50 feet.
What?
We gotta get these people
off the bus somehow.
You know I can't.
What did he say? Jack?
Jack, what did he say?
What's the matter?
- There's a gap in the freeway.
- What?
- What do you mean?
- How big is a gap?
50 feet. A couple of miles ahead.
This is crazy.
- Jeez.
- Jack.
Jack. What if I shift into neutral
and just keep the engine revving?
- No, he'd have thought of that.
- What, then? What? What?
What? Jack?
- Floor it.
- What?
Floor it. It's an interchange.
There might be an incline.
Fine.
Everybody hold onto your seats
or whatever you can.
When we hit the gap, heads down.
That's it? That's it?
That's all we can do. Let's put these
underneath your seat, all right?
Put your bags underneath the seat.
- Hey, I didn't mean to shoot the guy.
- Hold on.
Is this really gonna work?
Jack.
Yeah?
- Come on, come on, come on.
- Oh, God.
- Come on!
Oh, shit.
Everybody hold on!
Oh, God. Jack.
Shit!
Yes! We are way out of control!
- You OK?
- Yeah.
- I'm OK.
All right! Norwood, let's go!
- Is everybody OK?
- Yes!
We did it!
We made it.
You're the man. You are the man!
Thank you. Thank you very much.
Oh, shit.
- I think you missed your calling.
- Yeah? What was it?
Watch the road.
You should have been a pilot.
Ow.
- Get off.
- What?
Get off this. Now. Get off this.
In there.
- Where? Right here?
- Yeah.
- Right here?
- He's just entered the airport.
- There's thousands of people there.
That's my boy Jack. He can circle
the runways and buy us some time.
- Choppers can't fly there. It's restricted.
- He's headed for the end of the field.
- Bravo Tango, an emergency runway.
- Let's hope it's built. Let's move!
We're at the airport.
Yeah? So?
I already seen the airport.
- Yeah?
- Very, very exciting, Jack.
Some close calls, huh?
But you've done all right for yourself.
- What do you want?
- I want money, Jack.
I wish I had some loftier purpose, but
I'm afraid in the end it's just the money, Jack.
I would like large non-sequential bills
in two clear plastic bags, unmarked.
- Can you remember all that?
- What are you telling me for?
Because I want you to help me
to get it before it gets too late.
I hate negotiators, Jack. They talk to you
like they're your best friend
and they don't even know you.
Why are they messing with me, huh?
Do they think I'm doing this for fun?
- Aren't you?
- Oh, that's unfair, Jack.
You don't know how I feel about this.
You don't even know me.
You want a shitload of money
you didn't earn.
Oh, I earned it.
I spent my life earning it.
I got a medal, too, Jack, a medal and
a pink slip and a "sorry about your hand".
- You have to let me off.
- Oh, no.
- That's not good.
- You want me to help you?
I need to talk to these people face to face.
They think you're bullshit.
They don't think that.
Look, you want the money, I don't want
anyone else to die. Let me get on the ground.
Just me. That's not against the rules.
All right. I want you back real fast.
Fine.
Jack, nothing tricky now.
You know that I'm on top of you.
Do not attempt to grow a brain.
- So I guess there's a plan now?
- Could be.
- Yeah?
- He's letting me off.
- What?
- Just keep circling. You'll be fine.
- Sit tight. I'm getting off for a minute.
- Do you think that's a good idea?
- It'll be OK.
- Are you just gonna leave us here?
- I would.
- Don't worry. I won't go far.
Hey. Don't forget about us.
The choppers are gone.
Let's dump the passengers.
- He's ready for that.
- How is that possible?
I don't know how. I just know he is.
He's been a step ahead every time.
- If we unload, he'll take them out.
- So where does that put us?
I have to try and dismantle that bomb.
After an incredible ride on the 10 freeway,
the streets of Los Angeles
and the 105 freeway,
this bus has ended up here at Los Angeles
International Airport, circling the runway.
I'm telling you, he's somewhere jerking off.
He didn't have to get
on the bus in the first place, Ortiz.
Get your ass behind the yellow line.
What is that?
I have no idea.
We won't be able to hold this steady for long.
I just need a few minutes.
If I can't do it by then, I can't do it at all.
- Harry, you with me?
- Yeah. You be careful, Jack.
What's he doing? Oh, my God. He is insane.
OK, Jack, this is it. Don't get dead.
- This is not a very good plan.
- Have faith, sister.
Oh, Christ.
Just keep it steady.
Thank you for the tip, Ortiz.
This guy is nuts!
We'll try to bypass the remote current
with the battery.
- Can you find the tripwire for the remote?
- I don't know. I got a few choices here.
- Black and red?
- And green.
OK, I'm gonna guess he's not gonna go
with standard copper for the remote.
That'd be too weak. I'd use a fibre alloy.
Jack, I'm gonna need you to look at the wire.
Harry, it's covered.
I know. You're gonna have to cut off
the sheath. But don't cut the wire.
Right.
Fuck me!
Shit!
- Bull's-eye!
- Great.
OK. I want you to clip on the battery
and then run it to the lead wire.
Copy.
I can't bypass. It'll fire.
Oh, shit! It's a collapsible circuit.
Howard Payne, Atlanta PD Bomb Squad.
Retired in Sun Valley in 1989
when a small charge left him
with fingers numbering nine.
That's our scumbag!
We got him. Jack, we found him.
- We can get to his place inside of 15 minutes.
- Jack, get out of there.
- We're going after the source.
- Watch your back.
Wait for me!
Mac, get me outta here.
Somebody go to the back and check
and see if he came out the back. Go!
- Can you see him?
- He's not behind us.
- What?
- He's not back here.
Oh, my God. Go look!
Lay down and look under the bus
and see if you can see him down there.
- Can you see him?
- No.
You don't see him
back by the tyre or something?
- I can't see him.
- Are you sure?
I can't see him.
Oh, my God! We hit him!
Oh, my God! Do you see him?
- Did we hit him?
- Look out the sides.
- My tools!
- Will somebody get him his tools?!
Please help him! Hurry!
God, we're dragging him. Do you see him?
Where is he? Is he there?
- Do you see him?
- Jack! Jack!
- I see him!
- What?
- You do? Is he OK?
He's all right! He's all right!
Hold my legs. Hold my legs.
Somebody hold my legs.
Hold his legs.
- Hold his legs!
- Come on!
Come on! I got ya!
- Is he hurt? Is he OK?
- Pull! Pull!
Come on! Come on!
We got him now. Come on, pull!
Jesus. I can't believe it.
You are a complete jerk. You know that?
- Did you have any luck with the bomb?
- Yeah. It didn't go off.
Ortiz, thanks.
How many lives you got, man?
You're not too bright, man,
but you got some big, round, hairy cojones.
That's... very gross, Ortiz.
Can't even pay him a compliment.
- How you doing?
- You scared the shit out of me, Jack!
Other than that, I'm fine.
- What is that smell?
- It's gas.
- We're leaking gas?
- We are now.
You felt you needed
another challenge or something?
- Mac.
- Mac here. Go ahead.
Can you get a fuel truck to pace us?
We're losing gas.
- I'll see what I can find. How much time?
- 10 minutes? It doesn't look good.
Gotcha. Norwood, get a fuel car
out here on the double.
Is that gonna work?
I don't know.
Harry, save my life.
Harry, tell me good news, man.
Oh, I'm sorry, Jack. He didn't make it.
You fuck!
It was the watch that led him
to me, wasn't it? Huh?
It seemed a little hammy to me to build
the bomb out of my precious retirement gift,
but, you know, I figured a sign that said
"Howard Payne" would be pushing it.
I'm gonna rip your fucking spine out,
I swear to God.
You're gonna do exactly as you're told.
Jack, we both know that he was the brains
of your particular operation.
You can't beat me.
You're gonna pay me every dollar.
Otherwise, you, the wildcat
and every innocent person on that bus
are gonna end up just like your friend.
Are you paying attention?
Jack, are you listening to me?
- Jack? Jack?
- Yeah.
Good. You tell them that
the drop point is Pershing Square.
There's a garbage can
on the northeast corner.
You drop the bags and leave.
I don't show until all your people are gone.
It's getting on to 11am, Jack, and I think
it's gonna be a very pretty day.
Jack.
Come on. Don't give up on me, Jack!
Jack, stop it! Jack, come on!
Stop it, OK? Don't give up
on me right now, all right?
We're really scared and we need you
right now. I can't do this by myself. Please?
Jack, please.
OK? Please. All right?
- We're gonna die.
- No, we're not. We got this far, OK?
I'll be damned.
Did you go to the University of Arizona?
- Yeah? So?
- Good football team.
Yeah, I guess so. I don't really know.
Arizona Wildcats.
- Right.
- He can see you.
- What?
Just keep looking straight ahead.
He called you a wildcat before.
Bastard's got a camera right in your face.
He can see the whole bus.
He's been playing me from minute one.
- Well, he can see me, but can he hear me?
- Doesn't look like it. He's just watching.
We are following the progress
of what is turning out to be a harrowing story,
as a city bus,
rigged to explode if it slows down,
races around literally in circles
at the Los Angeles airport.
The dead are a female passenger and a driver
of another bus, both blown up by the bomber.
Others in jeopardy are the passengers of the
bus, held hostage at the whim of a madman.
"The whim of a madman."
I like that.
There's a camera on the bus
just over my left shoulder.
I want you to stare straight ahead.
Don't make any big movements, OK?
It's Jack.
Yeah, I know about Harry.
Is that news van still around?
- Get those cameras to stop taping.
- Right.
LAPD. I need this unit.
You can broadcast UHF, right?
There's a signal going to that bus.
I want you to find it.
We're gonna have to
take you off the air.
Please, sir, stop taping.
Come on, hurry up. Good! Tape off of that.
Remember, no big movements.
Just look whipped.
That ain't gonna be too hard.
- Tape it. Good. Come on, tape it.
- It's taping!
- Jack.
- Yeah?
Look.
- Mac, fuel.
- Jack, five minutes.
Not enough time. Run the tape.
We have to unload.
- I only have a minute of tape.
- Do it now.
I want you to make a tape and loop it
so that it runs over and over, OK?
- All right, run it. Run it!
- All right. Tape's rolling.
We still have no live picture, but reports
are that the bus continues to circle...
Everyone is safe for the moment.
Hard to imagine what's going
through their thoughts at this time.
Certainly, a sense of community...
Rig the steering wheel and the gas pedal.
All right, let's get 'em off.
OK, you, you, and you.
Police have just issued a general
statement, which doesn't tell us much more...
Grab my wrist. That's it. Good.
Come on. Look straight ahead.
- That's good, that's good.
- Grab my wrist.
Put your hand out. Take his hand.
Come on, buddy. I got ya.
Give me your hand. Your hand.
Grab my hand. Don't look down.
Shit!
Jack!
Grab my hand! Grab my hand!
Jack! Jack, I can't hold this any more.
Annie!
You... hold on!
No! No! No!
Hold it.
- Oh, God.
- Wedge down the gas pedal.
OK, I got it.
- You got it?
- Yeah. I got it.
- OK, Annie, get on.
- Jack, I can't do this.
- Let's go! Let's go!
- Shit. Shit.
- Jack.
- Shit!
Hold on.
Shit!
Are you all right?
No.
It's OK. It's OK. It's over.
It's over. You did it. You did it.
I hate the airport.
You're not gonna get mushy on me, are you?
Maybe. I might.
I hope not, cos relationships that start
under intense circumstances never last.
- Oh, yeah?
- I've done extensive studying on this.
Here comes the cavalry.
- How ya doing?
- We're OK.
I just might be a nice guy
and let you have the rest of the day off.
Oh, boy.
Mac, this is Annie.
Annie, meet Lieutenant McMahon.
- How you doing?
- OK.
- This should take care of it.
- Ow!
- Watch it.
- Sorry.
- We're gonna have you guys checked out.
- Lieutenant!
It's him. He wants to know
when he's gonna get his money.
I'll tell him what to do
with his goddamn money.
He doesn't know it blew up.
30 minutes.
I'll be right back.
All right, here's our target. Fox, I want you
in 4-1, you in 1-2. You're in 3. Let's move it.
- Is the paint bomb in with the money?
- It's done, sir.
Too bad, Jack.
You could've made a good cop.
OK.
We still have no live picture. Reports are
that the bus continues to circle inside LAX.
No! No!
Miss, you can't be this close.
You need to move back.
No. Jack Traven said...
Jack Traven asked that you be brought
out of harm's way. Just move right over here.
- He's running a little late.
- He's not late.
- What?
- He's never late.
Well, that money hasn't moved.
We got 200 eyes on that can, a bird dog
in the bag. I'd say he's covered.
- Turn it on.
- What for? It hasn't moved.
Just do it.
Shit. It's moving.
He's got the money.
Jack!
Shit!
Freeze!
Pop quiz, asshole.
You have a hair trigger aimed at your head.
What do you do? What do you do?
Turn around. Turn around!
- Oh, no.
- I'm sorry.
Be prepared.
It's the Boy Scout marching song.
What are you gonna do, Jack?
I don't think you can shoot her.
Let her go.
No, I don't think I'm gonna do that.
Fill it. Now.
I think Harry would be very disappointed,
feeling that we're right back where we started.
Let her go. You don't need her.
You have the money. Take it and walk.
Come on. Just take it and walk.
You don't need her.
- Just take your goddamn money and walk!
- Stay right there.
I'll do it. I'll let go. I'll let go.
Oh, yeah.
You still don't get it, do you, Jack? Huh?
The beauty of it.
A bomb is made to explode.
That's its meaning, its purpose.
Your life is empty because you spend it
trying to stop the bomb from becoming.
And for who? For what?
Do you know what a bomb is, Jack,
that doesn't explode?
It is a cheap gold watch, buddy.
You're crazy. You're fucking crazy.
No. Poor people are crazy, Jack.
I'm eccentric. Get the money. Let's go.
Come on! Let's go! Move it! Move it!
You stay! Move it! Move it!
In the door. In that door! Now!
Bye, Jack. Punk.
All right!
Get in there. Go on, get in.
You get back in there!
You get this train moving! Go on!
Are these seats taken?
No. Go.
Come on. Back over here.
Hands around the pole.
Damn.
Come on, come on, come on!
Please report, Westbound 501.
What is your position?
Westbound 501, please check in.
Westbound 501. We have police orders
to return to the station. Do you copy?
You have to hold this. It's like a grenade.
You have to help me now. Come on, hold it.
Don't let it go. Huh? I'm counting on you.
Do you copy?
Hey! I'll take it from here.
Uh-oh. Uh-oh.
Maybe you'd better let me have this after all.
I'm afraid you're a bit hysterical
and you might let this go a mite early.
Hey! Hey, buckaroo!
It's not cos you're a woman, all right?
Hey, it's all right. Looks like we're all alone.
You won. You beat Jack. You beat everybody.
Just throw me off the train. I don't care.
This stick works on a remote.
When you explode, that's where they'll come,
but it's not where I'll be.
I have a different plan. Mess like that,
they don't even count body parts.
Gives me more time.
It's not gonna hurt, Annie.
Hey, Jack, is that you?
He's so persistent. He always gets his man.
Wouldn't be able
to interest you in a bribe, would I?
I've got plenty to go around.
My money!
You bastard! How does that feel?
You like that, huh? You like it, you bastard?
My money!
Shit!
You! I'm coming for you, Jack!
Hey, I'll drop the stick, boy. You want that?
I'm gonna get you.
Oh, yes!
What do you do, Jack? What do you do?
You're so smart, right, Jack?
You piece of shit! I'm the guy
with the plan cos I'm smarter than you.
I'm smarter than you.
Yeah.
But I'm taller.
Jack.
Jack!
Oh, God! I thought you were dead. Jack.
- Turn around.
- Where's Payne?
He lost his head.
Oh, God.
- Let's take this off, shall we?
- Yes. Let's take this off.
- Take it off.
- Hello? Hello?
Does anyone copy?
Jack, this is Mac. Can you hear me?
Jack, if you're there, you've got to stop
the train. The track isn't finished.
Mac, I copy.
- Mac.
- If someone can hear me...
- Mac, can you hear me?
- Try the emergency brake. Do you copy?
Nothing works! Annie, you won't believe this.
What?
We have to jump.
You can't stop it?
Well, OK, undo me,
and I'd love to go with you. Come on.
- I don't have a key.
- What?
I don't have the key.
Shit.
You gotta get off... You gotta get off the train.
Jack, please! This track dead-ends.
You gotta get off this train. This is crazy.
There's a curve ahead.
I'm gonna speed it up, make itjump the track.
This is really stupid.
Jack, please. You can still jump.
Jack, please. Please, Jack?
I can't believe he hit my van.
Come on. It's all right.
Unreal.
You didn't leave me.
I can't believe it.
Didn't have anywhere to be just then.
Check it out.
I have to warn you.
I've heard relationships
based on intense experiences never work.
OK.
We'll have to base it on sex, then.
Whatever you say, ma'am.
# Running from the nightmare
# In the middle of the road
# Hell's no place for sleepin'
# In a world beyond control
# Caught in the headlights
# Comin'after you
# When I woke up this mornin'
# I had to do what I gotta do
# Blast me to heaven
# For lovin'you
# Speed
# Give me what I need, yeah
# White lightnin'
# Let's speed, on speed, on wheels, on wheels
# Speed
# Oh, let it bleed, yeah
# Greased lightnin'
# Let's speed, on speed, on wheels, on wheels
# I seen a train full of pain
# On the edge of overload
# We're in heaven, baby
# You are gonna implode
# I've got these crazy feelings
# That I can't explain
# I've got to save you, baby
# Or I'll die in vain
# Blast me to heaven
# For lovin'you
# I said blast me to heaven
# Just for lovin'you
# I said speed
# Give me what I need, yeah
# White lightnin'
# Let's speed, on speed, on wheels, on wheels
# Speed
# Oh, let it bleed, yeah
# Greased lightnin'
# Let's speed, on speed, on wheels, on wheels
# Blast me to heaven
# For lovin'you
# I said blast me to heaven
# Now I'm rushin' on the run, yeah
# I wanna have me some fun
# I'll speed
# Give me what I need
# Oh, set me free
# Let's speed on wheels,
on wheels, on wheels
# I said speed
# Give me what I need, yeah
# White lightnin'
# Let's speed, on speed, on wheels, on wheels
# I said speed
# Oh, let it bleed, yeah
# Greased lightnin'
# Let's speed, on speed, on wheels, on wheels
# Speed
# Oh, let it bleed, yeah
# White lightnin'
# Let's speed, on speed, on wheels, on wheels
# Come on
# I said speed
# Speed
# Give me what I need
# I said speed
# Speed
# Give me what I need
Subtitles by Visiontext
ENGLISH SDH