How was Europe?
Oh, it's still there.
Except for France. She's
not sore at us anymore.
I was hoping you'd
have a couple hours
'cause I'd like to
talk about something.
Honey, in a couple of hours,
I'll be halfway to L.A.
Board of directors just
can't wait for these reports,
but, uh, I can do
wonders in 30 minutes.
Well, I can't.
I guess we'll just
have to wait till tonight.
What flight are you on?
The red-eye special.
Alan, why don't you
wait and fly with me?
I'll have my work all finished
by the time you get there.
I was really hoping we'd
have a chance to talk now.
It didn't feel to me like you were
interested in talking just now.
(SIGHS)
Are you back in that
same old kick about us?
If that's what
you want to call it.
Come on! What's all
the rush all of a sudden?
Rush?
I've been on this particular
kick for six years now.
Maybe I'm tired of
one-night stands.
Look,baby, I've only
got half an hour.
Can't we talk it out
when you get to L.A.?
Don't miss your
flight, Murdock.
You wouldn't want to keep
that boss of yours waiting.
But...
Did you enjoy your stay in
our city, Miss Swanson?
Yes, I did.
Will you be
returning anytime soon?
I don't know. I can't tell. My life is a
surprise. One surprise after another.
You look lovely,
Miss Swanson.
Thank you, Mr. Kelly.
Imagine getting
gussied up like this
to watch a lot of Supreme
Court judges chew.
Miss Swanson, what is the
secret of your eternal youth?
This way, please.
I just take natural food.
I will not have poisoned food.
I don't like it. It's
not good for anybody.
Just one more question.
It's a...
WOMAN ON P.A.: Northwest
Orient passenger, Janet...
Who is she, Sister Beatrice?
Do you recognize her?
I believe it's one of
those Hollywood persons.
Oh!
You mean, an actress?
Or worse.
MAN ON P.A.: Mr. Kelly, line six, please.
Mr. Kelly, line six.
Columbia Airlines flight 10 for
Albuquerque and Denver, now boarding.
Kelly here.
This is Dr. Weiner.
Jefferson Memorial Hospital.
Yes, Doctor,
how are you?
Fine, thank you. Listen. We have
a patient on the way out there.
Name's Janice Abbott.
She's booked on flight
409 for Los Angeles.
Yes. Everything's
been set for her.
Fine. Thank you.
I just wanted to make sure
and to let you know
that the ambulance was
late in getting away.
No need to worry
about that, Doctor.
If we have to delay
departure, we will.
Fine, thank you. Listen, it's
been touch and go for us.
She's scheduled for a transplant
and the kidney's in L.A.
Now, we can't have her off
the dialysis machine too long.
Yes, Doctor. I was told.
I wanted you to understand
the urgency of the situation.
We'll take good
care of her, Doctor.
Thank you.
WOMAN: Yes, sir.
- Check Columbia maintenance.
Make sure the arrangements for that
kidney patient on 409 have been set.
Yes, sir.
You really want to sail a
35-footer all the way to Hawaii?
What's wrong with that?
Nothing, if you have
an all-girl crew.
My first mate
wouldn't dig that.
What's his problem?
Hers. First mate's my wife.
Oh, I can dig it.
Oh, that's nice.
Nice, nice, nice.
Conserve your energy, Urias. I hear
we can expect a bumpy ride tonight.
I used to know a stewardess
who thought that was sexy.
You're weird.
You know that?
How do you get
rid of this jet lag?
You just do.
- Why? You still tired in the morning?
- Uh-huh.
Give it a couple months.
Hey, do we have
a sexy crew tonight?
I don't check anymore.
In any case, it'll be a
change from Ogallala, Kansas.
Isn't everything?
There. You see why I
love my job so much?
Well, they sure have
all the right equipment.
But it would be wrong.
That's for sure.
How are your kids
and your wife, Julio?
Watch out for that one, Gary.
She's got seniority.
What about the teenager?
It's Ms. Teenager, please.
I'm emancipated and highly
skilled in kung fu.
Whatever happened
to womanhood?
Hey, that's enough
of that for you.
The convention's over.
I want you to taper off.
- No more!
- You should've stuck to that Blue Nun.
We got a plane
to catch, Sammy boy.
We got a plane,
Sammy boy.
Bartender, another
one all around.
No more. We got a plane...
California, here I come
Right back where
(GLASS SHATTERING)
-I'm sorry. I didn't mean that.
Oh, excuse me. I...
Sammy! What's
the matter with you?
I'm sorry.
It's my fault.
He's a little sloshed. You know
what I mean? I'm sorry, man.
Can I make amends?
Listen, we'd like
to buy you a drink.
I'd like to buy
you a drink.
Whatever you'd
like to have.
Please. Please.
Well, maybe a little
bourbon on the rocks.
You got it.
Nurse, bourbon on the rocks
for the lady, please.
With a small beer chaser.
Jesus Christ,
a boilermaker.
Where's the flight log?
Here it is, sir.
It's clean.
No deferred items?
Not a thing.
The crew chief was worried
about number three.
It's all taken
care of, papa.
Well, ain't that
thoughtful!
"...contains a concert hall,
an opera house and..."
Hello, Mrs. Patroni. What are you
doing on the red-eye special?
We stayed to see a play
at the Kennedy Center.
Nice to see
you again, Joseph.
Thank you, sir.
"The decor includes
flags of all nations."
This thing will
never get off the ground.
Never fly.
Take my word for it.
Young man, you think
this thing won't fly?
In 1917 I was flying in
something wilder than this.
You know who
the pilot was?
Wiley Post?
(CHUCKLING)
No. Cecil B. DeMille.
We flew from Hollywood
nonstop to Pasadena.
Yes, and on the way home
we did loop-the-loops
so that I could see
the moon upside down.
MAN: We need emergency
assistance at main artery.
Ambulance trying to get to Columbia
Airlines flight number 409.
(CARS HONKING)
You don't mind turning
off that music, do you?
Thanks.
Get us clearance.
Dulles Tower,
Columbia 409.
We're taxiing in five minutes.
Request A.T.C. clearance.
TOWER RADIO: On request.
How are you?
Go ahead.
Thank you!
- You all right?
- I'm fine.
All right. Okay.
We got him. It's all right.
I'm okay, I'm all right.
Yeah, right back
through there.
Down there. Down there.
(INDISTINCT CHATTING)
Is that Spanish
one really married?
His wife thinks he is.
Oh, well. The other
one's just as neat.
Eight years ago, I thought
they were all neat.
Thank you.
How are you?
(BEEPING)
Yes?
JULIO: Hey, mama, got a patch
on the company wire from L.A.
Some guy named Al.
You interested?
I'll be right up.
Thanks, Julio.
Arlene, could you
help Bette here?
Okay.
Hello there, Mrs. Patroni.
Hi, nice to see you.
Your seats are right over in there, Mrs.
Patroni. Good evening.
You better use code.
Neat.
Hello, Alan.
Hey, honey, I'm not getting
you into any trouble, am I?
I don't think so.
'Course that's what I've
been trying to do for years,
but you're too
smart for me.
Alan, what is it?
I just didn't like the way we
said good-bye. That's all.
I don't remember
anybody saying good-bye.
Come on, damn it.
You know what I mean.
Then why don't you tell me
what you mean, Alan?
(SIGHS) I guess I haven't been
too good at that, have I?
You've had your moments.
Yeah.
Look, that talk you mentioned?
We'll have that as soon as you get here.
I promise.
Okay.
Have a good flight.
Thanks.
Hey, I love you. Nancy?
Hey, you don't
look happy, baby.
I don't know what you mean.
STACY: Kelly, we're seven
minutes behind departure time.
KELLY: Yes, sir.
I'm aware of it.
What the hell is the word?
The ambulance should be close.
I sure hope so.
I got special clearance
through gate four, sir.
Please keep
an eye open for it.
Okay. We'll give 'em a hand.
Won't you, Julio?
Yes, sir.
Would you hold this, please?
I'll take care of Miss Swanson.
Good evening.
Right this way, please.
Thank you.
Hello. How are you?
Good evening,
Miss Swanson.
Good evening.
I mean, good morning.
Right here,
Miss Swanson.
Oh, yes, put it under my feet.
Thank you very much.
It's a pleasure to have you
with us, Miss Swanson.
If there's anything I can do
for you, just let me know.
I shall.
Never mind her, sister.
Put your ticket away.
Yes, sister.
(BARKING)
Sammy, will
you sit down?
Sammy, will you sit down?
You're a tiny bit
nervous, aren't you?
I know.
I've flown thousands of miles and
under very difficult circumstances.
I assure you there's nothing
to be worried about.
Oh, may I?
He's probably got
something on his mind,
and he's probably getting it
off his chest right now.
(SIREN WAILING)
Look, sister,
an ambulance.
Oh, I hope
it's not serious!
Clear the aisle, please.
Good evening.
Oh, how blessed I am.
Three children, seven grandchildren
and all healthy. Thank God.
Julio, this is fine
right here. Careful, careful.
It's a young girl.
Let me take that.
Let me take your coat.
Oh, thank you.
There.
- You want this?
- Please.
Thank you so much.
NANCY: We're happy to have
you aboard, Janice.
Thank you.
It's gonna be a lot of laughs.
I can see that right now.
Here we go, boys.
Right up here. Here we go.
I'm sorry, fellas.
The bar is closed till we
get to cruising altitude.
Why is the bar closed?
We're not at
cruising altitude?
No, not yet. Didn't I see
you guys over in coach?
Coach? Yeah, but we
always fly first class.
Why don't we go back and you
can fasten your seat belts?
We'll get your
drinks faster.
I want a dry vodka martini
with a twist of lemon.
I'm gonna fly
Rifka next time.
Please, Janice, remember
what the doctor said.
You must lie
very, very still.
I know, Mother.
But it's so exciting.
The people are
so interesting.
You'll have to turn your seat facing
forward for the takeoff, Mrs. Abbott.
Oh, thank you. All right.
And why don't you just
hold tight to that guitar?
- Okay.
RADIO: Columbia 409
clear for takeoff.
STACY: We're rolling.
This is it.
Count your beads, folks.
I hear Rosie
Grier does that.
Yes, he does.
RADIO: Here in Gallup
and surrounding areas
we can expect a massive cold
front moving in from the north.
Heavy turbulence is predicted
above 15,000 feet.
Storm warnings are posted over
most of northern Utah and Idaho.
Did you hear that, Scotty?
Looks like you're stuck here.
You might as well come on back to
town with us and try it tomorrow.
I wish I could stay. I've
enjoyed being with you fellas.
What's so goddamn
important in Boise?
If I miss that
meeting in the morning,
I'll lose about a half
next year's sales commission.
Well, the weather's not gonna change.
What are you gonna do?
I know I can make it
to Elko for refueling.
Maybe the weather
will thin out up there.
Okay, if you want to break up
this glamorous trio. Come on.
We'll help you untie.
RADIO: Massive cold front
is moving in from the north.
Heavy turbulence is predicted
above 15,000 feet.
You look a little
off-color, Scotty.
You sure you're
feeling all right?
Oh, I'm fine.
Good luck now!
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
(ENGINE REVVING)
Departure, Columbia 409 out of
2,000 feet for flight level 2-4-0.
RADIO: Roger, Columbia 409.
Radar contact.
Turn right to 3-0-0 degrees.
Report out at 7,000.
Columbia 409 turning right to 3-0-0
degrees, will check out at 7,000.
Landing gear?
The light's Off.
Flaps?
Up. Light's off.
Engine ignition?
Off.
- No smoking sign?
- Off.
Departure, 409
checking out at 7,000.
Roger 409. Contact
Washington Center, 128.2.
Roger. 409.
Washington Center 128.2.
So long, pal.
Well, we've done
it again, papa.
Once again skill and daring
have overcome fear and anxiety.
Study this chapter and don't
move anything till I get back.
Nancy, got a couple
of aspirin?
What's the matter?
You got a headache?
Did you ever take a tour of
Washington with a 10-year-old kid
who wants to see everything?
Everything!
Sure you don't
want a drink instead?
I'll give these
10 minutes.
(STRINGS VIBRATE)
(VIBRATING CONTINUES)
Which one takes
the sugar again?
The neat one.
- Oh, Julio.
- Mm-hmm.
Come on. I'll take
you into the lion's den.
Who's afraid of the
lion's den? I'm Jewish!
Jewish? From Ogallala?
And you gotta see Gloria Swanson.
She looks terrific!
- Oh, hi, Nancy.
- Bette, we've missed you.
It has been a long
time, hasn't it?
- Thank you.
- Nobody misses me anymore.
Well, you're
onto us, baby.
And I'm not, huh?
You're too young to know
what I'm talking about.
I know what
you're talking about.
Yeah, but you're
a dirty old man.
We need love too.
Nancy, how do you put
up with these monkeys?
I've been here so long,
I don't hear it anymore.
No wonder you're so
good at dodging passes.
The trouble with Nancy is she never
learned to rise above her principles.
No way. The trouble with Nancy is
she's a one-man girl. Right, baby?
Right, baby.
What a waste of talent.
Hey! There's no
sugar in this.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- This...
- This is it.
I'm sorry.
I like my coffee
sweet, mommy.
- Huh? Huh?
- I'll see you later.
Ay, chico!
Miss Devaney?
Miss Devaney.
There are two
empty seats up front.
Would you like to see
the picture up there?
Oh, that would
be nice.
Fine.
Plug it in right here.
MAN: Down in front, sir.
Yes, I'll be down.
I'm... I'm in
this picture.
You're in this picture?
It's just a small part,
but the producer said the next
picture I'll have a bigger part.
Good!
- Sister Beatrice?
- It's coming up now.
I'm going to see if I can
talk to that young girl.
- Pardon me, sister.
- Yes?
Don't you like the picture?
- Oh, I wasn't watching.
- Oh.
Here it comes.
(PASSENGERS GROANING)
The picture broke.
The picture broke?
The only reason I took the flight
was because of the picture.
(CHUCKLING)
It's all right.
I've seen this movie.
You have? How'd I come out?
- Fine!
- I did?
Just fine.
Oh, thank you.
Is this a double?
That's a double.
Keep 'em coming, will ya?
- Hi.
- Excuse me.
Would it be all right if I
said hello to the little girl?
I'm not sure.
I guess so. Go ahead.
Okay.
Hi.
- Hi.
- I'm Sister Ruth.
I'm Janice.
That's a nice guitar.
Thank you.
Do you play?
Oh, just a little bit.
What kind of
music do you like?
Oh, I like rock music,
folk music, all kinds.
Me too. Would
you like to try?
Okay.
Is it all right
if I sit here?
Sure.
Would you take
better care of yourself
Would you be
kinder to yourself
Would you be more forgiving
Of your human imperfections
If you realized your
best friend was yourself
Who is always
with you everywhere
Who is on your side
when others are unfair
Tell me who will
never let you down
In any situation
Who will always
see you get your share
That's why I am
A best friend to myself
And I take me out
Whenever I feel low
And I make my life as happy
as a best friend would
I'm as nice to me
as anyone I know
(HUMMING)
Oh!
Your book editor has a query.
In chapter two you tell how the
studios could tell the contract stars
what to do and
what not to do.
You had two friends who didn't
cave under studio pressure.
They want the names.
That's easy.
Carole Lombard
and Grace Moore.
I was a rebel too.
Miss Swanson, can I get you
something from the bar?
No, thank you.
I have my own. Tea.
Miss Griffith?
Yes. A martini, please.
MRS. PATRONI:
I don't believe it.
Did it again.
Who's winning?
You know my son Diamond Jim?
Wins at everything,
just like his father.
How long have you been
playing that game, Joseph?
Ever since we took off.
Better keep him
away from Vegas.
Hello, Mr. Patroni.
Hi, Mr. Patroni.
Hi.
Hey, Patroni, what the
heck you doing down here?
What's wrong with
your fancy new office?
New job doesn't
keep you busy, huh?
You know how it is. Just
like to keep my hand in.
Yeah! Listen, I just got this crew
broke in, so don't go screwing 'em up
with any of your old-fashioned
ways of doin' things.
You know what
I mean? Oops.
(CLAN KING)
Oops)'-
He dropped his
old-fashioned wrench.
Miss?
You need something?
I feel a little queasy.
The altitude, I guess.
I'll have a bourbon
with a beer chaser.
Miss Devaney?
Miss Devaney, do you know
what you just ordered?
They call those boilermakers.
I know.
Bourbon with a beer chaser.
SCOTT: Operator, I'd like
to place a credit card call.
My number is 644011-537F.
Calling Mrs. Scott Freeman,
same number, Boise, Idaho.
Area code 208.
(PHONE RINGING)
- Hello.
- Hello?
Where are you?
Elko. I've been
having weather problems.
Oh, really now, Scotty,
don't take any chances.
Don't worry.
How is the weather there?
Well, the moon's
out right now,
but there are
a few clouds around.
Well, there's a squall line
going through here.
I'll wait it out,
and then come on home.
Look, can't you just cancel
that meeting tomorrow?
No way!
Those guys only
come out once a year.
I'll find a hole in this weather,
and be there as soon as I can.
Okay. I'll wait up.
That'll be worth
coming through anything for.
I love you, darling.
I love you.
What's wrong, Junior?
A vibration.
- Number three, huh?
- Yeah.
Hey, when we get to Los Angeles,
you're gonna go see Fifi.
Gimme a kiss.
Oh, well, that's good.
I guess everybody'd given up
hope including the doctors.
Nobody expected me to live.
But then, I've never done
anything I was expected to do.
Is everything okay?
Yes, fine. Thank you.
I once went with a girl who was
half French and half Chinese.
I came home late one
night, she ate my laundry.
I want to be sure
and tell everyone
how you irrigate
those flowers.
(INDISTINCT CHATTING)
Hey, Plunkett, who do you guys think
is gonna make it to the Super Bowl?
Well...
New England probably
has the inside shot.
- Real funny, James.
(CHUCKLING)
Los Angeles Center,
Columbia 409
over Bryce Canyon at
flight level 3-5-0.
RADIO: Roger, Columbia 409. Stand
by for radar identification.
We gotta sort you out.
Identify.
Sort us out or deal us out?
Deal us out, I hope.
Sounds like they've got more traffic
stacked up than the freeway.
RADIO: Columbia 409, Center.
409. Go ahead.
LAX reporting zero-zero.
The whole
coastline's socked in
from San Diego
to San Francisco.
Well, well, well.
All right, thank you. We'll proceed
to our alternate, Salt Lake City.
- Do you have their current weather?
- Yes.
They're reporting
scattered clouds at 15,000.
For radar vector,
turn right to 3-4-0 degrees.
Roger, 3-4-0.
I hope you two won't
be lonesome tonight.
Julio, will we
be lonely tonight?
URIAS: That's it. Fly on.
SCOTT: Boise Approach,
this is Barron 232 Zulu.
Do you read me?
RADIO: Boise Approach.
Go ahead, 232 Zulu.
232 Zulu. Forty miles
southeast at 10,000.
V.F.R. on top. Request
landing information.
232 Zulu, we're fogged
in here solid.
Salt Lake City is open.
Roger, Boise. Will you give me
a vector direct to Salt Lake?
1-4-0 degrees, turn right.
Ladies and gentlemen, this
is Captain Stacy speaking.
May I have your
attention, please?
Due to extremely heavy fog up and
down the California coastline,
we're going to land
at Salt Lake City.
(PASSENGERS GROANING)
Our estimated time of arrival is
approximately 20 minutes from now.
We apologize for
the inconvenience.
We'll try and make your delay
as pleasant as possible.
Thank you.
What do you do
in Salt Lake City?
I went there once.
It was closed.
Miss Devaney?
- Miss Devaney?
- Yes?
Salt Lake City may
be very good for you.
It's dry there, you know.
Dry?
Do you know that my first trip
to California took five days?
So, if we have to spend a weekend
in Salt Lake, I'm still ahead.
But we have to
get to Los Angeles!
We'll make it all right, Mrs.
Abbott.
Wait'll I ask Dad if this is
any way to run an airline.
I suppose you'll want
to see the Mormon temple.
Hey, that'd be neat!
You don't understand.
She can't stay off that
kidney machine too long.
She's a very sick girl.
We'll make it.
I know we will!
Salt Lake Center
from Columbia 409.
RADIO: Salt Lake Center.
Go ahead, Columbia 409.
We're descending for
a landing in your fair city.
Please alert Brigham Young.
Roger, 409. We have
you in radar contact.
Checklist.
Windshield heat?
A-okay. Safe from
all kinds of birdies.
Except young flying quail.
You're a disgrace to your race.
Do you know that?
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
What'd you say?
I said, my mother loves me.
Salt Lake Approach.
Barron 232 Zulu.
RADIO: Go ahead,
232 Zulu 30 miles
northwest at 11,000.
Columbia 409,
Salt Lake Approach.
Descend to 12,000.
Maintain present heading.
Traffic at 12:00, five miles.
It's a twin-engine Barron.
Roger, Salt Lake.
Okay, Junior.
Let's get to it.
Checklist.
Seat belt sign?
On.
Helen?
No, thank you. Nothing.
I'm sorry to bother you,
but we're landing.
- Would you put your seat back upright?
- Oh.
And fasten your seat belts.
Okay, Joseph?
- Excuse me.
- Yes?
Could you put your
seat back upright?
Sure, you bet.
- I'll take that.
- Oh, thank you.
Anti-ice?
Check.
Altimeters?
Set.
Brake pressure.
Three thousand pounds.
RADIO: 232 Zulu, Salt Lake Approach.
Maintain your present heading.
You are number two for the
approach following a heavy jet.
232 Zulu, Roger.
Parking brake?
Off.
Checklist complete.
RADIO: Columbia 409,
maintain present heading
and altitude to
intercept the I.L.S.
Upon intercepting the I.L.S.,
you're clear for approach.
Ah, pardon me. Don't your
hands ever get tired?
Well, idle hands!
By the time we land,
you'll probably have a rug.
A rug?
Salt Lake, this is 232 Zulu.
What's the big delay?
RADIO: You're still
number two behind a 747.
Five degrees flaps.
Five degrees.
(GROANING)
STEWARDESS: Ladies
and gentlemen,
we have started our descent
into Salt Lake City.
Please make sure
your seat belts are fastened,
and put out your cigarettes
when the light goes on.
STACY: What's wrong, Junior?
That damn vibration again.
RADIO: Columbia 409,
the Barron is at 12:30.
Jesus!
(SCREAMING)
Sister Ruth!
Urias.
Urias!
Julio?
What happened?
I don't know, darling.
Bette, Carol, come here.
Handle him.
Oh, my God!
- Nancy.
- Yes.
Still flying?
Yes.
(GASPS)
Autopilot.
It's in "on."
Good.
Altitude. Hold.
Get help.
Radio.
I will.
(SCREAMING)
RADIO: Columbia 409.
Columbia 409.
This is Salt Lake Approach.
Do you read me?
Do you read me? Columbia 409.
Salt Lake.
Salt Lake,
this is Columbia 409.
It's Nancy Pryor, stewardess.
Something hit us!
All the flight crew is
either dead or badly injured.
There's no one
left to fly the plane!
Help us!
409, this is Salt Lake.
We read you, Nancy. Stand by.
(SOBBING)
Oh, my God, help us!
409, this is Salt Lake.
Stay on this frequency, Nancy.
Are you flying level?
I think so, yes.
- Is your autopilot on?
- The what?
Your autopilot. Is it on?
Oh, yes.
Very good. Now, describe the
damage to the aircraft. Over.
There's a hole ripped through
the plane on the right
just above the copilot's seat.
A lot of the gauges over the
engineer's panel are broken.
The front controls
seem to be all right.
All right, Nancy.
We have you in radar contact
and you look good.
We'll do everything
we can to help you.
Stay on this frequency, Nancy.
I'm goin' down
to the I.F.R. room.
STEWARDESS: Don't panic. Stay seated,
everybody. Please remain calm.
Sleep soundly.
We'll be all right.
(CRYING)
Bette? Bette.
Now, I want you to
get hold of yourself.
We're the ones who are going
to have to go down there
and calm everybody else.
What is going to happen?
They're going to
land the plane somehow.
H ow?
I don't know, but I
want you to go down there
and tell everyone that everything
is going to be all right.
We have to give them
something to hope for.
Damn it, I just got off
the horn with the boss
and I'm gonna
handle things here!
Now keep this line open!
They're gonna have to make a course
correction or hit the mountains.
I want Al Murdock on this.
Try his apartment.
Now, listen, how much
time do you estimate
before a course
correction is needed?
Ouch.
All right, hang on.
Have them get Exec One ready. We're
gonna take the Lear to Salt Lake.
All right, I understand. Now,
we're getting Al Murdock on this.
He was our chief instructor
pilot on 747s for four years.
I'll get back to you.
Bill?
It's ringing.
(SIGHS) Look, you know you're gonna
have to handle the news people on this.
Later on,
when the story breaks,
there's gonna be relatives and
there's gonna be friends, too.
Won't the directors
want you to handle that?
My wife and son are up there on that
airplane. I'm going to Salt Lake City.
I'm sorry, Joe.
How the hell are we gonna
get that aircraft down?
Damn it, I don't know! That
plane can do almost anything.
And Al Murdock knows more
about flyin' it than anybody.
- Now, where the hell is he?
- No answer.
Wait a second! He was going out to
meet 409. Try the V.I.P. lounge.
Yeah.
How's it flying now?
It's on autopilot.
How much damage was there?
Not a great deal.
There's just a big hole in it
where the pilots usually sit!
(BUZZES)
Yeah?
Right. Exec One is
ready when you are.
All right.
And they're paging Murdock.
Tell him to get his
ass out to Exec One.
WOMAN ON P.A.:
Al Murdock, emergency call.
Al Murdock.
Alan Murdock.
Al, it's Bill.
What's up? They said
it was an emergency.
It is.
My God.
Yeah. You sure it's 409?
Yeah, I understand.
I'm... I'm on my way.
I'm so frightened. What has happened?
Why won't you tell us?
Ma'am, we'll let you know
as soon as we know ourselves.
- There's nothing...
- Miss!
What's the matter,
Mr. Rogers?
Where are
the oxygen masks?
We're below 14,000 feet.
You don't need them.
Everything will
be fine, really.
What about the mountains? We're
flying into the mountains.
Everything will be just fine. Now,
sit back and relax. We'll be okay.
Can I help?
Mother? Mother?
It'll be okay.
(INAUDIBLE)
Darling, I'm gonna go
and see if I can help,
but I want you to stay
right in your seat.
- Do you want me to come with you?
- No.
And Mom, remember, the 747's
the best aircraft ever made.
Remember, it can almost fly by itself.
Dad calls it the big pussycat.
I remember.
ALAN: (OVER RADIO)
Nancy, this is Al, honey.
We're in Exec One on
the way to Salt Lake.
We've cleared this frequency.
Do you read me?
NANCY: Yes, I read you.
ALAN: Fine.
We don't have too much time.
I want you to sit
in the pilot's seat
and do exactly
what I tell you.
O... Okay.
Ready.
Now, look at the
instrument panel.
The altimeter is
marked A-L-T.
I know that.
What does it read, honey?
Twelve thousand feet.
Fine. The airspeed
indicator is to the left.
I know that too. It's 192.
Okay, honey, take it easy. Now I
want you to find the autopilot.
Look to your right
at the top of the panel
just below the windshield.
There's a switch
marked "autopilot."
It says "command,"
"manual" and "off."
- I see it.
- Don't touch it.
Is it in manual?
It's on manual. It's on.
I don't hear you, honey.
Nancy, press your mike button.
Yes.
Fine. Now, we don't have
anything to worry about.
We're just gonna help
the autopilot make a turn.
Do exactly what I tell you.
Put your hand to
the right of the console.
The what?
The flat panel just
below the throttles.
There's a gray knob about the
size of a milk bottle top.
I see it.
Okay. Now slowly
turn it to the right.
Nothing's happening.
Okay, honey, try it
to the left slowly.
NANCY: It's not working.
There's nothing happening.
It's not turning the plane.
Jesus, it's not
working for turns.
Can't you tell us
what's happening up there?
They want us to change course just like
I told you. It's a very simple thing.
There is a pilot on the radio
telling her what to do,
telling her exactly
how to do it.
Pardon me. What "her"?
The first stewardess
is at the controls.
But she is in constant
touch with the tower.
You mean, the stewardess
is flying the plane?
- Please keep your voice down.
- Sure.
The stewardess is
flying the plane.
The stewardess is... Thank you, Mrs.
Devaney, but I don't drink.
What difference
does it make now?
You're right.
No difference.
Alan?
I'm scared.
You're doing
just fine, honey.
There's a problem
with the autopilot.
It'll keep you
straight and level,
but I'm gonna have to help
you make the turns yourself.
I'm going to turn the plane?
No sweat.
Put both hands
on the wheel.
There's a button under your left thumb.
Press it.
(ALARM BUZZING)
What's that?
Don't worry. That's just an alarm.
Press it again.
(ALARM STOPS)
Okay.
All right, honey, now
you've got the airplane.
Just hold it steady
until I tell you.
I want you to find the artificial
horizon on the instrument panel.
That's the little airplane with
the horizontal line through it.
Alan?
I can't do this.
Why not?
You can do it, Nancy!
Nancy, come in!
Goddamn it, answer!
Okay. Okay, I'm gonna try it.
(SIGHS)
You scared the hell
outta me, honey.
What do you think I am?
Okay. What's your
altimeter read, Nancy?
11,500 feet.
That's good. All right now.
Turn to the right.
Turn the wheel to
the right slow and easy.
NANCY: Turning.
Good. Read me your airspeed.
It's going down.
It's only 184.
It's still all right.
Just keep turning.
183...182.
She's climbing in the turn. Get her
nose down or she's gonna stall.
Not till she
finishes the turn.
What's your airspeed now?
180. It's On 180.
All right. Now, turn the wheel to
the left again till it comes level.
ALAN: Now ease the wheel
forward just a little.
Watch the little airplane
in the instrument.
Don't let it
fall below the line.
Wings on the horizontal line.
All right.
Okay.
Let the autopilot
take it back now.
Turn the switch in the top
panel back to manual.
Take your hands off the wheel.
Is the airplane level?
NANCY: Yes.
Good job, honey.
You take a rest now.
We're almost to Salt Lake.
We got a big problem.
Look here.
There's Salt Lake
City and there's 409.
Look at the terrain
in between.
There is no way we can talk
Nancy through those mountains
and down through
a safe landing.
It's just too much for her.
The only way is to
put a pilot into 409.
You mean a midair transfer?
A jet helicopter is
fast enough to keep up.
We can put a man
out on a tether.
Do you know what it would be to
put a man through that hole?
Goddamn it! There
isn't any other way!
I think he's right.
The only question is who?
- Me.
- No, Al, you're too damn big.
What the hell you gonna do?
Go shopping for somebody?
Right!
I'll call Hill Air Force Base.
They're the experts.
You mean to tell me
you're going to try
to transfer a pilot
into a 747 in flight?
That's right.
We need your cooperation
and the fastest
helicopter you've got.
Now, wait a minute.
You intend to put one of
our men on an umbilical?
That's it!
How's he going to get inside?
The way the stewardess
described the hole
torn on the flight deck,
it's big enough.
If you'll excuse me, sir I think
it's one hell of a stupid idea.
That's all we've got,
Lieutenant!
Now, what have you
got to help us?
There's only one man who's
ever done anything like this.
A Major John Alexander.
He's in air rescue.
I can try to contact him.
You know how urgent... Who
is your commanding officer?
Uh... Colonel Moss, sir.
Thank you.
This is Exec One out.
(SIGHS) Now the question is,
can we get there in time?
RADIO: Columbia 409,
Salt Lake Approach.
We need another
instrument reading, Nancy.
Come in, Columbia 409.
Nancy, come in, please.
Come in, Nancy.
PILOT: Salt Lake Approach,
air force T37-Sage 14,
approaching Columbia 747.
The aircraft is
in level flight.
The flaps are 10 degrees
since the collision
occurred during
descent into Salt Lake.
Look, Mom, there's another
airplane out there.
Where?
Right out there!
Oh, my God, there is.
An air force jet.
PILOT: Jesus Christ,
you can't believe this!
There's a big hole on the starboard
side of the flight deck.
Doesn't look like there's any
other damage to the aircraft.
All four engines
seem to be running.
Hard to tell how
much instrument damage.
It looks like most of it's
near the engineer's panel.
Front part looks okay.
He's probably
checking the damage.
I'll bet he's gonna help us.
He is!
Can you see the fighter now, Nancy?
It should be on your right.
Yes, I see it.
He's gonna look you over and
report the damage. Stand by.
Nancy, the executive plane
is landing here now.
We're gonna have some help
up to you real soon.
Good.
Do you really think
they can do anything?
I know they'll do everything
that can be done.
You betcha! My dad
runs the airlines.
JOSEPH: Well, almost.
What does he mean about
"running" this airline?
My husband is vice
president of operations.
Ha. Some operations!
PILOT: Uh-oh.
There's a little crease on the inboard
section of the starboard wing.
I see some fuel coming
off the trailing edge.
Man, if this had happened
at 20,000 feet, forget it.
Plot a rendezvous point. Have the
47 make a 180 and bring her back.
We'll have to. We've gotta
make sure she holds altitude.
Col. Moss is on his
way from Hill Air Base.
What's the fuel situation?
There's enough, but we do
have a complication.
The air force sent up a
fighter to look things over.
He says there's a fuel
leak on the right wing.
Oh, damn!
That Nancy's some woman.
She better be.
How much do you think
we can ask of her?
There's a call
for you, Mr. Patroni.
Everything, I guess.
Yeah?
Your information is
correct, Mr. Purcell,
but we're clearing everything
out of our Los Angeles office.
You can understand
that our concern here
is for the safety of
those people. Excuse me.
- Who's that?
- A guy named Purcell.
Owns a local TV station. He's
sending a remote unit out.
What the hell does he want to photograph?
We don't have any bodies yet!
Take it easy, damn it.
We're gonna need all the
good press we can get.
Now let's go find
that colonel
and get that rendezvous course
plotted and on the boards.
Oh, my jewel case.
It's bombproofed. The insurance
people insisted upon it.
Oh, my idea of heaven is never
to have to pack or unpack.
Why didn't I think
of that before?
Here.
Here. You know what?
To hell with the jewelry.
Let's put my book in here.
Thank you.
Here you are, my darlings.
It's all yours.
I never wanted to have the damn thing
published while I was alive, anyway!
Colonel, is this
thing gonna work?
It's gonna be like trying to put
a raw egg back in its shell.
Your pilot confirmed
what the stewardess told us.
The hole looks
like it's big enough.
It's a hell of a risk, a long shot!
I gotta tell you that.
It's the only shot we got! How long
before that helicopter gets here?
About 10 minutes.
It's refueling right now.
Mean time I gotta
clear with Washington.
All right, make it fast.
Do we have any morphine
in the first-aid kit?
No. I'm sure we
have some sedatives.
No.
Help.
Yes, we'll help you.
It'll put you to sleep.
No!
Maybe...
Help.
I understand. He wants
to stay conscious
in case he can
help us later on.
RADIO: Salt Lake Approach.
Do you read me, Nancy?
This is Nancy. Go ahead.
In a little while, we're
gonna take you through
a 180 degree turn
like we did before.
Captain Murdock will talk you through it.
No sweat, okay?
I'm not looking
forward to it.
Just hang in there,
Nancy. You'll do fine.
You're doing great, honey.
We want you to look at
the flight engineer's panel
in the center
just above the desk.
Tell us what the third
fuel used gauge reads. Over.
Uh...
Twenty two thousand, 500 pounds.
Why, is something wrong?
No. We just want to keep track
of the rate of fuel flow.
We're not running low, are we?
No chance.
There's always
an extra amount just in case.
Besides that, the captain always
adds a few thousand pounds
for his wife, kids, his mother,
even his mother-in-law.
Nancy. Come in, Nancy.
Hello, this is Nancy.
Can you hear me?
Come in, 409.
Nancy, do you read me?
Flight 409 calling Salt Lake.
Nancy! Come in, 409!
This is flight 409
calling Salt Lake. Come in.
Columbia 409
calling Salt Lake.
It just went out.
I'll try it.
Columbia 409.
Do you read, Nancy?
Come in. Come in!
This is flight 409
calling Salt Lake. Come in.
- I've got her.
- What's the frequency?
125.4.
This is Salt Lake. 409, come in.
Can you read me?
Yes, thank God!
What happened?
A piece of wreckage
fell onto the radio panel.
Don't change anything.
Just stand by.
Standing...
Standing by.
Nancy?
Are you all right?
Yeah, I'm all right.
How is it down there?
It's better.
The sight of another plane
kinda perked everybody up.
Look at this.
What is it?
I don't know.
It looks like
it's cracked.
What is it?
What's the matter?
There's some fluid
coming out of the wing.
Did you hear that? There's some
gas coming out of the wing.
Didn't I tell you before I
don't want to hear that?
I don't want to hear it!
He doesn't want
to hear it. Oh, wow.
What the hell
is all of that?
That'll be Mr. Purcell.
TV has arrived.
He knows everybody in town. He'll
get clearance to come up here.
Leave her alone!
(INDISTINCT CHATTING)
You just sit here. I'll be back
in a minute, Mrs. Freeman.
And don't worry!
- Mr. Patroni?
- Yeah.
Glenn Purcell, KSL-TV.
Now I know how
busy you must be,
but we're going on a special
nationwide network hook-up.
I'm sorry, I'm busy.
Sir, this happens to
be a very big story.
We have Mrs. Freeman
downstairs
and I thought the
two of you together...
Who's Mrs. Freeman?
You know, the private pilot that went down.
She is his wife.
What the hell's
she doing here?
Trying to locate her husband.
Have they found him yet?
Mr. Purcell,
we don't know.
The highway patrol was alerted
at the time of the collision.
Why don't you
go talk to them?
You mean you haven't
bothered to find out?
No, because we're too busy trying
to save the 120 that are up there!
Why don't you just let us
get on with our job?
It seems to me it would be good
public relations to talk with her.
I mean, it was your plane
that killed him, wasn't it?
Listen, you son of a bitch!
Take it easy! Joe!
Take it easy you said. Right?
Al, you know, sometimes
the public's right to know
gives me a huge
pain in the ass.
We've got a problem,
Mr. Patroni.
Yeah?
We may lose radio contact.
We can barely read her.
And she's having
the same trouble.
What about another
frequency?
I'm afraid to let her try.
We might lose what we have.
We gotta get
started, Joe. Now.
409, 409, this is Joe Patroni.
How do you read me, Nancy?
Not very well,
Mr. Patroni.
How about now?
I can barely read
you, Mr. Patroni.
Nancy, is that my husband?
Yes.
Let me talk to him.
Joe!
Joe, this is Helen.
Can you hear me?
Yeah.
You're all doing a great job, honey.
We're proud of you.
We're doing everything that we can
here, and we're almost ready.
We... We have faith in you.
Ah, how is the captain?
In pain.
Well, he's a good man.
How...
(CLEARS THROAT)
How's Joe, Jr.?
He's fine!
We love you!
PURCELL: Ladies and gentlemen,
tension is thick here at
Salt Lake City Airport.
Just arriving is
the air force helicopter.
Major John Alexander
will make a dramatic attempt
to rescue 120
persons trapped aboard
a giant jetliner without
pilot and without crew.
And tragedy within tragedy, one
of them, a young girl dying,
unless she's delivered
to Los Angeles soon
for a kidney
transplant operation.
Major Alexander has volunteered
to make this daring attempt.
He will be lowered on a line
from the air force helicopter,
and try to crawl
through the hole
torn into the body
of the jumbo jetliner.
Here they are now.
What a moment this is.
This is KSL-TV.
Would you...
We want to...
ALAN: All right.
We're ready here, Nancy.
Remember, I'll tell you
everything you have to do.
You can do it.
I can't hear you
very well.
Take it easy, honey.
Very slow.
Are you ready?
Ready.
All right. We're going to turn
you around to a new heading,
260 degrees.
We don't want you
to lose altitude,
so we'll do it
very slow and easy.
Now first you have to
turn off the autopilot.
Put both hands on the wheel.
There's a button
under your left thumb.
Press it.
There now, honey,
you've got the airplane.
Now, read me your
compass heading.
Compass?
Okay. The arrow is on the "S."
Okay. Look at the numbers.
We're gonna turn until
it reads 260 degrees.
Are you ready?
Ready.
Turn the wheel to the right.
Easy now. Not too much.
You're doing fine, honey! Just watch
the little plane in the horizon.
I'm watching.
Now, read me the altimeter.
8,000 feet. Eight.
Read it again, honey.
Read it as it changes.
Seven-nine. Seven-eight.
She's gotta get
that altitude back.
She's only got
1,500 feet to play with.
Keep turning just the way
you're doing, honey,
but at the same time
ease the wheel back
until you see the little
plane lift up a bit.
Nancy, have you done that?
Yes, I think so.
What's your airspeed?
One-eight... 188.
188. Do you read me?
I read you fine, honey.
Now, what's your heading?
Your compass heading?
240, 2-4-0.
There's a 13,000-foot mountain
right in front of her.
ALAN: Read me
that again, Nancy.
That's 255, 2-5-5.
All right. Ease the wheel
to the left now, Nancy.
To the left a little.
Nice and slow. Not too much.
Tell me what's
happening, Nancy.
Press your mike
button, honey.
NANCY: We're turning back.
The little airplane is tilting
to the left, I mean back.
ALAN: All right, that's fine.
Bring it back to level.
Watch the little airplane.
All right, level now.
What's the airspeed now?
The airspeed, read it to me.
180.
Now the altimeter.
It's just over 10,000 feet.
She's still too low.
Let George take
it back now, Nancy.
Put it back on autopilot.
You're doing
just great, honey.
That helicopter's
ready, gentlemen.
The helicopter's ready.
We're going to be taking off now.
We'll be with you
in a little while.
She's gonna have to
have more altitude
or she's gonna take the tops
right off those mountains.
It's going to be tight if we're
gonna make that rendezvous.
You want to take it, Joe?
I'm going with you, Al.
DANTON: I can do it.
Her altitude's critical.
For God's sake, watch it!
We've been damn lucky so far.
Let's not push it.
Try not to rattle her.
DANTON: All right now, Nancy,
we're gonna watch your altitude.
And all of you across the nation
are seeing it as it happens.
The rescue team is going
to the helicopter now.
Gentlemen...
Gentlemen, may
I have a few words?
How do you propose
to slow the jet down?
Nancy?
I'm scared!
lam too.
(SCREAMS)
Nancy, look!
Nancy? Are you all right?
Nancy, what happened?
Salt Lake,
this is Columbia 409.
Come in.
Salt Lake, this is
Columbia 409. Come in.
409, this is Salt Lake.
Do you read me?
Come in, 409. This is
Salt Lake. Do you read?
409. Come in please.
What's wrong?
I don't hear anybody.
The frequencies.
Salt Lake, come in.
Nancy, come in.
Do you read me?
Salt Lake, come in please.
Goddamn it, we've lost her.
Why don't we have
that air force jet
try his frequency
again just in case?
Even if we can't hear her, there's
a chance she can hear us.
I'm gonna talk her through her climb
just on the assumption she can.
409, do you read?
They found the small plane.
It exploded on impact.
The radio's dead.
We're all
alone now, Bette.
The winch will hold
your position, okay?
You got it, sir?
Got it.
You'll find you can control
lateral movement somewhat.
Using the wind pressure
against my body.
You'll have to signal us
for in-and-out movement.
I must've made 20
drops in Nam, sir.
But what you're gonna do
scares the hell out of me.
Me too.
Nancy.
Oh, my God!
Bette, we're too low!
What are you supposed to do?
I don't know.
I know they worried
about airspeed.
Now...
If we Climb,
the airspeed drops.
I could stall us out.
The captain!
He said he could help us!
BETTE: Do you
understand me, Captain?
Thrust levers.
What about them?
Forward, an inch.
All right. Anything else?
(GASPING) 190. Hold.
1-9-0...
Airspeed.
I've done a few screwy
things in this outfit,
but this'll be
a first, huh, Gage?
She'll handle a lot like that 707
tanker you're used to flying.
But just remember, once
you get her on the ground,
you're still three
stories in the air.
I'll let you know
if it's true about
not being able to make
a bad landing in a 747.
Control reports 409
has lost radio contact.
Altitude.
What about the altitude?
Had they made corrections?
Negative.
What's our ETA at rendezvous?
Few minutes.
They haven't
got a few minutes!
ALEXANDER: We oughta
be able to see her soon.
Probably be below us.
Be harder to see.
MOSS: Two minutes to ETA.
She's gotta be
out there somewhere.
There she is.
She's flying it!
She's flying it herself!
Climb, baby. Climb.
The mountains. We're so close!
Ready, sir?
I'll see you in Salt Lake.
Lower away.
Ease him down
just a little. Steady.
(SCREAMS)
Dear God, he fell!
Good God almighty.
Oh, God.
- Get me in one of those jump suits.
- But, sir...
Get the suit, damn it!
You're not gonna do it, Al.
- Who's gonna stop me?
- I am!
You got anybody else up here who
knows how to fly that bloody plane?
This is just
plain suicide, sir.
We can't even let
you wear a chute.
It might deploy and pull
you up into the blades.
She's falling off.
Tell the chopper.
This the tether release?
Yes, sir.
She's losing altitude.
Get me outta here
before I change my mind.
Yeah! Yeah!
He made it! The
pilot's on the plane!
(CHEERING)
MAN: Salt Lake Approach.
Pilot is now
aboard Columbia 747.
Aircraft flying
straight and level.
Your hand.
I'll get you something.
Damn! That's all we need.
What is it?
Number three engine's running awful hot.
I'm gonna shut it down.
You tell the passengers. Tell
'em it's just a precaution.
- Okay.
- Tell 'em, baby.
(CHEERS AND WHISTLES)
Please, may I have
your attention?
Captain Murdock is now aboard,
and is flying this plane.
Thank you.
He wants me to tell you that
everything is under control.
However, he wants me
also to tell you
that he will have to shut down
one of the engines
which seems to be
running a little roughly.
We're gonna die!
But there is nothing
to be alarmed about.
Nothing.
Where are you goin', Arnie?
Arnie, where are you goin'?
Arnie! Arnie, come back.
Leave them alone up there.
Look, is everything all right?
I mean, there is
a pilot on board, right?
Yes, sir, there is.
I gotta tell him something, 'cause
I just saw something out there.
Wait! You can't go up there. Please, sir.
You're not allowed up there.
Please, sir, don't go up there.
I don't want you to go...
- What's going on?
- The gas is leaking.
I saw it out there.
It's leaking out of the wing.
We've got plenty of
fuel in the other tanks.
There's nothing
to worry about.
Why don't you go
back and sit down?
What about fire'?
It might explode.
There's no danger!
ARNIE: My God!
You get him
the hell outta here!
Please, sir, we know about the fuel.
Now, it's being handled.
It's all right.
We're handling it, okay?
Now go and sit down and relax. It's fine.
I'll get you a drink.
Shh!
Will you look at this?
The collision wiped out
so many instruments,
I can't tell what's
working and what isn't.
Alan, we are going to
be able to land, aren't we?
You tell me, honey.
I don't know if I can get
the landing gear down.
If it does come down, I can't tell
if it's locked into position.
Well, nothing I can
do about it, I guess.
How's Stacy?
Not good.
Radio too?
The radio's dead.
I've tried every channel.
Well, here we go.
Let's see if you can land one of these
things by the seat of your pants.
PATRONI: How long
before we land?
MOSS: Two minutes.
Salt Lake, this is Patroni.
We're on our way down.
We're gonna need ambulances for
the girl and the injured crew.
Hit the red button.
I want the field cleared!
Go have the passengers fasten
their seat belts, honey.
Tell the girls to hang on.
Go do your thing, baby.
Are we okay?
Have you heard anything?
Nothing.
Let's get back to work.
Prepare for landing.
Remember the intercom
systems aren't working.
Honey, we'll have to
stow this for landing.
I'll take good care of it.
(HONKING)
Buckle yourself in.
ALAN: They're down, baby.
Just hope they're locked.
Almost home.
Are we landing?
Yes, Janice.
I knew we'd be all right.
Nancy?
Yes?
I love you.
Over the fence.
(SQUEALING TIRES)
Damn!
- What's the matter?
- Brake pressure's dropping.
I don't know if we've got
enough left to stop this thing.
Jesus! This mother's got
10 backup systems too.
He can't stop her!
(SQUEALING TIRES)
Hang on.
(SIGHS)
Ladies and gentlemen, thank you
for flying Columbia Airlines.
Unfasten seat belts. Come on.
Let's go out this way!
What, are we here already?
Are we here already?
No! We're still in Washington.
What's going on?
Move, move, move, move.
The ambulance is waiting
to take you to the hospital.
They have a kidney, and they're
ready for the transplant.
All right. Get in there!
No, Miss Swanson, no.
You can't take that with you.
You'll get it later.
Jump! Jump!
Let's go. Get outta here!
I really was in that picture.
Remember when
the kids walked...
Ran into...
The hamburger shop?
I was the short-order cook.
No, I don't remember that.
Well I, I... One of the
hamburgers hit me on the head.
Don't you remember?
- I'll show you the scar.
- I believe you.
That's a big pussycat, dad!
No, it's a tomcat.
Oh, it's so beautiful!
Every morning is beautiful.
You're just too young to know.