Sincronia
Snoopysoft
From São Félix do Coribe to the World
# First, when there's nothing
# But a slow, glowing dream
# That your fear
# Seems to hide
# Deep inside
# Your mind
# All alone
# I have cried
# Silent tears
# Full of pride
# In a world
# Made of steel
# Made of stone
# Well, I hear the music
# Close my eyes
# Feel the rhythm
# Wrap around
# Take a hold of my heart
# What a feeling
# Being's believing
# I can have it all now l'm dancing
# For my life
# Take your passion
# And make it happen
# Pictures come alive
# You can dance right through your life... #
l'll tell you what.
l'll give you the Cowboys and three.
- Three and a half.
- Take three, be happy.
Three and a half. l'm ecstatic.
# What a feeling
# Being's believing
# I can have it all
Now l'm dancing for my life
# Take your passion
# And make it happen
# Pictures come alive
# Now l'm dancing through my life
# What a feeling... #
Hey, Is this surprise visit a one time shot?
If I said, it wouldn't be a surprise.
l'll buy you a beer.
# He doesn't mean a thing to me
# Just another pretty face to see
# He's all over town
Knocking 'em dead, honey
# l'd never let him next to me
# He's the kind of guy
Who thinks he's smart
# He's the type
That always looks the part
# He's so on the make
lt's so hard to take, honey
# l'd never let him touch my heart
# There he stands
Ask me if I care
# Look, he's coming close
# Oh, I swear
# He's got to be
The toughest guy l've ever seen
# I can't believe he's looking at me... #
Jake, sit down and play a game.
# He doesn't even catch my eye
# He's lucky he just walked on by
# 'Cause he hasn't met a girl like me
Are you kidding
# l'd tell him that l'd rather die
# There he stands
Ask me if I care
# Look, he's coming closer
# Oh, I swear, he's got to be
# The toughest guy l've ever seen
# I can't believe he's looking at me
# He's a... He's a dream... #
If I come up with a scoop on her,
I get Dallas and three and a half.
If you come up with anything on her,
l'll give you six.
# There he stands
Ask me if I care
# Look, he's coming closer
# Oh, I swear, he's got to be
The toughest guy l've ever seen
# I can't believe he's looking at me
# There he stands
Ask me if I care
# Look, he's coming closer
# I swear... #
Number 174-63-1503.
Pete, I don't want her zip code.
lt's her social
security number, asshole.
She works for you.
# He's a dream
# He's a dream #
One cheese, medium. Fries.
Two plain, rare,
tomato and onions.
One pastrami on kaiser.
Mayo, no mustard.
- What's a pimple on a Polack's ass?
- I need that BLT on rye, Richie.
A brain tumour.
- Richie.
- What's this?
Come on, Richie.
A lesbian with a hard-on.
l'm terrific, right?
You can tell me. I can take it.
Mayo, no mustard.
Can't you see me opening up in L.A?
Direct from Pittsburgh, it's
Richie Blazik, ladies and gentlemen.
L.A?
What's all this talk about L.A?
You've been on the stage two times.
I give you two lousy shots and
you're talking about going to L.A.!
Come on. What are you, crazy?
Besides, you're too short anyway.
They don't let short people
into Hollywood.
And you're making
the hamburgers too big again.
Make 'em smaller.
l'll give you small.
This place is so small you have
to go outside to change your mind.
My turn.
Ring, damn you.
I can't believe he didn't call.
- He'll call.
- Do you think so?
- Of course. Why wouldn't he?
- Yeah, why wouldn't he!
Maybe he'll call, I don't know.
When I talked to him, he seemed
funny. Like, ''l'll call you later, babe.''
I don't think he'll call.
- Don't worry, he'll call.
- You really think so?
- Why wouldn't he?
- You're right. He'll call.
- But if he doesn't call, should I call him?
- He'll call.
I love how you always try
to straighten out other people's lives.
Any time you want me
to straighten out yours, let me know.
Personally, I never call.
Because I don't have to.
- But if you want my advice...
- Not really.
- Hi, girls!
- Hi, Richie.
- Can I help? A foot massage?
- Get out of here!
- lt's been long since he's had some.
- I bet.
Hi.
Do you read lips?
What?
I saw you dance last night.
- I just wanted to say hi.
- Hi.
You're Alex.
I know.
l'm Nick Hurley.
Really?
l've seen your name
on my pay cheques.
What's a dancer doing
working as a welder?
A girl's got to make a living.
- You speak French?
- No. I just like the pictures.
Me too.
- Nick. They need you on ten.
- l'll be right there.
- You read Vogue?
- I used to.
My wife does.
I mean, my ex-wife.
l'm divorced.
We're divorced.
Sorry.
Listen, I got to get to work.
You never know when the boss
is going to be around.
You forgot your thermos.
Hi, Grunt.
So, did you get laid today?
'And now, news headlines
with Kevin Evans.'
'Good evening. In the news,
a fire caused extensive damage
'to the High View Lumber Company,
a dairy store
'and an American Motors
dealership in McDonald,
'Washington County,
this morning...'
Shit!
# Just a still town girl on a Saturday night
# Looking for the fight of her life
# In the real time world
No one sees her at all
# They all say she's crazy
# Locking rhythms to the beat of her heart
# Changing women into life
# She has danced into the danger zone
# When the dancer becomes the dance
# It can cut you like a knife
If the gift becomes the fire
# On a wire between will
And what will be
# She's a maniac
Maniac, on the floor
# And she's dancing
Like she's never danced before
# She's a maniac
Maniac, on the floor
# And she's dancing
Like she's never danced before... #
Excuse me. Do you know
where the admissions office is?
The door on the left.
- Where is the focus?
- Where is it?
Where is the centre?
Look up.
When you fill out this application, list all
your years of dance education.
Starting with the most recent
place you've studied,
and the number of years
at each institution.
Also, if you have any professional
or other repertory experience,
please list those.
When you fill out this application,
be sure to list all your years
of dance education.
And the number of years
you've spent at each institution.
- I got to go, you guys.
- See you, Alex. Don't get dirty.
- Hello, dancer.
- Hi.
- Want a hand?
- No, thanks.
You know, I have this close,
personal relationship
with the lady
who drives the lunch truck,
and I think I can get her
to make us anything we want.
- As long as it's on the menu.
- l'm not having lunch today.
- How about dinner?
- I can't.
I don't have dinner with the boss.
Thanks anyway.
No lunch, no dinner.
How about a snack?
Milk and cookies?
I love this dress. lt's exactly
like the picture I showed you.
Thanks so much for making it.
Now, more important,
did you go to the repertory?
I meant to. I was going to go
yesterday, but I didn't have time.
- You must make the time, child.
- I know.
Remember the first time
you took me to see them dance?
I have dreams about it.
Dreaming is wonderful, but it won't
get you closer to what you want.
But l've saved money, so if they take me,
I can support myself.
But, child, they won't take you
unless you apply and audition.
- I know, but sometimes...
- Alexandra, you are 18 years old.
Do it now! Do it!
OK.
You are a good girl.
May the Lord be in your heart
and mind that you confess your sins
in the name of the father,
the son and the holy spirit.
Bless me father, for I have sinned.
lt's been two weeks
since my last confession.
l'm doing OK. Sort of.
l've been thinking about sex a lot.
But you can't help
thinking about sex, right?
You probably can...
Help it, I mean.
Also, I told a lie.
I had to...
Well, I didn't have to, but...
All I wanted to do
is to make her happy.
Hanna wanted me
to get the application.
I couldn't tell her that I didn't have
the courage to go through with it.
If you had seen all those dancers...
all those people...
There is no way I belong there.
I want to make
something out of my life.
I want to do so much
and sometimes...
Sometimes I think
that it's just not going to happen.
Six beautiful girls! All nude!
Hi, baby, how are you doing?
Five dollars, right this way!
Five dollars! All nude all the time!
All nude, all the time!
Cecil, look at you.
Buy some threads,
l'm running a class act here.
You look like a one-man-slum.
All nude, all the time!
Right here, live!
Six beautiful girls!
Right here! Live!
Five dollars!
Right this way!
Five dollars! Live!
Nude! All girls, all the time!
Live! Nude! Right this way!
Right through the door!
Straighten yourself up.
Attract some customers.
Well, well, well, what are these?
They are very cute.
Very, very cute.
Alex!
Come on, give them back.
They are Richie's.
My dad's breathing down my neck.
He says Richie is no good.
If he ain't asked me to marry him
by now, he ain't gonna.
No kidding!
Did it take you long to learn
how to dance that way?
About 25 years.
- Will you teach me how?
- Yes.
- If you teach me how to skate.
Good evening, ladies.
Look at that.
$21,321, all leather, push-buttons.
You wanna go for a ride?
Jeanie, are you still fuckin' that cook?
Listen. Come see my club.
I just put this new PA system in.
The floor's lit up
where you're going to dance.
I want you to see
what you're going to call home.
Did you know that the smallest penis
ever measured was 1.1 inches?
You are some pair of cunts,
you know that?
I can't believe l'm working out
with this hangover.
Wait. l've lost my keys.
I can't believe this.
- Whoo!
- Hank! You moron!
Come on, let's go work out.
# I love rock 'n' roll
# So put another dime
In the jukebox, baby
# I love rock 'n' roll
# So come and take your time
And dance with me... #
He didn't call.
He'll call.
I don't think so, Alex.
He'll call, Tina.
- I don't know.
- Just look. Just call the man.
Say, ''Hey, baby,
what's happening?''
Your life's going to be
over before you make up your mind.
Just get up and call the dude.
Yeah? You really think so?
God, l'm glad I ain't no honky.
# Singing I love rock 'n' roll
# Put another dime
In the jukebox, baby
# I love rock 'n' roll
# So come and take your time
And dance with me #
# Watch me now
# Feel the groove
# lnto something
Gonna make you move
# Here we come
# On the run
# Don't know what
# We're running from
# Day or night
# Black or white
# Dance or sing
You gotta do your thing
# You gotta do your thing #
You girls eat like pigs.
What happened to the diet?
- I didn't eat anything yesterday.
- We'll work it off at the rink.
Is Richie going to be there?
Now there's a real winner.
No, we're gonna work.
- She thinks she'll be on the ice show.
- What's wrong with that?
- l'd make a lot of money.
- You're costing me a lot of money.
l'd just like to try it again, Daddy.
She's really good.
You ought to see her.
- She'll fall on her ass.
- She's got a tough ass.
Yeah, l've got a tough ass.
lt's not her ass l'm worried about.
Where are you?
Come here.
Here we go.
No, don't.
- You look great.
- Don't stop.
Do it again!
Shit, I can't do this.
No, go do your turn.
Do you know the triple one?
Hi. l'm Richie Blazik.
Hi. l'm Richie Blazik. Did you hear
about the Polack bank robber?
He tied up the safe, blew the guard.
Tied up the safe,
blew the guard.
Tied up the safe
and blew the guard.
Hey, Kid! Come here.
Come here!
- What's the matter?
- l'm nervous, Jake.
Now you ain't nervous anymore.
Now you're pissed off.
Good luck, baby.
Hi. How are you doing?
l'm Richie Blazik.
Did you hear about
the Polack bank robber?
He tied up the safe
and blew the guard.
So, the lady says to the waiter,
''Excuse me, sir,
do you have frogs legs?''
And the waiter says,
''No, that's just the way I walk.''
You want to talk about boogers?
I know a lot about them.
How about boogers?
Sports for fifty?
What's a pimple
on a Polack's ass?
A brain tumour.
Take a walk.
Bring on the bimbos.
Come on, guys.
Could you give me a break?
Look, l'm just a cook.
l'm just a cook, all right?
This is my big chance,
so if you screw it up for me,
l'm going to put cockroaches
in your hamburgers, you got it?
Miracles do happen, I guess.
It took the Steelers 40 years
to win a championship, didn't it?
Steelers!
I feel like Franco Harris when he made
the lmmaculate Reception.
It was amazing!
Did you hear about the Polack,
who locked his keys in the car,
and he used a coat hanger
to get his family out?
Did you hear about the Polack
who died drinking milk?
The cow fell on him.
A Polish terrorist
tried to blow up a car
and he burned his lips
on the exhaust pipe.
You guys have been real nice.
l've gotta go and cook the hamburgers.
No roaches, I promise.
So let me bring out our next act.
Direct from Mawby's.
lt's Tina Tech, ladies and gentlemen!
One, two, three, four!
# l'm going on a manhunt
# Turn it around
# Women have been hunted
Now we're hunting around
# Manhunt
# We all got the need
# The one that's been waiting
Has taken the lead
# Ruby lips in the mirror
# Black heels on the floor
# Perfume to draw him nearer
# A dress he can't ignore
# I know he'll be at the party tonight
# He'll be looking so fine
# He'll be surprised
When I walk up and say
# Man, I want to make you
Glad you're alive
# l'm going on a manhunt
# Turn it around
# Women have been hunting
Now we're hunting around
# Manhunt
# We all got the need
# The one who's been waiting
Has taken the lead
# l'm going on a manhunt
# l'm out for the kill #
Alex, sit down here a minute.
Cecil, this is a nice ass.
Soft...
Round. Snug...
Hey, she likes it!
Bimbo! Whore!
Fuck off!
Night, kids.
- Night.
- Night, Jake.
Hey, Richie, no more
jokes about cockroaches, huh?
You know, one of these days
I want to be like...
Richard Pryor, Eddie Murphy,
Steve Martin.
- Until that day comes...
- You'll just steal all their material.
- Hey, Alex.
- Let me go.
- What are you doing?
- Nothing to fight about.
- We're going to Cecil's.
- Let me go!
Drink a little wine.
Do a little weed. You and me.
How about Cecil?
You like Cecil?
- Get off of me!
- All three of us, real friendly.
Why don't you leave her
the fuck alone!
The comedian is
going to be a hero!
Cecil, what the fuck
is wrong with you?
Let her go, Johnny.
What are you doing here, Nick?
Slumming?
This ain't your
neighbourhood no more.
I didn't mean nothing.
I just got pissed off.
- Send me a bill, kid.
- Let me see.
- Is it bleeding? Oh, Jesus!
- Yeah.
Come on.
Here's your hat.
- Are you OK?
- Yeah.
- Are you sure?
- l'm OK. lt'll look good on stage.
- lt's going to be fine.
- Are you sure?
- Sure you're going to be OK?
- Yeah, fine.
Listen, what can I say?
Thanks a lot.
l'll give you a lift home.
lt's OK. l've got a ride.
Thanks anyway.
- What's his name?
- Grunt.
- Grunt?
- Yeah.
I can see that I don't have to
worry about you.
What was he
before he became a dog?
Well, he gets upset when people
he doesn't know follow me home.
Come on, Grant. This is the
man that feeds you.
Tell you what...
Tell him l'll bring him a doggy bag
if you'll have dinner with me.
Nick, I told you I don't think it's a
good idea to go out with the boss.
OK. Have it your way.
You're fired.
l'll pick you up tomorrow at eight.
How long does this thing last?
lt's cold in here.
- How's the nose?
- lt's broken.
Broke mine three times.
It was big in the '50s, wasn't it?
Busting noses?
'60s.
Think she can beat her?
'Miss Szabo.'
You're going to do great.
# Gloria
# You're always on the run now
# Running after somebody... #
Go Jeanie! Come on!
# I think you've got to slow down
# Before you start to blow it
# I think you're heading for a breakdown
# So be careful not to show it... #
Oh... look at that one.
There you were 20 years ago,
sweetheart.
There we go. Come on!
# If everybody wants you
# Why isn't anybody calling?
# You don't have to answer... #
Come on, Jeanie!
# Calling Gloria
# Gloria
# I think they got the number
# I think they got the alias
# That you've been living under
# But you really don't remember
# Was it something that they said?
# All the voices in your head
# Calling Gloria... #
Get up, Jeanie!
lt's going to be OK.
All that time and practice.
What a waste.
- Goddamn waste of time.
- Come on, It was not.
It wasn't.
You went out there, didn't you?
At least you had the guts to try.
How are you doing, sport?
l'm sorry, Daddy.
I love you more than l've ever
loved anything in my whole life.
What the hell.
You bounced pretty good.
She practised for two years.
- She'll do better next time.
- There won't be any next time.