All rise, please.
The Court of California
is now in session.
The Honorable Judge Lundstrom,
presiding.
Please be seated.
Mr. D'Ambrosia?
This case is a travesty!
You have no evidence whatsoever
linking the accused to the murder.
The gun found in his car was obtained
as the result of an illegal search.
In the eyes of the court
it does not exist.
The search was illegal
because Inspector Callahan...
...and this is an old story...
...did not have sufficient probable
cause for detaining Mr. Hawkins.
The gun is inadmissible and
the charges against the defendant...
...are dismissed!
Mr. D'Ambrosia...
...be assured that I will discuss
your case-preparation techniques...
...with the district attorney.
Bailiff, next!
How many times, Callahan?
You can't bust them
because you think they're dirty.
"Psychic" don't cut it.
Hey, Callahan.
Don't look so puked-out.
Better luck next time, fool.
Listen, punk.
To me, you're just dog shit,
you understand?
Many things can happen to dog shit.
It can be scraped up with a shovel.
It can dry up and blow away,
or be stepped on and squashed.
My advice:
Be careful where the dog shits you.
Class act, Callahan.
A real class act.
Loretta.
You did real good with that cop!
Now, I want everything.
Money, watches, rings, everything!
Quick! Move!
Come with me.
We'll have a little party!
What are you doing,
you pig-head sucker?
Every day for the last 10 years,
Loretta gives me a black coffee.
Today she gives me a black coffee,
but with sugar in it.
A lot of sugar.
I just came back to complain.
Now, you boys put those guns down.
Say what?
We're not just going
to let you walk out of here.
Who is "we," sucker?
Smith and Wesson...
...and me.
Go ahead...
...make my day.
Call D'Ambrosia in the D.A.'s office,
ask him if coffee is psychic.
- Ernie.
- What?
Look who's going into the hotel.
Is that who I think it is?
Shit!
Why me?
A nothing detail!
A lousy peeper tour!
So, what do we do now?
Call Captain Briggs, let him decide.
May I have your invitation, sir?
I don't understand,
Inspector Callahan.
You know the number
for San Francisco General?
Yes, I do.
Why don't you call,
have them send an ambulance?
Tell them there's two assholes...
...with multiple contusions
and sundry broken bones.
- Inspector Callahan.
- I want to talk to Threlkis.
At his granddaughter's wedding?
On what business?
- To help him catch the bouquet.
- They have harassment laws.
Sit down. Please.
Champagne? It's imported.
Men, like wine, should grow finer,
more civilized.
They should mellow,
become more worldly.
But not Callahan.
Callahan is the one constant
in an ever-changing universe.
Linda Doker?
Fished out of the bay a month ago.
Her breasts were slashed.
Her feet burned.
Her face smashed to a pulp.
I read about it.
A hooker.
A very expensive one.
In fact, her specialty was making
old scumbags mellow and worldly.
She had a special customer
who said lots of things.
You are a fool, Callahan.
She may have been clever
and written them down.
Maybe she made a copy of it.
Maybe she didn't tell
when she was being tortured.
What will the scumbag's bosses
say when they find out?
Or his family?
Maybe his ass is in a wringer.
You fucking...
Someone help us.
Call an ambulance.
Sorry, inspector, but captain...
What happened?
Someone grabbed their chest.
Must've seen the bill.
Oh, my God.
Stand back, please.
Harry, wait till you see this.
Some stiff got himself
a.38-caliber vasectomy.
Harry, you don't look so hot.
Bad night? All nookied out?
Gang hit? Screwed-up drug score?
Unlucky john?
Or an unhappy love affair?
Don't tell me this shit's
getting to you.
Not Harry Callahan. Say it ain't so.
No, this stuff isn't getting to me.
Shootings, knifings, beatings.
Old ladies getting bashed
for Social Security checks.
Teachers being thrown out of windows.
- That doesn't bother me a bit.
- Harry, take it easy.
Or this job, wading through
the scum of the city.
Being swept away by bigger and bigger
waves of corruption and red tape.
That doesn't bother me.
You know what does?
You know what makes me sick
to my stomach?
Watching you stuff your face
with hot dogs.
Nobody, I mean nobody,
puts ketchup on a hot dog.
What the hell you talking about?
Having our fingers in the holes and
the whole dike is crumbling around us.
Lt. Donnelly says to get your... self
to the commissioner's office.
Swell.
- Leah, can I speak with you?
- Jennifer, what marvelous timing.
I'm giving your work
the favorite positions.
I'm afraid you'll be wasting
good selling spots.
Nonsense.
They're the jewels of the exhibit.
Don't be discouraged
if they don't sell immediately.
They're intense. People need time
to get used to them.
I'm just getting used to them myself.
How can such a howl of anguish
come from such a sweet girl as you?
I'm leaving town.
- When?
- Today.
But you'll miss the exhibit,
the opening.
I'm better at painting
than receptions.
Can I give you an address
to send the paintings to?
Think positive. It's money
we'll send from the sales.
- Where are you going?
- North, to visit someone.
Look at the blond baby!
Mama, check it out.
How you doing?
She wants to play.
- Need a lift?
- Sure, baby.
Then shove a jack up your ass.
Puta.
In 30 years of police work,
this is the most outrageous...
...transgression of authority ever.
- What the hell were you doing?
- My job.
It's your job to harass and incite
an old man into a heart attack?
My job's to investigate homicide.
That old man is the
biggest crime lord in the West.
How did I know
he would vapor-lock?
You hoped he would.
The Doker case is mine.
It's stuck. I broke it loose.
- With threats and intimidation.
- Any way.
Are you aware...
...that you've destroyed
months of surveillance work?
Thousands of dollars.
Hundreds of man-hours.
Investigations is busting its ass
to build a case on Threlkis.
He would've snaked out of it.
Maybe we saved the taxpayers money.
I ought to bust your ass
down to Traffic.
Or better, kick it off the force.
You're a dinosaur, Callahan.
Your ideas don't fit today.
What ideas are these?
Murder's a crime,
it shouldn't be punished?
Don't lecture me, you son of a bitch.
You know who you're talking to?
You know my record?
You're a legend in your own
mind.
- Goddamn you, Callahan.
- Gentlemen, enough.
Inspector, your methods are
different. But you get results.
Often your successes
are more costly to the city...
...in terms of publicity and
destruction than most failures.
The press will have a field day
with this fiasco.
There may be legal repercussions.
There could be attempts at retaliation.
I think the inspector
should take some time off.
You're suspending me?
I'm suggesting you vacation
until it's calm.
I'm not up for vacation.
Callahan, I'm not fencing with you.
Take a few days off.
Harry, a couple of days.
Think things over, Callahan.
Get with it.
It's a new ballgame these days.
Funny, I never thought of it
as a game.
I examined your sister Elizabeth,
and I tested her again.
There are no changes.
The computerized tomogram
shows no evidence...
...of chronic subdural hematoma.
Physically, she's in good shape.
She remains in a vegetative state
that we can't penetrate.
Not even a primitive startle response.
We'll keep trying,
we're always hopeful.
You should be too.
Hi, baby.
It's me.
Jen.
I missed you.
Beth?
I saw one of them.
He just appeared on the street
in front of me.
At first I thought I was having
some horrible vision.
But no. He was there.
Older and uglier.
I followed him.
For days I watched him.
Then I bought a gun.
I followed him to a bar.
I let him pick me up.
Let him drive me to a deserted spot.
Let him think...
It was like I was outside myself.
Above me, looking down.
Then he touched me.
And I killed him.
Beth?
I love you.
- Hell of a way to have a night off.
- You in on the act?
No, for Christ's sake.
Back off a little.
I worry about your ass.
It'll be shot off or kicked out.
What else is new?
They're not a bunch of junkies.
To them, you killed Threlkis,
same as shooting him.
They'll keep coming after you.
Good, we'll know where they are.
You're incredible, Callahan.
You're also on vacation
as of right now.
- I'm not up for vacation.
- You are, I just put you up.
Go get some R and R
and stay out of trouble.
You hear me, Callahan?
Peace and quiet!
Good morning, Horace.
Sweet Sister Sadie,
where the hell did you get that?
I've had it a while.
Thought I'd get used to it.
I heard about the car.
Fabulous, coming after you in tanks.
Yeah, they're making those now, for
sheiks and business executives, hoods.
- Impregnable to anything but artillery.
- Well, you got that covered.
Not bad.
My ass! You have to strain
the remains for the fingerprints.
Well, this is the.44 Magnum Auto-Mag.
It has a 300-grain cartridge...
...and, if properly used,
it can remove the fingerprints.
I got just the place for you
to go on vacation.
- You got that wrong.
- You've no choice.
I think I do.
- You thinking about quitting?
- I might.
Look at the field.
Look what you did there.
Not quite good enough.
You can't quit, that's what.
Okay, jamf?
What's the brass going to do?
Who are they going to complain to?
And the PR men kissing ass,
ass that you kicked.
You're nothing but a cop.
That's all you've been
and all you'll be, jamf.
Thank you, doctor.
Listen, when you get cut,
you'll bleed P.D. Blue, jamf.
What the hell's a "jamf"?
- That means you're a jive-ass mother...
- Forget I asked.
Almost there.
I hope the house is suitable.
It's a bit deserted out in West Cliff.
I thought you'd appreciate
the solitude as you seek inspiration.
The house is lovely.
I've left the fridge stocked for you.
And there's firewood for a fire.
Let's see, here are the keys...
...for the carousel house.
Everything you need should be here.
But if you have any additional wants,
we have an account in Dunstan's.
Thank you.
I can't tell you how happy we are...
...that you're doing this work
for the Historical Society.
Because your work is so impressive
and so impeccably authentic.
I do my research.
It must give you great satisfaction
to make old, ugly things right again.
Yes, sometimes it does.
Like what I brought you, baby?
I like you, yeah.
Tell him that you like it.
Don't forget,
I get my shot at the other one.
Come on, Alby.
What are you, queer?
There he is.
- We'll show you dog shit, Callahan!
- Come on. Let's go kick some ass.
There he is! We've got him!
That's your idea of rest and
recreation? What's wrong with you?
Briggs is berserk and
the commissioner's on my ass.
I'm sorry to hear that.
Can't you do anything the easy way?
- Am I on the job or not?
- You are.
Good. Then I'll get to it.
It's not what you think.
Remember that cock-shot stiff
by the Cliff House?
He's been here a few years,
but in the shade.
He looks small-time,
but maybe he was never caught.
And?
He came from San Paulo,
born and raised.
I want you to go there
and find out about him.
- What is this crap?
- It's a murder case, Harry.
- You're shipping me out?
- I'm doing you a favor.
You are a walking combat zone.
People seem to die around you.
I don't want civilians
taking the fall.
You want to work?
Fine.
You got your assignment.
Get the hell out of here.
Take all the time you need. Maybe
the salt air will agree with you.
Any comments?
Swell.
Freeze!
Around the corner!
What's the matter?
You trying to kill someone?
Excuse me.
Police officer in pursuit
of a robbery suspect.
- Shag his ass!
- Get that sucker!
Nail that son of a bitch!
Is he all right?
I guess I'd better
read you your rights.
Best damn day trip I've had
since they put me in that home.
Holy mackerel.
So, you're the famous Harry Callahan.
I'll make this short and sweet.
I'll only say it once.
We don't need a hotshot to show
us dumb yokels how to do our business.
We know how to do our business,
so you keep your nose out of it.
You read me, Harry?
Aye, aye, sir.
Easy, boy.
Horace, you son of a bitch.
Swell.
Damn, Meathead.
What did you call me?
I was talking to the dog.
- Is that your dog?
- Yes.
Why? Do you want him?
If you can't control him, get a leash.
There are laws.
Quiet!
You seem to be all right.
I'm fine,
but you'd better get it together.
Quiet!
This way, inspector.
This is it, inspector.
The coffee room and john
are down the hall.
If that's all, I'll get back to work.
Nice work yesterday, inspector.
It was me. You saved my life.
Thanks.
Right.
If there is anything...
- Can I help you?
- Draft.
My game! My game!
You son of a bitch.
Come on, dickhead, fork over the bucks
before I kick your nuts up your nose!
I don't have any bucks, Ray.
I pissed it away.
And you? Pull something from
your pants besides your wet string.
I ain't got much.
We've been here all day...
...and they won't run us no more tab.
Give me it, twat-lips, or
I'll give your face its first period.
Want to go a couple of chugalugs
for some scratch?
- What about us?
- Suck my ass with a straw!
- How about it, Kruger?
- I'm out of here.
Shit, Kruger!
You're good for shit anymore.
What's happened to you?
Hi, cutie.
- Want to buy me a drink?
- Not today.
Come on, sailor. I know there's some
question you want to ask me.
Go ahead. You might get lucky.
Only with humans.
Shit!
Looking for trouble, pal?
Looking for friends
of George Wilburn's.
- Are you a cop?
- What did he do?
He lost his balls. He got killed.
- Turn it off.
- What?
You don't remember, do you?
Remember what?
My sister and I will never forget.
One night...
...long ago?
Under the boardwalk?
Remember?
Looks like I owe you one, Meathead.
- Inspector, what...?
- Where's Jannings?
Buckman Cove.
A fisherman discovered a body there.
He personally checks up
on every corpse?
No, sir.
But this was clearly a murder.
The victim was shot twice. Once in
the head, once in the genitals.
We should go to the outer office.
You know anyone in this picture?
Not really.
I think they're friends
of the chief's son.
And this girl?
The dyke? Yeah.
Everybody knows Ray Parkins.
She's just a local. Why?
Looks familiar.
I thought I'd seen her somewhere.
It's hard not to run across her
in San Paulo.
Why didn't you call me?
Who are you
that I should call you?
What went on at your hotel
this morning?
What do you think?
You tell me,
Mr. Big-City Inspector.
Everywhere you go,
somebody gets killed...
...and I don't like it.
And I don't like you.
So finish your research
and get out of my town.
It's more than research.
You're too stupid to realize that.
- Get out of here.
- The m.o.'s the same.
Ballistics will I.D. The bullet
as from the same gun.
You're not going to do anything
but get your ass out of here!
Right this damn minute or
I swear to Jesus I'll lock you up!
I told you
I don't want you in my store.
I've got to talk to you,
you stuck-up asshole.
We've got nothing
to say to each other.
You hear the radio?
Leave my store.
Kruger's dead.
They found him this morning.
He had his balls splattered
all over the front of his pants.
I don't care, Ray.
Same thing happened to Wilburn
in San Francisco.
Wilburn?
Remember him?
He's dead.
That's twice I don't care.
Well, you better care, prick!
- I think she's come back.
- Who?
Don't try to pretend with me,
you hypocritical shit!
You dipped your wick
just like the others.
You shut your mouth.
You evil witch.
What's the matter,
afraid somebody's going to hear?
Afraid you'll lose some of
your customers if they find out?
There's nothing to find out.
You make me want to puke!
I'm going to call Mick.
You do what you want, but keep that
psycho bastard away from me.
I'll tell him you said that.
Watch them real good!
And be prepared...
...boy scout.
Now, see. Just like I told you.
Hurt me this time,
and it'll be your last.
Hurt you, babe?
What do you take me for?
- Let me up.
- Sure, babe, sure.
In a minute.
Say it first.
Say it!
- Mickey.
- Yes.
Baby...
...you're so beautiful.
I want you, Mickey.
- How bad do you want me?
- I want you bad.
You're so strong.
You're all a man should be.
Baby, that's right.
Keep talking, baby. Come on.
- Don't stop now, bitch!
- I can't! The phone!
Who the fuck is this?
Well...
...how do?
Getting near my time to call you.
I like it like this.
Maybe we'll just keep it this way,
since you know how to find me.
That so?
We'll just have to do something
about that, won't we?
Horace, do me a favor. Get me
the ballistics on the Wilburn killing?
The what?
I got him.
Almost as ugly as you are.
He does have his good points.
Can you wire the report
in the morning?
You keep your ass covered
until I can get this arranged.
Thanks.
Kruger.
Okay.
- If Chief Jannings finds out...
- He won't.
Just get me the information.
Names, where they are,
where they work.
It's not easy, inspector.
I won't risk taking that photo
off his wall.
One other thing,
could you get me Kruger's sheet?
Anything else?
Just the address.
Mrs. Kruger?
Can I have a word with you?
- You from the insurance company?
- No.
If you don't want fish,
get your ass out of here.
Mrs. Kruger, my name's Callahan.
You got shit in your ears, buddy?
I'd like to ask a few questions
about your husband.
That lousy son of a bitch?
He leaves me nothing.
I'm up to my ass in bills.
He let the insurance run out.
Then he's killed
looking at dirty pictures...
...when he ain't touched me
in months, bastard.
Can't you see our sister's mourning?
Get out of here.
Why don't you go suck
some fish heads?
Don't even think about it.
Well, I'll come back...
...when you're less bereaved.
You've come a long way.
Somebody told us to get it together.
I have a feeling
you've heard that before.
Sorry if I was a little gruff...
...but you and your friend
took me by surprise.
Buy me a beer,
and we'll call it even.
Stay, Meathead.
Waiter, a beer for Mr...?
Callahan.
- And another for me, please.
- Right away.
I'm Jennifer Spencer.
How's police business?
What makes you think I'm a cop?
I saw the commotion. You're either
a cop or public enemy number one.
Some people might say both.
Really? Who?
Bozos with big brass nameplates
on their desks...
...and asses the shape
of the seats of their chairs.
Why?
It's a question of methods.
Everybody wants results...
...but nobody wants to do
what they must to get them.
And you do?
I do what I have to.
I'm glad, Callahan.
But you're an endangered species.
It's the age of lapsed
responsibility and defeated justice.
"Eye for an eye" means
"Only if you're caught."
Then it's an indefinite postponement
and "settle out of court."
Does that sound profound
or just boring?
Sorry, I'm sure you get
that sort of thing often.
No, I don't hear it enough.
I promise to adjourn Philosophy 101.
- What do you do for a living?
- I paint.
Paint?
Houses, cars, what?
Horses.
Horses?
Hobbyhorses.
I'm restoring the carousel here.
You don't seem like
a typical San Paulo policeman.
I'm not.
- Typical?
- San Paulo.
San Francisco P.D., Homicide.
Don't say this is your idea
of a vacation.
No, I'm down here on a case.
Just gathering information in general.
Anything interesting?
It's coming around.
Got any theories?
Somebody's doing some killing
and I think it'll go on.
- A psycho?
- Probably.
It could be somebody
just collecting on a debt.
Revenge?
The oldest motivation
known to mankind.
You don't approve?
Till it breaks the law.
Are you gonna want
another one of these?
No, I work early.
- I'll get that.
- No, no.
A deal's a deal.
- Good night.
- Hey, is that your dog?
- Why, you want him?
Swell.
The witch was right.
It is you.
Put down the gun.
Now look, you've got to
understand something.
That was a long time ago.
It was 10 years ago.
I was just a kid.
I didn't mean anything by it.
I know it was wrong...
...but I was drunk.
I didn't even know what I was doing!
I'm a businessman now.
I'm making money.
I can give you some of it.
You need money, right?
Please.
It wasn't my fault.
The others made me do it.
Don't make me beg.
It wasn't that bad, was it?
Not bad enough to kill me for.
People sell it every day.
They give it away.
Christ, don't.
Please.
Don't shoot me.
Come in.
Close the door.
Sit down.
It's for you.
What's going on? Jannings
has got the commissioner's ear.
He's a good guy.
Go easy with him, will you?
Harry, you don 't have
a hell of a lot of friends upstairs.
Don 't screw yourself, okay?
Understand?
No, I don't understand...
...at all.
Here's the ballistic reports for
the Kruger and Wilburn killing.
I think you'll find
they match up perfectly.
So that's the story, kid.
So our little college honey
is collecting dues?
You got it.
Heads up.
- So, what are we going to do?
- We snuff her.
This town's got thousands of people.
Maybe she's not even staying here.
How do we find her?
We don't.
- What do you mean?
- We wait.
She's coming after you, too,
sometime, right?
I suppose.
And we'll be here.
Make her feel real welcome.
What about Tyrone and Alby?
I don't give a fuck about Tyrone.
And Alby's covered.
How? The guy's a zombie. He doesn't
even know if he's pissing himself.
He's covered.
Okay.
- You never give up, do you?
- It's my job, remember?
What do you want from me, Callahan?
Why are you delaying
this investigation?
Every available man's on the street.
We're logging more overtime
than the town can afford.
We'll get that maniac.
- Do you think the killings are random?
- I reject no theory at this time.
There's been no truth declared on the
muggings...
...the burglaries,
the drunken driving.
All the less-headline-grabbing crimes
that we face everyday.
Now, we're doing the best we can.
Maybe that's not good enough.
Callahan, this is not, repeat, not,
your jurisdiction, so stay out of it.
I'm warning you.
Aren't you curious as to why I'm here?
Coming to the party I told you about?
I can't. My sister's visiting.
She a college girl, too?
No, she's a junior in high school.
Bring her.
The more, the merrier.
I don't think so.
What's the matter?
Us locals not good enough for you?
It's not that!
You don't understand.
All right, we'll come,
but we have to leave early.
Leave whenever you like.
Who knows?
You may have a nice time.
It's Callahan.
Can I talk to Bennett?
I'll patch you through.
Bennett here.
Bennett, would you run a plate for me?
1 -Adam-Queen-Ida-1-7-5.
All right, inspector.
What the fuck are you doing?
- You fucking pig!
- Give me a little!
Get your hands off of me!
All I wanted was...
Wait!
What the hell is this?
Police officer.
I have a few questions.
My ass!
Get him, goddamn it!
Son of a bitch!
You bastard!
Knock it off!
Stop it!
Now, you're coming downtown
and answering some questions.
Don't answer nothing, Mick!
Son of a bitch, I'll get a lawyer!
He'll be out tomorrow,
you fucking bastard!
The bitch is here.
So tell me.
How's your slut sister?
Book him!
A little late for wave-watching,
isn't it?
I couldn't sleep.
- A beer?
- Thanks.
It's not safe to be out alone
after dark.
Life is full of risks, isn't it?
I better go home.
Thanks for the beer.
- Did you bicycle down here?
- No, I walked. It relaxes me.
I'll give you a ride home.
No, that's all right.
It's okay, it relaxes me.
This is it.
Well, thanks for the lift.
Want something stronger
to drink than beer?
Come on in.
I don't mind if I do.
I'll get some brandy.
Unusual.
I have a rule.
Never drink with a critic.
You want to be alone tonight?
Neither do I.
Harry, wake up, sucker. The heat's
off and we're going to celebrate.
Well, well, well.
Kiss your ass good-bye, Sambo.
Bennett.
Bennett, send someone to Ray
Parkins' place. She's getting ripe.
Bring that punk to the interrogation
room. I've got questions for him.
Sorry, inspector, he's been released.
Who sprung him?
Kruger's brother-in-law picked him up.
Swell.
Inspector, I'll get
that license plate number you wanted.
No, forget about that.
That turned out to be nothing.
Thanks.
I don't know where they are.
Just leave me alone!
Hotshot cop.
Your ass is mine!
Mick, the gun!
Cocksucker!
Drop the gun.
He couldn't live with it.
The other vermin didn't care.
But the guilt ate at his gut...
...like an acid.
He actually wanted you to come back.
He used to sit, waiting,
praying that you'd come back.
One night
he couldn't wait any longer.
He just got in his car and smashed
himself into a retaining wall.
Now you're here
and he doesn't even know it.
It's my fault.
I should have let him
be punished then...
...along with the other filth.
He's my only child.
His mother died giving birth to him.
We're all each other have.
I was afraid for him.
I was afraid for me.
You see, I was a public figure.
So...
...I did things. I fixed it.
And now I want you to just go.
Let it end.
There's one left.
And I've got him...
...in my jail.
You just leave him to me.
He's preyed on Alby and me ever since.
That too is going to end.
Is that so, Lester boy?
Put down the piece, Lester.
Or I'll splatter what's left
of the retard's brains...
...all over the floor.
Hi, babe.
Is this what you had in mind for me?
You almost fucked up here, Lester!
But don't worry,
I'll take care of everything.
And you won't have to do a damn thing
but sit on your fat ass.
But first, me and the little babe
are going to relive some old times.
Damn, Mick! You didn't say nothing
about doing the chief.
Don't sweat it. It's a freebie.
We just signed
our little honey's name to it.
Horace?
Shit, man.
Hey, you remember this place, babe?
Sure. You remember.
I wonder if it's any better
after all these years.
If there's anything left,
you boys can have a piece.
Okay, you prickless scum!
You want to try it again?
Think you can get it up this time?
Think you can make it work this time?
You want me, you filthy maggot?
You take me!
Because this time
you'll have to rape my dead body!
No!
The bitch is mine!
All right.
You lousy cunt!
- You all right, Mick?
- Get her!
Get the bitch!
Where is she?
You ain't getting out of here.
The door!
Get her!
No you don't, sweetie.
Holy shit!
Come on, cop!
Come up and enjoy the party!
We've got a class reunion
happening up here!
Let the girl go, punk!
Let my baby go?
I can't do that!
This is my baby.
This is my prize.
Come on, cop!
You know I can't do that!
I can't just let her go!
Then it would be just you and me!
Come on, make my day.
That's not a bad idea, is it?
What happens now?
- I guess now I've got to...
- Read me my rights?
What exactly are my rights?
Where was the concern for my rights
when I was being beaten?
What about my sister's rights
when she was brutalized?
There's a thing called justice.
And was it justice
that they should all walk away?
You'll never understand, Callahan.
Inspector,
we found a.38 snub in his belt.
Run it through ballistics.
I think you'll find his gun
was used in all the killings.
Then it's over?
Yeah, it's over.
Subtitles by
SDI Media Group
[ENGLISH]