- Here, give me the bottle.
- Go to hell.
Goddamn ya!
Get your own bottle!
Give me the bottle!
Give it to me!
I'll give you nothin'.
- Give me the bottle.
- I'm givin' you nothin'.
Give it.
Give me the bottle!
I'll give you nothin'.
Give me the Bo...
♪ see that cloud ♪
♪ There in the sky ♪
♪ Slowly drifting by ♪
♪ Well, that's the way ♪
♪ She's a-driftin' ♪
♪ From me ♪
Good morning.
Hi.
♪ I know there's someone else ♪
♪ But, oh, it hurts ♪
♪ So much to face reality ♪
♪ A little child ♪
♪ Boy or girl ♪
♪ Will dream at night ♪
♪ In their own dream world ♪
Forty cents short of makin' it.
- You got forty cents in your purse?
- Let's see, now.
- Here ya are.
- Thank you.
♪ Well, I'm no child ♪
♪ But times it's true ♪
♪ Because it hurts ♪
♪ So much to face ♪
♪ Reality ♪
Your friend said to tell ya
he had to move on.
How long will I have been here?
Two days.
- How far is it to the nearest town?
- Four Miles.
♪ With me ♪
♪ It's reality ♪
Fella I was with pay
for the room before he left?
No.
♪ Will take my place ♪
♪ I'll go on ♪
♪ Lovin' you ♪
♪ Through eternity ♪
♪ But, oh, it hurts ♪
♪ So much to face ♪
♪ Reality ♪
lady?
I'm broke.
But I'll be glad to work out
what I owe ya.
All right, but there's no drinkin'
while you're workin' here.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Are ya hungry?
Well, I, I could
eat somethin', yeah.
Everything was said and done
- sure is a pretty day, isn't it, Sonny?
- Yes, ma'am.
Wish I had time to stay out here in
the yard and enjoy it a little bit.
Why don't you?
Oh, I can't, honey.
I've got a million things
to do today.
I'll help ya.
Oh, I know you will.
Yes?
If you still need help the next
couple of days, I'd like to work on.
All right. I can give you your room and
your meals and two dollars an hour.
Thank you.
Find out what ya got to say
we first got this letter from a
very nice lady and her husband...
Who moved here to Texas,
and they like it.
And they liked the program. And they
said the only thing they didn't...
mister, what's your name?
Mac.
Don't throw stones at me, son.
- How was school?
- All right.
You learn anything?
Not much.
What are you doin' down here?
- Thinking.
- About what?
Things.
Good things or bad things?
Some of both.
You never knew
my daddy, did ya?
I never did.
Think you would have liked him
if you'd known him?
Sure. What do you think?
I guess.
I'll learn to love again
somehow
I'll even learn
to play the fool again
no, I'll never even learn
to say good-bye
to the woman that I've known
for so long
we have heard the joyful sound
Jesus saves, Jesus saves
spread the tidings all around
bear the news to every land
climb the steeps
and cross the waves
onward 'tis our lord's command
Jesus saves, Jesus saves
sing, ye islands of the sea
echo back, ye ocean caves
earth shall keep her jubilee
Jesus saves, Jesus saves
shout salvation full and free
highest hills and deepest caves
this our song of victory
Jesus saves, Jesus saves
good to see you, sir.
- Very nice.
- See you at the midweek service.
- Well, hi, Sonny. How are you doin'?
- Hi.
Hi, reverend.
I want you to meet Mac sledge.
- He works for me down at the motel.
- How are you, sir?
How do you do, Mr. sledge? Sonny
tells me he wants to be baptized.
I know that makes
you proud, rosa Lee.
- Yes, it does.
- You were baptized in this church, weren't you?
- Yes, sir, I was.
- And where were you baptized, Mr. sledge?
I haven't been baptized.
- Well, we'll have to work on you then.
- Yes, sir.
So long, Sonny. See you later.
Turn off the TV, Sonny, and get to bed.
You got school tomorrow.
- Can I talk with you all a little bit first?
- No, sir.
- Good night.
Good night.
Good little fella.
Yeah. He's growin' up so fast, he'll
be gone before I even know it.
- You have any other family?
- No.
I was the only kid my mom and daddy had...
had me kind of late in life.
My daddy's been dead... He died
two years after my husband was killed,
and mama died a year
and a half ago last spring.
My mama and daddy are dead too.
But I have a brother
out in California someplace.
We... lost track of each other.
- I have a daughter.
- You do?
Yeah, she's seven or eight
years older than your boy.
- Well, where is she?
- With her mama. Me and her mama are divorced.
We didn't get along
too well. I reckon I...
would you all stop talkin'?
I can't get to sleep.
I haven't had a drink
in two months.
- I think that drinkin's behind.
- Do you?
I'm glad. I don't think
it gets ya anywhere.
You ever thought
about marryin' again?
Yeah. I have.
Have you?
I thought about it lately.
I guess it's no secret how I feel about ya.
A blind man could see that.
Would you think
about marryin' me?
Yeah. I will.
Hey!
Your dad's dead.
I know he's dead.
He got killed in some dumb war.
- I know that. He got killed in Vietnam.
- What was his name?
Carl Herbert wadsworth. I was named after him.
I'm Carl Herbert wadsworth, Jr.
Well, how come everybody
calls you Sonny?
I don't know. They just do.
That man your mama's
married to now ain't your daddy.
I know that, dummy. I know what he is.
He's my stepdaddy.
Is he still a drunk?
- Hi. How was school?
- Okay.
Did my daddy go to the same
school I go to?
- Yes.
- Do I look like my daddy?
- Comin' with us, Mac?
- You go on. I'll wait here.
Here it is.
I couldn't put down the day he
died because the army didn't know.
Was there a big crowd
at his funeral?
Yeah, there was.
- Did I go?
- No.
Why not?
'Cause you were too little.
Did people cry at the funeral?
- Yes, they did.
- Did you?
Yes, I did.
Morning.
Wanna fill it up?
- Mr. sledge.
- Yes, sir.
Are you Mac sledge, the singer?
I mean...
I was a singer, I mean.
I mean, I am Mac sledge.
You were married
to Dixie Scott, weren't ya?
- I got nothin' to say about that.
- She never married again, did she?
Are you remarried?
Is that your boy?
That's not your boy, is it?
Mr. sledge, it took me
quite a while to track you down.
I'd really appreciate
an interview.
I got nothin' to say
to anybody.
Well, are you doin'
any singing anymore?
Writin' any songs these days?
Somebody said that... I heard your new
wife is singing at the baptist church.
Say, I guess your daughter
by your first wife...
Has gotta be
goin' on 18 by now?
Hey, I'm gonna do a story,
Mr. sledge.
You ought to talk to me
to make sure I get it right.
You got two minutes? Won't ya
sit down and talk to me?
No, sir. Sonny.
K.O.K.E. Fm and am
in Austin, Texas.
People 'round here
know who you are?
Your ex-wife is singin' over in Austin in the
next couple of nights. Did you know that?
You gonna go over and see her?
Maybe your daughter'll be along. Maybe
she'll come over here and see you.
Does she know where ya are?
Well, Dixie told me
a lot about you.
Don't you wanna tell me
a few things about her?
She said alcohol...
alcohol is what licked ya.
You still drink?
- They say you were a rich man once.
- Who said?
Kids at school said
they had it in the paper.
I don't know if I was what you call
rich, but I had a few dollars.
How'd you get it?
- Writin' songs.
- And how do you get money for that?
Hell, if people are crazy enough
to pay for it, they do it.
- What happened to your money?
- I lost it.
- How?
Too much applejack.
You think you'll ever
be rich again?
Well, I tell you what, Sonny.
I don't lay awake nights
worryin' about it. Now, look.
There's a d, right? D as in dog.
Now watch me. I'll call 'em out.
I've decided to leave G.
Here forever not really.
Let me know if you're stayin'
behind that's a seven.
Otherwise, I'll be gone
in the mornin'
D as in dog.
Let me know
if you're staying behind
now you can play a covered
chord or a rhythm chord.
Let me know that's G.
If you always will want me
or if you'll wander
into another's arms
A or a seven.
G. Let me know what
you decide dear
then let me rest A.
My head for a while
I've decided
to leave here forever
D as in dog.
Let me know
if you're comin'
along
otherwise, I'll be gone
in the mornin' D.
Let me know
if you're stayin' behind
- hi.
- Hi.
- What can I get ya?
- About five dollars worth, please.
- Oh, excuse me. Is this where Mac sledge stays?
- Yeah.
- Is he here?
- Yes.
- Well, could we talk to him?
- What about?
- We just wanna meet him.
- We're admirers of his.
See, we saw the story in
the newspaper this mornin'...
And... Well, we got a band.
We'd just like to say hello
and pay our respects.
Yeah, we got all his records. We
grew up on his music. He's great.
That's five dollars.
- Pay up.
- I bought the beer.
I paid for the gas last time.
It's his turn.
- It's your turn, man.
- Pay up.
Well, could we see him?
- I'll ask.
- Great. - All right.
- Hello, boys.
- Hello, sir. - Howdy.
- I was tellin' this pretty lady here...
- This is my wife rosa Lee.
Pleased to know you, ma'am.
Ma'am.
We were sayin' we got a band,
you know, and...
- you five boys?
- Yes, sir.
I'm the manager.
And I play the guitar.
And bertie's on bass,
Steve's on the fiddle.
And Henry plays the steel,
and Jake's drums.
Who does your vocals?
Well,
we all take turns on that.
See, you've been
a real inspiration to us all.
That's most gratifyin' to hear.
When you gonna start
singin' again, sir?
I'm not gonna start singin'
again, son. I've lost it.
You don't miss singin'?
No. Oh, I miss some things,
but I don't miss a lot of it.
So maybe we'll come
listen to ya some night.
Hey, we sure would like that.
Hey, we... we wonder
if you have any advice for us.
No, I don't really. Just, you know,
sing it the way you feel it.
Pleased to know you.
Nice to meet you.
- Bye-bye.
- So long.
♪ It's a cozy place
for sleepin' lazy nights ♪
♪ I shut the door
for a little peace and quiet ♪
♪ But the best part of all ♪
♪ The room
at the end of the hall ♪
♪ That's where you and me ♪
♪ Make everything all right ♪
♪ We can't afford good wine
or pink champagne ♪
♪ We ain't got
no open fireplace flame ♪
♪ But we celebrate
the happiness we've found ♪
♪ Every night in the best
bedroom in town ♪
♪ Any fool can see
that love is blind ♪
♪ Here I am to prove it
one more time ♪
♪ Forget about my pride ♪
♪ I didn't mean to catch you
by surprise ♪
♪ I hope that isn't pity
in your eyes ♪
♪ I've tried so hard
to stay away ♪
♪ And keep you off my mind ♪
♪ I know I should
but it's no good ♪
♪ As time goes by and I'm not ♪
♪ Over you ♪
♪ I'll gladly be a fool ♪
♪ In love again ♪
♪ If there's a chance
that you might see me ♪
♪ Touch me, want me
never leave me ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm still goin' crazy
over you ♪
♪ I'm never gettin' over you ♪
♪ It's been a month.
How do you like it? ♪
♪ One more cup of coffee ♪
♪ Then I'll go ♪
♪ But there's one more thing
I think you ought to know ♪
♪ The days go by
but nothin's changed ♪
♪ I'm still here
for the takin' ♪
♪ And just a touch
would mean so much ♪
♪ To one whose heart
is breakin' ♪
Good to see ya. What are
you doin' around here?
- I live around here.
- You do?
Things goin' all right for ya?
- Pretty well.
- You, you wanna see this show?
- I mean, it started, but I can get ya in there.
- No, thanks.
Harry, I have a song here. I thought you
might give it to Dixie to look over.
If she likes it,
maybe she'll record it.
All right, Mac.
Kind of a surprise.
I thought maybe you quit
the business.
I have, but I just wrote this
song and I thought, you know...
I'll see that she gets it.
You workin'?
At a motel.
Mac, it's good to see you. You look great.
Good luck to ya.
Ladies and gentlemen, let's give a big
warm Texas welcome to Billy Bob and...
♪ I'm in another time again ♪
♪ Tryin' to find
my way around again ♪
♪ Same old drink across
that dim-lit bar ♪
♪ Checkin' out
who the singles are ♪
♪ Bartender
send her one on me ♪
♪ She smiled and turned to me
cautiously ♪
♪ I hear my guitar on... ♪
What the hell
are you doin' here?
I was hopin' to say hello
to sue Anne.
Get Harry in here right away.
You stay away from her.
Do you hear me?
You stay away from her, or I warn
you, I'll have the law on you.
All she remembers about you is a mean
drunk tryin' to beat up her mama.
- You're dead as far as she's concerned, Mac.
- How you been?
She never thinks about you.
She's happy.
Lady, you're not tellin' me
what to do. You never have.
Harry, get him out of here.
I do not want him around.
Who the hell does she think she is?
She starts yellin' at me.
He is jealous of me because I am successful and he's not.
It's the way it's always been.
Bullshit.
Bullshit! Make sure he
doesn't see sue Anne, okay?
All right.
Just make sure he does not
see sue Anne. You understand?
- All right. Settle down.
- Okay?
Settle down! How could... what...
I... you know, sometimes...
Jesus Christ.
You're home early.
Concert must not
have been very long.
- It was the regular time. I left early.
- Why?
- I didn't care for it.
- Why not?
Sonny in bed?
What you been doin'?
Not much.
You watch your TV?
Nope.
Then why are you so quiet?
Are you mad about somethin'?
My God, woman.
Don't tell me you're jealous.
Rosa Lee,
are you jealous of Dixie Scott?
- Maybe I am.
- Why?
'Cause, you know.
No, I don't know.
Well, because she's rich and famous,
and you used to be married to her.
My God, don't be jealous of her, rosa Lee.
She's poison to me.
- She's absolutely poison to me.
- Then why did you go listen to her sing?
Someday I'll tell you.
Why can't you tell me now?
- Because I can't.
- Why not?
- Why?
Because I can't. Goddamn it,
don't you understand English?
I understand English, and
you don't have to yell at me.
You'll wake up Sonny.
Look, Mac.
If you went hopin' to see your
daughter, I could understand that.
I mean, you could come right out
and tell me that.
I'd be lyin' if I told you
that was the reason.
Why? Didn't you want
to see her?
Of course I did. I tried to, but
Dixie saw me and pitched a fit.
How long's it been
since you saw her?
Since before the divorce...
seven, eight years.
Sorry.
Mac, Dixie told me to bring that
back to you myself...
tell ya it ain't no good.
She told me even if it was good,
she wouldn't sing it,
and she don't wanna have
nothin' to do with you.
I don't want anything
to do with her either.
I just wrote this song. I thought it was a
good song for her. I guess I was wrong.
- Now did you get a look at it?
- Yeah. I looked at it.
Well, what do you think?
I don't think
it's no good either.
It's a different game now.
Well, that's fine.
Ma'am.
I don't give a goddamn about any of this
no more, so what in hell is wrong with me?
I guess it's about sue Anne
bein' grown up and all.
No, no, no. It's gotta be hard on
you not bein' able to see her.
I love you, you know?
Every night
when I say my prayers...
And I thank the lord for his blessings
and his tender mercies to me,
you and Sonny head the list.
Thank you.
Would you... would you sing
the song you wrote to me?
- Well, it's no good.
- Well, I sure would like to hear it.
All right,
but it's kind of corny.
I don't care.
Well, you asked for it.
Let me get your guitar for you.
All right.
Let's see now.
Baby, you're the only dream
I've ever had that's come true
there's so much more
to reach for
thanks to you
all that I have is...
got no voice.
You know I don't like a song.
I never have, and I never will.
- Mac.
- Hey, don't feel sorry for me, rosa Lee.
I'm not dead, you know.
I don't feel sorry for you.
Mac.
Then he gets what he came after
you're gonna wake up all alone
- what do you want?
- I don't know.
You want a beer? You want food?
- You want a drink?
- I don't know yet. When I do, I'll let you know.
Pass the sugar, please.
Thank you.
I'm not strong mind not
playing that damn music?
Hell, yes, I mind.
Like I used to be
no, let me bring him back
what's wrong with him?
I don't know.
Get over, you redneck bastard!
- What are you doing, you dumb son of a bitch?
- Are you crazy?
- Hi.
- Hi. Is Mr. sledge around?
No, he's not here right now.
Tell you the truth, I don't know where he is,
and I'm not real sure when he's coming back.
Oh, well, I just wanted to
holler at him if he was here.
We're playin' at a dance
around here this Saturday night,
and I was wonderin' if we could
leave one of our posters with you.
- Oh, sure.
- Thanks.
Well, I'll be seein' ya.
Sometimes
some things are hard to break
with me
it's reality
and though someone
will take my place
I'll go on
lovin' you
through eternity
but, oh, it hurts
so much to face
reality
I wonder where Mac is.
I don't know, Sonny.
He's older than you are.
He's 15 years older than you.
That's no secret.
Everybody knows that.
I didn't know it
till they told me at school.
Well, I would have told you
if you'd asked me.
- Was my daddy older than you?
- Two years.
Let's see...
I got married when I was 16,
and I had you when I was 17.
And I was a widow at 18.
Then how come he went
to Vietnam?
He got drafted. He didn't know I was gonna
have you till after the army got him.
Boy at school says his daddy told him all
they learned in Vietnam was to take dope.
- Do you think that's right?
- I don't know, Sonny. I hope not.
- You think my daddy took drugs?
- No, I don't think so.
The kids at school take drugs.
I don't wanna hear of you takin' 'em.
If you do, I'll have your hide.
- What are you so mad about?
- Never mind that. You just listen to me about them drugs.
Where are you goin'?
I don't know.
I don't wanna stay around you.
All right. Look, Sonny.
I'm sorry.
Come over here with me.
Come here.
Look. I...
I didn't mean to yell at ya.
I'm just a little nervous
tonight, okay?
What song is that?
That's somethin' Mac wrote.
I wish he'd come on home.
Where do you think he is?
I don't know, Sonny.
Your guess is as good as mine.
- Fur.
- Very good.
Come on. Alpaca?
- Alpac...
- Is he here?
- No.
- Why'd you turn off the TV?
Because I was sick of it.
- You goin' to bed?
- Yes.
- When?
- Soon. Go to sleep!
Show me thy way, o lord,
and teach me thy path.
Lead me in thy truth
and teach me,
for thou are the God of my...
salvation, on thee
do I wait all the day.
Mac?
That you?
I'm not drunk. I bought a bottle,
but I poured it all out.
And I'm not drunk.
- Have anything to eat?
- No.
- Are you hungry?
- I guess so.
Let me get you something.
What do you want to eat? I made some soup.
Want me to heat it up?
- A little soup will do me.
- Okay.
I rode by here
six or seven times.
I could see y'all
sittin' here watchin' TV.
- See me ride by?
- No.
I rode all over town tonight. Started twice for San antone.
Turned around and came back.
Started for Austin;
Started for Dallas.
And I turned around, came back.
You remember that song you took
over to that guy in Austin?
Yeah.
Remember those boys who had that
band who came down here to see you?
Well, two of them came by today,
and they left off a poster.
And I asked them if they could read
music, and one of them could, so...
I asked him to teach me
that song you wrote, as I...
I thought I'd try to surprise you
by singin' it when you came home.
I think it's
a real pretty song, Mac.
Well, and he did too.
And he thought... well he'd
like for his band to sing it.
I said I didn't know.
I'd have to ask you.
I did say I would ask, but I
said you probably wouldn't care.
It's an old song.
It wouldn't make any difference.
Oh, it's no old song, rosa Lee.
I only wrote it last week.
That's why I got upset when
Harry said he didn't like it.
I been writin 'em all along.
I... I even got more in here.
You say the boy liked the song?
He said he did.
I sure liked it.
What are the names
of some of your other songs?
Well, one is called
"the romance is over,"
and one is called "God can
forgive me, why can't you?"
Did you learn the song?
Not well enough to sing it.
Can't read music.
How did you learn
to read music, Mac?
I had an auntie that taught me.
She had an old,
half-busted piano,
and she sat me down at that piano one
summer when I came in from the fields.
She taught me.
I've been missin' my music.
It may not be any good anymore, but
that don't keep me from missin' it.
- When did you get home?
- He got in just a minute ago.
- You said you were going to wake me up.
- I forgot.
- Good night.
I don't care if you give that
song to those kids to play.
- All right.
- Come on. Try it with me.
Baby, you're the only dream
I've ever had that's come true
come on.
If you just hold
the ladder, baby
I'll climb to the top
- sing it.
- I can't.
Why?
Come here.
Come over here.
You just walked
right outta here.
Drinkin' Canada dry
since my woman said bye
yes, I'm up here in the cold
and I want to get home
but I'll settle for a high
and as each double goes down
I toast another lonely town
this bottle's all I can see
till she comes back with me
drinkin' Canada dry
I call on
all the radio stations...
And try to get 'em
to play our records.
I've gotten to know some
of those boys pretty well.
I was tellin' 'em about this song...
the ladder song you let us play.
- Yeah.
- They...
they said we ought to try to talk
you into lettin' us record it.
Hi.
Course, they thought
the best idea would be...
To try to get you to give us
another song too.
- And then... then these friends of mine said...
- I do have another song.
Come by the house, and
I'll let you listen to it.
- Okay. Yeah.
- Thanks.
- How you doin'?
- Mornin'.
- What'll you have?
- Bag of feed.
- Okay.
- See...
we've been at this now for four years,
and everybody's married but me.
Jake's got a little girl too.
We still gotta travel all over
the state to get engagements.
Yeah, we didn't clear but a
hundred bucks last week.
We showed up at the golead the other night,
and they had another band a-pickin'.
How many recordings you make?
Three. But I haven't exactly told
you the truth about that, though.
- They broke even on all our records, but...
- yeah?
Even so, they're not gonna
record us with our own songs.
Yeah, it's a...
it's a dirty business.
Maybe it's the best thing that
can happen to you for now.
World isn't gonna come
to an end, I'll tell ya.
Yeah, I guess, but like I said,
we heard last week they'd record
us if we used two of your songs.
I gave you my permission.
I told you that.
Yeah, but...
it's not just your songs.
They want you to sing 'em.
- Who does?
- The record company.
What record company?
It's called the aztec.
Never heard of it.
How do you make it
on a hundred a week?
We all got other jobs.
Jake's in construction.
I'm a substitute teacher.
I don't know.
- Thank you.
- You bet.
Let me think about it.
Sure mean a lot to us.
You understand that.
It'd be a real incentive
for us all.
I'll tell you what.
I ain't promisin' nothin',
you understand.
I'll give it a try.
If I don't like the way it sounds,
we'll just back away from it.
- Okay.
- Give me a couple days to think it over.
Thank you.
Hey, mister,
were you really Mac sledge?
Yes, ma'am. I guess I was.
See that cloud
there in the sky
so lonely
drifting by
well, that's the way
she's adrift
from me
keep all my pride
to myself
I know
there's someone else
but, oh, it hurts
so much to feel
reality
- how you doin'?
- Hi, Mac.You got a visitor.
- Where?
- Living room.
Yeah?
Do you recognize me?
- Yes, I do.
- How did you recognize me?
I just did.
Y'all excuse us, please?
You've changed. You don't look
like your pictures anymore.
Don't I?
Well, God knows when the last
picture of me was taken.
It don't make a whole lot of difference,
but I did try to get in touch with you.
I wrote a few letters.
- Did you ever get 'em?
- No.
Well, your mama didn't have
to give 'em to you.
Courts gave her
complete jurisdiction.
Quite rightly,
I guess, considering...
My state at the time.
I told mama I was comin' here.
She told me she'd have me
arrested if I did.
And Harry reminded her that I'm 18
now, and I don't have to mind anybody.
Mama says you tried
to kill her once.
I did.
Why'd you try to kill her?
Well, she got me mad some way.
I was drunk. I don't know.
One of those things.
Someone told mama the other night you were
the best country singer they ever heard.
Mama threw a glass of whiskey
right in her face.
She said they were just
sayin' that to spite her.
You think you ever will
sing again?
Oh, I think about it
once in a while.
Sometimes I think I'd like
to earn a little money to...
Make things a little easier
around here...
Or to help out
if you ever needed anything.
I don't need any money.
Mama set up a trust fund out of all
the royalties she ever earned...
Singin' the songs
that you wrote.
I can buy myself
anything I want.
Anything I got
has come from your music.
Well, I'm happy for that.
But it wasn't just my music. It was your mama
singin' it too. You mustn't forget that.
- I know.
- Yeah.
You have some supper with us?
Well, thank you, no, I can't.
I have a date tonight.
Plays in mama's band.
We have to sneak around,
'cause mama don't like him.
Would you like to meet him?
He'd like to meet you.
I don't think that's
such a good idea.
I really wouldn't want your mama to think
we was gangin' up on her behind her back.
I could tell her
I was bringin' him here.
Well, all right, then.
- How about tomorrow afternoon?
- Fine.
- 2:00?
- Anytime. I'll be here.
You know, you haven't spoken my
name once since I've been here.
Don't you know my name?
Sure, I know your name.
I just kinda been figurin' out to
myself what I ought to call you.
When you were a little girl,
I used to call you "sister."
I started to call you that
this time, when I saw you,
but I didn't know if it would
mean anything to you or not,
or if you'd remember
me doin' that.
There was a song you used to sing
to me when I was little, I think.
It was somethin' about a dove.
Mama said she never heard
you sing it to me, but...
I think it went
somethin' about a...
"on the wings
of a snow-white dove,
he sends
his somethin'-somethin' love."
I don't remember that. I don't.
So who else had a good
science project besides you?
Cy Henderson.
Cy did? What'd he do?
He made this gigantic picture
of the world...
And he showed the crust
and the...
the core of the earth,
and you could open it up.
When Jesus went down
to the waters that day
he was baptized
in the usual way
when it was done
God blessed his soul
he sent him his love
on the wings of a dove
on the wings
of a snow-white dove
he sends his pure sweet love
a sign from above
on the wings of a dove
♪ I'm still goin' crazy ♪
♪ Over you ♪
♪ And no, I'm never gettin' ♪
♪ I'd gladly be a fool ♪
♪ In love again ♪
♪ I know I'm never ♪
♪ Gettin' over you ♪
She left a note.
Dixie found it this morning
in a hotel.
Sue Anne's eloped.
- Shit.
- Her mama's gone crazy.
Doctor's got her
pretty well doped up,
but it looks like we're gonna
have to cancel that show.
I don't know what she expects.
She spoiled that kid rotten.
I try to tell her a lot of people have
been married at 18. Some of 'em got kids.
Dixie was married at 18, but
I guess you know about that.
I guess so. Yeah.
What's the boy like
she's marryin'?
No boy.
Thirty years old. Been
married three times already.
Look, if you see her,
if you hear from her,
ask her to please
call her mama.
All right. I will.
I shouldn't have said
what I did about your music.
- It's all right.
- I can't promise ya nothin', Mac,
but I'll take the song
with me to Nashville.
I'll show it to whoever I can.
What's the $500 for?
It's earnest money. It's good faith money.
I owe you that.
No way, Harry. No, sir.
- Come on, Mac.
- No, sir.
You don't owe me anything.
Besides, I've got... Other
plans for the song right now.
You got other songs, Mac?
Yeah, I do.
- You gonna show 'em to me?
- No.
- Come on, for Christ sake!
- No, goddamn it, Harry. Don't you understand English?
- I don't want to show 'em to you.
- Why?
Because I don't want to,
so stop buggin' me.
You can't get sore at me
for askin' you that.
Change the subject, Harry. This
is my business, for Christ sake!
Look, you want to do somethin' with your
music, you know how to get ahold of me.
All right.
- You were 16 when you got married?
- Yeah.
Dixie was, what, 18
when I married her,
and I was 17 when I
married the first time.
You never told me
you were married before Dixie.
No?
I thought I told you
everything about me.
Oh, well, you didn't
tell me that.
Well...
I was tryin' to get
started in the business.
I was singin' in any honky-tonk bar
that would let me through the door.
And I wandered from town
to town, city to city,
lookin' for places to sing.
Findin' any kind of work I could
in a day to keep me alive...
So I could sing
and play at night.
Finally, Lois...
my first wife's name...
couldn't stand it;
She went home.
And I went back six months
later lookin' for her,
and I found her
livin' with another man.
Said she wanted a divorce,
so, hell, I gave it to her.
Swore I'd never marry again.
And when I met Dixie,
it changed my mind.
I was makin' a few records by then,
and she was singin' when I met her,
and she said she'd give it up
when she got married,
but then she recorded a song of
mine, and she done well with it...
And said she wanted to sing for five
years and get it out of her system.
Never happened. Never did.
Never did.
When at last
I kneel on the shore
and the fearful breakers wall
which span the peaceful lands
the valley of the blessed
then I hear him saying to me
then I
will finally see
upon your profession of faith
in our lord Jesus Christ,
I baptize you in the name
of the father...
And of the son
and of the holy spirit.
Upon your profession of faith
in our lord Jesus Christ,
I baptize you in the name
of the father...
And of the son
and of the holy spirit.
Amen. Amen.
Well, we done it, Mac.
We're baptized.
Yeah, we are.
Everybody said I was gonna feel
like a changed person.
I guess I do feel a little different,
but I don't feel a whole lot different.
Do you?
Not yet.
You don't look any different.
- You think I look any different?
- Not yet.
♪ Baby, you're the only dream ♪
♪ I've ever had ♪
♪ That's come true ♪
♪ There's so much more ♪
♪ To reach for ♪
♪ Thanks to you ♪
♪ All I've had is me till now ♪
Come on. Let's dance.
♪ But I see ♪
♪ What we've got ♪
♪ And if you just hold ♪
♪ The ladder, baby ♪
♪ I'll climb ♪
♪ To the top ♪
♪ If you'll just stand ♪
♪ Beside me ♪
♪ All the way ♪
♪ I'll do all the things ♪
♪ That didn't matter ♪
♪ Yesterday ♪
♪ And I'll be everything ♪
♪ This man can be ♪
♪ Before I stop ♪
♪ If you'll just hold ♪
♪ The ladder, baby ♪
♪ I'll climb ♪
♪ To the top ♪
♪ Things just started ♪
♪ Changing ♪
♪ With your touch ♪
I like him.
♪ Yesterday ♪
♪ Tomorrow ♪
♪ Just didn't mean ♪
♪ As much ♪
♪ Now I'll be everything ♪
♪ This man can be ♪
♪ Before I stop ♪
♪ If you'll just hold ♪
♪ The ladder, baby ♪
♪ I'll climb ♪
♪ To the top ♪
♪ If you'll just hold ♪
♪ The ladder, baby ♪
♪ I'll climb ♪
♪ To the top ♪
And just like the old days.
Hey, Mac, that sounds great, okay?
- Real good, Mac.
- Thank you.
- That was wonderful.
- Thank you. I was a little nervous.
- Were you?
- Yeah, a little bit.
- Couldn't tell, could you?
- No, ma'am.
- It was all right?
- I thought it was great. - I liked it too.
- Mind if your mom and I dance?
- No, sir.
Come on. Let's go.
- Is that your daddy?
- No, that's my step-daddy.
My mama says he was
a famous singer.
- I guess so. Where's your mama?
- Over there.
- Shit.
- Is that your daddy with her?
No, that's a friend of hers.
My mom and dad were divorced.
Were your mom and dad
ever divorced?
No, he died in Vietnam.
- Did he get shot?
- I guess so.
- Don't you know?
- No.
I don't know how he died.
- Didn't you ever ask?
- No.
Come on. Let's dance,
will ya? Come on!
- I hope that man's never my step-daddy.
- Why? Don't you like him?
No. Do you like
your step-daddy?
Yes, I do.
- Better than your own daddy?
- I never knew my own daddy.
I know mine, and he's
not so much either.
- Hi.
- Is my daddy here?
No, he's in town.
He'll be back in a little while.
I wonder if he could cash
a check for me.
- How much?
- It's just a hundred dollars.
Oh, I don't know.
- Well, the check is good.
- I'm sure. I just don't have that much in the drawer.
I just have 25.
Oh, well, that'll help.
I appreciate it.
You been back long?
Well, we been back
a couple days.
You guys plannin'
to stay around here?
I don't know. We may stay.
We may move on.
My husband has to find work.
Mama stopped my trust
fund out of spite.
We met some musicians
in Austin the other night...
That said my daddy
just made a new record.
- Oh, he did.
- How did it go?
Pretty good, I think.
He seemed pleased.
Hey, are you a singer too?
I sing with the choir...
you know,
down at the church.
I thought about bein' a singer.
But I don't think I have any
voice, to tell you the truth.
I guess I was just goin' on
about singin' to devil mama.
My daddy's quit drinkin',
they tell me.
Yes, he has.
How'd he quit?
I don't know. He just quit.
Well, did you ask him to quit?
No.
He was working here, and I told him
he couldn't drink while he worked.
Sometimes he used to go off
and load up,
but gradually he even
stopped that.
My husband drinks.
Most musicians do, you know.
He says he'll quit
soon as he gets work, but...
sue Anne, do you have
a place to stay?
Yeah, we're stayin' at the
Jeff Davis hotel in Austin.
Well, if you need a place tomorrow
night, you're welcome here.
Thank you.
Has anybody in the orchestra
heard from them?
I give the marriage a month.
How long do you give it?
I don't know, Dixie.
- Don't you at least have an opinion?
- No. Not about that.
You know what's
just come to me?
I can't imagine.
- You can't imagine?
- No.
Mac is lyin' to you.
- What's he lyin' to me about?
- To spite me.
He knows where they are, and he's
just not gonna tell us out of spite.
He's tryin' to get back at us 'cause I
wouldn't sing that old song of his.
- Howdy there. How you doin'?
- Great. Here it is.
We just heard it.
We're real proud of it.
The record company says
it's gonna dorealgood.
Even Jake likes it.
Not much pleases old Jake.
- I'm glad you boys are pleased.
- We'll have to get a record player so we can listen to it.
- What, y'all don't even have a record player?
- We have a radio and a TV.
Y'all come over to my house right
now, and I'll play it for you.
- All right.
- I'd love to hear it.
We'll see y'all over at the house.
Better start listenin' to the radio too,
because they're givin' it some play.
- You bet.
- Get in there.
See y'all later.
See ya in a bit.
- Bye. So long.
- Bye.
Hello?
That was Harry silver.
They got a wire this mornin'
that my daughter was killed...
In an automobile accident
somewhere...
In northern Louisiana.
I didn't catch
the name of the town.
A little child
boy or girl
will dream at night
in their own dream world
and as they play
they pretend that they
believe
well, I'm no child
but times it's true
I pretend
I'm not losing you
because it hurts
so much to face
reality
Dixie's not doing well at all.
What about sue Anne's husband?
Well, he's gonna live. In the hospital.
He was drunk.
It was all his fault.
Dixie wanted a closed casket
on account of the accident.
I thought it would be easier
on her, on everybody...
If we left this down
at the funeral parlor, but...
She wanted it brought
back home.
Little sister.
Dixie?
Dixie, Mac is here.
- Where is he?
- He's right here.
Hello, Dixie.
Hi, Mac.
Mac,
why has God done this to me?
Why has God done this to me?
Oh, you know, I did everything
I could to stop her. I...
I begged and I pleaded and...
I gave her everything
in the world she ever wanted.
I had nothin'
when I was her age.
Do you remember?
Yeah.
I gave her everything
money could buy.
That was our little girl, Mac.
No, see, I want to see
my little girl.
I brought her back here to be with me.
Just let me out!
I want to be with my little girl!
Let me go, you son of a bitch!
- No! No!
- Be still. Be still.
Mac?
You okay?
I was almost killed once
in a car accident.
I was drunk...
And I ran off the side of the road
and I turned over four times.
And they took me out of that
car for dead, but I lived.
And I prayed last night
to know why...
I lived and she died, but I
got no answer to my prayers.
I still don't know why
she died and I lived.
I don't know the answer to nothin'...
not a blessed thing.
I don't know why I wandered out
to this part of Texas drunk...
And you took me in and pitied me
and helped me to straighten out,
marry me.
Why? Why did that happen? Is
there a reason that happened?
And Sonny's daddy died
in a war...
my daughter killed in an
automobile accident. Why?
You see,
I don't trust happiness.
I never did. I never will.
- Where's Mac?
- He's outside.
He got you something.
It's in your room.
How did my daddy die?
- I don't know, Sonny.
- Was he killed in battle?
Honey, I just don't know.
Didn't you ever ask anybody?
Yes, I asked someone.
And they couldn't tell me anything
except that he'd been found dead.
See, he was alone
when they found him,
and they couldn't be sure
how long he'd been there...
Or if he'd been in a battle, which battle,
because there were three in the area that week.
It could have been
in any of 'em, they said.
Or he could have been out walking,
they said, and a sniper got him.
Where would he be walking to?
They didn't have
any more idea than I did.
He was just a boy.
But he was a good boy.
I think he would have been
a fine man.
I think you would have been
proud of him.
I know he would have been
proud of you.
Thanks for the football, Mac.
You're welcome, Sonny.
Good!
Hey!
I'm gonna send the ball.
Come on. Throw it to me!
Go on!
Come on.
With tender hands
you gathered up the pieces
of my life
lying in your loving arms
never felt so right!
The hard-luck road
behind me
is reflected in your eyes
and the glory
of the bright lights
can't compare to this feelin'
when you smile
you're the good things
I threw away
comin' back to me every day
you're the best
it could ever be
you are what love means to me
I've been around
and seen it all
from the bottom to the top
and honey
I can tell you now
I'm thankful for what I've got
these prison walls
inside me
never let this poor soul free
till the power
of your true love
broke them down
just in time to rescue me
you're the song
I could never write
you're the magic
in my heart tonight
when the morning sun
comes shining through
I'll still be holding you
you're the good things
I threw away
comin' back to me every day
you're the best
it could ever be
you are what love means to me
you're the good things
I threw away
comin' back to me every day
you're the best
it could ever be
you are what love means to me
you're the best
it could ever be
you are what love means to me