If we look at the base of a brain
which has just been removed from a skull,
there's very little of the midbrain
that we can actually see.
Yet, as I demonstrated
in my lecture last week,
if the under aspects of the temporal lobes
are gently pulled apart,
the upper portion of the stem
of the brain can be seen.
This so-called brainstem
consists of the midbrain,
a rounded protrusion called the pons,
and a stalk tapering downwards
called the medulla oblongata
which passes out of the skull
through the foramen magnum
and becomes, of course, the spinal cord.
Are there any questions before we proceed?
I have one question, Dr Frankenstein.
That's Fronkonsteen.
I beg your pardon?
My name. It's pronounced "Fronkonsteen".
But aren't you the grandson
of the famous Dr Victor Frankenstein,
who dug up freshly buried corpses
and transformed dead components into...
Yes, yes.
Yes.
We all know what he did.
But I'd rather be remembered
for my own small contributions to science
and not because of my accidental
relationship
to a famous... cuckoo.
Now, if you don't mind,
can we have your question?
Well, sir, I'm not sure
I understand the distinction between
reflexive and voluntary nerve impulses.
Good. Since our lab work today
is a demonstration of just that distinction,
why don't we proceed?
Mr Hilltop here,
with whom I have never worked
or given any prior instructions to,
has graciously offered his services
for today's demonstration.
Mr Hilltop, would you hop up on your feet
and stand beside this table?
Nice hopping.
Mr Hilltop,
would you raise your left knee, please?
You have just witnessed
a voluntary nerve impulse.
It begins as a stimulus
from the cerebral cortex,
passes through the brainstem
and to the muscles involved.
Mr Hilltop, you may lower your knee.
Reflex movements are those
which are made independently of the will,
but are carried out along pathways
which pass between the peripheral nervous
system and the central nervous system.
You filthy, rotten, yellow son of a bitch.
We are not aware of these impulses.
Neither do we intend them
to carry out our contraction of muscles.
Yet, as you can see, they work by themselves.
But what if we block the nerve impulse
by simply applying local pressure,
which can be done
with any ordinary metal clamp
just at the swelling
on the posterior nerve roots
for, say... five or six seconds?
Why, you mother-grabbing bastard.
As you can see,
all communication is shut off.
In spite of our mechanical magnificence,
if it were not for this continuous stream
of motor impulses,
we would collapse
like a bunch of broccoli.
In conclusion, it should be noted...
- Give him an extra dollar.
- Extra dollar. Yes, sir.
...that any more than common injury
to the nerve root is always serious.
Because once a nerve fibre is severed,
there is no way, in heaven or on earth,
to regenerate life back into it.
Are there any last questions before we leave?
Dr Frank...
- Fronkonsteen...
- Yes?
Isn't it true that Darwin preserved
a piece of vermicelli in a glass case
until, by some extraordinary means,
it actually began to move
with a voluntary motion?
Are you speaking of the worm
or the spaghetti?
Why, the worm, sir.
Yes. It seems to me I did read something
of that incident when I was a student.
But you have to remember that a worm,
with very few exceptions,
is not a human being.
But wasn't that the basis
of your grandfather's work, sir?
The reanimation of dead tissue?
My grandfather was a very sick man.
But as a Fronkonsteen,
aren't you the least bit curious about it?
Doesn't bringing back to life what was
once dead hold any intrigue for you?
You are talking about the nonsensical ravings
of a lunatic mind. Dead is dead.
But look at what has been done
with hearts and kidneys.
Hearts and kidneys are Tinkertoys.
I'm talking about the central nervous system.
- But, sir...
- I am a scientist, not a philosopher!
You have more chance
of reanimating this scalpel
than of mending a broken nervous system.
- But what about your grandfather's work?
- My grandfather's work was doo-doo!
I am not interested in death.
The only thing that concerns me
is the preservation of life!
Class...
...is...
...dismissed.
Dr Frankenstein...
That's Fronkonsteen.
My name is Gerhart Falkstein.
I have travelled 5,000 miles to bring you
the will of your great-grandfather.
Baron Beaufort von Frankenstein.
Oh, my sweet darling.
Oh, my dearest love.
I'll count the hours that you're away.
- Oh, darling, so will I.
- Not on the lips.
I'm going to that party at Nanna and Nicky's.
I don't wanna smear my lipstick.
- You understand.
- Of course.
All aboard!
- Oh, dear.
- Well, I guess this is it.
Freddy, darling.
Oh, how can I say in a few minutes
what it's taken me a lifetime to understand?
- Won't you try?
- All right.
You've got it, mister.
I'm yours. All of me. What else can I say?
- My sweet love...
- The hair. Just been set.
Sorry.
- I hope you like old-fashioned weddings.
- I prefer old-fashioned wedding nights.
- You're incorrigible.
- Does that mean...
...you love me?
- You bet your boots it does.
- Oh, my only love.
- Taffeta, darling.
Taffeta, sweetheart.
No, the dress is taffeta. It wrinkles so easily.
All aboard!
There's that horrid man again.
Well, hurry now,
before I make a fool of myself.
Oh, my nails!
Sorry.
- Goodbye, darling.
- Goodbye, Freddy.
Darling.
- Harry, he was at it again.
- So what do you want me to do about it?
Every day.
Let him. Let him.
New York next. Everybody out for New York.
Pardon me, boy.
Is this the Transylvania Station?
Ja, ja. Track 29.
Oh, can I give you a shine?
No, thanks.
Dr Frankenstein?
Fronkonsteen.
You're putting me on.
No. It's pronounced Fronkonsteen.
Do you also say Frodorick?
No. Frederick.
Well, why isn't it Frodorick Fronkonsteen?
It isn't. It's Frederick Fronkonsteen.
I see.
- You must be lgor.
- No. It's pronounced I-gor.
- But they told me it was lgor.
- Well, they were wrong then, weren't they?
You were sent by Herr Falkstein, weren't you?
Yes. My grandfather
used to work for your grandfather.
- How nice.
- Of course, the rates have gone up.
Of course. I'm sure we'll get along splendidly.
Sorry. I...
You know, I don't mean to embarrass you,
but I'm a rather brilliant surgeon.
Perhaps I could help you with that hump.
What hump?
Let's go.
Allow me, master.
Thanks very much.
Walk this way.
This way.
I think you'll be more comfortable in the rear.
- What was that?
- That'll be Inga.
Herr Falkstein thought you might need
a laboratory assistant temporarily.
Hello.
Would you like to have a roll in the hay?
It's fun.
Roll, roll, roll in the hay
Sometimes I am afraid of the lightning.
It's just an atmospheric discharge.
Nothing to be afraid of.
Werewolf.
Werewolf?
- There.
- What?
There wolf.
There castle.
Why are you talking that way?
- I thought you wanted to.
- No, I don't want to.
Suit yourself. I'm easy.
Well...
There it is.
Home.
What knockers.
Thank you, Doctor.
Oh, that's all right.
There we are.
I am Frau Blücher.
Steady!
How do you do? I am Dr Fronkonsteen.
This is my assistant.
Inga, may I present Frau Blücher?
I wonder what's got into them.
Your rooms have been prepared, Herr Doktor.
If you will follow me.
I-gor. Would you bring the bags
as soon as you're finished, please?
Yes, master.
After you, Frau Blücher.
Blücher!
Follow me, please.
Stay close to the candles.
The staircase can be treacherous.
Und this is your room.
It was your grandfather Victor's room.
I see.
Well. Seem to be quite a few books.
This was Victor's...
...the Baron's medical library.
- Where is my grandfather's private library?
- I don't know what you mean, sir.
Well, these books are very general.
Any doctor might have them in his study.
This is the only library I know of,
Dr Frankenstone.
- Fronkonsteen.
Well, we'll see.
Good night.
Would the doctor care for
a brandy before retiring?
No. Thank you.
Some warm milk...
...perhaps?
No, thank you very much.
No, thanks.
Ovaltine?
Nothing.
Thank you.
I'm a little tired.
Then I will say... good night.
Good night!
Good night, darling.
Good night, Herr Doktor.
Good night, Frau Blücher.
No, no, no...
I'm not a Frankenstein.
I am not a Frankenstein.
I'm a Fronkonsteen.
Don't gimme that!
I don't believe in fate.
And I won't say it.
All right, you win. I give.
I'll say it. I'll say it, I'll say it.
Destiny. Destiny.
No escaping that for me.
Destiny. Destiny...
No escaping...
Dr Fronkonsteen. Wake up.
- What is it?
- You were having a nightmare.
- What's that strange music?
- I have no idea.
But it seems to be coming
from behind the bookcase.
Behind the bookcase...
Hand me that robe, would you, dear?
You were right.
It's coming from behind this wall.
Where is it?
- Where is it?
- What?
There's always a device.
If I can just spot the triggering mechanism...
Hello.
It seems louder over here.
Hand me that candle, will you?
Put the candle back.
All right. I think I have it figured out now.
Take out the candle
and I'll block the bookcase with my body.
Listen to me very carefully.
Don't put the candle back.
With all of your might,
shove against the other side
of the bookcase.
Is that perfectly clear?
I think so.
Good girl.
Put the candle back.
Oh, look, Doctor. A passageway.
Whatever that music is,
it's coming from down there.
- I'd better take a look.
- Oh, let me come with you, Doctor, please.
I don't wanna stay up here alone.
All right, then.
Close your robe and follow me.
Oh, Doctor. The candle...
Good thinking. Let's try this one.
Stand back!
Don't be frightened, dear. Just a rat.
A filthy, slimy rat.
Good Lord!
I-I-I-I-I-I
Ain't got nobody
And nobody cares for me
- I-gor.
- Frodorick.
How did you get here?
Through the dumbwaiter. I heard
strange music from the upstairs kitchen
and I just followed it down.
Call it... a hunch.
- There must have been someone else here.
- It would seem that way.
And there's the only other door.
Wait, master.
It might be dangerous.
You go first.
Aren't there any lights in this place?
Two nasty-looking switches over here,
but I'm not going to be the first.
Damn your eyes.
Too late.
So this is where it all happened.
Just think. A dead brain
ready to live again in a new body.
Look. No blood, no decomposition.
Just a few sutures.
- Throw the main switch.
- Yes, master.
What a filthy mess.
I dunno. A little paint, a few flowers,
couple of throw pillows...
Well, it seems as if our mysterious violinist
has disa... p...
- Disa... what?
...peared.
There is a light
coming from behind that door.
Follow me.
Doctor, look!
Well... This explains the music.
It's still warm.
But who was playing it?
I don't know.
But whoever it was just barely finished
putting out his cigar.
Such strange goings-on.
What is this place?
Music room?
But there's nothing here
but books and papers.
Books and papers?
It is!
This is my grandfather's private library.
I feel it.
Look! Look at this.
"...until, from the midst of this
darkness, a sudden light broke in upon me."
"A light so brilliant and wondrous,
and yet so simple."
"Change the poles from plus to minus
and from minus to plus."
"I alone succeeded in discovering
the secret of bestowing life."
"Nay, even more..."
"I myself became capable
of bestowing animation
upon lifeless matter."
It could work.
- Kipper?
- Thank you, Doctor.
"As the minuteness of the parts
formed a hindrance to my speed,
I resolved therefore
to make the creature of a gigantic stature."
Of course.
That would simplify everything.
In other words,
his veins, his feet, his hands, his organs
would all have to be increased in size.
Exactly.
He would have an enormous Schwanzstück.
That goes without saying.
Woof.
He's gonna be very popular.
So then. What we're aiming for is a being
approximately seven feet in height,
with all features either congenitally
or artificially proportionate in size.
Something like...
...this?
Hello...
You've caught something there.
Crude, yes, primitive, yes,
perhaps even grotesque,
yet something inexplicable tells me
that this might be our man.
All right, all right.
That's good enough for the likes of 'im.
Get down, you fool.
Now.
What a filthy job.
- Could be worse.
- How?
Could be raining.
Quick.
Need a hand?
No, thanks. I have one.
Thanks very much all the same.
Just a moment, sir.
I know everyone around here,
but I've never seen your face before.
Can you account for yourself?
Yes. I am Dr Frederick Fronkonsteen,
newly arrived from America.
Oh, yes, sir. I was told you were here.
Well, I'm Constable Henry, sir.
Pleased to meet you.
How very nice to meet you, Constable.
Why, you're chilled to the bone, sir.
A nice, warm fire would be the thing for you.
A little nip from the old bottle
wouldn't be too bad either, sir.
That's the ticket, yes.
Well, if you have everything in hand, sir,
I'll say good night.
Thank you very much, Constable.
At your service, sir, always.
- Good night, Constable.
- Good night, sir.
Oh, what an awesome sight.
What a profound and reverend night is this.
With such a specimen for a body,
all we need now is
an equally magnificent brain.
- You know what to do?
- I have a pretty good idea.
Good man.
Didn't you... Didn't you use to have that
on the other side?
- What?
- Your...
Never mind.
- Do you have that name I gave you?
- I have it written down.
- H Delbruck.
- Hans Delbruck.
- He is hideous.
- He's beautiful.
And he is mine.
Hurry now.
We're fighting time and the elements.
- Are you ready?
- Are you sure this is how they did it?
Yes. It's all written down in the notes.
Now tie off the kites
and hurry down as fast as you can.
What's the hurry?
There's a possibility of electrocution.
Do you understand?
I say: "There's a possibility of electrocution."
I understand, I understand.
Why are you shouting?
Did you...
- Did you tie off the kites?
- Of course.
All right. Good.
- Check the generator.
- Yes, master.
I-gor,
- release the safety valve on the main wheel.
- Yes, master.
Can you imagine the brain
of Hans Delbruck in this body?
Oh, Frederick.
This is the moment.
Well, dear...
Are you ready?
Yes, Doctor.
Elevate me.
Now? Right here?
- Yes, yes. Raise the platform.
- Oh, the platform.
Oh, that. Ja... yes.
From that fateful day
when stinking bits of slime
first crawled from the sea
and shouted to the cold stars:
"I am man",
our greatest dread has always been
the knowledge of our own mortality.
But tonight
we shall hurl the gauntlet of science
into the frightful face of death itself.
Tonight,
we shall ascend into the heavens.
We shall mock the earthquake.
We shall command the thunders
and penetrate
into the very womb
of impervious nature herself.
When I give the word,
throw the first switch.
You've got it, master.
Get ready.
Get set.
Go!
Throw the second switch.
Throw the third switch.
Not the third switch?
Throw it, I say. Throw it!
Life.
Life, do you hear me?
Give my creation
life!
Turn everything off and bring me down.
Nothing.
- Oh, Doctor. I'm sorry...
- No, no.
Be of good cheer.
If science teaches us anything,
it teaches us to accept our failures
as well as our successes
with quiet dignity
and grace.
Son of a bitch, bastard. I'll get you for this.
What did you do to me?
- What did you do to me?
- Doctor, stop it!
You'll kill him!
I don't wanna live.
I do not want to live.
Quiet dignity and grace.
Mama!
Oh, tosh! This man is different, I tell you.
You can see that after you've
talked to him for five minutes.
Yes?
He's a Frankenstein!
And they're all alike.
It's in their blood. They can't 'elp it.
All those scientists, they're all alike.
They say they're working for us.
What they really want is to rule the world.
That's enough now. I will not have
this meeting become a free-for-all.
These are very serious charges
you're making,
and all the more painful to us, your elders,
because we still have nightmares
from five times before.
Now, we haven't heard from the one man
most qualified to judge the situation fairly.
Inspector Kemp.
Will you talk to us, please?
A riot is an ugly thing
und once you get one started
there is little chance of stopping it
short of bloodshed.
I think before we go around killing people,
we had better make damn sure
of our evidence.
Und...
...we had better confirm the fact
that young Frankenstein is indeed
vollowing in his grandfather's vootstaps.
What?
Vollowing in his grandfather's vootstaps.
Vootstaps.
Oh, footsteps.
I think
what is in order
is for me to pay a little visit
on the good doctor
und to have a nice, quiet chat.
Reputation.
Oh, Doctor. You mustn't do this to yourself.
You've got to stop thinking about it.
Why, look.
You haven't even touched your food.
There.
Now I've touched it. Happy?
You know... I'll never forget my old dad.
When these things would happen to him...
the things he'd say to me.
What did he say?
What the hell are you doin'
in the bathroom day and night?
Why don't you get outta there
and give someone else a chance?
Oh, maybe it's better this way.
The poor lifeless hulk.
Maybe it is better off dead.
What is this?
Schwarzwälder Kirschtorte.
Do you like it? I'm not partial to
desserts myself, but this is excellent.
Who are you talking to?
To you. You just made a yummy sound,
so I thought you liked the dessert.
I didn't make a yummy sound.
I just asked you what it is.
- But you did. I just heard it.
- It wasn't me.
It wasn't me.
Well, now, look here.
If it wasn't you and it wasn't you...
Alive. It's alive.
It's alive!
Stand back.
Hello, there.
I'm going to set you free.
- Is the sedative ready?
- Yes, Doctor.
I want you
to sit up.
Stand on your feet.
You can do it.
Now walk.
Doctor, I'm frightened.
Don't worry.
Good.
What is it? What's the matter?
Quick. Give him the...
What? Give him the what?
Three syllables.
First syllable - sounds like...
Head. Sounds like head.
Bed... Said...
Said.
- Said.
Second syllable - little word.
This, that, the...
A...
- Said a...
Dirty word. He said a dirty word.
Sounds like...
To give. Give.
Said... Said a give... Give him a said a give.
Oh, tive... tive... Sedative.
On the nosey.
Said a give?
Oh, Frederick. Are you all right?
Yes.
- Would you excuse me for one minute, dear?
- Of course, Doctor.
I-gor...
- May I speak to you for a moment?
- Of course.
- Sit down, won't you?
- Thank you.
No, no. Up here.
Thank you.
Now, that brain that you gave me...
Was it Hans Delbruck's?
- No.
- Good.
Would you mind telling me...
...whose brain I did put in?
- Then you won't be angry?
- I will not be angry.
Abby someone.
Abby someone...
- Abby who?
- Abby Normal.
Abby Normal...
I'm almost sure that was the name.
Are you saying that I put an abnormal brain
into a seven-and-a-half-foot long,
54-inch wide
gorilla?
Is that what you're telling me?
Quick, quick. Give him the...
What?
Three syllables, yes.
I wonder who that could be at this hour.
Inga, quick. See who that is.
You... put that thing
back on the operating table.
And strap him down tightly.
- Where are you going?
- To wash up. I've got to look normal.
We've all of us got to behave normally.
Monsters!
Excellent shot.
This is the 20th century, Kemp.
Monsters are passé like ghosts and goblins.
Not to the good people
of this village, Herr Doktor.
To them
he is a very real thing.
Especially when...
there is a Frankenstein residing in this house.
Nice grouping.
Thank you.
I wouldn't think an intelligent fellow like you
would fall for all this superstitious rot.
It is not superstition that worries me,
Herr Doktor, but genes und
chromosomes.
- Rubbish.
- Well, you might say, but this is
Transylvania.
Und you are a
Frankenstein.
You... seem unusually upset
by this discussion.
Not in the least.
I find it extremely amusing, that's all.
Well, this was fun.
Now, if you don't mind, Inspector,
I'm a little tired.
Then
I may give the villagers
your complete assurance
that you have no interest whatsoever
in carrying on your grandfather's work?
May I take that for a yes?
Very well.
- You can find the way out by yourself?
- Of course.
Until we meet again... Herr Baron.
Yes. Drop by any time. We are always open.
Oh, Victor.
Victor...
We have done it.
I'm going to set you free.
Would you like that, meine Seuchekopf?
They wanted to hurt you.
But I'm going to help you.
Thank heavens that's over with.
Frau Blücher.
Stop. Don't come closer.
- What are you doing?
- I'm going to set him free.
No. No, you mustn't.
Yes.
Are you insane? He'll kill you.
No, he won't. Not this one.
He is as gentle as a lamb.
Stand back. Stand back.
For the love of God, he has a rotten brain.
It's not rotten. It's a good brain.
It's rotten, I tell you. Rotten.
Lxnay on the ottenray.
I'm not afraid. I know what he likes.
That music.
Yes. It's in your blood.
It's in the blood of all Frankensteins.
It reaches the soul when words are useless.
Your grandfather used to play it
to the creature he was making.
- Then it was you all the time.
- Yes.
- You played that music in the night.
- To get us into the laboratory.
- Yes.
- That was your cigar in the ashtray.
And it was you who left
my grandfather's book out for me to find.
Yes.
- So that I would...
- Yes.
- Then you and Victor were...
Yes! Say it!
He was my boyfriend.
You will never catch him now.
He's free. Do you hear?
Free.
Gone.
Gone!
We've got to find him, do you understand?
We've got to find him
before he kills someone.
What have I done?
Oh, God in heaven.
Oh, I love my pretty little flower
Oh, I love my flower
That monster is loose...
Boards must be tight.
There.
Thank God you put Helga to bed.
With all this monster business,
I take no chances. I remember the last time.
But, Papa. I told you that I was turning
the Rostbraten, don't you remember?
I asked you to put Helga to...
You...
Now throw a kiss and say bye-bye.
Oh, dear. Nothing left.
What shall we throw in now?
Maybe she was in the bathroom
when you looked.
But I didn't even look upstairs.
I thought you did.
You didn't look upstairs?
Sit down.
Sit down!
A visitor is all I ask.
A temporary companion to help me
pass a few short hours in my lonely life.
Thank you, Lord. Thank you.
Oh, no, no, no.
Don't speak. Don't say a word.
Oh, my joy and my prize from heaven.
Oh, you must have been
the tallest one in your class.
My name is Harold and I live here all alone.
What is your name?
I didn't get that.
No...
Forgive me.
I didn't realise you were a mute.
You see how heaven plans.
Me, a poor blind man, and you a mute.
An incredibly big mute.
But your hand is frozen, my child.
How does a nice bowl of soup sound, huh?
Well, I know what it means
to be cold and hungry.
Yes...
And how much it means to have
a little kindness from a stranger.
Are you ready for your soup?
Hold out your bowl, then.
Oh, my friend...
You don't know what your visit means to me.
How long I've waited for the pleasure
of another human being.
Sometimes in our preoccupation
with worldly matters,
we tend to forget the simple pleasures
that are the basis for true happiness.
And now a little wine with your soup?
Good, good.
Huh? Good. Yes.
Wait!
A toast.
A toast to long friendship.
How hungry you must have been.
Now for a little surprise.
For a special occasion, I've been saving...
...cigars.
Take one.
What?
No, no, no.
Fire is good.
Fire is good. Yes, fire is our friend.
Yes. I'll show you.
You see?
You have your cigar?
Let me see. Let me see.
All right.
Now, now, now...
Just hold it right there. Now,
don't inhale until the tip glows.
Wait.
Where are you going?
I was gonna make espresso.
Now!
Quick. Give him the sedative.
He's out.
I know.
I'm going in there. Bring me that candle.
- No.
- Yes.
Love
is the only thing
that can save this poor creature.
And I am going to convince him
that he is loved
even at the cost of my own life.
No matter what you hear in there,
no matter how cruelly I beg you,
no matter how terribly I may scream,
do not open this door,
or you will undo everything I've worked for.
Do you understand?
Do not open this door.
Yes, Doctor.
Nice working with you.
Let me out. Let me out of here.
Get me the hell out of here.
What's the matter with you people?
I was joking.
Don't you know ajoke when you hear one?
Jesus Christ. Get me outta here!
Open this goddamn door
or I'll kick your rotten heads in.
Mommy!
Obviously...
Hello, handsome.
You're a good-looking fellow, you know?
People laugh at you.
People hate you, but why do they hate you?
Because they are jealous.
Look at that boyish face.
Look at that sweet smile.
Do you wanna talk about physical strength?
Do you want to talk about sheer muscle?
Do you want to talk
about the Olympian ideal?
You are a god!
And listen to me...
You are not evil.
You are good!
This is a nice boy.
This is a good boy.
This is a mother's angel.
And I want the world to know,
once and for all and without any shame,
that we love him.
I'm going to teach you.
I'm gonna show you how to walk,
how to speak, how to move, how to think.
Together,
you and I
are going to make
the greatest single contribution to science
since the creation of fire!
Dr Fronkonsteen. Are you all right?
My name...
...is Frankenstein!
Distinguished colleagues,
ladies and gentlemen.
Tonight it is my great privilege
of introducing to you a man
whose family name was once both
famous
and infamous.
And now may I present to you
Doktor Baron Friedrich von Frankenstein.
My fellow scienti...
...tists... and neurosurgeons,
ladies and gentlemen.
A few short weeks ago,
coming from a background,
believe me, as conservative and traditionally
grounded in scientific fact as any of you,
I began an experiment in,
incredulous as it may sound,
the reanimation of dead tissue.
What I have to offer you might possibly be
the gateway to immortality.
Ladies and gentlemen, may I present for
your intellectual and philosophical pleasure
the Creature.
Remain in your seats, I beg you.
We are not children here. We are scientists.
I assure you there is nothing to fear.
First may I offer for your consideration
a neurological demonstration
of the primary cerebellar functions.
Balance and coordination.
Walk heel to toe.
Backwards.
Ladies and gentlemen, you've seen
the Creature perform simple motor activity,
but for what you will see next
we must enter quietly
into the realm of genius.
Ladies and gentlemen,
from what was once
an inarticulate mass of lifeless tissues,
may I now present
a cultured, sophisticated
man about town.
Hit it.
Nothing. Nothing, I tell you.
Five, six, seven, eight...
Come on. Are you trying
to make me look like a fool?
Please. I beg you.
For safety's sake, don't humiliate him.
Come back. Do you hear me?
I will not let you destroy my work.
As your creator
I command you to come back.
Chained.
Chained like a beast in a cage.
Oh, Doctor. I feel so terrible.
There's only one answer.
If I could find a way to equalise
the imbalance in his cerebral-spinal fluid,
why, he'd be as right as rain.
But how?
How, before it's too late?
Oh, Frederick...
If only there was some way I could...
...relieve this torture you are going through.
If there was some way I could help to...
...relieve the tension. If there was just
some way I could give you a little peace.
Doctor, I have...
Doctor?
What is it?
Doctor...
Where are you?
I'm sorry, Doctor.
This cable came while you were gone.
I thought I told you never to
interrupt me while I'm working.
I'm sorry, Doctor.
I thought this was an emergency.
You see, your fiancée
will be arriving any second.
What? Elizabeth here tonight?
Yes. I will go prepare a room at once.
I suggest you put on a tie.
Darling.
- Surprised?
- Surprised.
- Love me?
- Love you?
Well...
- Let's turn in.
- Darling.
It's been a long day. I'm sure you're very tired.
I'll just pay the driver.
- Darling.
- What?
- Surprised?
- Yes.
- Love me?
- Well...
Well, let's turn in.
- Darling.
- Yes.
Say nothing, act casual.
- Ready?
- Yes. I think...
Yes.
I am a bit tired after all.
I'd like you to meet
my assistants, Inga and I-gor.
How do you do?
- This is my financier Elizabeth.
- I'm so happy to meet you at last.
Financée.
Excuse me, darling.
What is it exactly that you... do do?
Well, I assist Dr Fronkonsteen
in the laboratory.
We have intellectual discussions und we...
As a matter of fact, we were just having one...
- May I?
- What?
Wait a minute...
l-gor, would you give me
a hand with the bags?
Certainly, you take the blonde
and I'll take the one in the turban.
Stop that. I'm talking about the luggage.
Yes, master.
Ladies, this way.
It'll be a long night.
If you need any help with the girls...
You settle down now.
Cos we gonna be pals.
Right?
Nice and cosy.
Just like old friends.
What's the matter?
You're afraid of this little fire?
This can't hurt you.
See?
Some monster you are.
See, Mama was right.
Little boys ain't supposed to play with fire.
Is they? Cos they might get hurt.
Halt!
Up.
A riot is an ugly thing.
Und I think that it is just about time
that we had one.
Kill the monster.
As heaven is my witness... Up.
...he will curse the day
that he was burn a Frankenstein.
What?
I said: "He will curse the day
that he was born a Frankenstein."
Loose. He's broken loose.
Do you know what that means?
Darling, you mustn't worry so.
I suppose you're right.
Of course I am.
Now come along like a good boy.
What would I do without you?
Is your room just down the hall
in case I get the frights during the night?
Well, yes, but I thought perhaps tonight,
under the circumstances, I might
stay here with you.
Would you want me like this now?
So soon before our wedding,
so near we can almost touch it?
- Yes!
- Whoa, boy.
Or
to wait just a little while longer when
I can give myself to you without hesitation,
when I can be totally
and unashamedly and legally yours?
That's a tough choice.
You're a tough guy.
I suppose you're right.
Of course I am. I always am.
Now give me a kiss and say good night.
No tongues.
Good night, darling.
Good night, sweetheart.
- I love you.
- I love you, too.
You love me? I love you, honey.
- Sweet dreams, darling.
- Sweet dreams.
Good night, don't let the bedbugs bite.
He has loosed the fateful lightning
of his terrible swift sword
His truth is marching on
Glory, glory, hallelujah...
Where am I?
Who are you? What are you?
What do you want?
What are you going to do to me?
Calm down.
I'm not afraid of you.
My father is very rich.
You'd have the world at your fingertips.
Listen. I have to be back by 11.30.
I'm expecting a very important call.
Speak! Why don't you speak?
What are you doing?
Oh, no, you can't be serious.
I'm af...
Oh, my God.
Woof.
I'm engaged.
And once he... But I didn't... It was never...
Sweet mystery of life
At last I found you
At last I know the secret of it all
Penny for your thoughts.
You're incorrigible, aren't you?
You little zipper-neck.
All right.
Seven has always been my lucky number.
Come over here, you hot monster.
What is it? What's the matter?
Is it that music?
It's probably from some nearby cottage.
Nothing to worry about.
Where are you going? Where...
You men are all alike.
Seven or eight quick ones
and you're off with the boys.
To boast and brag.
You better keep your mouth shut.
Oh, I think I love him.
Look, he's coming back.
Look, the music...
Keep playing. It's the music.
It's the music that's bringing him back.
Come on.
Come on. Come.
Come on. You can do it.
Don't touch him!
He wants to do it by himself.
You can do it. You can do it.
Please, my creation.
Quick. Catch him.
Have all the preparations
been made for the transference?
Yes, Doctor.
Are you sure you want
to go through with this?
It's the only thing that can save him now.
You realise you're risking both your lives?
Yes.
Switching off.
How will I know when they are done?
The doctor said to allow 15 minutes.
Not one second more
or less.
How long now?
Two minutes.
- What's that noise?
- I don't know.
- What time is it?
- Almost time.
Oh, my God. It's the villagers.
No! No! Please.
Just another seven seconds.
No! No!
No! No! No!
- Put that man down.
- It's the monster.
- No, it can't be.
- It is.
I said: "Put that man down."
Undjust who do you think you are
that you order these people about?
I am the monster.
Ja. I see that you are the monster.
For as long as I can remember
people have hated me.
They looked at my face and my body
and they ran away in horror.
In my loneliness, I decided that if I could not
inspire love, which was my deepest hope,
I would instead cause fear.
I live,
because this poor, half-crazed
genius has given me life.
He alone held an image of me
as something beautiful.
And then,
when it would have been easy enough
to stay out of danger,
he used his own body as a guinea pig
to give me a calmer brain
and a somewhat more
sophisticated way of expressing myself.
Well, this is, of course,
an entirely different situation.
As the leader of this community,
may I be the first to offer you my hand
in friendship.
- Thank you.
- You are entirely welcome.
Und now let us all go to my house
for a little sponge cake und a little wine...
... und shit!
To the lumberyard!
Hello, Mrs Frankenstein.
Mrs Frankenstein. What a beautiful name.
Oh, darling.
Hold on to your hat.
What?
I'll be right back.
I'm holding on to it, darling.
Just a few more seconds.
Honey, I hope you didn't find
Daddy's little party too boring.
He did it just for you
and he meant so well. Say you liked it.
Honey, did you see?
I put a special hamper in the bathroom
just for your shirts
and the other one is just for socks
and poo-poo undies.
Here I come.
The feeling is mutual.
You know, it's a puzzlement.
There's something I've always wanted
to ask you about that operation.
You know in the transference part,
the monster got part of your wonderful brain,
but what did you ever get from him?
No. I don't believe...
Sweet mystery of life
At last I found you
Subtitles by Visiontext
UK ENGLISH