~ Risin' up ~
~ Back on the street ~
~ Did my time, took my chances ~
~ Went the distance,
now I'm back on my feet ~
~ Just a man and his will to survive ~
~ So many times, it happens too fast ~
~ You change your passion for glory ~
~ Don't lose your grip
on the dreams of the past ~
~ You must fight just to keep them alive ~
~ It's the eye of the tiger,
it's the thrill of the fight ~
~ Risin' up to the challenge of our rival ~
~ And the last known survivor
stalks his prey in the night ~
~ And he's watchin' us all
in the eye of the tiger ~
- Come on! We made a deal.
- I know, but it's extremely crazy.
It's mentally irregular, but
it makes all the sense in the world.
- You owe me a favour.
- I know, but...
- When did you think of this?
- About three years ago.
- This is very crazy, Apollo.
- Stallion, when you won that last fight,
you won by one second.
You beat me by one second.
That's very hard for a man
of my intelligence to handle.
Didn't you say you learned
how to live with it?
- I lied.
- Oh, you lied?
Oh! So now you just gotta
prove it to yourself, right?
Just for myself. No TV,
no newspapers - just you and me.
Nothin' - just you and me.
Age before beauty.
- Anything you say.
- I do all the work. OK.
I tell you, Apollo, you'd better go slow.
You ain't as young as springtime no more.
- I'm still young enough to whip your butt.
- Oh, yeah? How you gonna do that?
- You taught me everything you know.
- Almost everything.
You gotta remember: You fight great,
but I'm a great fighter. You ready?
- Absolutely.
- You know, Stallion,
it's too bad we gotta get old, huh?
Oh, just keep punchin', Apollo.
- Wanna ring the bell?
- All right.
Ding, ding.
Come on, Stallion.
Come on, come on.
Boy, you really move
good for an older guy.
- Look at him fly.
- Look out now.
No, you don't want any of this.
- Come on.
- Maybe I'm in here with the wrong guy.
Dad, you're late. Mom's gonna yell at you.
- So how you doin'?
- Fine.
You know, don't you think
that's a little bright?
- A little bit?
- Where'd you get that hat?
- A friend gave it to me. Like it?
- Who punched you in the eye?
- Same friend.
- That's weird. Better hurry, Dad.
You know, you're developin'
a very, very loud personality.
Don't go too fast,
or you're gonna get out of focus.
Oh, really?
- Yo!
- Yo. It's about time.
I'm sorry I'm late.
- Why don't you go and get ready to eat?
- Great. You're here.
- Now you can stop calling him names.
- You been callin' me names?
We wait any longer,
it'll be my next birthday.
- Where have you been?
- Oh, gettin' punched.
Bring the cake in and we can
get this celebration under way.
- Boy, am I hungry.
- Baby, why don't you get the cake?
We got a great surprise.
You're gonna love this cake.
- And your present.
- Where is it?
Let me set the mood. I gotta turn
the lights down and everythin'.
- Watch this.
- Is it parked outside?
Just be patient, would ya?
I'm so excited, I'm startin' to sweat.
I feel like I'm gettin' ready to go into
a big fight or somethin'. Watch this.
Happy birthday, Paulie.
- What the hell is this?
- Your present.
I wanted a sports car for my birthday,
not no walkin' trash can!
- Come on! He looks great.
- This is extremely psycho.
You have no friends,
so we thought you'd like it.
Pretend you're happy.
It'll keep you company.
- That's a great-lookin' guy.
- Please make a wish.
It's creepy! It talks!
Creepy? I wish I had one of these
when I was growin' up.
- Go on, make a wish, like he says.
- I wish I wasn't in this nightmare.
Very classy wish. What do you think?
Very good, huh?
You wanna help me
put out this forest fire?
- Sure.
- OK. On the count of three. One...
two... three!
- Well, they're out.
- You "drownded" me!
Oh, don't worry.
I'll clean it up for you, Paulie.
- Rocky!
- Yeah, you noticed.
What are you doing with that cake?
The party ain't over yet, you know.
We still gotta celebrate some more.
- It's a special night.
- Yeah, it's Wednesday.
It's Wednesday, but in case you forgot,
it's almost been nine years since
you've been married to me, so...
here's your prize.
- But our anniversary's a week away.
- That's true, but... why wait?
- Has it been that rough?
- No, no.
I tell you, it's been excellent.
Open your prize. Go on.
- Go on, open your prize.
- OK.
- Do you like it?
- It's beautiful.
All right!
I was so nervous. I didn't know.
I... I hope you like it.
The guy I bought it from says even if
it looks like a snake, don't worry,
cos it won't bite you.
It's beautiful.
You know what's amazing?
That after all these years,
everything still seems kinda new.
You remember a long time ago
I told you that...
I said that you ain't never
gettin' rid of me. Remember that?
Well, you're not.
You're never gettin' rid of me.
Happy "almost anniversary".
- A few questions, please.
- How long are you here for?
- We talk later.
- When are you gonna fight, Drago?
We talk later.
Is it definite that the Soviet Union
will enter professional boxing?
No more talk now.
We will talk at press conference.
~ Oh, golden dishes
from Church's and catfish at Church's ~
~ Have some catfish from
Church's Fried Chicken ~
~ Catfish from Church's! ~
Today may be a landmark
in sports history.
After unravelling years of red tape,
Russia will throw its hat into the ring -
the prize ring. The introductions were
made by his wife, Ludmilla Vobet Drago -
gold medallist in swimming.
Today the Soviet Union has officially
entered professional boxing.
My husband and great undefeated
heavyweight world amateur champion,
Captain Ivan Drago, has come here
with his trainers to America
to compete as an international
sportsman and ambassador of goodwill.
Has he boxed against a professional?
From having been trained in Russia
by great boxing coach Manuel Vega,
and now by Sergei Rimsky,
we hope he's qualified to do so.
- Hope?
- Well, I know he is,
but I don't want to sound too confident.
We would like an exhibition bout with
your famous champion, Rocky Balboa.
You think he can fight
someone as seasoned as Balboa?
There is no one who can match his
strength, endurance or aggressiveness.
You make him sound indestructible.
Yes, he is.
Can this mammoth Russian,
nicknamed the Siberian Express,
wreak havoc among
the professional heavyweight ranks?
Whoever he fights first,
it'll be one hot ticket.
We'll be right back with a check on
today's pro football sports scoreboard.
Dad, when can I learn to fight?
- I can't hear you. What?
- I wanna learn to fight.
Yo. Could you turn your robot down?
You see, I fight so you don't have to fight.
I want you to use your head for somethin'
instead of a punchin' bag, like I do.
Your head doesn't look
like a punching bag.
No? That's nice. Thanks a lot.
It looks like a catcher's mitt!
Oh! A wise guy, huh?
Mr Balboa! Mr Creed's on the phone.
- Yeah? I'll be right there.
- You can get it right here.
- I hope it's not another rematch.
- Oh, don't worry about it.
Hello? Yeah, Apollo... Turn that down.
Apollo, how ya doin'? Yeah?
You're comin' out? That's great.
What am I doin'? I'm just gettin' dizzy.
My husband and I thank you for
coming to our training quarter today.
As you can see, it is highly advanced,
and we wish to show the American press
a small portion of the advances
our country has made
in the technology of human performance.
Coach Rimsky, what does this do
to enhance performance?
- Well...
- If I may answer.
It makes a man a better man,
a great athlete a superathlete,
by harnessing all his strength.
Though most of the world is
ignorant in body chemistry,
- we wish to... educate your country.
- There have been rumours of doping,
and widespread distribution of
anabolic steroids in the Soviet Union.
- Has Drago partaken in any experiments?
- No! Ivan is naturally trained.
Then how do you explain
his... freakish strength?
Like your Popeye,
he ate his spinach every day.
- Shall we have a demonstration?
- Please do.
A normal heavyweight averages
700 pounds of pressure per square inch.
As you can see,
Drago averages 1850 pounds.
- So the result's quite obvious.
- And what results are those?
Whatever he hits, he destroys.
I've seen Drago fight when he was an
amateur. He's big and strong, but clumsy.
I know I can beat him.
- Why do you wanna fight again?
- Let's just say it's somethin' I believe in.
- You can do your homework.
- OK. Later, Dad. Later, Uncle Paulie.
- Later, Apollo.
- Later, big man.
See you later, kiddo.
Don't you think people are expectin'
- to see Rocky whack this bum out first?
- Yeah. And he will, when it's for real.
- This is an exhibition bout. Kids' stuff.
- What's the purpose?
What at this point in your life
is worth getting hurt for?
~ Double or nothin',
you've gotta have a partner... ~
- What the hell is that?
- That's my girl.
~ Takin' and givin',
it's time we started livin'... ~
- Thanks, honey.
- You're welcome.
- That's a nice song.
- It's my favourite. You're the greatest.
See you, sport.
- See you.
- Paulie, who taught it to talk like that?
She loves me.
~ You stepped out of the night... ~
Like I was sayin', I don't want this chump
to come over here with all that hype,
tryin' to make us look bad.
They try every other way.
With Rock's help, we can get great
media coverage. We make them look bad.
- I think it's wrong.
- No. It's never been more right.
You're a great fighter,
but you've been retired five years.
Isn't it time to start
thinking about something else?
How much can you take? Either of you?
I'll... get the coffee.
Look, I'm sorry. I didn't mean to...
I just care about you both. I...
You ever try these comics?
- No, no.
- Keeps your fertility.
Hey, Paulie.
In the ring now... Rocky's holding that
right hand. He's fighting right-handed!
Oh, now this was a great fight.
Great! I'm gettin' punchy just watchin' it!
Mamma mia! What you usin'
for a chin there, Stallion?
- I should've slipped that one.
- You definitely should've slipped that.
It's crazy how people just care about you
in that ring and when you're bleedin',
but once you step out,
you're ancient history.
It ain't ancient history.
I don't see anybody askin'
for autographs, do you?
Hey, Apollo... Can I... ask you somethin'?
What?
Well, this fight you're havin' against
the Russian. Do you think maybe...
it ain't against him?
If it's not him, Stallion,
then who's it against?
Well, do you think maybe it's, like...
you against you? What do you think?
You know, I think you really
are gettin' brain-damaged.
Maybe, but... really.
I'm speakin' the truth here, Apollo.
- Are you?
- Yeah.
- I don't think I wanna hear this, Stallion.
- Hey, Apollo, you were a great fighter,
but, look, we gotta face the facts too.
You don't wanna believe it,
but maybe the show is over.
That's easy for you to say.
You're still on top.
What happens when
you're not on top? Then what?
Where do we go, Stallion?
Cos we sure as hell can't be born again.
I know we can't be born again, but, let's
face it, we... we gotta change sometime.
I don't wanna change! I like who I am!
I like who you are, too, but look at that.
That ain't us up there no more, Apollo.
We can't do that the way we did it before.
We're changin'. We're, like,
turnin' into regular people.
No, Stallion!
Maybe you think you're changin'.
But you can't change what you really are.
You can forget all this money and stuff.
Cos it don't change a thing.
You and me, we don't even have a choice.
We're born with a killer instinct that you
can't just turn off and on like some radio.
We have to be right in the middle of
the action, cos we're the warriors.
Without some challenge,
some damn war to fight,
then the warrior may
as well be dead, Stallion.
So I'm askin' you,
as a friend,
stand by my side this one last time.
You're a great talker, Apollo.
All right, but... when this is over?
You know me, Stallion.
I always think of somethin' else.
That's what I'm afraid of.
All right. You got a deal there.
I feel sorry for that guy, you know?
What made you decide to put on
an exhibition fight with Drago?
Let's call it a sense of responsibility.
Responsibility, how?
I had to teach this young fella
to box - American style!
Isn't Drago a little inexperienced
to be in the same ring?
Well, you know, some folks
got to learn the hard way!
- No quick knockout predictions?
- No. I'm not angry with him.
I just wanna show the whole world that
Russia doesn't have all the best athletes.
Rocky, how do you think
Apollo should fight Drago?
Well, personally, I think the first thing
you'd better get Apollo is a ladder.
Drago, how does it feel to spar
with the great former champion?
The man's tongue didn't
come through customs.
My husband is very happy
to have this opportunity.
- It's his dream.
- Dream? How do you mean?
In our country, Apollo Creed is
well known and very respected.
- It could be a good victory.
- Whoa! Wait a minute, now. Hold it.
When? Now you don't really think
you're gonna whip me, do ya?
- Well, he didn't come here to lose.
- You hold on, little lady.
- Lose, and lose royally, he's gonna do.
- How can you be so sure?
I've been with the best. I beat the best.
I retired more men than Social Security!
Excuse, please. You are not
very realistic, are you, Mr Creed?
What are you talkin' about?
You can box, yes, but you are far too
old to think you can win over Drago.
- Is that a fact?
- Yes! And it could be a painful one!
Put that heavy bag with eyeballs
in the ring with me and you'll see pain!
- Why do you insult us?
- Now you just hold on here.
I'm not the bad guy. I came to talk
about a friendly exhibition bout
- till Comrade Bigmouth started up!
- It is you who are the aggressor.
I wish to say to the press, in all fairness,
Drago should not even fight this man,
because he is a has-been.
You get that big chump
in the ring right now...
- Stop this before you get hurt.
- I don't wanna hear! Let that chump go!
All right, all right. I've said what I feel.
- We'll finish this in the ring!
- Wherever you like.
You shut up, and all these puppets you
brought with you! You're history, chump!
- How did I do?
- A little loud for me.
- But good?
- Oh, yeah. Very good.
Welcome to the City of Lights -
Las Vegas -
and to one of the most unusual
events in years... East meets West.
Age versus youth in
a goodwill exhibition match,
as the former champion Apollo Creed
takes on a mountain of muscle
from the Soviet Union... Ivan Drago.
- Come on.
- Patience is a virtue.
- I'm ready to rock 'n' roll.
- You gotta get your equipment.
- Now you look like a mummy.
- I feel like a mummy.
- How does it feel? OK?
- Feels great. I feel like I could eat nails.
- I never tried them snails.
- What are you talkin' about?
Snails. I never had 'em. I see 'em in
the garden, but I never want to eat 'em.
I didn't say anythin' about snails.
I said nails. N-N-Nails, Stallion!
You look pretty good, but, you know,
just do me a favour when you go up there.
- Try not to wear yourself out, OK?
- Yeah, wear myself out. Sure.
Well, it's just that you ain't
been in the ring for five years.
- I just want you to... maintain a little bit.
- I'm in the best shape of my life.
- I'm stronger, I'm quicker...
- Hey, I'm not sayin' you're not ready,
but personally, if it were me,
I wouldn't mind postponin'
a couple of weeks.
Postpone?
Come on, Apollo. We don't know anythin'
about this guy you're fightin', really.
Let's say I postpone. I pull out, somebody
else steps in and whips this chump.
- Then where does that leave me?
- This is just some kind of exhibition fight.
- This thing don't mean nothin'.
- No, man. That's where you're wrong.
This is not just an exhibition fight
that doesn't mean anything.
This is us against them.
What are you talkin' about? Come on!
Stallion...
Maybe you don't know what I'm talkin'
about now, but you will when it's over.
Believe me, you will when it's over.
Ivan!
Good luck. I hope after we can be friends.
- I hope so.
- Of course. They're sportsmen,
not soldiers.
Enjoy the fight.
~ Ow! Get up! ~
~ Knock it out! Dig! ~
~ Hit it! ~
~ Superhighways ~
~ Coast to coast ~
~ Easy to get anywhere ~
~ On the transcontinental overload ~
~ Just slide behind the wheel ~
~ How does it feel?
~ When there's no destination ~
~ That's too far ~
~ And somewhere on the way
you might find out who you are, wow! ~
~ Livin' in America ~
~ Eye to eye ~
~ Station to station ~
~ Livin' in America ~
~ Hand to hand, across the nation ~
~ Got to have a celebration ~
~ You may not be lookin'
for the Promised Land ~
~ But you might find it anyway ~
~ Under one of those old familiar names ~
~ Like New Orleans
New Orleans! ~
~ Detroit City
Detroit City! ~
~ Dallas
Dallas! ~
~ Pittsburgh PA
Pittsburgh PA! ~
~ New York City
New York City! ~
~ Kansas City
Kansas City! ~
~ Atlanta, yeah!
Atlanta! ~
~ Chicago and LA ~
~ I live in America ~
~ Head to head ~
~ Toe to toe ~
~ I live in America ~
~ Say it loud ~
~ It’ll make you proud ~
~ I live in America ~
~ Hey, I know what it means ~
~ Livin' in America ~
~ Got it made! I said now,
eye to eye, tooth to tooth ~
~ This is undisputed truth ~
~ Livin' in America
Yeah! ~
~ All the way with your bad self ~
~ Livin' in America
Yeah! ~
~ I feel good! ~
Good evening. Along with
Warner Wolf, I am Stu Nahan.
We welcome you to an unusual
event: For the first time ever,
West against East in professional sports.
Thanks for gettin' me here. I owe you one.
- Oh, no, no. We're even.
- God, I feel born again.
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome!
I would like to announce the presence
of a true fighting champion
that defines the word "courage".
The Italian Stallion: Rocky Balboa!
- Excuse me, would you?
- Certainly.
Rocky!
Tonight's special event
features two great athletes.
In the blue corner, weighing 221 pounds,
a former heavyweight
champion of the world,
the Dancing Destroyer,
the King of Sting,
the Count of Monte Fisto...
- Think you got enough names?
- Be patient. Almost done.
The Master of Disaster,
the one and only Apollo Creed!
The crowd anticipating a great fight now
as Apollo plays to the crowd.
In the red corner,
weighing an even 261 pounds,
gold medallist and undefeated
world amateur champion
from the Soviet Union,
the Siberian Bull,
Ivan Drago!
I want you! I want you! I want you!
The two fighters come to the centre
for instructions from referee Lou Filippo.
You know the rules. Watch the low blows,
kidney punches and rabbit punches.
In case of a knockdown, go to the corner
and stay there until I tell you to come out.
- Shake hands. Let's have a good fight.
- It's time to go to school, son.
Get your hands up! Do you need an
interpreter? It's time to go to school!
You will lose.
All right!
The bad blood between these two
can be felt all over this arena.
I can't get over the size of this Russian!
- Apollo! Apollo!
- Get ready, cos it's showtime! Showtime!
- It's showtime!
- Excuse me. Didn't you forget somethin'?
Apollo seems to be in great spirits.
He's really putting on a show
for this capacity crowd.
Be back in a minute, all right?
Round one.
Creed's dancing around.
Creed back-pedalling now.
He's been away five years.
Neither fighter ready to throw a punch.
A left jab there... and once again.
- A slip by Creed.
- This is bizarre.
Creed is over the hill, and...
the Russian hasn't fought anybody.
- Keep movin'. Stick him!
- Drago's moving in again.
A left hand by Creed. Another left hand
by Creed, and Drago moves away.
Another left hand by Creed. Drago
waiting, waiting, cocking that right hand.
A punishing right by the Russian.
Get outta there! Get outta there!
A left. He's taking some punishment now.
Drago moves him against the ropes.
Tie him up now!
The Russian ties him up
and throws Creed across the ring!
Move!
It is Drago with the upper hand now.
Get outta that corner!
Another right! Another right!
Creed is against the ropes!
I think they may stop it.
What are you guys doin'?!
This is supposed to be an exhibition!
Tremendous end to the first round by the
Russian, and a very bloody Apollo Creed.
The Soviet's strength is incredible!
Champ, look. I gotta stop ya.
This fight's finished. I gotta call it.
- You can't do no more.
- I'm here to fight him.
- He's killin' ya! I gotta stop this thing.
- Promise me you're not gonna stop it.
That was a pulverising round
for the ex-champion.
Hey, folks. Ivan Drago is definitely for real.
You don't stop this fight, no matter what.
Apollo! Apollo!
No matter what.
Creed now comes out
for round two dancing around.
The legs appear to be still a little rubbery.
Get your hands up.
And now it is the Russian just standing
there, trying to intimidate Creed.
And the Russian throws a right hand
to the jaw! Another right to the head!
Creed's being pounded without mercy!
Stop the fight!
- The referee is thrown across the ring!
- Throw the towel! Throw the towel!
- I've never seen Apollo take so much.
- Throw the damn towel!
No!
- My God!
- Creed is down!
Apollo is down,
and he could be badly hurt.
- Get these guys outta here.
- The winner, Ivan Drago.
- Let me through! Apollo!
- I cannot be defeated.
- Is he OK?
- Somebody get a doctor in here!
- There is no movement by Creed.
- I defeat old man.
- Is he dead?
- Get outta here!
It's absolute pandemonium!
Will ya let him breathe?
Soon... I defeat real champion.
Where's the stretcher?
Let him breathe, for God's sake!
What started out as a joke
has turned out to be a disaster.
Creed is in a very serious condition.
- Is the man alive?
- You can make it, Apollo.
If he dies... he dies.
There's a lot I could say... about this man.
But I don't know if it matters now.
I guess what matters is...
what he stood for,
what he lived for, and...
what he died for.
You always did everything...
the way you wanted it.
I know I didn't understand that, but...
now I understand.
I'll never forget you, Apollo.
You're the best.
- Rocky, is the decision final?
- Yes.
Is this the first time
the champion has given up his crown?
- I don't know about that.
- Doesn't the title matter?
Not until this is over.
Considering Rocky's punching power,
do you still expect an easy fight?
- Yes, of course.
- It's a matter of size...
and evolution. Isn't it, gentlemen? Drago
is the most perfectly trained athlete ever.
This other man has not the size,
or the endurance, or the genetics to win.
It's physically impossible
for this little man to win.
Drago is a look at the future.
Champ, how much
are you making for this fight?
- No money. It's not about money.
- Has the fight date been set yet?
- December 25th.
- Why Christmas?
- That's what I was told.
- Where?
- It's in Russia.
- Are you nuts?
Rocky, what's going on?
We fight in Soviet Union,
or we fight nowhere.
Why don't you ask Drago's wife
why she is afraid? Tell them, please.
I'm afraid for my husband's life.
We have threats of violence everywhere.
We are not in politics. All I want is for my
husband to be safe, to be treated fairly.
You call him a killer.
He's a professional fighter, not a killer.
You have this belief that
you are better than us,
that this country is so very good,
and we are so very bad.
You have this belief that you are so fair,
and we are so very cruel.
It is lies and false propaganda
to support this antagonistic
and violent government!
Violent? We don't keep our people
behind a wall with machine guns!
- Who are you?
- Who am I?
- I'm... the unsilent majority, bigmouth!
- Good! Yes, good!
Insult us! Is more typical rude behaviour
towards visiting foreigners!
But perhaps this simple defeat
of this little so-called champion
will be a perfect example
of how pathetically weak
your society has become. We go!
Mrs Balboa!
- How do you feel about Russia?
- Is your husband going to Moscow?
How does it feel to be part of
such a controversial decision?
Did Creed's death
make up your husband's mind?
- I don't know what you're talking about!
- Why is he going at Christmas?
When will you be going to Russia?
I'm not going to Russia. I don't know
what you're talking about!
I don't know what you
people are doing here!
- Rocky?
- Yeah?
- You all right?
- Yeah.
Fine.
Why'd you do it?
- I just gotta do what I gotta do.
- You don't have to do anything.
No, Adrian, I do, and...
I gotta leave this place, too.
So where are you... going?
They said they were gonna
let me train in Russia.
I just wanna go someplace where I ain't
gonna think about nothin' except him.
Rocky, give it some time. Don't do this.
A lot of people live with hurt.
A lot of people don't have a choice. I do.
And for that you're willing
to lose everything?
Adrian, this ain't everything.
This house, and the cars, and all
the stuff we got... that ain't everything.
There's a lot more than this, Adrian.
Before, there were reasons to fight I
understood, but I don't understand this.
Even if you win, what have you won?
Apollo's still gone.
Why can't you change your thinking?
Everybody else does!
Cos I'm a fighter!
That's the way I'm made, Adrian.
That's what you married.
We can't change what we are.
- Yes, you can.
- You can't change anythin'.
- All we can do is go with what we are.
- You can't go with what you are!
Have you read the papers?
Do you know what everybody says?
It's suicide! You've seen him.
You know how strong he is.
You can't win!
Oh, Adrian.
Adrian always tells the truth.
No, maybe I can't win.
Maybe the only thing I can do...
is just take everythin' he's got.
But to beat me...
he's gonna have to kill me.
And to kill me, he's gonna have to
have the heart to stand in front of me.
And to do that, he's gotta
be willin' to die himself.
And I don't know if he's ready to do that.
I don't know.
~ We're not indestructible ~
~ Baby, better get that straight ~
~ I think it's unbelievable ~
~ How you give in to the hands of fate ~
~ Cos some things are worth fightin' for ~
~ Some feelings never die ~
~ I'm not askin' for another chance ~
~ I just wanna know why ~
~ There's no easy way out ~
~ There's no shortcut home ~
~ Givin' in can't be wrong ~
~ I don't wanna pacify you~
~ I don't wanna drag you down ~
~ But I'm feelin' like a prisoner ~
~ Like a stranger in a no-name town ~
~ I see only angry faces ~
~ So afraid that could be you and me ~
~ Talkin' about what might have been ~
~ And thinkin' about what used to be ~
~ There's no easy way out ~
~ There's no shortcut home ~
~ Givin' in can't be wrong ~
~ Baby, baby, we can shed this skin ~
~ We can know how we feel inside ~
~ Instead of goin' down an endless road ~
~ Not knowin' if we're dead or alive ~
~ Cos some things are worth fightin' for ~
~ Some feelings never die ~
~ I'm not askin' for another chance ~
~ I just wanna know why ~
~ There's no easy way out ~
~ There's no shortcut home ~
~ Givin' in, givin' in can't be wrong, no ~
~ There's no easy way out
There's no easy way out ~
~ There's no shortcut home
There's no shortcut home ~
~ There's no easy way out
There's no easy ~
~ No easy, no easy way out ~
~ There's no easy way out
There's no easy way out ~
~ There's no shortcut home
There's no shortcut home ~
~ There's no easy way out
There's no easy ~
~ No easy, no easy way out ~
~ There's no easy way out ~
~ There's no shortcut home ~
Be careful with those plaid ones.
They belong to the boss.
Paulie, did you pack your toothbrush?
You know how tobacco stains your teeth.
- If I've told you once, I've told you...
- Hey! Hey!
- Stop bustin' my chops.
- Paulie!
I'm gonna have her wires
tied when I get back.
When will you be back?
- Oh, pretty soon.
- Are you scared?
- Nah.
- Yes, you are. A little, maybe?
Well, wouldn't you be?
If a big giant man wanted to
beat me up, I'd be real scared.
Well, the truth is, you know, sometimes...
I do get a little scared, you know.
When I'm in that ring
and I'm really gettin' hit on,
and my arms hurt so much I can't
even lift them, and I'm thinkin',
"God! I wish this guy would hit me on
the chin so I don't feel nothin' any more."
Then there's another side that
comes out that isn't so scared.
There's another side that, like,
wants to take more, that wants
to go that one more round,
because by goin' that one more round
when you don't think you can,
that's what makes all the difference
in your life. You know what I mean?
And will you remember one more thing?
Will you remember that... Daddy thinks
you're the best boy in the world, hm?
And that Daddy loves you...
no matter what?
Will you?
I gotta go now.
- You gonna take care of everythin'?
- OK.
And don't forget to feed your robot.
Bye, baby.
Good luck.
Thanks.
Come on! The meter's runnin'!
~ Two worlds collide, rival nations ~
~ It's a primitive clash,
venting years of frustration ~
~ Bravely we hope against all hope ~
~ There is so much at stake ~
~ Seems our freedom's
up against the ropes ~
~ Does the crowd understand? ~
~ Is it East versus West ~
~ Or man against man? ~
~ Can any nation stand alone? ~
~ In the burning heart ~
~ Just about to burst ~
~ There's a quest for answers,
an unquenchable thirst ~
~ In the darkest night... ~
What a horrendous flight.
This is Russia?
It don't look so tough, Rock.
Mr Balboa.
We take you to quarters now.
Hey, when does the sun come up?
This is detrimental to my sinuses.
Weather changes, hour to hour.
Get used to it.
Get in car now. We have very long trip.
He sounds like Dracula's cousin.
~ In the warrior's code
there's no surrender ~
~ Though his body says "Stop",
his spirit cries "Never!" ~
~ Deep in our soul a quiet ember ~
~ Knows it's you against you ~
~ It's the paradox that drives us on ~
~ It's a battle of wills ~
~ In the heat of attack,
it's the passion that kills ~
~ That victory is yours alone ~
~ In the burning heart ~
~ Just about to burst ~
~ There's a quest for answers,
an unquenchable thirst ~
~ In the darkest night, rising like a spire ~
~ In the burning heart,
the unmistakable fire ~
Like you requested, yes?
- You requested this dumb location?
- Yeah.
Why? You plannin' to grow
reindeer or somethin'?
- I just wanted to get away from things.
- The equipment you requested is in barn.
- Who are they?
- They?
They are assigned to you.
Official chaperons, yes?
Where you go, they go.
Oh, I have a bad dream here.
- Paul, it's OK.
- OK? This is below human standards.
There's no antennas. You gotta
complain. We'll crack out here!
You have everything
I have been instructed to provide.
We are finished, yes? Da svidaniya.
No sparrin'?
I don't think I need it any more, Paulie.
No sparrin', no TV, nothin'?
How the heck is he supposed
to train around here?
No TV. What about the Rose Bowl game?
No room service, I bet.
I hope they got my comics here.
What a depressing vacation.
Goddamn!
All right, you Chipmunks.
Ready to sing your song?
~ Christmas, Christmastime is here ~
~ Time for toys and time for cheer ~
~ We've been good, but we can't last... ~
Checkmate, friend.
- Yeah?
- Hey, champ. Can I come up?
Yeah, sure.
- How you doin'?
- Pretty good.
- Some kinda weather we're havin', huh?
- Yeah, it's pretty rough.
But for what you gotta do, it's good.
- Toughen you up.
- I guess so.
I know you're gonna have to do almost
everything alone, but I'll be with you.
Yeah, I know.
Apollo was like my son.
I raised him.
And when he died... a part of me died.
But now... you're the one.
You're the one that's gonna keep
his spirit alive. You're the one...
that's gonna make sure
that he didn't die for nothing.
Now you're gonna have
to go through hell,
worse than any nightmare
that you ever dreamed.
But in the end...
I know you'll be the one standin'.
I'll try.
You know what you gotta do.
Do it.
Do it!
Thanks, Duke.
I couldn't stay away any more.
I missed you.
I'm with you, no matter what.
No matter what?
No matter what.
~ Silent darkness creeps into your soul ~
~ And removes the light of self-control ~
~ The cage that holds
you captive has no doors ~
~ Burnin' with determination ~
~ To even out the score ~
~ Heart's on fire ~
~ Strong desire ~
~ Rages deep within ~
~ Heart's on fire ~
~ Fever's risin' high ~
~ The moment of truth is here ~
~ Oh! ~
No pain. No pain.
~ Heart's on fire ~
~ Strong desire ~
~ Rages deep within ~
~ Fever's risin' ~
~ Energisin' ~
~ Fight until the end ~
~ Heart's on fire ~
~ Strong desire ~
~ Rages deep within ~
Drago!
Hello, and merry Christmas
from a very unusual place.
We're in Moscow. I'm Barry Tompkins,
along with Al Bandiero,
and this promises to be the most
watched event in boxing history.
The Iron Horse from America, Rocky
Balboa, comes here to the Soviet Union...
Ivan Drago: Since that tragedy in Las
Vegas and the death of Apollo Creed,
he's been re-nicknamed
"Death from Above".
Drago! Drago!
The general secretary of the Soviet
and other members of the Politburo
have now made their way to their seats
high above the ring here in Moscow.
I know you're kinda busy, but I wanna
tell you some things I never told you.
I know sometimes I act stupid and I say
stupid things, but you kept me around
when other people would've said
"Drop that bum." You give me respect.
It's hard for me to say these kinda
things because that ain't my way,
but if I could unzip myself and step out
and be someone else, I'd wanna be you.
You're all heart, Rock.
Thanks, Paulie.
Now blast this guy's teeth out!
I'll try.
One of the fighters is starting to make his
way through this crowd toward the ring.
- Listen to this crowd!
- This borders on pure hatred.
Rocky's face: Absolutely like stone,
a picture of concentration,
and the booing crowd here does
not seem to bother him one bit.
The champ has a look that
could burn through lead.
It seems the booing crowd has
absolutely no effect on the man.
His concentration is like stone.
- That's my dad.
- We know.
What do you think we are - nerds?
Listen to this crowd. It sounds insane.
And now the entrance
of the Russian national champion.
Ivan Drago, a man with
an entire country in his corner.
Look at the expression
on the face of Ivan Drago.
He seems impervious
to this madness of the crowd.
He's like a volcano just waiting to erupt.
The Russian is cool
as he acknowledges his premier.
I would like to point out again,
this is a non-sanctioned fight.
This is not for the title. The American
Boxing Commission has not sanctioned it.
Ladies and gentlemen...
Rocky Balboa!
It's unbelievable.
I have never seen such a hostile crowd.
Ivan Drago!
Roaring for their champion!
The two men are walking to the centre.
It's an unbelievable sight to see.
They're toe to toe.
The Russian towers above the American.
It's a true case of David and Goliath here.
It's unbelievable, the...
the condition of both men.
I must break you.
Remember what I said
about wanting to be you?
Forget it.
Thanks, Paul.
Take it straight to him, and be
a rock for me, you understand?
Be a rock for me! Be strong!
All right? Take it to him! No pain.
- No pain. No pain.
- No pain. No pain. All right, Rock. Do it!
There's the bell.
Rocky comes to the centre of the ring,
like the Russian, way back
into Balboa's corner now.
- Get outta there!
- Let's go, Rocky!
Balboa gets out of the corner, and it is
Drago backing Rocky up with a jab.
And Balboa is not staying on balance
because of the long jab of the Russian.
Brace yourself! Brace yourself!
Hands up!
- Charge him!
- Now!
He can't seem to touch the Russian.
Rocky pounding away, and he's just hit
him with everything he's got.
And Drago just smiled at him.
- Keep choppin' away!
- Chop him down! Chop him down!
Rocky Balboa is in serious trouble!
They might have to stop this one
before somebody gets killed.
Reach and grab him! Reach and grab him!
Rocky woke the sleeping giant,
and now he's paying the price!
A right hand from Drago sends Rocky
Balboa 15 feet across the ring,
and the champ is down!
Come on! Get up!
Hands up! Hands up!
Drago continuing to punish Rocky.
He will not let him out of that corner,
and Rocky Balboa is just trying to
get through this first round.
The Russian just threw Rocky Balboa
into his own corner like a rag doll.
What a tough three minutes
for Rocky Balboa.
He's not only fighting
an invincible opponent,
he's also fighting a hostile crowd,
and the Russian premier and
most of the Politburo looking on.
- What's happenin' out there?
- He's winnin'.
- I see three of him out there.
- Hit the one in the middle.
- Right! Hit the one in the middle!
- Yeah.
You're not doing as you're told.
The American is small and weak...
Weak.
Take his heart. If you hurt him, you'll
take his heart. No pain! Keep workin'!
Round two.
It's been a one-sided fight so far.
It'll take more than luck
for Rocky to survive this round.
Slip him a hook, Rock! Slip him a hook!
Balboa trying to stay in the middle
of the ring against the big Russian.
Do what you gotta do! Stay with him!
For all intent,
Balboa should be all finished,
but he's fighting back ferociously.
Rocky!
Balboa goes down again from
a right hand! Bounces right back up.
He's gettin' killed out there!
Rocky Balboa has taken
Ivan Drago's best punches so far.
He's cut and he's bleeding,
but he's on his feet and he's on the run!
- He's cut! He's cut!
- The Russian's cut!
And it's a bad cut! And now it's
Rocky Balboa coming after Ivan Drago!
Incredible! Get him!
Drago wants to go on!
He grabs Balboa by the throat!
Balboa picking up the Russian and throws
him to the ground like a wrestler.
It's a gutter war!
No holds barred in Moscow!
Rocky may be on the receiving end
so far, but he's here to fight.
This is shaping up to be
a personal war, and right now
it's anybody's boxing match.
You're doin' good, Rocko.
I couldn't do better myself.
How can you do this?
He's nothing... soft!
You got him hurt bad. Now he's worried.
You cut him! You hurt him! You see?
You see? He's not a machine. He's a man!
He's not human...
He's like a piece of iron.
- You want it more than he does! No pain!
- No pain.
- No pain. OK! Take it to him!
Take it to him! Take it to him!
Get up!
And a big right hand by Rocky Balboa!
You're doin' fine. You're doin' great.
Come on!
A few cheers now for Rocky Balboa!
Suddenly Moscow is pro-Rocky!
No pain. No pain.
Al, this place is ready to explode.
Lethal punch after punch.
Amazing willpower!
And Rocky's determination is beginning
to win over what was a hostile crowd.
This is incredible.
- What round is it?
- 15. One more round.
There's no stoppin' us now.
This is our round.
Rocky! Rocky!
No stoppin' now!
You start and you don't stop!
All your strength! All your power!
All your love! Everythin' you've got!
You trained this fool. He's a disgrace.
Listen to them...
Our people cheer for HIM! You idiot.
WIN!
Nyet!
I fight to win!
For me!
To win you gotta knock him out! Punch
and punch till you can't punch no more!
- This is your whole life here!
- Yeah, knock him out, Rocko.
Do it now! Now!
- There's the bell. The war is on.
- This is the last round.
To the end.
Which of these magnificent fighters
will be standing at the end?
Drago snaps out a stiff jab. And another.
Rocky taking punishment. Trying to get
inside. He's completely exhausted.
Come on, Rock! What are you waitin' for?!
Rocky! Rocky!
Hit him!
Come on! Fight!
Balboa is chopping the Russian down!
Rocky Balboa throwing
punches at the Russian.
And Drago throws a hard right hand
that stuns Rocky Balboa!
Don't go down! Don't go down!
Forget technique, forget strategy.
This is a street fight. Who wants it most?
- What is he doin'?!
- He's winnin'!
To the body! To the body!
Rocko, knock his head off!
You're gonna do it!
Ivan!
Four!
Rocky Balboa has done the impossible!
And these people love him!
It is absolute pandemonium!
More than ever, Rocky has
proven himself a true champion!
Rocky! Rocky!
Thank you.
I came here tonight,
and I didn't know what to expect.
I seen... a lot of people hatin' me,
and... I didn't know
what to feel about that, so... I guess
I didn't like you much none either.
Durin' this... fight...
I seen a lot of changin'.
The way... youse felt about me,
and the way I felt... about you.
In here, there were two guys...
killin' each other, but I guess...
that's better than 20 million.
What I'm tryin' to say is...
that if I can change...
and you can change,
everybody can change!
Excuse me!
I just wanna say one thing to my kid,
who should be home sleepin'.
Merry Christmas, kid!
I love you!
~ Silent darkness
creeps into your soul ~
~ And removes the light of self-control ~
~ The cage that holds
you captive has no doors ~
~ Burnin' with determination ~
~ To even out the score ~
~ Heart's on fire ~
~ Strong desire ~
~ Rages deep within ~
~ Heart's on fire ~
~ Fever's risin' high ~
~ The moment of truth draws near ~
~ Time will not allow you to stand still ~
~ No ~
~ Silence breaks the heart
and bends the will ~
~ Revenge and guilty passions
are your swords ~
~ Rules and regulations ~
~ Have no meaning anymore ~
~ Heart's on fire ~
~ Strong desire ~
~ Rages deep within ~
~ Heart's on fire ~
~ Fever's risin' high ~
~ The moment of truth is here ~
~ Oh! ~
~ It's here ~
~ Oh, yeah! ~
~ Heart's on fire ~
~ Strong desire ~
~ Rages deep within ~
Visiontext subtitles: Paul Murray