Dearest,
I feel certain
that I am going mad again.
I feel we can't
go through another of these
terrible times,
and I shan't recover
this time.
I begin to hear voices
and can't concentrate.
so I am doing what seems
to be the best thing to do.
You have given me the greatest
possible happiness.
You have been, in every way.
All that anyone could be.
I know that I am spoiling
your life
and without me,
you could work.
And you will.
I know.
You see, I can't even
write this properly.
What I want to say
is that I owe all the happiness
of my life to you.
You have been entirely
patient with me.
And...
incredibly good.
Everything has gone from me,
but the certainty
of your goodness.
I can't go on spoiling
your life any longer.
I don't think two people
could have been happier
than we have been.
Virginia.
- Good morning, Doctor.
- Mr. Woolf.
No worse, I think.
I see.
The main thing is to keep her
where she is. Keep her calm.
Friday, then.
- Good morning, Leonard.
- Good morning, Virginia.
How was your sleep?
Uneventful.
- The headaches?
- No.
No headaches.
Doctor seemed pleased.
- Tha's all from this morning?
- Yes.
This young man has submitted
his manuscript.
I've found three errors
of fact
And two spelling mistakes,
And I'm not yet
on page four.
Have you had breakfast?
Yes.
Liar.
Virginia,is not at my
insistence,is your own doctor's.
I'm going to send Nelly up
with some fruit and a bun.
Right, lunch, then.
Proper lunch, husband and wife
sitting down together,
soup
pudding and all.
By force, if necessary.
Leonard, I believe I may have
a first sentence.
Work, then.
Then you must eat.
Mrs Dalloway said
she would buy the flowers
herself.
Mrs Dalloway said she would buy
the flowers herself.
sally, I think I'll buy
the flowers myself.
What?
What flowers?
shit, I'd forgotten.
You're never gonna be a big boy
if you don't eat your breakfast.
You're gonna be the big brother,
i's a very important job.
Happy birthday.
- Morning, honey.
- Dan...
Roses, on your own birthday.
You're too much really.
Well, he'll eat it now
that you're here.
I's your birthday, you shouldn't
be out buying me flowers.
Well, you were still sleeping.
so?
Well, we decided it
would be bette
if we let you sleep
in a little. Didn't we?
Good morning, bug.
You know, you need to rest, Laura.
You're only four months away.
I'm fine.
I'm just tired.
I've been telling him
he's gotta eat his breakfast.
Tha's true.
so,is a beautiful day.
What are you two going
to be doing with it?
We've got our plans.
Don't we?
What plans?
Well, it wouldn't be much
Of a party
would it, if I told you
every detail in advance?
Well, I'd better just stop asking
questions, then, huh?
Is that the time?
I'd better get going.
- Have a good day.
- You, too.
- Happy birthday.
- Thank you.
You need to finish your breakfast.
You know, I'm gonna make a cake.
Tha's what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna make the cake for daddy's
birthday.
Mommy, can I help?
Can I help make the cake?
Of course you can, sweet pea.
I'm not gonna do anything
without you.
No, of course,
you have to come.
Of course.
Well, I always wanted you,
and everybody involved
in the actual ceremony.
I don't know.
Around sixty.
Well, it will. I'll mean so much...
The whole occasion.
I's the least I can do to
have a nice dinner
and say thank you to everybody.
Oh, I take that as a yes.
- Oh my God.
- Oh, tha's great. I'm thrilled.
- What if nobody comes?
- This is Clarissa Vaughan.
Yes, I am just confirming that you're
sending the car to pick me up first.
- Hi, Clarissa.
- Hi. Can't talk.
And then we're going
over to 679, Hudson...
which is at 9th
and 14th.
Then you will take me uptown
and you will wait for us.
And I'll be over at seven.
Flowers.
What a beautiful morning.
Hi, Clarissa.
How are you?
I'm having a party. My friend
Richarďs won the Carrouthers.
Well, tha's just terrific.
If I knew what it was.
I's a poetry prize.
For a life's work.
I's the most prestigious. For a
poet,is the best you can do.
Very good. so, what would you like?
The lilies are perfect.
No, too morbid...
Hydrangeas, I think.
And...
le's just have buckets
of roses. And...
I think I'm gonna take these
with me.
Okay.
Thank you.
I actually tried
to read Richarďs novel.
You did?
Oh, I know.
I's not easy.
It did take him ten years to write.
Maybe it just takes
another ten to read.
-is you, isn't it?
- What is?
In the novel?
Oh, I see.
Yeah.
sort of...
I mean, in a way.
Richarďs a writer.
He uses things which actually happen.
Yeah.
And, years ago, he and I were
students, tha's true,
but, then he changes things.
Oh, sure.
I don't mean in a bad way.
I's more like...
he makes them his own.
A woman's whole life
in a single day.
Just one day.
And in that day
her whole life.
This is what we need:
shortening...
Mrs Dalloway,is you.
Yes,is me!
- Oh,is me.
- Come in.
Richard,
i's a beautiful morning.
How about we let
in a little more light?
Is it still morning?
- Yes, it is.
- Have I died?
Good morning, my dear.
- Any visitors?
- Yes.
Are they still here?
No, they've gone.
- How did they look?
- Today?
sort of like black fire.
I mean, sort of light
and dark at the same time.
There was one a bit like an
electrified jellyfish.
They were singing...
It may have been Greek.
so the ceremony is at five...
Do you remember?
And then, the party
is right after.
They did bring you breakfast,
didn't they?
What a question.
Of course.
Richard, you did eat it?
Well, can you see it?
Is it here?
Is there any breakfast
- lying around?
- No, I don't see it.
Well then, I must have eaten it,
mustn't I?
- I suppose.
- Does it matter?
Of course it matters.
You know what the doctors say.
Have you been skipping pills?
- Clarissa, I can't take this.
- Take what?
Having to be proud and brave
in front of everybody.
Oh, honey,is not
a performance.
Of course it is. I got the prize
for my performance.
I got the prize for having AIDs and
going nuts and being brave about it.
I actually got the prize for
having come through.
I's not true.
- For surviving.
-is not true.
Oh, you think they would have
given it to me if I were healthy?
Yes, as a matter of fact, I do.
Is it here somewhere?
- What?
- The prize. I'd like to look at it.
No, you haven't gotten it yet.
-is tonight.
- Are you sure?
I remember the ceremony perfectly.
I seem to have fallen
out of time.
Richard...
I's a party
I's only a party.
Populated entirely by people
who respect and admire you.
small party, is it?
select party, is it?
Your friends.
I thought I lost all my friends.
I thought I drove them crazy.
Jesus.
"Oh, Mrs Dalloway,
always giving parties
to cover the silence.
Richard...
You won't need to do anything.
All you have to do is appear.
sit on the sofa.
And I will be there.
This is a group of people
who want to tell you
your work is going to live.
Oh, is it? Is my work going
to live?
I can't go through
with it, Clarissa.
- Why do you say that?
- I can't.
Why?
8ecause I wanted
to be a writer, tha's all.
so?
I wanted to write about it all.
Everything that happens
in a moment.
The way the flowers looked when you
carried them in your arms,
this towel, how it smells,
how it feels, this thread.
All our feelings,
yours and mine.
The history of it...
Who we once were.
Everything in the world.
Everything all mixed up.
Likeis all mixed up now.
And I failed at it.
I failed.
No matter what you start with, it
ends up being so much less.
sheer fucking prid
and stupidity.
We want everything,
don't we?
I suppose we do.
You kissed me on a beach.
Yeah.
Do you remember...
how many years ago?
Of course I...
What did you want... then?
Come closer.
I'm right here.
Come closer would you, please?
Take my hand.
Would you be angry...
Would I be angry if you didn't show
up at the party?
Would you be angry if I died?
If you died?
Who is this party for?
What do you mean, who is it for?
What are you asking?
- What are you trying to say?
- I'm not trying to say anything.
I'm saying
I think I'm only staying alive
to satisfy you.
Well?
That is what we do.
That is what people do.
They stay alive
for each other.
And the doctors told you:
You don't need to die.
They told you that.
You can
- live like this for years.
- Well, exactly.
I don't accept this.
I don't accept what you're saying.
Andis for you to decide,
is it?
How long have you been doing that?
How many years...
coming to the apartment?
What about your own life?
What about sally?
Just wait till I die, then
you'll have to think of yourself.
How are you going to like that?
Richard.
It would be great if you did
come to the party.
If you felt well enough
to come.
Just to let you know, I am making
the crab thing.
Not that I imagine it makes any
difference to you.
Of course it makes a difference.
I love the crab thing.
Clarissa!
Yes?
I'll be back at three-thirty
and I'll help you get dressed.
Wonderful.
Three-thirty.
I's on this day,
this day of all days,
her fate becomes clear to her.
Excuse me, Mrs Woolf,
Mr Woolf said I was to come
and speak with you.
I've nearly finished, Nelly.
Please attend me in the kitchen,
I'll be down very soon.
she says she wants something,
then it turns out she doesn't.
Well, she never does, does she?
she never wants anything.
Especially when she's particularly
asked for it. Tha's a sure sign.
- I wish I'd been there.
- I wish you had too.
Did you give her that look?
That sort of look you do?
I said, "Madam..."
Yes, Nelly, tell me,
- how can I help?
-is about lunch.
I just had to go ahead
on my own.
I understand.
You chose a pie?
I chose a lamb pie.
That seems suitable.
You being so busy
with your writing.
I had no instructions.
You do remember that my sister
is coming at four with the children?
Yes, ma'am, I hadn't forgotten.
China tea, I think.
And ginger.
Ginger, madam?
I'd like to give the children
a treat.
We'd have to go to London
for ginger, madam.
I haven't finished this, and there's
the rest of lunch to get ready.
The twelve-thirty train, Nelly, will
get you into London just after one.
If you return on the two-thirty,
you should be back
in Richmond soon after three.
Do I miscalculate?
No.
Well, then, is something
detaining you, Nelly?
I can't think of anything more
exhilarating than a trip to London.
- Good morning, Mrs Woolf.
- Good morning.
We shall publish no more
new authors.
I have to tell you
I have discovered ten errors
in the first proof.
Lucky to have found them.
Paschendale was a charnel-house
from which no min returned.
Do you thinkis possible that bad
writing actually attracts
a higher incidence
of error?
Ifis all right, I thought I
might take a short walk.
Not far?
No, just for air.
Go then.
If I could walk mid-morning
I'd be a happy man.
she'll die.
she's going to die.
Tha's wha's going to happen.
Tha's it.
she'll kill herself.
she'll kill herself over something
that doesn't seem to matter.
Le's think.
You grease the pan, mommy.
I know you grease the pan,
sweet one.
Even mommy knows that.
This is what we're gonna do.
Flour,
bowl,
sifter.
Can I do it, mommy?
Can you sift the flour?
Yes, you can sift the flour, baby,
if tha's what makes you happy.
There.
Isn't it beautiful?
Don't you think it looks like snow?
Okay. Now,
the next thing
I'm gonna show you...
is...
we measure out the cups.
Mommy, it isn't that difficult.
No, I know it isn't difficult.
I's just that I...
- just wanna do this for daddy.
- Becauseis his birthday?
Tha's right.
We're baking the cake to show
him that we love him.
Otherwise he won't know
we love him?
Tha's right.
I got all the stuff.
I'm going right out again.
My God, what a zoo.
Why do people have to talk about dry
cleaning? What is there to talk about?
I bought you some flowers.
Where are you?
In here.
I got someone at work
to cover me.
I'll be with you all night.
Are you all right?
sure.
I guess you saw Richard.
Tha's right.
Well, of course.
I bet he said,
"Oh by the way, honey,
do you mind,
can I skip the party?".
- Don't worry, he always shows up.
- Oh, sure.
In the end.
What, Richard miss an award? A
chance to talk about his work?
I don't think so.
He'll show up.
You did the seating.
I did.
I don't believe it,
Louis Waters?
Is Louis coming?
Richarďs Louis?
He is.
You put him next to me.
Why do I always have
to sit next to the exes?
And, anyway, shouldn't the exes
have a table of their own
where they can all 'ex'
together
in exquisite agony?
I'm off.
Try not to pass out from
excitement.
Clarissa...is going to be
beautiful.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Why is everything wrong?
It didn't work, dammit.
- Hey, scott.
- Hi, Mrs Dryer.
There's someone at the door!
Hello?
Laura?
- Hi, Kitty.
- Hi. Am I interrupting?
- Of course not. Come in.
- Are you all right?
Why, sure.
Hi, Richie.
sit down, I've got coffee on.
- Would you like some?
- Please.
Look, you made a cake.
I know.
It didn't work.
I thought it was gonna work.
I thought it would work better
than that.
Oh, Laura, I don't understand
why you find it so difficult.
I mean, anyone can make a cake.
- I know.
I's ridiculously easy.
Like I bet you didn't
even grease the pan.
I greased the pan.
All right.
But,
you have other virtues.
And Dan loves you so much
he won't even notice.
Whatever you do, he's gonna say
i's wonderful.
Well,is true.
Does Ray have a birthday?
- sure he does.
- When is it?
september.
We always go
to the country club.
We drink Martinis and spend the day
with fifty people.
Ray's got a lot of friends.
He does.
You both have a lot of friends.
You're good at it.
How is Ray? I haven't seen him in
a while.
Ray's fine.
These guys are something,
aren't they?
You can say that again.
They came home from the war...
they deserved it, didn't they?
After what they'd been through.
What... did they deserve?
I don't know.
Us, I guess.
All this.
You're reading a book.
Yeah.
Wha's this one about?
I's about...
this woman who's incredibly...
...well, she's a hostess
and she's incredibly confident.
And she's going to give a party.
And maybe because she's confident,
everyone thinks she's fine.
8ut she isn't.
so...
Well...
Kitty, what is it?
Is something wrong?
I have to go into the hospital
for a couple of days.
Yeah, I have...
some kind of growth
in my uterus,
and they're gonna go in
and take a look.
When?
This afternoon.
I need you to feed the dog.
Of course.
Is that what you came here to ask?
What did the doctor say, exactly?
Well,is probably what the
trouble's been...
About getting pregnant.
The thing is
I mean, you know, I've been...
really happy with Ray.
And now it turns out
there was a reason
I couldn't conceive.
You're lucky, Laura.
I don't think you can call yourself
a woman until you're a mother.
I mean, the joke is
all my life I could do
everything.
I could do anything, really.
Except the one thing I wanted.
Yes.
Tha's all.
Well, at least now they'll be
able to deal with it.
Tha's what they're doing.
I'm not worried. What would be
the point of worrying?
No,is not in your hands.
Well, tha's it.
I's in the hands of some physician
I've never even met.
some surgeon who
probably drinks more Martinis
than Ray, and,
I mean, of course I'm worried
about Ray.
- Come here.
- I'm doing fine.
- Really.
- I know. I know you are.
No. I'm more worried about Ray,
he's not good with this stuff.
Forget about Ray.
Just forget about Ray.
You're sweet.
You know the routine, right?
Half a can in the evening, and
check the water now and then,
Ray will feed him in the
morning.
Kitty, you didn't mind?
What?
I didn't mind what?
Do you want me to drive you?
I think I'll feel better
if I drive myself.
Kitty,is gonna be all right.
Of course it is.
Bye.
What?
What do you want?
Mr Woolf, Mrs 8ell has arrived.
she's not due till four.
Well, I can't help that.
she's here.
You look a perfect angel.
Don't let the boys make fun
of you.
Fly away.
Virginia.
Leonard thinksis the end
of civilisation,
people who are invited at four
and arrive at two-thirty.
Oh God!
Barbarians.
We finished lunch sooner
than we imagined.
I've had to send Nelly off
to London for sugared ginger.
Oh, Virginia...
you're not still frightened
of the servants, are you?
Come on.
And how are you, sister?
Frantic.is been ridiculous
in London.
Ridiculous how?
Busy.
Why is busy ridiculous?
I would have invited you
to our party...
- but I knew you wouldn't come.
- Did you? How did you know that?
I thought you never came to town.
Tha's because
you no longer ask me.
Are you not forbidden to come?
Do the doctors not forbid it?
Oh, the doctors...
Do you not pay heed
to your doctors?
Not when they're a bunch
of contemptible Victorians.
What are you saying?
Are you feeling better?
Has this vastness made you
stronger?
I'm saying, Vanessa, that even
crazy people like to be asked.
Nessa, Nessa!
Hello, changelings.
What have you got?
- What have you found?
- We've found a bird.
- Did you?
- Yes.
Where did you find that?
I think it must have fallen
from a tree.
Oh my goodness,
just look at him.
We might be able to save him.
save him?
I think you have to be careful,
Quentin.
There's a time to die...
...and it may be the birďs time.
Come on, le's pick some grass
to make a grave.
- Oh, Julian.
- I'm just saying.
Then at least there'll be
a bed for him to die on.
Come on, Nessa,
le's make a grave.
- Nessa, come on.
- Nessa, hurry up.
Oh God. Oh, very well,
I'm coming. Wait for me then.
Angelica, will you be all right?
stay with your aunt.
You're going too fast.
Look, Julian, over here.
Do you think she'd like roses?
Is it a she?
Yes, the females are larger.
And less colourful.
What happens when we die?
What happens?
We return to the place
that we came from.
I don't remember
where I came from.
Nor do I.
she looks very small.
Yes, tha's one
of the things that happens.
We look smaller.
But very peaceful.
We found you.
Nessa, where were you?
Come on, Nessa, le's go.
Is it done?
Have you finished?
- Is the bird funeral complete?
- Yes.
Very well then.
Are we to be denied tea altogether
for coming so early?
No, of course not.
Come on, Angelica.
Come on, boys.
Le's have some tea.
Nessa, tell him to stop it.
Oh, stop it, Julian.
Virginia?
We're going in.
Virginia!
Hey, bug...
I've got this idea.
We're gonna make another cake.
We're gonna make a better one.
What happened to the first one?
And after that,
I think we should go out.
Yes?
Clarissa,is Louis.
- Louis Waters.
- Louis?
Oh my God. You're early.
Do you mind? Is it all right?
Why should I mind?
I'm delighted.
Well now.
- I feel like I'm interrupting.
- Oh, why? No.
Well, I know the ceremony isn't until
five, but I flew in this morning.
Richarďs going to be thrilled.
- He'll be thrilled to see you.
- You think so?
Of course.
What are we doing?
We should go in.
Are you all right?
Yes.is nothing.
I's just the party.
Oh, right.
Oh,is looking beautiful.
Thanks.
Are you still with?
Yes, I am still with her.
Ten years.
I's crazy.
Why is it crazy?
No reason. Would you like
something to drink?
some water.
And you're still an editor?
Oh, sure.
With the same publisher?
How's san Francisco?
I's one of those cities
people tell you to like.
Richard said he thought
you were happy out there.
Oh, great. so now the illness
makes him psychic.
You have to prepare yourself,
Louis.
He's very changed.
I read the book.
- Oh God.
- Exactly.
I thought you were meant to do more
than just change people's names.
Isn't it meant to be fiction?
He even had you living
- on 10th street.
- It isn't me.
Isn't it?
You know how Richard is.
I's a fantasy.
A whole chapter on 'should she
buy some nail polish'?
And then, guess what?
After fifty pages she doesn't.
The whole thing seems to go on
for eternity. Nothing happens.
And then wham - for no reason,
she kills herself.
His mother kills herself.
Yeah, sure, his mother,
but still for no reason.
Out of the blue.
I know the book is tough,
but I liked it.
I know.
Only one thing upset me.
Wha's that?
That there wasn't more
about you.
Tha's kind.
I went back to Wellfleet.
- You did?
- One day.
I didn't tell you?
No.
But then I never see you.
You remember the house?
-is still there.
- I think you're courageous.
Courageous? Why?
To dare
go visit.
What I mean
is to face the fact
that we have lost
those feelings for ever.
I don't know wha's happening.
I'm sorry.
I seem to be in some strange sort
of mood.
I'm sorry,is very rude
of me.
I seem to be unravelling.
- I shouldn't have come.
- No,is not you.
I's more like having a presentiment.
Do you know what I'm saying?
Oh God,is probably
just nerves about the party.
Bad hostess.
Clarissa, wha's happening?
Jesus.
What is it?
Oh God.
Do you want me to go?
No, don't go. Don't.
Don't go. Explain to me
why this is happening.
Don't...
Don't touch me.
I's better if you don't.
I's just too much.
You fly in from san Francisco,
and I've been nursing Richard
for years
and all that time
I've held myself together.
- No problem.
- I know.
One morning,
in Wellfleet,
you were there,
we were all there,
I'd been sleeping with him,
and I was out on the back porch.
He came out behind me,
and he put his hand
on my shoulder.
"Good morning, Mrs Dalloway."
Tha's...
from then
on I've been stuck.
stuck?
Yeah.
With the name, I mean.
And now you walk in.
To see you
walk in...
Because I never see you.
Look at you.
Anyway...
It doesn't matter.
It was you he stayed with.
It was you he lived with.
I had one summer.
The day I left him,
I got on a train
and made my way across Europe.
I felt free for the first time
in years.
so, tell me about san Francisco.
Wha's to tell?
I still teach drama to idiots.
Mostly.
They can't all be idiots.
No. No. In fact...
I shouldn't
tell you this...
I've fallen in love.
- Really?
- Yes.
- With a student.
Exactly. I know.
You...
You think: "Am I still up for
this?". All this intensity,
all those arguments.
Doors being slammed. Well, you
know whatis like.
Are you feeling better?
A little.
Thank you.
You think I'm ridiculous?
Ridiculous?
Fortunate... too.
I'm gonna leave you at Mrs Latch's.
I have to do something.
Mommy, I don't wanna go.
You have to.
I'm sorry. I have something
to do before daddy gets home.
Hello.
Hi, Mrs Latch,
My boy's not very happy.
Mommy,
I don't wanna do this.
I have to go, honey.
Your mommy has things to do.
Come in, I got cookies.
Okay, baby?
You have to be brave now.
Don't worry now,
he's gonna be fine.
Come on.
Honey.
Come on, darling.
Mommy!
- stop it.
- No!
Mommy!
- Mommy!
- Come inside.
Come on.
No!
Breakfast
is served between seven
and eleven in the Regency Room.
And room service is available
twenty-four hours.
Thank you, ma'am.
- Is there anything else you need?
- Yes.
No...
Not to be disturbed.
Did it matter, then,
she asked herself,
walking toward Bond street,
did it matter that she must
inevitably,
cease completely
all this must go on
without her...
Did she resent it
or did it not
become consoling
to believe that death
ended absolutely?
It is possible to die.
There was a lovely coat for Angelica
at Harrods, then nothing for the boys,
and it seemed so unfair.
Why should Angelica be favoured?
Virginia?
What are you thinking about?
Are you still with us?
Your aun's a very lucky woman,
Angelica,
because she has two lives.
she has the life she's leading,
and also the book
she's writing.
This makes her
very fortunate indeed.
What were you thinking about?
I was going to kill my heroine.
But...
I've changed my mind.
I can't.
I fear I may have to kill someone
else instead.
Quentin, I'm dropping them.
We're ready.
- Mind the shopping.
- I am minding the shopping.
It was a fascinating visit.
And they enjoyed it thoroughly.
Do you have to go already?
I do wish you wouldn't go.
The last thing you want
is our noisiness.
My hopeless,
clumsy boys.
- say goodbye, boys.
- Bye.
And you'll return to what?
Tonight?
Just some
insufferable dinner
that not even you could envy,
Virginia.
But I do.
say something, Nessa.
Didn't you think I seemed better?
Yes, Virginia, you seem better.
You think?
You think I may one day escape?
One day. One.
Nessa.
Come on, Nessa.
Come, Angelica, we must go.
Come on.
Goodbye.
Goodbye, little girl.
Angelica, the train.
We're gonna miss the train.
Come on,
I wanna go home.
We've stayed too long,
we've missed the train.
stay close.
I'm sorry, I know.
I tried to get here earlier.
Don't start.
I know,is incredibly
important becauseis your party.
Julia...
- How have you been doing?
- I'm fine.
Come here.
What have you been doing?
Well, studying, mom.
so, what should I do?
Chairs?
No, le's clear the desk first.
We can take it
into the bedroom.
I bumped into Louis Waters.
Oh, you did? Where?
In the street.
They're all here, aren't they?
All the ghosts.
All the ghosts are assembling
for the party.
He's so weird.
Oh, what?
You can't see that?
You can't see that
Louis Waters is weird?
I can see that he's sad.
Well,
all your friends are sad.
You've been crying.
Wha's happening?
All it is
I looked around this room,
and I thought:
"I'm giving a party. All I
wanna do is give a party".
And?
He does it deliberately.
Is this Richard?
He did it this morning.
He gives me that look.
What look?
To say:
"Your life is trivial.
You are so trivial".
Just
daily stuff, schedules
and parties and details.
Tha's what he means by it.
That is what he's saying.
Mom, it only matters
if you thinkis true.
Well?
Do you? Tell me.
When I'm with him I feel
yes, I am living.
And when I'm not with him,
yes, everything does seem
sort of...
silly.
I don't mean with you. I...
God. Jesus.
Never with you.
I's all the rest of it.
sally?
The rest of it.
False comfort.
Because?
If you say to me
"When were you happiest?",
"Tell me the moment
you were happiest..."
I know, it was years ago.
Yeah.
All you're saying is
you were once young.
I remember one morning
getting up at dawn.
There was such a sense
of possibility.
You know?
That feeling?
And I remember thinking
to myself:
"so this is the beginning
of happiness.
This is where it starts. And, of
course, there'll always be more."
It never occurred to me
it wasn't the beginning.
It was happiness.
It was 'the momen'.
Right then.
Nelly, good evening. I was
wondering if you'd seen Mrs Woolf.
I thought you knew,
sir. Mrs Woolf has gone out.
Excuse me, excuse me.
Very kind, sir, thank you.
Papers.
Mr Woolf, what
an unexpected pleasure.
Perhaps you could tell me exactly
what you think you're doing?
What I was doing?
I went to look for you
and you weren't there.
You were working in the garden.
I didn't wish to disturb you.
You disturb me when you disappear.
I didn't disappear.
- I went for a walk.
- A walk?
Is that all, just a walk?
We must go home now.
Nelly's cooking dinner. she's
already had a very difficult day.
I's our obligation
to eat Nelly's dinner.
There is no such obligation.
No such obligation exists.
Virginia, you have an obligation
to your own sanity.
I've endured this custody.
I've endured this imprisonment.
Oh, Virginia! I am attended
by doctors, everywhere.
I am attended by doctors who inform
me of my own interests.
They know your interests.
They do not speak
for my interests.
I can see that it must be hard
for a woman of your...
Of my what exactly?
Your talents,
to see that she may not be the
best judge of her own condition.
Who then is a better judge?
You have a history!
You have a history of confinement.
We brought you to Richmond because
you've a history of fits,
moods,
blackouts,
hearing voices.
We brought you here to save you
from the irrevocable damage you
intended upon yourself.
You've tried
to kill yourself twice!
I live daily with that threat.
I set up the press,
we set up the printing press
not just for itself,
not just purely for itself,
but so that you might have
a ready source of absorption
and of remedy.
Like needlework?
It was done for you!
It was done
for your betterment!
It was done out of love!
If I didn't know you better,
I'd call this ingratitude.
I am ungrateful?
You call me ungrateful?
My life has been stolen from me.
I'm living in a town I have
no wish to live in. I'm living
a life I have no wish
to live.
How did this happen?
It is time for us
to move back to London.
I miss London.
I miss London life.
This is not you speaking,
Virginia.
This is an aspect
of your illness.
I's not you.
It is my voice.
It is mine and mine alone.
It is the voice that you hear.
It is not, it is mine!
I'm dying in this town!
If you were thinking clearly,
Virginia, you'd recall
it was London
that brought you low.
If I were thinking clearly?
If I were thinking clearly.
We brought you
to Richmond to give you peace.
If I were thinking clearly,
Leonard, I would tell you
that I wrestle alone in the
dark, in the deep dark,
and that only I can know,
only I can understand
my own condition.
You live with the threat
of my extinction.
Leonard,
I live with it too.
This is my right.
It is the right
of every human being.
I choose not the suffocating
anaesthetic of the suburbs,
but the violent jolt of the
capital. That is my choice.
The meanest patient,
even the very lowest
is allowed some say
in the matter
of her own prescription.
Thereby she defines her humanity.
I wish for your sake,
I could be happy
in this quietness.
8ut if it is a choice
between Richmond and death
I choose death.
Very well. London, then.
We go back to London.
Are you hungry?
I'm a little hungry myself.
Come along.
The London train on platform one.
This is the London train
terminating at Vauxhall.
You cannot find peace by avoiding
life, Leonard.
This is the London train.
This is the London train
on platform one.
Mommy!
Hey there, bug.
Wha's wrong?
Hi, Mrs Latch.
sorry I'm late.
He's fine. He's been fine.
He's just happy to see you.
It couldn't have been
that bad, could it?
so you got it cut, then?
Yes. No problem.
Looks great.
They didn't have
to do very much.
Well, we had a fine time
together.
Thank you very much.
so that wasn't too bad,
was it?
I wasn't gone too long.
No, you weren't long.
Tha's right.
At one point,
I don't know,
there was a moment
where I thought I might be longer.
But I changed my mind.
What is it, honey?
Mommy, I love you.
I love you too, baby.
Wha's wrong?
What?
Don't worry, honey,
everything's fine.
We're gonna have a wonderful party.
And we've made your daddy
such a nice cake.
I love you, sweetheart.
You're my guy.
Mommy!
Richard,is me.
I'm early.
What the hell is going on here?
What are you doing here?
You're early.
What is going on here?
What are you doing?
I had this wonderful idea.
I needed to let in some light!
Richard, what are you doing?
I had this fantastic notion.
I took the Xanax and the Ritalin
together. It had never occurred to me.
Don't come near me!
It seemed to me I needed
to let in some light.
What do you think?
I cleared away all the windows.
All right, Richard, do me one
simple favour. Come...
Come.
I don't think I can make it
to the party, Clarissa.
You don't have to go to the party.
You don't have to go to the ceremony.
You don't have to do anything you
don't want to do.
You can do as you like.
But I still have
to face the hours, don't I?
I mean, the hours
after the party.
And the hours after that.
You do have good days still,
you know you do.
Not really.
I mean,is kind of
you to say so, butis not
really true.
- Are they here?
- Who?
The voices?
The voices are always here.
Andis the voices that
you're hearing now, isn't it?
No, no...
Mrs Dalloway,is you.
I've stayed alive for you.
But now you have to let me go.
- Richard, I...
- No, wait.
Wait.
Tell me a story.
What about?
Tell me a story from your day.
I got up...
Yes?
...and I went out. And...
I went to buy flowers. Like
Mrs Dalloway in the book, you know?
Yes.
And it was a beautiful morning.
Was it?
Yes, it was so beautiful.
It was so fresh.
- Oh, fresh, was it?
- Yes.
Like a...
Like a morning on the beach?
- Yes.
- Like that?
Yes.
Like that morning when you walked
out of that old house and you were...
You were eighteen and maybe
I was nineteen.
Yes.
I was nineteen years old
and I'd never seen anything
so beautiful.
You coming out of a glass door in
the early morning, still sleepy.
Isn't it strange?
The most ordinary morning
in anybody's life.
I'm afraid I can't make it
to the party, Clarissa.
The party
doesn't matter.
You've been so good to me,
Mrs Dalloway.
I love you.
I don't think two people could have
been happier than we've been.
Oh God, no!
Happy birthday.
- Happy birthday, Dan.
- This is perfect.
This is just perfect.
Do you think so?
- Do you really think so?
- Why, sure.
- You must have been working all day.
- Well, tha's what we were doing.
Weren't we, bug?
We were working all day.
This is just fantastic.
I's what I've always wanted.
One day, Richie, I'll tell you
how it all happened.
Don't.
I want to. I wanna tell him
the story.
What happened
when I was in the war, at war
I found myself
thinking about this girl
I'd seen.
I'd never met her
at high school.
This strange,
fragile-looking girl
named Laura McGrath.
Yeah.
And she was shy.
And she was interesting.
And well, your mother won't
mind if I tell you this, Richie,
she was the sort of girl that
you see sitting mostly on her own.
And, I tell you
sometimes when I was in the
south Pacific,
the fact is, that I used
to think about this girl.
Dan...
I used to think about bringing her
to a house,
to a life,
pretty much like this.
And it was the thought
of the happiness,
the thought of this woman,
the thought of this life,
tha's what kept me going.
I had an idea of our happiness.
Why does someone have
to die?
Leonard?
In your book. You said
someone had to die.
Why?
Is that a stupid question?
No.
I imagine my question
is stupid.
Not at all.
Well?
someone has to die in order that
the rest of us should value life more.
I's contrast.
And who will die?
Tell me.
The poet will die.
The visionary.
What are you doing?
I'm brushing my teeth.
Are you coming to bed?
Yeah, in a minute.
Come to bed, Laura Brown.
I ran into Ray. He said Kitty
had to go to the hospital.
I know.
It was nothing serious, he said.
Just a check-up.
I'm terrified.
Why?
The idea she could disappear.
Maybe you could go see her
in the morning, honey.
I was going to.
I was gonna stop by.
I've had a wonderful day.
And I have you to thank.
Come to bed, honey.
I'm coming.
so are you coming?
Yes.
What?
I was hoping you were going
to bed.
I am...
I am going to bed.
What, then?
All else is clear.
The outline of the story is
planned. Now one thing only.
Mrs Dalloway's destiny
must be resolved.
You're Laura Brown.
Yes. I'm Richarďs mother.
Of course.
I'm Clarissa Vaughan.
Please, come in.
My friend sally
is in the kitchen.
And my daughter.
I'll take this.
We were having a party.
We were going to have a party.
I was lucky, I got the last plane
from Toronto.
so tha's the monster.
I hope I did the right thing.
I found your number
in his phone book.
Yes, he had it.
We didn't speak often.
I's a terrible thing,
Ms Vaughan,
to outlive your whole family.
Richarďs father died.
Yes, he died
of cancer quite young...
And Richarďs sister is dead.
Obviously you feel unworthy.
It gives you feelings...
of unworthiness.
You survive and they don't.
Have you read the poems?
Oh, yes.
I also read the novel.
You see,
people say the novel's
difficult.
I know.
They say that.
He had me die in the novel.
I know why he did that.
It hurt, of course, I can't
pretend it didn't hurt. But I...
I know why he did it.
You left Richard,
when he was a child.
I left both my children.
I abandoned them.
They sayis the worst thing
a mother can do.
Yeah.
You have a daughter.
Yes.
But I never met Julia's father.
You so wanted a child?
Tha's right.
You're a lucky woman.
There are times
when you don't belong
and you think you're going
to kill yourself.
Once I went to a hotel...
Later that night I made a plan.
The plan was I would leave
my family
when my second child was born.
And tha's what I did.
I got up one morning,
made breakfast,
went to the bus-stop,
got on the bus.
I'd left a note.
I got a job in a library
in Canada.
It would
be wonderful
to say you regretted it.
It would be easy.
But what does it mean?
What does it mean to regret
when you have no choice?
I's what you can bear.
There it is.
No-one's going to forgive me.
It was death.
I chose life.
Time to take your coat off.
I thought you might
like a cup of tea.
Oh my goodness...
Thank you, dear.
I feel like I'm stealing
your room.
We put the food away, so if you're
at all hungry in the night,
- just help yourself.
- I will.
- Where will you sleep?
- Oh, the sofa.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Goodnight, sweetheart.
Goodnight.
Dear Leonard,
to look life in the face,
always to look life
in the face.
And to know it
for what it is.
At last,
to know it,
to love it,
for what it is.
And then,
to put it away.
Leonard,
always the years between us,
always the years,
always
the love,
the hours.