It was a long time ago.
Sometimes I can still
hear their voices
across Sally's woods.
There was Billy,
Steve, Tommy,
and the tall kid from
down the street... Joey.
Yeah, it was
Joey Walsh.
My best friend
was Timmy Burns
who lived two blocks
away from me.
We turned the woods
into a battlefield
and dreamed that someday
we would become men.
Did you hear it?
What?
Let's go, Timmy!
Let's go!
Come on, Major!
They've got to be
somewhere, Ronnie.
Watch out.
You've got to stay
in the ravine.
Shh.
Go! Go! Go!
Look, there they are!
Wipe them out!
Aah!
- Aah!
You're dead,
and you know it!
No, I'm not!
Ronnie's dead!
Look at the mayor.
I wonder where your mom is.
Where is that woman?
Hey!
Hi.
3 o'clock,
4 o'clock rock
5, 6, 7 o'clock
8 o'clock rock
9, 10, 11 o'clock,
12 o'clock rock
We're gonna rock
around the clock tonight
Put your glad rags on
And join me, hon
We'll have some fun
when the clock strikes 1:00
We're gonna rock around
the clock tonight
Donna!
Donna,
come back here!
Get out of the way!
Hey, you boys! Stop that!
When the band slows down
We're gonna yell for more
We're gonna rock around
the clock tonight
Donna! Donna!
Stevie Boyer
just gave Mary Barnett a ring.
Can you believe it?
Over there.
O.K.
Come here,
come here.
What is this?
Is this
a firecracker?
What's wrong with you?
Hey!
This is boring.
Yeah, square, man.
Look, Daddy,
the soldiers!
Happy birthday,
Ronnie Kovic.
For me?
Yes. Open it.
That's really
nice, Donna.
Say thank you,
Ronnie.
Thanks, Donna, but
you didn't have to.
Going to
the woods tonight?
They'll have
fireworks there.
Should be
a real blast.
Yeah, O.K.
What is it?
Open it.
Leave him alone.
Beautiful.
Hey, it's
the real thing, Ronnie.
Feel that.
Just like
Mickey Mantle, Ronnie.
Ain't he
a 4th of July firecracker
in that hat?
Yeah. He's my little
Yankee Doodle boy.
Hey, get it!
Get it!
Come on!
Let's go!
Did you like it?
I don't know.
Hey, look how many
push-ups I can do.
Wow! Yeah!
Yeah!
Come on, Ronnie!
Go, Ronnie, go!
Go, Ronnie!
You can do it!
Go!
Yes!
Yes! That's my boy!
That's my boy!
Yes!
Ronnie, you made it!
Yeah, all right!
Tommy! Ronnie!
Come on!
You're going to miss it!
Michelle! Barbara!
You've got to see this!
Not as a call
to bear arms,
though arms we need,
but a call
to bear the burden
of a long
twilight struggle,
a struggle against
the common enemies of man...
tyranny, poverty,
disease, and war itself.
You'll get a licking
if you're late!
In the long history
of the world,
only a few generations
have been granted the role
of defending freedom...
Look, President Kennedy,
Daddy.
That's right.
He's so handsome.
I do not shrink
from this responsibility,
I welcome it.
Let the word go forth
from this time and place
that the torch
has been passed
to a new generation
of Americans
born in this century.
Let every nation know
that we shall
pay any price,
bear any burden,
support any friend,
oppose any foe
to assure the survival
and the success
of liberty.
I had a dream, Ronnie,
the other night,
and you were speaking
to a large crowd
just like him.
Just like him.
And you were saying
great things.
And so,
my fellow Americans,
ask not what your country
can do for you,
ask what you can do
for your country.
Right! Right up!
Get out!
Got to get out!
You got to get out!
Hit that switch!
Hit the switch!
All right,
hit the ropes!
Go, go, go!
Hand over hand over hand!
Get those legs
off those ropes!
Come on, ladies,
let's come down!
Let's come down!
That rope is like life!
You grab it
and hang onto it! Next!
I want you to kill!
You hear me?
Yes, sir!
Kill!
I want that
conference championship!
Do you want that conference
championship?
Yes, sir!
Get up! Heads!
Get them up!
Do you hear me?
Get your heads up, ladies!
Get your heads up!
I want that
conference championship!
If you want to win,
you got to suffer!
You want to be the best?
You got to pay the price
for victory,
and the price is sacrifice!
Susanne, no homework
at the table, please.
No, Tommy.
After supper.
Dad?
Yeah?
Can I come
with you?
There's the next
conference champion.
Sorry I'm late, Ma.
There's rice
on the stove
and fruit
in the icebox.
I can't.
It's on your diet,
right?
I got to drop 3 pounds
by Saturday.
Your brother's
a hard worker, Tommy,
'cause he wants
to be the best.
Win or lose... in school,
in sports, in life...
as long
as you do your best,
that's what matters
to God.
Win or lose,
we still love him.
Can I go
to my room?
Yeah, sure.
Thank you, God,
for this food.
In the name of the Father,
the Son, the Holy Ghost, amen.
Daddy, Jimmy
took my doll!
I'll get the doll.
I hate his guts!
Just go to bed.
I didn't take anything!
Where's
your sister's doll?
Jackie? Why
is Jackie not in bed?
Ronnie.
Where'd
you get this?
Why are you
in my room?
Don't change
the subject.
I don't allow Playboy magazine
in this house.
Stevie gave it to me.
You have filthy,
impure thoughts!
God's going
to punish you.
I haven't even looked
at it yet, all right?
Go to confession. I want you
to tell Father McKenna.
I don't want to see
this filthy magazine
in my house again.
Now, take this away!
What's going on?
Nothing.
What do you mean,
nothing?
Nothing, Dad. O. K?
You're out of bounds, guys.
Back inside.
Come on, Kovic, back inside.
Come on, Kovic.
Go, Ronnie.
Kovic, back inside.
Come on, Kovic.
Back inside.
Let's go.
I want to see
some explosion!
Come on, Ronnie!
No messing around!
You're great, Ronnie!
Stay with him!
Come on down!
All right!
O.K. Get off
the mat.
You're going
to get...
Get him! Get him!
Reversal.
2 points!
All right!
Oh, yes, yes, yes,
yes, yes!
Ohh, you!
One, red!
You're both up.
All right, fresh start.
Fresh start.
Stand up.
Don't let him get you!
Don't
let him get you!
Pull him out!
All right!
Watch those legs.
Watch him!
Get him down!
Don't let him get the neck!
No! No!
No!
You can beat him,
Ronnie!
Come on! Come on!
Come on!
Ronnie, Ronnie, Ronnie!
Bridge! Bridge!
You can win!
Don't give up!
Aah!
Oh, no!
O.K., son?
Oh, no.
Come on. Get up.
Attention!
Forward march!
Left, left.
Left, right, left.
Seats!
Good morning.
I am Gunnery
Sergeant Hayes.
This is
Sergeant Bowers.
United States Marine Recruiting Station,
Levittown, New York.
We are here today
at the request of your principal
Mr Richards
and other members
of the faculty
to tell you a little bit
about the Marine Corps.
First off,
young men,
let's get
one thing straight.
Not everybody becomes
United States Marines.
We want the best,
and we'll accept nothing
but the best,
because there
is nothing prouder,
nothing finer, nothing
standing as straight
as a United States Marine.
Now, they've got the Army.
They got the Navy.
They got
the Air Farce.
And if you want
to join them,
be my guest.
But if you want
a challenge...
if you want to try
something difficult...
if you want to try to
achieve the impossible...
you try 13 weeks of hell
at Parris Island,
South Carolina,
and you'll find out
if you got what it takes.
You'll find out
if you really are a man,
then the Marines may be
what you're looking for.
Tarawa...
Iwo Jima...
Belleau Wood...
the frozen
Chosin Reservoir.
First to fight.
We have never lost a war.
We have always come when
our country's called us.
Now, Sergeant Bowers and I
would like to open this up
to questions.
So if any of you young men
do have questions,
go ahead
and raise your hands.
Come on, now.
Don't be afraid.
Don't forget, a good
Marine's a thinking Marine.
Billy Vorsovich, sir.
When would I get to wear
a uniform like you?
You can be wearing this
in 13 weeks.
Go! Go!
Go, Massapequa!
Go! Go! Go!
- Yay!
Hi, Donna.
Go! Go!
Go, Massapequa!
Go!
My brother's at school
at Adelphi.
He said there will be a war in...
what is it?
Vietnam.
The Marines will be
the first in,
and it won't
last long.
So if we don't sign up
soon, we'll miss it.
I've already decided.
I'm going in.
Really?
Just like that?
I'm not waiting.
I'm going in now.
You're crazy.
Our dads
got to go to WWII.
This is our chance
to be part of history.
Yeah, just like
our dads.
Think about
what you're doing.
It could be dangerous
over there.
You could
get yourself killed.
Where are you going,
squirrel head? College?
I want to do something
with my life.
I can get a degree in
business administration.
You don't need
to serve your country?
Don't you care
about anybody but yourself?
Better dead than red.
They got missiles pointed
at us everywhere. ICBMs.
Coming in
all around us.
Cuba now.
90 miles away.
They're taking over.
When will we stop them?
You can't stop them
by yourself.
Communism is
moving in everywhere.
Where, Ronnie?
I don't see them.
They're not here
in Massapequa,
so I'll just take care
of number one.
That's right.
Me... Stevie, number one.
Someone's got to stay
with the women and children
while the men
go do the fighting.
All I'm saying is,
think about it.
Think about it,
Ronnie.
Stevie, who are you taking
to the prom?
Wendy Daniels.
Wendy Daniels?
He got desperate.
Well, who are you taking,
Joey, your mother?
Ronnie, who are you going
to take to the prom?
You don't know her.
She's a pretty girl
from Ronkonkoma.
What's her name?
You don't know her.
What's her name,
Ronnie?
Her name
is Lombardi.
Lombardi?
Yeah.
Vince Lombardi?
Rosanna Lombardi.
She's from
out of town, right?
She going
to get a motel?
'Cause I'd like
to get in on that.
Ronnie, would you take this
to section three?
Check the stock
for dog food.
Dog food.
Then finish
stacking the potatoes.
Come on. Let's go.
Let's do some work
for a change.
This goes
in section three?
Section three.
O.K., Dad.
Hey, Donna.
Hi, Ronnie.
How you doing?
How's...
Good.
I heard that you were going
into the Marines.
Yeah, yeah.
It's better than
working at A&P.
That's great,
Ronnie.
That's wonderful.
I'm going
to boot camp soon.
I joined
for four years,
so I go to Vietnam,
probably on
the front line.
Really?
I'll see
a lot of action.
Wow.
That's neat.
Heard you got
into that school.
The letter?
Yeah.
Yeah, Syracuse.
It's going to be
really hard.
Could I... Could I talk
to you in private?
Oh, yeah. Sure.
I've been meaning
to call you.
I was wondering,
are you going with
someone to the prom?
Yeah. I'm going
with Jed.
Oh, yeah?
That's great.
I mean, he's
a nice guy... Jed.
Stevie Boyer told me
that you were taking some girl
from Lake Ronkonkoma.
Yeah. No, no.
No?
No. I don't have time
for that stuff.
There's a lot of things
to take care of
before you go
in the Marines.
I didn't even know
how much stuff.
Maybe I'll see you
before I leave, O. K?
Soldier boy
Oh, my little soldier boy
I'll be true to you
You were my first love
And you'll be my last love
I will never
make you blue
I'll be true to you
In this whole world
You can love
but one girl
I told you
I love you.
You promised.
Let me be
that one girl
For I'll be
true to you
The batter is
Mickey Mantle.
Mickey has two strikes
and the chance
to put the Yankees
ahead in this game.
The pitcher
gets his sign,
takes his stretch,
checks the runners.
Here's the pitch.
Mickey swings,
and he connects!
There's a long drive
deep to centre field!
It is going, going!
It is gone
into the bleachers,
455 feet away
for Mickey's
491st home run!
How about that?
The crowd is
on its feet,
giving Mickey
a standing ovation.
And rattle your walls
For the times,
they are a-changin'
Come, senators
and congressmen
Please heed the call
Don't stand in the doorway
Don't lock up the hall
For the times,
they are a-changin'
There's absolutely
no question.
The First Cavalry Division
is the latest concept
in mobile warfare.
One division is worth
21/2 Russian
and 6 Chinese divisions.
How well will
the individual soldier
stand up here
in Vietnam?
What do you think,
Dad, about that?
I don't know.
13,000 miles...
that's a long way to go
to fight a war.
They fought the French
and the Japanese
for 30 years.
Can they
be weeded out?
Anything
that lives in a cave
can be weeded out.
I just hope they send you
to Europe or Korea or...
They can't.
Someplace safe.
Every Marine has
a tour of duty there.
It's not like the Army.
What's wrong with you?
You served.
Uncle Bob served.
I know, Ronnie.
I know.
Remember what
President Kennedy said?
There won't be
an America any more
unless people are willing
to sacrifice.
I love my country.
I know.
And you're right,
Ronnie.
You're doing
the right thing.
Communism has
to be stopped.
It's God's will
you go.
We're proud of you.
Be careful,
that's all.
Up there in Hanoi,
they don't allow magazines,
newspapers, and televisions
to cast doubts
on the military system.
Don't you know what being a Marine
means to me, Dad?
Ever since
I was a kid,
I've wanted
to serve my country,
and I want to go.
I want to go
to Vietnam,
and I'll die there
if I have to.
The attitude of people
on the home front
is very important
in this war.
Not a nice night
for the prom.
Can the South Vietnamese
government
stand up
to the North?
We wouldn't
be here
if we didn't
think so.
Sometimes, God,
I'm so confused.
Sometimes
I think I'd just...
like to stay here
in Massapequa
and never leave...
but I got to go.
Just help me, Jesus.
Help me to make
the right decision.
Please, dear God.
Ron.
Ronnie, what
happened to you?
Ronnie.
What...
Oh, Jeez.
Donna.
Ronnie.
Will you
dance with me?
Oh, yes.
Yeah, sure.
Moon River
Wider than a mile
I'm crossing you
in style
Someday
Oh, dreammaker
You heartbreaker
Wherever you're goin'
I'm goin' your way
Two drifters
Off to see the world
There's such
a lot of world
To see
We're after
the same...
2-Alpha, 2-Alpha, this is 6, over.
6, 6, 2-Actual, over.
2-Actual, this is 6. That's a roger.
You have beaucoup gooks.
They're coming at you.
Echo-1's
pushing them. Over.
6, 6, 2-Actual.
Sit Rep
as follows...
two set in
on the beach.
The tracks are
moving this way.
Sounds like
beaucoup gooks in there.
I'm finally
going to see one.
Relax, you'll be
all right.
Where you from, Wilson?
First Battalion,
Ninth Motor "T."
The Sergeant Major said the grunts
needed replacements,
so they took me out
of battalion supply.
Where are you from
in the world?
Oh, Venus, Georgia.
This is my second tour.
I haven't seen a Georgia boy
get hurt yet.
You'll be all right.
Echo-6, Echo-6,
Snake 1-9er...
All right.
Echo-1's taking incoming
northwest edge of the ville.
We got gooks
moving this way.
Look out there,
Sergeant.
Can you see them?
Right there.
You see them?
They got rifles.
Can you see
the rifles?
Right there.
You see them?
Can you see
the rifles?
Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
Pass the word.
When I give
the order,
I want to light up
this ville
like a motherfucking
Christmas tree.
This time I think we got them!
Move out.
Pass the word!
Fire on command!
Wilson, come with me.
Cover that big hooch!
Fire on my command!
Pass the word!
Corporal, start ranking.
Fire on my command!
Cease fire!
What happened?
What the fuck are you doing?
Cease fire!
What happened?
I want to know
what happened!
I don't know, sir.
Possible accidental
discharge, sir.
We better get
a sweep team in there.
Take five men.
Tell me how many we got.
Yes, sir.
Motherfucker!
Baldy on me!
Brooks!
Martinez! On me!
Wilson!
Wilson, on me!
2-alpha, moving on the ville
at this time. Over.
Line! Line! Line!
Ironhand for fire mission.
Stand by.
Grid: 1-5-6-3-7-9er.
Direction: 5-800.
Gooks in the ville,
Battery 6.
Victor, Tango in effect.
How copy? Over.
Baldy! Baldy!
Lai dai! Lai dai!
Get him out!
Come on,
Baldy, come on.
Check it out over there!
Everything out!
Baldy, get
everything out!
Baldy! There!
Check it out!
Echo-2, Alpha.
Echo-2,
send your Sit Rep. Over.
Lai dai! Lai dai!
Get him out!
Check those hooches
and clear ASAP.
We've got a fire mission
inbound. Over.
Oh, my God.
We didn't
do this, did we?
Oh, my God.
Jesus Christ.
2-Actual-2, better get down
here quick,
and bring
the corpsmen.
We got beaucoup wounded.
Civilians.
Martinez, help me!
We wasted them.
Motherfucker!
We wasted them!
Oh!
Det roy.
Where are the rifles?
There ain't no
fucking rifles.
Damn it.
Jesus fucking Christ!
Well, help him then!
Help him!
Help him! Help him!
Oh, motherfuck...
I want you
to help him.
Forgive us.
Help me!
Somebody help me!
6, 6, 2-Actual.
Request
emergency medevac.
We got a lot
of friendly wounded. Over.
Get out of there!
Leave those wounded!
You got Arty inbound!
Get out! Get out!
Get back
to the dunes!
We got gooks
in the ville! Move out!
Get out! Move out!
That's a direct order!
I want you
out that door!
It wasn't your fault,
goddamn it!
They got
in the goddamned way!
Get off the deck!
We got gooks
in the ville!
The baby!
Get back to the dune!
No! Move out!
Let's move!
Kovic, move!
Move out!
Move! Move!
The ville is
going to blow!
Aah!
Red! Abbot!
Wilson!
Wilson's hit!
What happened?
Where's
First Platoon?
For God's sake,
Corpsman!
Where's my "A" gunner?
Sergeant Kovic
here to see you, sir.
Stand easy, sergeant.
Yeah, Kovic,
the lieutenant told me
that was
a pretty rough time.
Yes, sir.
It was pretty bad.
Ran into a few
of them?
Yes, sir.
You want to see me
about something, Sergeant?
Yes, sir.
Like I said to the captain,
uh, sir...
it was a very
confusing day.
The villagers...
Yeah. I know about
the villagers, Sergeant.
They...
the villagers...
It was very,
very unfortunate.
The enemy used
the villagers as cover.
Yes, sir.
They popped up,
started firing.
We were
running back, sir.
It was real glary.
Very confusing,
and that's when
it happened, sir.
What happened?
Sir, that was when
Wilson was killed, sir.
Yeah, I know
about Wilson.
Sir, see...
he was
the last one out,
and that's when
it happened, sir.
Sir, I think
I might...
I might have
killed him, sir.
I don't think so.
He was coming up
over the dune.
I think I might
have killed him.
It's hard.
I was out a couple
of weeks ago.
Sometimes it's... very hard
to tell what's happening.
Yes, sir.
But, sir, I think
I killed Wilson.
I don't think so, Kovic.
But, sir, I want you
to know that...
Don't talk like that!
Don't tell me this shit.
I'll take your head off.
Is that clear?
Yes, sir.
That clear?
Yes, sir!
All right.
Carry on.
X.O. Ought to
court-martial his ass.
Sergeant K.
Get some sugar
in the blood.
Ain't no thing, dog.
Ain't nothing
but a thing, baby.
It's so hot out here, I want
to kill some motherfucking gooks.
Dog, you're sounding
like a bitch, man.
Ain't nothing
but a thing.
Nothing but a thing.
It's so hot out
in this motherfucker,
this must be hell!
Or purgatory.
Where's the motherfucking devil at?
Take cover!
Snake 1-9er airborne,
Be advised machine guns
now approaching
at your 12. Over.
No. No, people!
Move forward!
Gun up! Gun up!
2! 2! 2-Alpha!
Contact! Contact!
Heavy incoming
from both tree lines. Over.
Uhh!
Son of a bitch!
Aah!
Fuck, man!
Uhh.
Aah!
Fuck!
Son of a bitch!
2-Actual!
Heavy incoming
from the ville!
I'm in trouble!
2, 2, Charlie,
be advised
there's more of them.
We see two squads
moving in
from the left
tree line.
Aah!
I'm in trouble
out here!
I'm in trouble out here!
2, Echo-6!
Get out of that ville!
They're going to
cut you off! Get out!
I need everything
you got!
We're going down!
I can't hold this bitch!
Hold it, goddamn it!
Pull up! Pull up!
Aah!
Goddamn it!
God damn it!
Corpsmen...
Corpsmen... Corpsmen.
Goddamn!
Motherfuckers!
Goddamn motherfuckers!
Motherfucker!
Goddamn!
Motherfuckers!
Fuckers!
We got six
sucking chest wounds
and 12 crispy critters
coming in!
Zap him with 250 mils
of happy juice
until he crashes out.
Just get him to sleep.
Open table!
Who's got a hot one?
What do we have?
His kidney
and liver are gone.
We better just kiss
this one goodbye.
All right, take off.
There's something
wrong with me.
Code blue! Code blue!
Let's go!
He's code blue!
Code blue! Code blue!
Get the machine!
Let me in.
Stay with me, Marine.
Stay with me!
Give me
the shock defibs!
Stay with me now.
We're going to
jump-start you. Clear!
Where's the priest?
Get me a priest.
Breathe! Breathe!
Breathe!
I took the Packers
at minus 7.
Shit. They ain't
got a chance.
How are you?
You tell them
they've got to operate.
There's something
wrong with me.
The doctors
are real busy.
There's a lot
of wounded here.
There's no time
for anything
except trying
to stay alive.
You got to try
and stay alive. O. K?
Try and stay alive.
I've come to give you
your last rites.
Are you ready?
I'm ready, Father.
I am the resurrection
and the life.
He that believeth in me,
though he were dead,
yet shall he live.
We brought nothing
into this world,
and it's certain
we can take nothing out.
The Lord giveth, and
the Lord taketh away.
Blessed be the name
of the Lord.
I got sunshine
On a cloudy day
And when it's
cold outside
I got the month of May
Eddie, I need
some help in room 13.
Give me
a second, man.
His catheter's
plugging up.
It's backing up
into his kidney.
I said I'd be there.
Give me a break.
Man, what's going up?
Nothing, man.
You ain't supposed
to be having this.
Oh!
Didn't I tell you not
to do that to him
in the A. M?
Take the needle
out of my arm.
Good morning,
Nurse Washington.
How are you today?
You up bright
and early today.
Everybody up!
Good morning, gentlemen.
Let's rise and shine.
Pea!
Can I have some aspirin?
I ain't feeling well.
I'd like some aspirin.
Hmm. I'll get to you.
Leon! How you
doing today?
Look at this shit.
Mm-hmm!
My catheter's
clogged.
Give it a minute.
They're getting
bigger every day.
You don't bother them,
they ain't going
to bother you.
That's why
I'm feeding him.
Keep on feeding him,
and everything'll be fine.
Up and at 'em!
Frankie's here!
Hey, Frankie.
What's up?
Hopkins, come on,
wake up.
All you guys,
6:00 special.
Fuck you.
Fenaday,
I'm looking at you.
Keep looking.
My man Kovic.
Up already?
That's good. Let's go.
Let's do it.
Let's go.
Give me a hand over here.
How you doing,
Eddie?
Yeah, you about ready.
Let me have that thing there.
Hey, where did we go
Days when the rains came...
I think my stomach
is bloated.
Just take it easy.
Eddie going to take care
of all you boys.
It's like
a car wash.
Bernstein,
what's wrong today?
You got shit up you
ain't coming out.
Stick your head up my ass,
see what the problem is.
Your piss bag's
cloudy, too.
You been drinking
enough water?
You gots to flush
them kidneys every day.
Yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah.
Frankie,
I think I'm done.
I think I'm ready.
Are you fucking
with me again?
You better
chill out.
I'm not
fucking with you.
I'm not fucking
with you, man.
My man Kovic!
Mr 4th of July.
Politicians,
protesters, and police
are all here in Chicago
for the 1968
presidential election.
Chicago police tonight
charged the crowd...
Gook-Iovers.
They ought to die.
Hey! Hey!
There he goes, man.
It's Leon.
Hey!
They're coming
through the wire!
Hey!
Chieu hoy!
Chieu hoy, Leon.
They're going
to overrun us!
Shut up!
They're going
to overrun us!
Hey, John!
Hey, hey, hey,
chieu hoy, Leon.
Chieu hoy, man!
Shut the fuck up, Leon!
Hit him with
some morphine.
Chicago has an Alice in Wonderland
quality about it.
Things are getting
curiouser and curiouser.
Everywhere you go, there's a sign
reminding you...
Love it or leave it,
you fucking bastards!
Hey, you ready, Kovic?
They're burning the flag.
They're fucking burning
the American flag.
Come on.
Let's look alive.
Looking good.
Come on, Kovic.
Real nice.
How many
did I do yesterday?
Three.
Three?
You had enough?
Let's do seven.
There you go.
Let's go for seven, then.
Come on, Ronnie.
That a way.
Get up there.
Keep going.
Come on, fucking Marine.
There you go.
Real nice.
This'll be the day
that I die
We want
to make one thing
very clear to you, Ron.
The possibility of your
ever walking is minimal.
Almost impossible.
You're a T-6, paralysed
from the midchest down.
Probably you'll be
in a wheelchair
for the rest
of your life.
Do you understand
what I'm saying?
Well, doctor, will...
Hmm?
Will I ever be able
to, uh...
to have children?
No.
No, but we have a very good
psychologist here.
He's helped...
Oh, I'll walk again.
I know I'll walk again.
Let me
tell you something.
You will never
walk again.
Let's go.
Uhh!
You're walking good
in these things.
What am I
looking like, good?
You're one crazy Marine.
So gung ho,
but you don't know shit
about what's going on
in this country.
Fuck you, Willie.
It ain't about burning the flag
and Vietnam.
Why fight
for rights there?
We ain't got rights
at home.
It's about Detroit
and Newark.
It's about racism, man,
but you can't get
no job at home.
Vietnam's a white man's war,
a rich man's war.
Where's my money?
You got
to read some books.
There's a revolution
going on.
If you ain't part
of the solution,
then you's part
of the problem.
Jesus Christ, Willie.
Just get my chair for me.
You got to watch
for her.
Oh, man.
Some good weed.
Take the bra off.
I'll give you
another 10.
Why, sure, sugar.
Like this?
Oh, shh! Shh!
Yeah. Yeah.
Suck on my tits.
Honey, anything
you want.
Shh!
Oh!
Jesus!
I guess you'd say
What could make me
feel this way
My girl
Talking 'bout my girl
Good.
Easy now.
Very good.
Hey, Doc...
it's really beautiful
up here.
Ha ha ha!
I'm walking
out of here, guys.
You'll see.
Right, Willie?
Right.
Easy.
Oh... I'm all right.
I'm all right.
O.K. That's enough
for today.
O.K.
Now, good. Good.
Easy, now. Easy, now.
Don't go too far.
Don't do too much.
Looking good today.
Looking good.
Don't go too far.
All right!
Way to go, Kovic.
Amazing, huh?
Nothing from
the chest down.
It can be done.
Semper fi, motherfucker!
All right!
All right, Harry, man.
Keep it going. Let's go!
Let's go. Let's go.
Let's go.
Aah!
Oh!
Willie!
I think I need...
Oh! Oh.
Get him up.
Somebody...
Something snapped.
It's my neck.
All right.
Just my neck.
Ah, shit! Harry!
Hang on. Hang on.
What was that sound?
Oh, shit.
What?
Oh!
It's fine.
We're doing fine.
Is that my bone?
Harry, Harry,
get a doc.
Am I O. K?
It's O.K. Everybody, relax.
Harry! Let's go!
Oh, fuck.
- Shit.
- Fuck.
Washington!
Washington,
where the fuck were you?
I've been pushing
this call button
and staring at my own vomit
for two hours.
What's the matter
with you fucking people?
I'm laying
in my own shit.
Why don't you
change the sheets?
This goddamned fucking place.
I need a bath.
Don't be raising
your voice to me!
You watch your mouth.
Why don't you help me?
What's the matter
with you?
I don't feel right.
I need to see
the doctor now!
He's not available now.
I want to see him now!
He's always too busy.
What's eating you now?
You going off
the deep end?
We'll amputate
that leg,
you go on
like this.
Don't put
your hands on me.
I want to be treated
like a human being.
I don't want
any of that shit!
Trying to
keep me fucking drugged
so I don't know
what's going on.
This is a fucking slum.
We take that leg,
you're out
in two weeks.
I want my leg.
Why?
You can't feel it.
It's my leg.
I want my leg.
Can't you
understand that?
I want to be treated
like a human being.
I fought
for my country.
I'm a Vietnam veteran!
I fought
for my country!
Shut the fuck up!
I should
be treated decent!
Vietnam don't mean
nothing to me, man,
or any of these other people.
You got it?
You can take
your Vietnam
and shove it up your ass,
you hear?
No! I don't
need this!
Hey, you fuck!
Hey, goddamn you!
Goddamn it.
I am a fucking
Vietnam veteran!
This isn't...
Marvin!
Marvin, now!
What's up?
Marvin, look!
Oh, fuck!
It's off.
It ain't
going to work.
Start!
Washington,
get the doctor.
Wait a minute.
OK. Yeah.
All right. I will.
How you doing, Eddie?
Let's see what's
wrong with this.
They tell me if we don't
get this pump working,
they'll cut my leg off.
I want my leg.
Do we have another pump?
It's the only one, Eddie.
Ron. It's Ron Kovic.
Sorry, man. Ron.
You... You are a doctor?
It's the Vietnam war.
Cutbacks.
The government's not giving us
the money we need
to take care
of you guys.
We're doing our best.
It's really too bad.
It's not fair.
I've tried hard
to keep this leg.
I've been strapped in
this bed for four months
so I could
keep this leg.
Maybe I can rig up
a substitute.
I'll look in the basement
and see what we got.
You're coming back?
Soon.
Let go, Ron.
Let go.
We really did try
to help Mr Kovic.
Aah!
Susanne, he's here.
Ronnie's home.
O.K. Out on 3.
All right, 1...
2...
3.
Oh, that's great.
Did you
paint the house, Dad?
Yeah. I painted it.
Yellow. It looks good.
It looks pretty good.
I got that.
That's all right. Let's go.
The kids have been
talking about you.
They can't wait
to see you.
It's great to be back
in the neighbourhood.
I got it. I got it.
Everything looks
so different.
Major.
Hey, Major.
Major, you know
who this is?
Yeah.
You know who this is?
He's gotten old, huh?
Just like your old man.
Hey, Tommy.
Good to see you.
Look at that hair.
Dad lets you
look like that?
I don't have
much say.
How are you, Jimmy?
Good to have you home.
You're out for good?
I'm out for good.
Patty, gee,
look at you.
Timmy.
That's Jackie.
Jackie?
I wanted to visit you
in the hospital.
How many pull-ups
you do, huh?
You know, I did 23...
23 pull-ups.
23 pull...
I'm O.K. I'm O.K.
I'm all right.
Ronnie.
Susanne.
Good to have you home.
You didn't tell me
she was this beautiful.
She's a woman, huh?
I'm sorry.
That's O.K. I can't
feel anything anyway.
I'm only paralysed.
You look great.
Yeah?
Ronnie.
Mom.
Hey, Mom.
Oh, look at your hair.
It looks great.
You like it?
Oh, you look beautiful.
Thanks.
It's good to be home.
It's better
than seeing me
at that hospital, huh?
It's O.K.
I know.
I'm O.K.
It's good to
have you home, Ronnie.
Gee, everybody
looks so good.
Everybody looks so good.
I'm going to go inside
for a minute.
Mom, wait.
She'll be O.K.
Ronnie, how are you, man?
You look good.
Ronnie,
you look good.
Welcome home.
It's so good
to see you.
Welcome home.
Nice to see you.
Look at Harry.
You look good.
Welcome home.
Let's go in
the house and help.
Come on, Mom.
It's all right.
Looks good.
Yeah?
You need some help?
No. I'm O.K., Dad.
Fixed up a bathroom
for you, Ronnie.
Put a wider doorway in.
I built a shower
for you, too.
You can get in here
pretty easy.
Oh, and I
put some handles
on the toilet
for you.
Ronnie.
Thanks, Dad.
It's really great
to be back in my room.
It's good to have you.
It's good to have you,
Ronnie.
Come on, I'll show you...
I'll show you
some new stuff we got
in the bedroom
over here.
My Happauge Boyer's grossed
85 grand last six months.
My competitor's rushing in to build,
but I was first.
The people are loyal.
You probably think
it's just a hamburger.
A patty's
just a piece of meat,
but it can
have character.
See that doughnut hole?
Gets 18 patties to the pound
instead of 16.
Saves me
about $40,000 a year.
That's serious
money, Ron.
I plug the hole
with lettuce, tomatoes,
onions, spices.
I cover it
with a pickle.
They'll never
miss a thing.
Give me a good one
for Ronnie. Thanks.
Good job. Try this.
You don't find that
at McDonald's on Sunrise.
I got a drive-in
window, too.
It's Long Island's first.
It's clean,
it's cheap, it's fast.
Feed the family
for $3.95.
Check out these chicks.
They're wearing
those new miniskirts.
It's my idea.
It's good for tips.
The customers
always come back.
Massapequa's changed.
Watch yourself.
It's no mom-and-pop
operation any more.
This is our town.
You're doing a nice job.
Keep up the good work.
Good.
Copiague, Ronnie,
Jericho, Bayville,
Valley Stream, man.
I want to turn Boyer's
into a whole
Long Island thing.
I want you to come
to work for me.
What can I do?
This is our town now.
You're a war hero,
and you can benefit.
You should benefit,
Ronnie.
You mean, like partners?
We open a place
together?
You got to walk
before you run.
I could start you out
as a cashier.
Then you could
learn the business,
work your way up
to be manager,
just like your dad.
I get 1,700 a month
from the government.
I'll take my time.
That's charity money.
This isn't.
Charity?
Here's your cola.
You got to put
the war behind you.
Forget about
this chair you're in.
Sometimes,
you know, Stevie,
I think people know
you're back
from Vietnam,
and their face changes,
the eyes...
the voice, the way
they look at you.
I know, but people here,
they don't give a shit
about the war.
It's just a million miles away.
It's all bullshit.
The government sold us
a bill of goods.
We got the shit
kicked out of us.
What do you mean "we"?
You were in college.
It was you who bought
that communist bullshit.
Yeah. They were going
to take over the world.
Do you remember that?
Finnelli, you, Walsh.
The whole town
was devastated.
For what?
For lies?
For bullshit lies?
They burn the flag.
They demonstrate
against us
on the cover
of the paper today.
They have no respect.
They have no idea
what's going on
over there
and the men that are
sacrificing their lives.
Nobody here
seems to care.
It's a bunch
of goddamned shit.
Don't take the Lord's name in vain
in front of the children.
I agree with
everything you say.
I served my country.
They just want
to take from it.
Love it or leave it.
The other side's angry
because
we're not winning.
How can we win?
Tommy,
what's the matter?
Nothing.
Anybody listening here?
Tommy?
What?
Tommy's going
to fail English.
He doesn't believe
in the war.
What?
He thinks we're doing
the wrong thing
over there.
He thinks
it's all a mistake.
Mistake? What's this?
Spit it out.
You believe
in demonstrators?
Huh? What?
I just don't agree
with everything you're saying.
I don't think
you understand.
What does
Tommy know?
I don't understand?
He's hanging around
with longhairs
who take drugs!
That's not the reason.
Have they ever worked?
You want to burn the flag?
Huh, Tommy?
What is this?
You want to
bring down this country?
Love it
or leave it, Tommy.
All they're
trying to say, Ronnie,
is they don't
want more people
to come back like you.
That's an easy excuse.
Where were they when
their country needed them?
You served your country.
What did you
get out of it?
Look at you.
Well, look at me.
Look at you, man.
I got to go. I'll see
you around, all right?
What's wrong
with me, Tommy?
with me?
Is there something
wrong with me?
I volunteered,
Tommy!
You don't know
what you're talking about!
Were you there?
You can just love it
or leave it, Tommy!
Mom, I can't believe
what Tommy just
said to me.
I can't...
I can't believe
what Tommy just said to me.
Parade time, Ronnie.
You tell them I'll be
right there, all right?
What kind of car is it?
I think it's
a Continental.
Continental?
A convertible?
Yeah.
They said
it would be.
Coming up
in the world.
Would you like to ride
In my beautiful balloon
We could float among
the stars together
You and I
For we can fly
We can fly
Up, up and away
In my beautiful
My beautiful
Balloon
Die!
Today is July the 4th,
and I believe in America.
And I believe
in Americanism.
But most of all,
I believe in victory
for America.
Some people are starting
to say the war is wrong,
that we shouldn't be there.
Some people would like to
tear our country down.
But who are the kids
defending their right
to protest?
These are the kids
who care about America,
kids who have respect
for their flag
and their parents
and their government
and their religion.
Kids like Joey Walsh.