I'll bring you back a slice of cake.
Get away from the window.
Now don't forget.
Mr Punch, you will call me, won't you?
This way, please.
No, no, I'll take them.
Look, Ma, it's gorgeous.
Well, you're very welcome, Christy,
very welcome.
To your humble abode.
Oh, my humble abode.
Yes, well, I suppose so.
Hello. My name is Mary.
I'll be with you till you go on this evening.
I have to take him into the library.
- I'll see you later.
- See you later.
Be careful of that fella.
I'll be okay.
I wouldn't be too sure about that.
Now, you're all very welcome
to my humble abode,
and to this benefit,
organised by my friend Dr Eileen Cole,
Dr Eileen Cole.
Now I'm not going to ask you to put
your hands in your pockets, not yet,
because we're going to start the evening
with a little concert.
Do you want to go out and watch?
No.
Do you want to see the original?
The original?
Of the book.
It looks good.
Looks can be deceivin'.
It's a bit sentimental.
Did you paint this?
Yes.
That's very good.
Mr Brown?
Your son was born a couple of hours ago.
There's been some complications.
Where's the small one?
A pint and a small one?
- That's what I said.
- So long as you're payin' for it.
Are you gonna put him in a home, Paddy?
He'll go in a coffin before
any son of mine will go in a home.
Paddy... I believe it's the end of the road
for you in the breedin' stakes.
Who told you that?
Now... What are you goin' to do?
Are you goin' to tie a knot in it?
Now, Paddy, there was no need for that.
A shut mouth catches no flies.
Where's Tom?
Is Tom not up yet?
It's all right! I'm up! I'm up ages!
Say goodbye to Christy, Father.
Goodbye, Christy.
Be a good girl. See you later.
See you, Christy.
- See you, Christy.
- Bye, Christy.
Something for the money box, Christy.
Another pound saved, Christy.
Here, Christy.
Good boy, that's it.
I have to go away, Christy.
To hospital.
Don't worry, Sheila's going
to look after you while I'm gone.
Do you understand, Christy?
That's my Ma. That's my Da.
I was their baby.
It's only for a few days, Christy.
I'd better get this house organised
before I go.
You can't be stickin' to me
like stickin' plaster forever, Christy.
Nearly there, Christy.
Christy, I have to go and make a phone call.
Stay there.
Oh, my God... Nan...
Nan! Nan!
I heard this terrible bangin' and rushed over.
She was carryin' Christy down the stairs
when she fell.
And there he was,
lyin' at the bottom of the stairs like a moron.
God help her.
He's a terrible cross to the poor woman.
Sure he has the mind of a three-year-old.
A is for apples.
B is for butter.
C is for carrot.
And D... is for dunce.
Poor, unfortunate gobshite.
Enough to feed an army.
God, you'll never go hungry, Christy.
Would you like to come back with me
till your mammy comes home?
What's 25% of a quarter?
25% of a quarter?
Now that's a stupid question.
I mean, 25% is a quarter.
You can't have a quarter of a quarter.
You can. Can't you, Christy?
What would he know?
Ma! Ma, Christy picked up the chalk.
Go on, Christy. Go on, make your mark.
It's a Y.
It's an X.
- What's that, Christy?
- That's only an auld squiggle.
There's something in that.
Nah, don't be gettin' notions
into your head, woman.
The child's a cripple. Face facts.
It won't do anybody any good
trying to put ideas in his head.
- Oh, that's great.
- We're gonna put the engine on now.
- You're puttin' an engine in it?
- Yeah. Come on.
Come on, engine.
All he needs now is a license.
It's great!
Take it easy, will ya?
Go on, take it easy.
He'll play in that all day now.
He can go out with the other boys now.
- Look at those!
- They're massive!
- What's that?
- That's her thing.
You put your thing in there
for a half an hour and you get a baby.
If you do it for an hour you get twins.
My cousin's a twin.
- Benny! Brian! Come on!
- There's your Ma.
Quick, Tom. Here's Ma!
- It's not my magazine!
- Is Benny in there?
- Hide it!
- Where?
- Just hide it!
- Are you deaf? Come in for your tea!
- Hide it under Christy!
- Are you all deaf?
I've been calling you for 20 minutes
to come in for your tea. Come on, Christy.
- It's okay, Mam, we'll take him.
- Well, take him in now.
It's been on the table
for at least a half an hour.
See?
Why won't he go to bed?
He loves that auld chariot.
Come on, get him up.
I want to go and have a pint.
Come on, Christy.
It's way past your bedtime.
It's nearly closin' time.
Now, son, you know
you can never get out of Hell.
You can get out of Purgatory
but you can never get out of Hell.
Do you know that?
Do you?
Mrs Brown...
I don't think you should bring him
to the altar just yet.
You've been very helpful, Father.
Christy, do you know all
about All Souls' Night?
Did I ever tell you about that?
It's a very special night,
you know, because...
every time that you light a candle
on All Souls' Night,
you have to say five Our Fathers
and five Hail Marys and five Glory Bes,
and then a soul flies up out
of the flames of Purgatory
and goes straight up to Heaven.
Say some prayers for the poor souls in Purgatory.
Right.
What's wrong with you?
Christy, keep your voice down.
What's wrong with you, son?
What's the matter with you?
What do you want?
Do you want to light another candle?
Is that it?
Do you? For the poor souls?
Good boy. That's a good boy.
And don't forget, Christy,
if we can't understand you, God can.
See, Christy?
Even God has to lock his house.
Look, Christy! There it is! Look!
See, that's your soul going up to Heaven!
Oh, look! Look, Christy. Oh, look.
- You frightened the life out of him.
- Here, Christy.
You're king of the bonfire.
Don't be frightened, Christy.
It's only your brother- Tom.
This way, Christy. This way.
Get him over here!
You all right, Christy?
What's Christy doing, Sheila?
Is he all right?
He's drawing.
He's drawing a triangle.
No, Christy, you don't start there.
Here, son.
Now, that's a triangle.
That's not a triangle.
That's an A.
- What's up?
- Keep quiet.
All I said was, "What's up?"
Sit down!
Here, Paddy.
Why don't you go and have a pint?
- What?
- Here.
- What's that?
- It's money.
Where'd you get it?
From the fairies.
Go and have a drink, Paddy.
I don't need a drink!
All I need is to be obeyed in me own house!
Mother.
Sweet Jesus.
Jesus suffering Christ.
He's a Brown!
He's a Brown, all right!
Christy's a Brown!
Out!
Where you goin', Paddy?
Where do you think?
This man deserves a jar!
This is Christy Brown!
My son. Genius.
Hello.
Is he okay?
- He's grand.
- Good.
It's just that he can be a bit...
What?
A bit like Christy.
He's fine. He's asleep now.
Well...
I'll leave you alone, then.
14...
15, 16...
- Keep your voice down.
- 17. Great.
Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday, dear Christy
Happy birthday to you!
Go on, go on.
- Go on now, me boy.
- He's a man now, Father.
Come on, Christy. 17 candles.
Now take a deep breath. Come on.
Will you shut that baby up,
for Christ's sake?
- Take it easy, Christy.
- Go on. Make a wish.
- Come on, Christy.
- Go on, Christy.
Go on, Christy!
Go on, Christy.
Go on!
It's like the bleedin' fire of Hell,
that one is.
Here you go, Christy, here.
There, now. Go.
That's it. Well done.
Don't worry, you'll get your wheelchair, Christy.
Get it! Go!
Get the fuckin' ball!
Save it, Christy!
Well saved, Christy!
Good save!
He bit me!
It's a free out! A free out!
- We're taking it.
- Okay, come on.
Pass it, will ya?
Stay away from them sheets!
He handled it!
Penalty right here. Give us it.
Let Christy take it.
You can't hold him up.
Right!
He's got a left like a cannon!
If it stops at Tom, I'll kill you.
Nobody...
No, nobody.
It's pointin' at Christy.
He's not in the game.
He is if it's pointing at him.
I don't think it's pointing at me.
You're the nicest of the lot.
And you've nice eyes, too.
Come on, let's go.
Christy, you boy, you.
Chasin' the women.
See you, Tom.
See you, Rachel.
Not here, Brendan. Later.
This is a fine time of night
to be coming in.
- What's wrong, Ma?
- I don't like these late nights, Sheila.
What's this?
Holiday pay, isn't it?
I got laid off.
What about Christy's wheelchair?
Christy will get his wheelchair, okay?
Why did you get laid off?
Don't you question me
in front of the children.
A brick hit the foreman in the head
accidentally on purpose.
It's Rachel.
- How are ya?
- What?
"Your beautiful eyes are splendid pools of blue...
"in whose depths I swim regularly."
It's lovely, isn't it?
He even signed it himself.
Even signed it himself. "C.B."
That's not Tom Brown. That's Christy.
Surely he does it with his left foot!
You're in love with a cripple!
She's in love with a cripple!
Rachel, come back!
Anyone not abed?!
Can I speak to Christy Brown, please?
Christy! You're wanted.
Did you paint that?
Yeah.
I can't take it.
Sorry.
Tell your brother Tom
we were asking for him.
What's this?
What does it look like?
But we had porridge for breakfast.
So?
And we had it for dinner.
I'm not eating any more.
You get that into you.
I can't.
Get it into you.
Go on, more.
Who's been eating my porridge?
What did you say?
What did he say, missus?
He just said the porridge is lovely.
Burst his brain, the barbarian.
Keep quiet!
Come on, Christy.
Everybody has to go to bed.
I have to do my painting.
I know you have to do your painting
but everybody has to go to bed
because there's no coal.
Don't push me nerves any further, all right?
I'm sorry.
Christy, someday you'll have
a place of your own.
All right, come on, you lot.
Mind my paintings.
Are all those kids in bed?
What's up, Christy?
Coal.
- What?
- Coal!
Coal?
It's too early.
Coal!
All right, all right!
Mister! Mister!
Me driver abandoned me.
Can you push me?
Come back, you bastard!
Your plan's not working, Christy.
Wait till he goes up the hill.
Hold the baby.
Come on, Christy!
We'll be warm for the whole winter, Christy!
Jesus, Mary, and Joseph!
What's happened to you?
It's all right, Ma. It's only coal.
I know where you got that coal.
You know it's a sin to steal.
And you know that God is looking down
on you right now.
And that coal is not coming into this house.
Come in here and sit by the fire, woman.
You want me to wash you, Christy?
No.
- Good night, Christy.
- Don't you be late!
Ma! There's something wrong with Christy!
There's something wrong with him.
What's wrong with you, Christy?
What's wrong?
Fire!
Jesus, Mary, and Joseph!
Ma, what are you trying to do?
Get water, quick!
Hurry up!
What's wrong with you? Are you mad?
What have you got in the box, woman?
Christy's money.
- What?
- Money for Christy's wheelchair.
Must be twenty pounds in there.
28 pounds, 7 and threepence.
We've been sitting here in the freezing cold,
eating porridge for breakfast, dinner, and tea,
and you have 28 pounds, 7 and threepence
up the fucking chimney.
Tom, Brian.
Everybody, upstairs.
Now!
- Ma, what's wrong?
- You, too, Christy.
Your daughter's getting married.
Well, that's wonderful news.
- When?
- Friday.
What's the rush?
She's pregnant.
That's great news.
I mean, that's wonderful.
That's just what we need.
Who's the father? Or do you know?
Leave me alone.
It's not my fault.
Then whose fault is it, then?
Is it mine?!
Oh, that's a lovely picture.
The old woman that lives in the shoe
and the daughter that couldn't keep
her knickers on!
Stop it. Stop it!
- You dirty, sleazy bitch!
- Stop it, Father!
- Get out of here, Sheila.
- She should be thrown out!
Her and her swollen belly! Fornication!
Get away from me!
That'll keep your legs shut for you!
Paddy, leave her!
When I get hold of you...
I'll break every bone
in your fucking body!
- Fucking kill him.
- Christy, stop.
Jesus Christ!
What am I gonna do in this fucking house?
Tom, Benny, stop him.
Stop, Christy! Stop him!
Christy, stop!
Christy, please stop!
Christy, stop! Christy, please stop!
Christy, please! Christy, stop!
Stop it, Christy! Come on!
Christy, stop.
Christy. It's all right, Christy.
He's gone now, Christy.
Christy, come on.
Christy, it's all right.
Christy, I'm going away.
I'll miss you, too.
Look after me Ma for me.
I need a light.
What?
I don't smoke.
I need a light!
I'm not deaf. I can hear you.
You need a light.
I haven't got any matches,
so you'll have to wait here
while I go and get one.
Don't you think I'm your mother
just because I'm looking after you for the evening.
I don't need a fucking psychology lesson.
I just need a fucking light.
Light.
Have you got a cigarette?
I'm just after telling you I don't smoke.
Is there anything else
I can do for you?
Glass.
No point in drinking out of the bottle.
Hello. Dr Cole, please.
Hello, Eileen.
Yes. Yeah.
Athetoid cerebral palsy.
- He's 19?
- Yes, 19.
Yes, 19.
Yes. That's correct.
I'll get his address.
Okay. Okay.
Dr Cole thinks that this model
would be the best for your son.
- Which one?
- This one.
That is grand.
Yeah.
See, that there, he won a prize for that.
- That's lovely.
- His best one's here. Wait till I show you now.
- What's that?
- Nothing. See that one? Isn't that lovely?
And that one- torn, but you get the idea.
That's his first one
he ever did there. See?
- Watch your step there.
- I'm fine.
Christy, there's someone to see you.
This is Dr Cole.
Hello, Christy.
You're a great painter.
No.
Look, I'm a doctor, like your mother says,
and I specialise in cerebral palsy.
We've just started a clinic- here in Dublin
and I wonder, would you like to attend it?
No, we don't have to pay, Christy.
Well?
Hope deferred maketh the heart sick.
- He said, "Hope deferred..."
- "Maketh the heart sick."
I understood that.
Come on.
Maybe.
Good.
- Come on in!
- Please!
- No!
- You have to.
What do you want them to do,
tow you behind?
Do you want to ride up front
with the driver?
Come on, Christy.
Come up in the front with me.
I'm all right.
He said he's all right.
Eileen.
Eileen, come here.
Easy. Come on. Relax.
- What?
- I want to go home.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
The door's been locked
for a few days now.
I've got to try.
Christy.
Go away.
Christy, there's somebody here to see you.
Christy?
I'm not a child.
Not a child, he says.
There's too many children at the clinic.
Christy, if you like,
we can work here.
Fuck off.
With speech therapy, I could teach you
how to say "fuck off" more clearly.
One, two...
three, four, five.
And over again.
One, two...
Just relax with it. Relax.
Three, four, five. That's it.
One, two, three, and out.
Breathe.
Nope. Your lungs are too weak.
Leave it be.
That's right. Try this instead.
Right. Now you have a go.
Yes. Blow.
Steady, steady.
And one big breath.
That's very good.
Now focus the breath.
Breathe slowly and...
He's been like that for three days now.
I don't know what's wrong.
He won't talk to me.
Go on up and see him.
I've brought you a present.
Thanks.
There's a speech in there
I'd love you to have a look at.
It's "To be or not to be." Hamlet.
I wish you'd stop feeling sorry for yourself.
I don't want to be a failure, either.
Will you have a look at it for me?
Maybe.
"To be... or not... to be.
"To be... or not to be.
"That is the question.
"To be or not...
"To be...
"That is the question...
"Whether...
"nobler in the mind to..."
"To be... or not to be."
"To be or not to be...
"That is the question.
"Whether it is nobler in the mind..."
to have to fucking suffer listening to that.
He's in love with this girl Eileen.
Well... so long as he's getting better.
He could get hurt, Paddy.
A broken body's nothing to a broken heart.
Yeah!
Eileen, how's it going?
Very, very well.
I've got some news for you.
What?
Remember I told you
about Peter and his gallery?
Yeah.
Well, he's offered you
an exhibition of your own.
What do you think about that?
I think you're brilliant.
Yeah. I'm only as brilliant as my patients.
"Consummation...
"devoutly to be wished.
"To die, to sleep..."
"To sleep...
"perchance to dream.
"Aye, there's the rub.
"For in that sleep of death
what dreams may come."
Is that our Christy up there?
Does that sound like our Christy?
Sounds a lot better.
Not to me, it doesn't.
Are you mad, woman?
You can understand your child
for the first time.
I always understood him.
Nobody else ever did.
At least he can function now.
There's something in that voice that...
that disturbs me.
What do you mean?
Too much hope in it.
What?
There's too much hope in it.
"Fly to others that we know not of?
"Thus, conscience does make cowards of us all."
What was it?
- "And thus, the native hue..."
- "And thus, the native hue of resolution
"is sicklied over with the pale cast of thought
"and enterprises of great pitch and moment
"with this regard, their currents turn awry
and lose the name of action."
What do you think about Hamlet, Christy?
A cripple. He can't act.
He did in the end.
Too late.
Eileen...
I like you very much.
And I like you, Christy.
You have the heart of a poet.
No.
Oh, well.
What?
Nothing.
I better go.
Ladies and gentlemen?
Ladies and gentlemen. Thank you.
It gives me great pleasure
to open this exhibition...
of the work of Christy Brown.
A lot of people say that Christy
is a great crippled painter.
I think that's an insult to Christy.
That's right!
Christy is simply a great painter, full stop.
He has struggled with his material...
as every painter must do,
to bring it under control.
If you look around the walls today
you'll see the forces that shape Christy Brown.
His mother...
his father...
his brothers and sisters...
and the lady who brought him
to public recognition,
Dr Eileen Cole.
Yes!
So, what do you think?
There are only two kinds of painting-
religious and the circus.
Give me some wine.
You know, on each side of the nose.
That's what it says here- "Seven-day Seascape".
Something like that.
There you go.
And you've had enough to drink.
Don't have any more drink.
Do you hear me?
I'm going for a meal, Ma. You coming?
No, no, no. I'm...
I'll take your father home.
He's not feeling well.
There's no pints, you mean.
It's good wine, tell him.
Your father never drank anything
but pints in his life. I'll take him home.
You getting a taxi?
- Eileen's giving us a lift.
- Right.
- I'll see you later, Ma.
- I'll see you later.
I think Mulcahy is a great painter.
In the... soul.
You see? I agree with Christy.
He's too uncontrolled for me.
Tim. Let Christy try the wine.
Introibo ad altare Dei.
- What's he saying?
- The Latin mass.
I thought that was James Joyce.
The wine's A1.
- Can you tell us what year it is, Christy?
- I'm not that sophisticated.
Not yet.
I love you, Eileen.
And I love you, Christy.
No. I really love you.
I love you all.
That's good.
I even love... Peter.
I'm glad you like Peter, Christy,
because we're going to get married in six months.
Christy, what do you think of that?
Con...
Congratulations...
Peter and Eileen...
on the won...
wonderful news.
I'm glad you taught me how to speak...
so I could say that, Eileen.
Well... Where were we, then?
- Discussing Mulcahy.
- Mulcahy's empty.
I thought you said Mulcahy was full of soul.
I said he was empty. Whiskey!
Take it easy, Christy.
You're not my mother.
Never forget that.
You know, I know what age that is.
That's ten-year-old...
same age as me.
- Don't give him any more.
- Pour!
Take that whiskey from him, Tony.
Touch it, and I'll kick you...
in the only part of your anatomy
that's animated.
Stop it.
Why did you say you loved me?
Because I do love you.
You mean platonic love.
I've had nothing but platonic love all me life.
Do you know what I say?
Fuck Plato!
And fuck all love
that's not 100% commitment!
Pour!
- I can't let you go any further.
- Let's discuss nature.
Keep quiet, Christy.
What are you going to do about it, Peter?
You're a nice man.
What are you going to do about it?
Peter, sit down.
- I'm going to wheel you out of this restaurant.
- Yeah?
Stop it!
- Wheel out the cripple! Wheel out the cripple!
- Stop! Just stop it.
- Where's the fucking brake on this thing?
- Stop it!
Stop it! Stop it, you bastard!
Stop it!
Sharon!
Sharon, come in for your tea.
Come on in for your tea, will you?
Come in now for your tea, please. Come on.
All right, Ma.
- Get up, Christy.
- I'm not well.
You've got a hangover, that's all.
Leave me alone.
You get more like your father every day.
All hard on the outside
and putty on the inside.
It's in here...
battles are won.
Not in the pub...
pretending to be a big fella
in front of the lads.
Right. If you've given up, I haven't.
What do you think you're doing, Mum?
Building a room for you.
Don't be mad.
Maybe if you have a room of your own...
you might start painting again.
You have me heartbroken, Christy Brown.
Sometimes, I think you are me heart.
If I could give you my legs,
I would gladly take yours.
What's wrong with you, Christy?
I'm sorry, Mum.
What in the name of God is going on here?
Christy and me's building a room.
- Youse are you building a room?
- Yep.
Will you have a look at this?
Christy, you may be a great painter
but you'll never be a brickie.
Fair play to you, missus.
Right, lads.
You bring in some more bricks.
Mix up a bit of muck.
Bring me in me level, will you?
Brown and Son Contractors are on the job.
Here. You start over there.
I'll start over here
and by the time you have
three courses up there
I'll be finished here
and inside having me tea.
Not at all.
Water. More water.
I'm not beaten yet, bejesus.
My dad.
Brian, boys. Listen to me.
Let your father win.
- What?
- He needs it.
Here.
Take it easy, Father, will you?
Take it easy?
I was never able to take it easy
and you of all people ought to know that.
Right, lads?
That's her finished.
They've a long way to go
to be a better man than their father.
Yeah.
Well, Christy, that's the nearest
he'll ever come
to saying he loves you.
How are you?
Did you see the face on them?
To see you pushing that cart.
I'm parched now.
Do you want a cup of tea?
I'm going to make a nice cup of tea.
I'm going to have the cake here.
Oh, Christy.
- I'll just put the kettle on.
- All right, Ma.
Come on. Who's in there?
These kids.
What's happening?
Come on, let me in.
What's going on?
- Jesus, Mary and Joseph. Christy!
- What?
Your father's on the floor
and I can't open the door.
Jesus, Mary and Joseph. Paddy!
Christy, I can't open the door.
Get out of the way.
Christy, you can't open the door.
Oh, Jesus. it doesn't open.
Christy, push!
Jesus.
Paddy?
Jesus, Mary and Joseph. Paddy.
Seven pounds, five shillings
and sixpence he owed, missus.
I was the best of them all
Fair play to you, Christy.
Drinks for everyone.
- Take it easy.
- That's my painting money.
I'm trying to get some drinks.
Get her a cider. Shut the old bitch up.
Fair play to you, Christy.
Your old fella will never be dead.
How's me Ma going to survive?
Don't be worrying about them.
They'll be all right.
Terry, will you tell us about
when you and the old fella
carried the fireman up the ladder?
What happened there?
- Later.
- Yeah.
Give us a song, somebody.
Give us a song. Tom, give us a song.
Christy.
- Sing Daddy's favourite.
- Yeah.
As down the glen
One Easter morn
To a city fair
Rode I
There, armed lines
Of marching men
In squadrons...
Will somebody shut him up?
No fife did hum
Nor battle drum
Did sound its dread tattoo
And the Angelus bell...
Hey. Keep it down a bit there, lads.
...rang out in the foggy dew
He was singing that for his father.
His father was nothing but a mouth...
High over Dublin
like all the Browns.
All right, lads... take it easy.
Respect for Da.
I don't fight cripples.
Hold on.
Wreck the pub!
Somebody get the till!
Get the till! Get the money!
Get the till!
Drinks are on the house!
That's great, Christy.
No, it's not.
Why not?
He's not there. I've no eye.
What?
I'm not a painter.
I think it's brilliant.
It's the image of Da.
Poor Tom, what?
Yeah.
"All is nothing.
"Therefore nothing must end."
- What's all this, Christy?
- Nothing.
Sorry I asked.
Benny, would you help us?
Doing what?
Writing.
Yeah. Writing what?
Me own story.
Yeah. Course I will.
No.
Don't worry, Christy.
The book is great.
It's not bad.
Do you know what I was going to call it?
What?
The Reminiscences...
Reminiscences?
Of A Mental Defective.
That's a terrible title.
It was my blue period.
And you typed all of it
with your left foot?
I didn't do it with me nose.
I really wanted to finish it.
You'll hear it later.
I have an appointment. I told you.
Is he good-looking?
- Who?
- Your appointment.
Yeah, in his own way he's nice.
It doesn't matter to me.
You can meet who you like.
- Is he now?
- What?
Is he good-looking?
Yeah.
Are you in love with him?
You're very bloody nosy, Christy Brown.
I was only asking.
Would you like a drink?
I'm working. I can't.
Later.
I have a date, I told you.
Yeah. I forgot.
- You're a fast worker, aren't you?
- Read your book.
I can't with you staring at me.
So I'll look away.
Oh, God.
- She's very pretty, isn't she?
- Prettier than that bloody picture.
Just a minute.
Ma, are you in?
All right. Go ahead.
Jesus! 800, Christy.
Are you finished?
That was scrumptious, Ma.
Like you.
I fancy something sweet now.
What have you for dessert?
Ma, what have you for dessert?
Dessert?
Kids, do you not fancy
of drop of ice cream now?
- Ice cream, Ma.
- Get some ice cream.
Some raspberry ripple.
No, some Neapolitan.
- All right!
- The pink and green stuff.
But just this once, mind you now.
Won't see me spending money
on an ice cream.
Jesus, what's this?
Here now, Ma!
What's this?
It's Christy's money, Ma!
- Count it!
- Bring it here!
800.
That's more money than your poor father
ever earned in a whole year.
I can't take it.
It's for you. It's yours.
I can't take it, son.
Da was a bricklayer, Ma...
and I'm a writer.
I know it's mad money.
I want you to have it.
What would I do with it?
To start, get yourself a dress
and a new pair of shoes.
Will you?
Christy? You have a visitor.
- You look well.
- So do you.
Thank you.
Sit down.
Look, I won't stay very long.
Stay as long as you like.
I need to ask you a favour.
What?
A benefit.
Where?
Lord Castlewelland's.
Him? He's mad.
Posh.
Filthy rich.
I know you don't like appearing in public
but it's for a good cause.
- For the cripples.
Yeah.
I'll try to behave myself.
Sure it won't upset you too much?
So I'll anaesthetise myself.
No! Not too much.
How's Peter?
We have to get going, Christy.
Yeah.
What do you think?
Too much self-pity?
No. I think he's a lovely man
and not in the least sentimental.
Mary, do you really think so?
Yep.
And would you go out with him?
Certainly.
Now listen, everyone...
So you'd go out with me?
I might. He's talking about you.
I want to introduce you to one of the brave...
Well, no, quite the bravest chap
I've ever come across.
Yes, well, when Christy Brown was born,
the doctors told his mother
that it was just no good...
- Stay with us for a couple of hours.
- a vegetable for the rest of his little life.
But Bridget Brown, she wouldn't take that.
Oh, no. She knew...
Would you go out with me tonight?
I told you, Christy.
I have an appointment.
And so we have with us here tonight...
Are you in love with him?
Her faith in him and...
Well?
I asked you did you love him, Mary?
Introduce to you Christy Brown,
a man of genius.
Mary?
Christy.
Mary, I asked you a question.
- Do you?
- That's none of your business.
- So you won't answer me?
- Why should I?
- What are you afraid of?
- I'm not afraid of anything.
You imagine that people are afraid of you.
I'm not afraid of you, okay?
You're afraid of yourself.
- Oh, come on. Look, just...
- You're afraid of me.
I can't talk about this now. I'm going.
Why can't we talk now?
Now's good enough for me.
- I'll see you again some time.
- "Again some time." I heard that before, Mary.
Why is it always some fucking time?
Mary, stay!
Stay!
Christy.
We've got to go.
Right. Take me out to the firing squad so.
I must say I'm really honoured to be asked
to give voice to the words of Christy Brown.
"I was born in the Rotunda Hospital,
on June the 5th, 1932.
"There were 22 children in all,
"of which 13 survived.
"It would not be true to say
that I am no longer lonely.
"I have made myself articulate and understood
"to people in many parts of the world
"and this is something we all wish to do,
"whether we're crippled or not.
"Yet, like everyone else,
I am acutely conscious sometimes
"of my own isolation,
"even in the midst of people.
"And I often give up hope of ever being able
to really communicate with them."
- "It is not only the sort of isolation..."
- What's the matter with Christy?
"that every writer or artist
must experience in the creative mood
"if he is to create anything at all.
"It is like a black cloud,
sweeping down on me unexpectedly,
"cutting me off from others.
"A sort of deaf-muteness.
"I lay back in my chair
"while my own left foot
beat time to a new rhythm.
"Now I could relax
and enjoy myself completely.
"I was at peace. Happy."
Thank you.
Come on, Ma, stand up.
Ma! Mother, come here.
Christy, no, don't.
All right.
These are for you.
Give us one of them flowers, Ma.
You're not coming with us in the car, Christy?
No.
You're mad, Christy. It's great.
Get in the car before I kick your arse.
Good luck, Christy.
Good night, Christy.
Good night, Ma.
Go on. I'm all right.
Will you get in the car now, Ma? I'm fine.
Night, Christy. Be careful.
You're not me Da, Tom.
You take it easy, Christy.
Take it easy yourself!
Let's go.
Christy, tuck that under you.
Great stuff.
I hope to see you again.
Yes. I hope to see you again, Christy.
Before closing time.
- I thought I'd lost ya.
- Not at all.
- You can just see Joyce's Tower down there.
- Oh, aye?
And that's where JM Synge was born,
at the foot of the mountains.
What'll we drink to?
Let's drink to Dublin.
To Dublin? Why?
Because Christy Brown was born there.