Look at the birdie---look at the tree
My girls are the prettiest
known to the county
That's all
Mr. Durin, you've made us all models
Young ladies and gentlemen---
Now, young ladies and gentlemen---
alright, you cloud-headed
You've still 2 weeks before graduation
Let me remind you
Mr. Durin's picture taking is completed
You prepare yourself to Mr. Durin here
some time this week
an individual photograph
to appear in the Academy Album
Miss Kader---why are you standing there
as if transpiring?
ls it because you've left your books
in the study at the expense of
your splendid youth and innocence
or is it because you've already entered
into the miserable Harvard womanhood
there bitter with them?
Alright, stop all of that
or stop blushing
Seanacy---
He's not here
0h, you mustn't see me hiding
Hide what?
Happy graduation, Seanacy
Thank you
Happy graduation to you
l guess every thing, my dear
lsn't that nice?
We think the same thing
lsn't that crazy?
0pen your present, Johnny
lt's all about Raintree County
lt's illustrated with colored maps---
statistics and history---
and place adventures
lt's wonderful---just wonderful
Look---prominent citizens of
Raintree County
There're over hundred of them
Johnny, someday your name will be
the first on that list
Naturally
0pen yours, come on
Well, l think you'll like it---
it weighs 6 lbs
0h, l think Baron the most magnificent
man ever lived
He seemed so much in need of
a good woman to love and love him
He never really found one
Yes---
There's a photograph inside---
l wrote something on the back of it
Johnny, it's beautiful
You know what l think?
l think someday you're going to be
a great writer
lt's just beautiful
l've never heard such nonsense
wasting 3 days write this
What's this---a speech?
lt's not nonsense
lt's an honor to validate Victoria
lt goes to student first ranking
with scholarship
You know so much about it
What did you ever valid---validate---
whatever it's called?
Pap validated Victoria for the whole
Raintree County
Did you know that, Mom?
Your father?
Preach the sermon of the most
undesirable element
Waste the elegance that carries
a lot of ground
Undesirable element which we desire---
You object Pap elevating virtue welfare
to people?
What about my virtue welfare?
Why can't we get an inside pump?
Yeah, Pap---what about an inside pump?
That's not a joke
What you learn at that school?
You learn to have beer?
Your mother has pretty confused
with Heidelberg
You learn to smoke like tobacco?
Like a chimney
Huh, your father likes that ever here
he's German on the evil to tobacco
and at the regular pond some do it chew
and some do it smoke
But some end up there like still pole
l do offer the same
You know anything else?
Hm ---l learn my mother is a flaw and
what she said is hateful
by the way she said it
You never mount anything like---like that
Well, he ought to mount to something
He's related to one of the greatest
writers in the English language
Who's that?
Thomas Carlyle naturally
l think you're old enough to know
Joe, stop that foolishness
Well, l always thought one day
there'd be a great man in the family
Great man?
lf a great man is more than good
to find a job and farm this land
Why ever l curse with such a burden?
0h---which reminds me
How are you and Nell getting along?
Nell is a fine girl and she is---
Well, she's Raintree County
That means a lot of people like us---
people with roots
A man should not only marry his beloved
He should marry his region
A good wife is a good start---
taught greatness
Pap, define greatness
Greatness?
Well, a great man is one
who does good for others and
that's the way your father qualified
Greatness?
Ha---
lf that great philosopher Socrates
were living today---
lf he were chosen sitting on that crack
chewing tobacco---
that's America---that's greatness
Do l shock you?
How can l shock such unenlightened
ground heads?
Are you stunned, Mrs. Lydia Gray?
0h, stop looking at me, child
That's big brown cow eyes on mules
like wax in the plate
Yeah
Do l shock you, Miss Nell Kader?
Not as much as you like to
0h, there must be someone l shook
How about you, Johnny Seanacy?
l---relish it
You don't want to shock me
if you don't want shocking
Hm ---thanks, my boy
Now, about greatness---
We Americans measure greatness
in simple terms---in terms of money
We're always hunting with a tree of life
whose root is pure gold---
You have beautiful chest-like color
hair, my dear
But, there's another tree---
not of gold, but fulfillment---
whose flower is accomplishment
and fruit is love
They're the ways---
the ways of pleasantness
and these parts all leave to peace
Find that tree and
you'll find greatness
ln every land, every language toils
some of these trees
And we lndiana have our miss about it
That's the tree from which our county
takes the name
0ne day l ragged a creature who was
wandering on the shore of the lake
in the middle of the county
That creature was the man you all know---
Johnny Appleseed who spent his life
traveling to the pioneer West
planting apples in the wilderness
Among these thousands of seeds
there was one seed he cherished---
not Appleseed's, but exotic seed from China---
the seed of the golden raintree
The creature searched the tiny earth---
the one place---
Well, this one seed by taking root---
blandished
Someone from this county found
that place
But where that raintree was founded?
Nobody knows
Professor, how could such a tree grow
on cement in the county?
There's a swamp by the Paradise Lake
There perhaps stands the tree
lts sacred tonic trunk towering up
in chill silence
smacks deep in the middle of the county
Find that tree, boy,
and you'll learn
the secret of life yourself
Find it and become a hero of
Raintree County
Do you really think it there?
Why don't you have a real good see
for yourself?
Professor, you still haven't answered
the question
Do you really think it there?
lt's there alright
lt's there---
But the sacred fire is ready to be back
if you look for it
l'm sure you'll find it
What'll happen if what you presume
the raintree we don't find?
You see before you a seeker
who didn't find
No man of the race as the pitiable and
harmless creature you hold in vain
Alright, human---the show is over
Now, disappear---all of you
Attention, now easily slip away
Mrs. Gray, it's my time with you, huh?
Nell, what if you and l going to find
the raintree?
Professor said looking for the raintree
appears to be business
That asshole
So even dressed for it?
Are you serious?
Certainly l am ---come on
We mind it---find it
Johnny, not now
Why?
You scared?
Ah---is he fooling?
Look at him
What's up because of the tale
told by that idiot---
that expert in that calculated sanity?
Are you coming?
ls there the swamp---just because
Professor put a barge on you a year ago
about the raintree?
Would you take care of this for me?
lf you mind l take care this for you?
You can go ahead just now
Sure, Johnny---go right ahead
Huh, don't hurry back, brother
l hate with a thing like this happen
l'll never know how it happened
Yeah---it's really a shame
Well, Sir---is it Johnny Seanacy?
More like Johnny Appleseed
Ha---where have you been, Sir?
l'm walking
Get in, Johnny---we'll take you home
Come on, Johnny---get in there
Poor boy, you look half drowned
lt's nearly all drowned
You mean you look for that---
what you call it?
Yes, looking for the watch, Galwood
Did you find it?
No
0h, what a shame, pal
0r a pitiable harmless creature
Johnny, tell me what happened
Yes, brother---tell us all about it, huh?
Well
Boy, it's hard to tell us like this
Galwood, when you tell our folks
about it---
Huh?
l mean, say, you get the story straight
l entered the swamp like around here---
see it around that way
What are you---
0h, excuse me---you're quite right
l entered the swamp this way and
shove coming along that way
That's how he came over the swamp
‘You find the raintree?' l said
‘No' he said, ‘l nearly all drowned'
l figure that tried to cool his head---
But then she said
What did she say?
She said what a poor
‘pitiable harmless creature'
What's going on, boys?
0h, hello, Dr. Seanacy---
We were just talking about
your son Johnny
Nice brew
Don't you know your body is temple
of the spirit?
And you defined and polluted with
the devil brew you've had here
Why you say so, but---
Why don't you come around to our
next gathering, huh?
Come around to take a total afternoon
to pledge
l'll take the pledge right now
0h, no---we want men to take pledge
only when they're sober
But if they're sober, what's the sense
having the pledge taken place?
Wait, man---l want to testify that
l've been drunk for 2 weeks
l buy beer, wine and most of them
for friends
l'm drunk here now this minute
l can't find a man who can drink
as much as l can walk straight and
l can still foll any man around the county
Thank you now you just---
mark it day and hit town
Stand at any corner and listen to the
chapter of referendum of voice---
didn't he?
l hoped this subject under discussion
was sufficiently elevated to engage my interest
However---
Professor, we were just talking about
your prominent student---
Speak of angels and hear their wings
Hm ---not that prominent student
Ah---Mr. Gray and his charming wife
How the entire world of possibility
did that chilly January win
such a blithesome man?
That reminds me---
Do you know the story about the old
judge who married an 18-year-old lady?
Sure you'd excuse me
Ha---
0h, Pap---
Wow, here comes the hero of
Raintree County
l guess he'll go again for the raintree
Ha---
Bob is here shitting his big fat mouth
again
Yes, man---if you really want to be hero
in Raintree County, all you gonna do
ls play the Flash Burgins
for the bare-foot race
Flash Burgins?
So you're Johnny Seanacy
Could be---who wants to know?
Do you hear that boy?
Should l tell this child who l am?
Why don't you tell him, Flash?
Son, you'll give me great satisfaction
and relegation to introduce to you and
these handsome intelligent dummies that
l'm the gentleman
who's better known as Flash Burgins,
fast runner in Raintree County
Never heard who he is
Listen, child---he's me
l certify most of the runners in the
north and the south
before they're qualified for the
0lympic Games
l'm half the horse and half the asshole
in their spare time
l buzz more skulls and rag more campus
and chase more ladies---
That's true
And there's a fine jump this year
Now little boy like you should
stand by and watch
Now who are you?
l'm Johnny Seanacy and
l can outrun any mule in the county
Come on, lad---what are you waiting for?
l race you right now
Alright
Race---
How about the church over there---
alright?
Right, any place you say
0n your march---1 ---2---
Stop it
What for?
Put your coat on, Johnny
They're not racing
This man Burgins here is afraid to run
you in regular official
because he's frightened of
losing money
Here's hat on somebody
l give you 1 for 2 note
You're just talking---
you know no one here can match you
lf someone came up here with hard coins
you'll try to wake out
Try me and see
Gold?
My yarn is type of a teacher---
a molder for the young mind
This is done
This is not much, but it's the mind
l mold
l'll cover---me and the side kick
l'll postpone it to July 4
l'll take a bite of that myself
Strange, Johnny---but this is a sure win
See you in the race time, Johnny,
and l promise not to beat you for a while
Until then we'll see
Why did you do a thing like that?
Well---
Excuse me
lt has been 5 years since anyone laid
a bet against Flash Burgins
Now, if you can beat Flash, we'd clear
the biggest bit of money
ever waged in Raintree County
Fine---
What happens if l don't and
lose all your money?
My dear boy, l've certain well-laid
plans which at the moment l'm at liberty
as to what do l vote, not even to you---
dear boy
My plan is called for a certain---
concentration of capital
l don't know, Professor---
sometimes you bother me
What are you up to?
Not more than 20 ways---l guess l can
Now, you relax for the athletic order
ahead
You're going to win the race
You're going to be the hero in
Raintree County
l got to go
And your beautiful girl
would be the carnival feat on your
sun-colored lucks
Gonna be fine---don't move
Here we go
Look at the birdie---look at the tree
My girls are the prettiest
known to the county
Alright, you can relax
Thank you very much
0h
0h, it's you
Alright, you're next
0h, yeah---sure
Stand over there please
Now stand properly still
Hurry, Siona
Sure
0h, put this gown on
Let me help you
Look at the camera please
Please look pleasant
Here we go
Look at the birdie---look at the tree
My girls are the prettiest
known to the county
That's it
That's all?
Huh, how long it's supposed before---
l mean l was just wondering
how many days before l can...
Maybe 2 or 3 days
2 or 3 days?
0h, that's fine---
Ah, l'll see you in 2 or 3 days
Wait for me
0h, l didn't mean to scream
l'm afraid you'll find me
very unlady obviously
l like unladies
l saw you down the street ready to run---
what happened?
Well, me---postponed to July 4
You're a fast runner?
Pretty fast
l'm pretty fast runner myself
Well, how about a race some time?
You don't believe me, do you?
You'll be surprised how fast l can run
l'm as good as you can
You're Johnny Seanacy?
Say that again
Johnny Seanacy---
l found out from the phone book
Professor
Boy---you're definitely ready to graduate
l was never so embarrassed
Why?
Because l screamed
l enjoyed it
This is where l live
You live here?
Hm ---
Come on, Siona---you slow as a swan
l'll be saying goodbye now
You live by yourself?
l have 2 nigger girls to do the work
l love this house
l just opened it up again
My Dad loved it too
He was Senator for Louisiana and
New 0rleans before
Some people thought he could be
president
l mean President of the United States
We had---that what we had before Daddy died---
the plantation in New 0rleans
We had another one outside Bubana
When my aunt died last year---
l inherited this place
My name is Susana
Johnny, you want to say something?
0h, no---
You're cute---Johnny Seanacy
That July 4 race---what happens
when you win?
Well, according to a friend of mine---
lf l win, a beautiful girl will place
a wreath of olive leaves
on my sun-colored lucks
l like to be that girl
Maybe can be arranged
0h, it can be arranged alright---
l'll arrange it
You know l think l'm going to take
my picture too
There's always nice surprise---
Huh, what did l say?
Nothing, Galwood---
that was made for Johnny
0h
Johnny
Thank you, Ed
Nell
Ah, Johnny, there you're---
l'm looking all over for you
How are you feeling?
Nervous
What you need is calm down---
you nerve is over juice
Good luck, Johnny---
l got a payback on you
Thank you---l'll do my best
How about a little drink?
0h, l used to lemonade
Lemonade?
Lemonade is something
that will give you ulcer
What l mean was how about a little
drink of Bourbon
Bourbon---me?
Now, don't get excited---
all l mean was just---
Even the present President would agree
the whole time l put it in, Jack
A draw---
God bless you
How about a little drink?
This old horse---
he doesn't think
l shouldn't touch any draught
Just to be sociable
Well, l'll give if you both drink
alright
Splendid
l've never been drinking in my life
What's going to happen l come out here---
Son, it'd be good for you to turn up
those muscles that's give you extra---
Forget about it, Professor
l forgot this boy can never win yet---
Burgins, l'll match you drink for drink
0h, come on
Let's be sociable
What to be, boy?
You name it and l order
Ah, what do we get?
How about a little Bourbon?
There's a couple of bottles right
out of steer---a bottle for each boy
Ah, just a minute---
let's have the drinks
poured from the same bottle
Why?
l just don't want any trick monkey do
around here
What are you---
we just have a bottle for each
They'll drink from the same bottle
Wow, you don't mean to say---
Kid me a fool, Professor
That's a new situation that you may do yourself
May l---?
Professor, l don't trust you---
you got sneaky eyes
lt's tea---cold tea
And you---you must've thought it
really a good thing
And fill it right up
Alright, man
New, let's get started
Johnny
There's nothing to it---nothing to it
Come on---just fill the glasses
Johnny, you're unable---
How do you feel now?
l feel fine
0h, that's enough
Gentlemen, this boy is not used to
strong alcohol
Just to be sociable
Professor, don't worry about me
There's nothing to it, really
Stand back---give the boy a chance
Good work to Jack---alright to youth
New gentlemen, stand back---give me room
How you like that?
l tell you l've got another trick
l want to show you
Watch this---give me a hand
Alright, boys---watch this
That's enough---dry him off
That's only God would choose
He's out there now---
laughing to beat the kid
How dare you play a trick like this
on your best friends?
And poor Johnny here who never drinks
in his life
0h, he'd have been killed fresh
Flash is there hours ago
He bid me to chase---yelling for action
You'd better get Johnny out there
Johnny, this is it---are you ready?
Yes, let's go on ready
0h, l'd better put on my pants
Hello, boys---help yourself
When l wanna voice, you wanna be set
by hailer like this
l wonder a cannon Johnny can hear it
lt'd be 1 , 2, 3 and bang
Now remember, Johnny
l got 100 bet on you---100 dollars---
good luck
Where's it?
ls that we end up?
Yeah
How about the girls down there?
You think too close?
They'll kill themselves
0nce again, boys
Alright---quiet everybody
0n your march---1 ---2---3
Who won---?
We've done it---we won 250 dollars
To me is 150
Where's Flash?
The king is there---long live the king
Johnny
Nice to see you around here
Quiet voice
You've beautifully done it
Johnny Seanacy, allow me to present
to you on behalf of all these people
Present this wreath to the---
victory belongs to this boy
What about that race you and l
going to run?
l wouldn't have a chance
0h
You, dear boy, are the wicked
pagan spirit
And you're the poor the financer
Today is the day of high hopes and
fair promises
Ah, l wonder the worker of the age
Professor, you've enough zidar
Hm, not enough---l gonna catch up with it
l've to protect my league
Why don't you run away and play with
this charming ambassador's
in the land of magnolia?
Let's go swimming---come on
What?
You're sick of that thing
But you can think anything
Ah, life---liberty and pursuit
of happiness
0h, l gonna hate to leave here
Leave---when are you leaving?
Tomorrow---l'm going back to New 0rleans
You can't stay for a while?
0h, you're sweet
But you can come to visit me some time
You'd love there for sure
You have to go?
Well, l only came up here to resettle
the house
l was going to sell it---
but l think l'll hold it for a while
When you'll be back?
l don't know---maybe never
Tell me about the raintree
Where did you hear about that?
Do you think you'll never find it?
You don't think it a joke?
No, l believe it
l'll be looking for the raintree always
Supposing you do find it---
0h, it opens all locks---
it heals all wounds
Yes---maybe l'll never see you again
Nell
Nell---
lt's silly---you've been running away
from me for weeks
Why don't you talk to me?
You weren't so anxious to talk to me
when that girl was in town
What do you mean?
Are you mad just because l saw her
a couple of times
A couple of times?
Huh, did you like that book of poetry
l gave you?
Yeah
No, Baron was immoral---
he was a libertine
He was a great writer
l think being a good man is
far more important
Maybe a writer has a lot of experience
0h, so that's it---so that's what you're
doing with Susana
Johnny Seanacy---Baron of Raintree County
That's right---l'm a genius
Maybe someday l'll write
About what?
About the sullen tales l've known?
No, l think l'll write Raintree County---
about the lndians
when they first came here...
about Johnny Appleseed and the raintree---
The raintree?
That's another thing, Johnny
That day you went chasing the raintree
l was waiting for you
l didn't know where you had gone---
but l knew the swamp
l'm sorry---l guess l didn't realize
You just didn't realize anything
Johnny---to some people you're a man
of great importance
Your exact location is of intense
concern to---to some people
l'd better go, Johnny
Not yet
Johnny
Please
Johnny, l'd better go
lt's getting late---we'd better go
0h, no---you don't
Who's that?
Why don't you move up here and
find out?
So it was you
Who would you think it was?
You know anything about this?
You got anything to do with this?
Doing that?
The Professor---he ran off with Lady Gray
lf he is still in the county, he'll get
a chance out of thousand to get alive
We've got hundred men looking for her
Nobody can come to this county and
run off with another man's wife
lt occurs to me, young man, you're
a friend of this---
this man's
But a thing like this---
there're no nobbles
Whose side are you on?
l'm taking Nell home
No, l'll see you tomorrow
Alright, young man---l'm still waiting
for your answer
You'll get yourself a long wait---
l'm going home
Hello, Johnny
And what have you been up to?
Where's Lydia?
Wonderful woman---l did try carrying her
away from her husband
That's the day you won your race
Where's she?
She had missed the train
at the 3-mile junction
0r we'd have been hundred miles away
by now
As l got back to the buggy, 3 men
with guns marched up to the platform
l grasped the situation once thereon---
But that was only the beginning
0n the way back, the first man l met
asked if l heard about the man
who ran off with a man's wife
l'm a stranger here myself, l said
0n the road, l met a troop of camions
caring for the station---
Where's Lydia?
She's home right now
waiting for Mr. Gray
l took her straight back home
As for myself, l took off
like a street beggar
l guess you think l'm a bit scoundrel
right, Johnny?
l don't know---l don't know what l think
Don't think too bad of me
l suppose the heroic thing to be done
would be to stick around and
let the outraged husband discharge
his fury with a shotgun
But l hate that Sanctimonious warthog
too much to give him the satisfaction
Besides, l was scared
But one thing, Johnny---
Nothing happened---absolutely nothing
And that's the end just for it all
lf there's any phantom to be hanged---
the county would say
there might be some truth in it
Alright
l just managed the whole thing badly
Did you?
Come on
Where are we going?
You got to get out of the county
Well, good idea---it occurred to me
Johnny, why not up with us?
Study my example---
get out of Raintree County---
someone like you with a shotgun
Not me---you
l guess you're right
(ln French) Good for you---
good for us both
There he is
Come on---
Get on the train
Goodbye, dear boy---
go on for great better things
Get on the train
Wee want him
Where you've been, Mr. Gray?
Your wife has been home
for the past 12 hours
Nothing happened---absolutely nothing
He's a liar
You want to shoot me and later find out
he was right?
What are you afraid of?
You want him ---you take him
l'm going home
You get out of my way, boy---
or l'll cut your eyes out
Goodbye, dear friend
Remember me as a man who loves
Raintree County---
but just happens to lose
most of the people in it
Johnny
Johnny, l had to come back---
l'm going to have a baby
Johnny, this letter was left
on the door steps for you
0h, thank you
Johnny, this marriage you announced---
Sit down
l can't honestly say l'm entirely
approved specifically---
But, under the circumstances of necessary
haste with which you've gone into---
l know---l certainly understand
Anyway, l think you're doing
a manly thing
l hope the young lady achieves
what she appears to be
Judge not the year be not judged
l know, Sir
Marry her, son---and be happy
Thank you
You need any money?
l don't know---l don't think so right now
0h, there was a letter that
came for you---
l---l have it here
0f course
Hello
Hello, Johnny
l got your letter
Johnny, as one for whom you want for perfection,
l just want to say good luck
and wish you all the happiness
in the world
And the poem you wrote for me and
the picture you gave me---
l just feel that l want to return it
l thought maybe you want it back
l really don't want to give it up
lt's just that---everything has changed
and l don't mean anything to you
We don't mean anything
to each other anymore
Nell---l'm sorry
lt's not your fault, Johnny---
everybody knows that
lt was July 4---
You drank all that whisky and
you went out to the race
No, l was responsible---nobody else
That's so much like you, Johnny
Why do you have so much conscience?
Maybe that's why l love you
Johnny, l love you so much
Did that l wish l didn't---l wish l---
The words of Lawrence Baron on the back
you wrote for me---
‘Forever love and before ever..-'
Still forever---
l wish you well
You're right, Mrs. Seanacy
l like the river---it even smells good
l really don't understand it
Would you smell mouse like it too?
Now, there's something l understand
All you've to do is go south once and
you'll love it
Well, a north Yanky to the south
is not so easy to understand
You ever read ?
?
l've married an abolitionist, have l?
That's skeleton in my classic
Now, you mustn't joke about it
Are they friendly?
Anyway, the worst thing---
has ever been the abolition
Like what?
That cabin Negro blooded---Negroid
Just one little tiny drop in the person
makes him all Negro
They just can't tell either
ls it gonna be room for 2 of us?
lt's only sort of a hobby---
l'm taking with me wherever l go
This is Jimmy---l've had it the longest
Where did you get it?
He needs a bath
0h, Johnny---forgive me my foolishness
0h, l do love you so
When l'm with you, l feel like nothing
can happen to me as long as l have you
You won't let anything happen to me
Will you, Johnny?
Enjoy yourself, Johnny?
Very much
Then what do you think about
the ever-glooming south?
As l said, l love it---l do
That sounds general, isn't it?
What you really think of it?
Well, Sir---l think highly of it
l'm only worried by all this
aristocrat succession
Succession?
Remember, young man---
Union belongs to those who keep breath
in the cabinet
What cousin said means, Johnny---
if succession comes---
the north should succeed
Hear him say---
Sir, one thing you must understand
Johnny is a poet
He stays 2 months with his girlfriend---
therefore, he loves south
l'm not so sure you prove it
That's because he's a moralist
You won't get straight answers from him
He'll draw up opinion for another name
He's also a dreamer---
a seeker for the
meaning of life with capital wealth
Sir, your search has ended
Stay here with us and help us
to build our dream
We have thousand dreams
for a great republic on this soil of merit
with it's pretty homes and
most beautiful---women
0h, Sam ---you're wonderful
You shelf like some golden pitfalls
Cousin Sam ---Johnny doesn't like slavery
Does Johnny like to waive slaves
in the north?
Johnny doesn't like misery anywhere---
north or south
Here comes misery now---my wife
We're talking about the north, my dear---
slaves in the north---
Sam, you're boring---
l'll borrow your husband for a while
Excuse me
Don't look so serious
Here old men can only play
their dream of gold---
lt's not that---l'm counting
Cousin Johnny, are you ever in love?
Huh?
l mean---were you ever really---in love?
Cousin dear, l'm in love
You know l love the way you say that
You did such a noble sound
in your precious accent---
Frankly, Johnny---cousin Susana just
isn't the right type for you
You're an attractive young man
0h, Susana, why disposed---
she didn't marry down here?
l guess supposing down here people know
too much about her
Don't you hear me?
You've borrowed my husband long enough---
cousin Barbara---
l reclaim him
0f course
l must've been beautiful
0h, it was, Johnny
lt was all white when
l was a little girl
Marble house was right above over there
Johnny, our neggars built it by hands
The furniture came from France
lt was so beautiful
The tower columns shed the veranda
l used to play there when it rained
The garden was so lovely cool
with roses and lilies
How this fire started?
No one knows
Really?
That was my Daddy and Mama buried
l was lucky to get out alive
l slept next to Henrietta at this room
She was burnt too
Who was Henrietta?
She was my dearest friend---
she was a great lady
How old were you?
Three---maybe 4
And you could remember it all?
Yes---no, l don't know
l can't remember what l exactly saw
l was told later on
0h
What's the matter?
These used to be a little cabin
over there
l guess it's gone
This is where they buried her, Johnny
0h, you can't imagine
how lovely she was
She took care of me---
she was a great lady
l'm not ashamed to say that
although she was a Negro
0ne of these slaves?
0h, no---she came from Cuba
That was where l was born---Havana
Daddy was there for several years
and then came back with us
lt's funny to think of her now
Think of her lying down there
if she's lying down there
What do you mean
‘if she's lying down there' ?
lt's sort of family scandal
Some people say the graves were messed
My aunt said she wasn't sure if it was
her Henrietta sleeping in Mama's grave
l---l don't understand
l love you, Henrietta---l love you
Dear
Johnny, l know you don't understand
There was everything to me
because of her l was never alone
And now---do you feel someone watching
over us?
Just nobody here
How do you know?
Johnny, about this---this neggar girl---
l---l lied to you about it
lt---it never happened
Why did you tell me this?
You asked me about it
Well, you don't think my Mama---
You don't think my Mama would ever
allow me to---
l---l was always with my Mama---
l was always by her side
Why---why she loved me so much?
She never allowed me out of her sight
l---l was always with her
Susana---should we go home?
Good evening, l'm looking for Mr. Durex
Come on in, dear
Right in here
Thank you
Bobbie
Johnny, how do you know l was here?
Barbara said you were with Sam ---
she said you were here
Listen---l like to talk to you
Can you wait there?
We'd drive miles home
when we could talk then
No
Let's go in there
Would you excuse us?
Johnny, how about a drink?
Bobbie, what's all about
Susana's family and the fire?
Well, it's just old family scandal---
Johnny---but it's pretty gluesome
You see the day they had trouble to
identify a man in the,
fire but a woman
And the woman was another matter and
one of them was a lady of color
Why you go after that?
l like to know
Well it all began when Susana's mother---
you know
l don't know
She went insane
Susana's father gave up everything
to take care of her
At last he gave us his business
to seek her sense
But what they tried was too far gone
She couldn't be cured at all
lt was in Cuba
That's where he met another woman
What about the fire?
There were some wrangles---
2 bodies were found together
So?
So it looks like something funny
had been going on
They might've been killed
before the fire
l mean everybody else got up and away
Why didn't they?
That's the question of identification---
which woman was that woman?
Which?
There was talk of Susana's father with
the woman who was found in shock
The woman---the woman---
who was found with?
l exaggerated, Johnny
Anyway, the thing was hers---
it was better the way as it was
0f course, there was a lot of talks---
You know how woman talk in this family---
women are worse the most
l don't want to scare you, boy
But you don't need a private life
because you've a beautiful wife
That's the worth of it
Alright, what happened after the fire?
Well, nothing much
0h, the excitement Susana had taken
and disappeared for 2 or 3 days
l forget now
They found her finally
She was in Henrietta's cabin
all the time
And Susana had to go up
to her aunt's place in Pennsylvania
That's all l know about it
Does anybody else know?
There's just one person---
Who?
You've to wait until she's ready
to tell you
Not Susana?
lt's Susana
Susana was 3 years old
0h, my boy---you think you marry a child?
Well, at time of the fire, my cousin
Susana was 9 years old
Dear, l got it away from here
Alright, Johnny---where should we go?
Could we go to Europe?
No, l like to go back to
Raintree County
But why?
We've plenty of money
Honey, l---l got to get a job---
l got to work
That's why we should be back home---
so the 2 of you can be resting
Johnny, l haven't been very honest
with you
You haven't?
When l told you l was going to have
a baby, l lied
l'm not going to have a baby
l lied because l wanted you more than
anything l ever wanted in my life
Because l---somehow l just---
0h, l don't know
Darling, one thing you must understand---
l love you very much
You'd never leave me, wouldn't you---
Johnny?
Hm ---l'll never leave you
l love you---let's go home
0h, yes---Johnny
Well, Miss Nell Kader---shame on you
While here my husband and l have been
home settled this time
you have yet to call on us
with your prettiest escape
l leave the breeding to you
How do you like here in
Raintree County?
Well, l hardly feel this town
so small anymore
Whatever you do for the day?
l take walks
How really?
You tell me who you walk with
l'm interested in all aspects
of real life
You won't be interested in me---
l walk alone
l just don't understand here
You're still young, you know---
and pretty as a swan
Are you interested in man?
Perhaps
Well, good---l just talked to you
like a school teacher---
like Johnny
You know, Miss Kader---
a school teacher
almost has remote little habits
like read and write and mess around
in the classroom
Anyway, l did want you to know
you're always welcome
Any friend of my husband's is
a friend of mine
And Johnny always did tell me
all his best friends in Raintree County
You're the best---goodbye
Hello, Johnny
0h, where you pop up from?
No place special
Galwood asked me to marry him
Mr. Seanacy---
Hello
He's going to politics---
what do you think, Johnny?
l mean you're always---
being my best friend
l think Galwood will make
a fine politician
You know that's not what l mean
Mr. Seanacy---a few months in your class
l learned more about poetry and
politics and life and---
that l've all the time going to school
The students seem to enjoy
creeping up on me
They're all in love with you
Teachers get falling in love with
is not occupation, right?
Me was different---
l fell in love with the student
So did l
All l thought was a mistake, wasn't it?
She tricked you into marriage, Johnny---
she wasn't pregnant
lt's one thing people around here
can't do without denial
l'm sorry, Johnny---l'm so ugly
No, Susana and l are going to have
a baby in April
l want you to know you're my
best friend
Well, l'm very happy for both of you---
until then, goodbye
How do you feel?
0h, l've trouble to sleep again---
that dream ---
Why you got up so early?
Doesn't it school election day?
l got to vote
You were out so late last night---
speech---Lincoln?
l wasn't the only one up there
The speech was fine
Thank God when Jones delivered it wise
You want to read it?
Come in
Morning---Mr. and Mrs. Seanacy
Good morning, Siona
Galwood Vs Jones---
l always wonder what's the beast for
l give you one guess
Galwood Vs Jones---
Youngest candidate ever to seek office
in lndiana State Legislature last night
rounded up his program campaign
at 3-mile junction
His enthusiastic denunciation of
teachers who used schools as platforms
to corrupt the youths of
Raintree County---
Those who stand on slavery question
were most violent that
Jones declared the best look to
democracy they only wanted to shit
A certain young teacher who instructs
the young, inflammatory and seditious
about the abolition includes a domestic
arrangement of his own home to colored people
The status with respect to freedom whose
protection of abolitionists claims monopoly as---
Who said who's?
Questionable
Can you guess who's talking about?
But l think he's right
l think politics like charity
should begin at home
That's exactly what l intend to begin
What about Daisy and Siona?
What about them?
Honey, you lied to free those girls
and get rid of them
But they've been with our family
since they were born
They'd be unhappy any place else
l just don't understand you, Johnny---
after having insulted me
l just don't see how can you go on
being an abolitionist
Susana, you're not south now---
you can't have your slaves here
Johnny, l wish you wouldn't pick on me---
l don't feel well
Honey, l'm not picking on you
l---l just don't want slaves in my house
Alright, l wish we can get away
from here
l don't like this place
l just assume limited as a goat
in the hole
What anybody in the south ever did
to hurt you?
You know how nice and sweet they were
and how much they loved it
Jesus, l just don't see how you can
support a man like Lincoln---Lincoln
Why you despised Lincoln so much?
l mean it---that's well-known fact
You must've heard about it
What's about the fact?
l mean the fact Lincoln has
neggar blood in him
You don't believe it?
As Galwood or Jones
Dear, all l ask you just get rid of the girls---
pay them wages and do whatever you want
You don't love me...
you never did love me
You hate me because l'm southern
You've been asking questions about me
Dear, do what you want
But if those girls are not free by tonight,
l won't come back to this house
Hello, Johnny
Hello
ls it a wonderful victory?
You mean Galwood or Lincoln?
l haven't thought Galwood around here
You know sometimes being sick of people
is just afraid of people
You were so wrong with what you said
about Galwood
l think Galwood would make
a terrible politician
He was born in the year of 1835
with a little capital he built in 1860
That's funny
l also think he'd make
a terrible husband
How's he with you now?
Just fine
Good
Now you look---you look older
l'm older
How's everything with you?
Fine---
Good
Well, l guess it's good time ready
to say goodbye
Say what?
Say goodbye
Goodbye?
Hm ---
l'm going to lndianapolis
to live with my---my sister
l'm sorry---l mean l'm sorry
to hear you go
Goodnight, Johnny
Goodnight
Surprise---hello, our host Johnny boy
Johnny---it's for you, honey
lt's a party for you---
Galwood helped me do it
Dear---
A drink, Johnny?
Thank you, no
0h, come on, pal---
l made this punch myself---
old lndian recipe---pure corn and
a little bit of lime
0h, aren't you gonna congratulate me
on the personal triumph
for my stand on slavery?
You don't stand, Galwood
You point like a bird
set upon opportunity
Well, to you l'll turn any shoe
l admire your humility
Darling
Quiet, everybody---
l've an announcement to make
Daisy, Siona---come here
That's a wicked speech, Galwood---
l'm ashamed of you
Don't miss that, honey
l'd slap my own grandma better than
the abolition of the poll
Quiet, everybody---
l---l want you all to know
l don't keep any slaves in this house
ln order to support Mr. Lincoln's election,
l'll free both these girls
From now on, they'll work for me
for wages
Now we've all sisters under the skin
Siona---
Mr. Seanacy, we'll look after
your guests
Honey
What are you doing---?
Now you find me, Johnny
Go on beat me---hurt me
You're too good for me, Johnny
Honey
0h, Johnny---
What---what did l do wrong?
You didn't do anything wrong, honey
l love you, Johnny
l can do anything for you
You know---you know what?
Why don't we just start up
getting rid of these damn dolls?
Yes, Johnny---yes
You too, honey
Ah---
Now, maybe we have a little privacy
around here
Dear
Where's that doll?
Go to bed
No
No, l must find it---
l came up here to find it
You don't remember we got rid of
the dolls long time ago?
Come on
What's the matter?
What's the matter, darling?
0h, what's wrong?
l keep having awful dreams
The fire---Johnny, l'm scared
Susana, get some sleep, okay?
0h, Johnny
What's wrong?
What's the matter?
Wrong---l hate it come
Don't worry
l'm going---l'll be right back
lt hurts
l'll be right back
Hurry
Mom, it happened---can you come over?
Yes
Can you come right over?
0f course, Johnny---
now you pick a bad day
What's going on here?
You haven't heard?
They've attacked on us
That's for sure anything
l'm not so sure
Now say the Americans will never fight
each other
We'll settle our difficulties
peacefully
You mean right over?
Yes, Johnny baby---
come on
Every red-blooded boy in
Raintree County got into the fight
I'll be pig tide, hog tide---
Skined and stretched on the border---
Jack Seanacy
Flash?
Good to see you
How are you?
Fine
Corporal, we want get in the war
You want get in the army, the first
thing you'll do is disarm
Look, you jerk---
if you look me the same right,
will you write me down now?
I'll run and get a pencil
Wear a blue suit like that with a
couple of rifles,
l look like somebody
Flash---Susana is having a baby right now
Well, is that so?
Don't you worry, Jack
With me at this war, it'd be over
with your kid house broke
Your boy has had same guts as we had
back to 1846
You got to taste the Gulf of Mexico
by July 4, huh?
Right
l don't know everyone talks juice and
vinegar of this war
All we've done is lost for something
That's for Raintree County
Just the same, war is---
war is the most
monstrous thing to man's solution
Anything idea worth anything isn't
worth fighting for
Mr. Seanacy, your Mom said
you can go in now
Fastest man in Raintree County
Hm ---
Hello
lt's a boy
Yeah, it's a boy
Where was the other, Johnny?
What?
There's another---it isn't right
Dear, just your imagination
No, there was another---one with that doll
Did they throw it away, Johnny?
No, dear
Are you absolutely sure?
Absolutely
Dear, do get some sleep
Johnny
What?
I don't want you to go
I'll be right here
You won't go, will you?
Where do I go?
You won't go to the war?
You won't go to the war
No, dear---I won't go to war
GRANT BESlEGES VlCKSBURG
SEIGE 0F VICKSBURG ENTERS 35TH DAY
He'll make a runner like his Paw
Well, another little town will be made
reluctantly immortal by bloodshed
I got to have another bottle of whisky
with your father
To remove from battle seems to settle
my stomach
What did you have for your dinner?
No, it's the disease---
the disease is called ‘Civilian Paralysis'
l know---l guess l must be the only
civilian under 40 in the whole county
You got good reason, Johnny
I wonder
There're those you don't
Galwood would beat for good by
Syd Jones for instance
0h, he's a big man in the State Council
Maybe he could do better now
A hundred thousand happy boys have died
They couldn't spare me either
Galwood is a copper-head
Daddy, what's copper-head?
Well, l'll tell you later
How's your wife, Johnny?
She's alright
Hey
Hello, Johnny
This girl is jewel
She is
lt's something about a few years
in a big city
She left here a school girl
for sweetness in life
She returned a full-pledged newspaper
woman for justice in the crowd
Come on now---let's get back to work
Nell, how does it feel being back here
and free able?
Hm ---l like here better than lndianapolis---
it's a copper-head town
Daddy, what's copper-head?
Well, a copper-head is someone
who lives in the north
but sides with people living
in the south
You're still teaching---
still searching for the raintree?
That seems a long time ago, doesn't it?
You still think there's raintree
out there somewhere?
l don't know
Let's go and see?
Much too paralytic---
l know why you don't want to
look for it
You're afraid you'll find it
0nce upon a time, a war long time ago---
a little boy---
Daddy, when Mommy would come back?
l think she'll be back soon
Anyway, so there was the little boy
and he---
there's Mommy now
My darling---
Have you missed me today, Jimmy?
Have you missed me very much?
Mommy, l was afraid
You're afraid for Mommy---
isn't that sweet?
We don't leave you anymore, darling
Mommy is home---now you get to sleep
lt's way to your bed time---
sleep on luck, good boy
Goodnight, darling
Goodnight, Jimmy
Where were you all day?
Now Johnny, you know very well
where l was
l do?
l was in lndianapolis
lndianapolis?
As l very said on my note,
l just went there a few hours for shopping
What note?
Here---at the dress up
That's it---you see?
l can't find it, dear
l can't find the letter
But l put it there, you know
Don't worry, dear---
it really doesn't matter
You don't think they took it, do you?
0h, l must find it before it's too late
Why don't you find it tomorrow morning?
No, if l not find it now---
What did you have written on it?
Well, l---l wouldn't tell you---
l've promised not to
You believe me, don't you?
Yes, l do
You see, l have a great loss---
dearest thing in the whole world---
Daddy
Jimmy, my precious little Jimmy
Daddy---
Alright
What are you doing?
lt's the house, don't you see?
Something terrible might happen to him
What do you mean ‘something' ?
Nothing gonna happen to him ---you crazy?
l'm sorry, Susana
Jimmy doesn't like me
He loves you
You can't expect him to understand
everything
l don't understand either
l thought children were supposed to
create a boundary between parents
l think Jimmy has created
a great barrier
That's not true
Yes, it is, you 2 belong together---
you gonna part from me
l don't think so
0h, l wish only something l could do---
l gonna have something---
Dear, maybe you tell me
what happened the night of the fire
lt makes no different now---
don't you see, Johnny?
Things can't get better between us
lt's nobody's fault---
but it's such a pity
0h, Johnny, help me---help me---
you always help me
What can l do?
What happened that night?
l know something about that fire---
nobody else knows
l never told anyone
lt started not long before the fire
when Henrietta had been away
l was very excited the night
when she came back
l laid in the big house---
l couldn't sleep
l wanted my doll Jimmy, you know
And l remembered it left
in Henrietta's cabin
The house was so still that
l crabbed downstairs and went outside
The front door of the cabin was locked
So l went round to slip in
by the back door
lt was all dark inside the cabin
l listened---l couldn't hear anything
l crabbed to the stairs
l peeped up over the lamp
above the cabin
There were 2 people in the room
together
So l had the notion of what was like
between Daddy and Henrietta
l loved them both---
there was nothing
l'd have done for one of them
ln a few days Henrietta came up
to live in the house
There was my Mom who was so violent
0ne day when Daddy was away,
Mom came
down to find me in Henrietta's room
There was a terrible thing
She said awful things to me and---
all the time Henrietta just stood there
with her arms around me
So, that's why l hated Mama
l wanted to hurt her
l've been reading a book about
a person who wanted to hurt another person
He wrote him a letter---
but he didn't sign it
So l wrote a letter and left it in
Mama's picture album
which she was always looking through
lt was---it was just a little note
lt said ‘Daddy loves Henrietta..-
Yours truly well-meaning friend'
A well-meaning friend---l signed it
Was that silly?
That night l was in bed with Henrietta
lt must be very late when l found
l got to sleep
Suddenly l heard something like
fire-crackers
so soft and mouthful through next room ---
Henrietta's room
l guessed l must go in bed to sleep
because the next thing l knew l---
l woke up coughing
The room was terribly hot and
there was a cracking sound and
my dolls were on fire
l tried to beat the fire
out of my dolls
l began to scream
George---one of our neggars came through
the window
and wrapped me up over the blanket
lt's somehow---it's somehow l could
hardly yap
They said ‘You still have dolls'
They sent to stay with my aunt
lt was until quite a while after this
she told me about Daddy,
Henrietta and Mom
Finally she brought me to Georgia
and here---
Did you tell her about the
fire-crackers?
l told her, but she said to me not to
tell anything about it to anyone
But l didn't tell her about the note
l left in Mama's picture album because l thought
because l thought l---
maybe l caused her to do this some way---
Then l cried and cried,
but no one knew
what l was crying about
They thought it was about the fire---
but it wasn't just that
What was it?
She killed them ---she killed them and
l hated her
l still hate her and
l hate myself for what l did
You didn't do anything, my dear---
you didn't do anything
0h, l don't know---l don't know---
BULLETlN
DEFlNlTE REP0RTS 0N BlG BATTLE
AT GETTYSBURG
LEE ATTACKlNG HEAVlLY
VAST L0SS 0N B0TH SlDES
ACTl0N C0NTlNUlNG
Johnny
Mom, hello
You see this?
Rivals invade Pennsylvania
Johnny, l want to talk to you
about this
lt looks like there's going to be
a big fight
lf Lee won this one, we're through
How's Susana?
l think she's alright
Johnny, if you ever need me
or l can help about it---
Mom, you know you'll be
the first person l'll come to
Well
Johnny
What?
Nobody is here
What do you mean ‘Nobody is here' ?
She is not here
Susana
Jimmy
‘Darling, l've a safe conduct
to cross the lines
So by the time you read this,
little Jim and l will be on our way to Georgia
Don't be alarmed about me---
they can't follow me
l'm outwitting them this time
They'll stop at nothing---simply nothing
Unless l can get away from them ---
my life is not worth anything
You understand, don't you, Johnny?
You understand
Your loving Susana'
lf you find her, what good will do?
lt's all hopeless and useless
You can find Jim after the war
But right now what you're doing
is crazy
That's fool's madness what it was
l always have the high hope---
Well, what l mean is you're
such a long-headed boy
always so full of laughter
Now, she's drained and left out of you---
who do you have to do it?
She's alright, l tell you
l know why you're doing it---you pity her
Pap, l love her---
You take care of yourself, Johnny
Don't worry, Mom
l don't think the war will last
any longer
He'll be back anytime
l think of hope, kid
Dear Lord,
please bring this boy back
safe and---Amen
l've been with you for lifetime
l believe this is the shortest prayer
you've ever had
Board---
Goodbye
Johnny
My dear
Johnny, that's all l can say---
it's Johnny
lt's fine after all these years in this
town we stopped
and talked and---
l never had any trouble talking
just like it now
lt's true
Johnny, just come back safe
l'll try
Try hard
lf anything happened to you, it'd be
the most beautiful murder
since the beginning of time
Nothing is gonna happen to me
lt just can't, Johnny,
because somehow
l know we'll find each other again
l don't know how, but l know that
l always know that and that's why
l came back here
l never stop loving you
When l walked these streets,
l said this is his town and
these people are his people
and this earth is his---his earth
You just don't know, Johnny
Army---halt
Unarm
Dismiss
Well---while l'll be cousin l'll be squaw
Ladies and gentlemen---
Just start to dance to walk my Jack's
brand new pant
l've been squashing and rolling loud
Hey
l've been looking for you, Jack---
l see your name on the roll of new crew
Hey, boys
Store your kits over there
There's still space
That's port for you
Troopers, l want you to meet my old and
alcoholic drunken body, Jack Seanacy
Hey, Seanacy---
the man from Raintree County
Alright---now let's go
l just got here
Come on now
Sorry, l got to report in this soon
0h, let them find you---
they're pretty good
And besides, we got things to do and
somebody to meet
Come on
Who?
0h, never mind---let's go
Hold out, dear boy
Well---
Professor
Well, that was a long train
How did they set me on, Johnny?
What are you doing here?
Well, one battlefield is as dirty
as another
Where else should l be over the brave
half-yearly throwbacks of
Raintree County---my kind of people
Been chased by any towns lately?
0h---l never stayed long enough, dear boy
l'm a dear man walker on correspondence
with infinite capacity for being afraid
Tell me, what's the state scene
in lndiana these days?
l don't have to go around, l trust
0h, it's lack and off considerably
since you left
lt hasn't changed a lot, has it?
Time passes---
Deep scar of thunder has trenched me
and cared as on this bearded cheek
But bearded marks you know too many
a plant myth City of New York
0h, you're a freckle professor
Not at all
l loved that girl in Raintree County
He hasn't said this for 2 whole days
By the way, what was her name?
Her husband has somehow blacked my---
otherwise in memory
Lydia Gray---her husband only died
a couple of months ago
So the great mother finally got her
in a lukewarm bosom apocalypse, l presume
Measles, l guess
So the wit of guess is available
in case you want to know
Dear boy, for such romantic dreamer---
l envy you this simplicity of your concern
You see there?
What?
Those fires over there
Hm ---
That one hill behind it---the one behind
are lousy with the rats
They'll be fighting for sure
in the morning
They look close already
Ah, the white destroyer---
gun of the arms---a toss
To all the men who go out and die
because they have luck to be born
one side or another of the south
or the north---and here to sleep
Let's have a goodnight with it
until tomorrow
Crusaders, you're starting a journey
to a new and unknown land---
a place called hell
Toward---
September 19, 1863
Chucamargua
Reach of majority language means
‘River of Death'
May 16, 1864
0saka, Georgia
Another day of dramatic call is making
Sniper---
Canasona Mountain
June 27, 1864
The army twisted the railroads to
something called ‘Southerners Neckties'
Atlanta
November 16, 1864
The first mortar cracked at the south
of summer
This year our army will cut us off
all major operations
as it gonna strike straight into
the heart of the enemy
And you brothers gonna stick to job and
your job is next stomach of this war
You gonna travel the army in front of
the ranks and
you gonna point the way to provision
of the ranks
You gonna believe the fact and
lead the land
You gonna be on your own free and
forget command
Good
What's so good about it, north man?
l always say the general sends us
to our own deaths
Alright
Ha---
Alright, hold your mouth
Tell me, 0rvil---
Are you animal, vegetable or mineral?
What's mineral?
0h, there's no time to spare---
Johnny , leaving all day
So you join this play for August, huh?
Lucas sis the best fighter
in all the world
The time you're confused in ferocity
with ability
But never mind, Lucas,
if you should get squashed
allowing you with the small
and that's it
To Johnny Seanacy, it's upset
Even sleeping,
l hear him pray for his loving boy
Professor, go home
As a matter of fact, l'm going
l'm going to marry Mrs. Lydia Gray
Now the chief obstacle in our way
has been removed
Thinking one day, boy, there're many
a devil as guards of the night
The home glooms make us always better
l like it
l've been a road runner long enough---
so much for me
But you, l can't follow---
you're with the battles
We'll be marching to New Georgia---
we're free of command
Free of command?
So this is your way finding Susana
yourself
Hm ---yes
Well, toss to the union and the real
You'll see the country swamp
where is lying seeing volume
So it's not easy to find us
There're only ourselves where we are---
folks of the north all lost in lndiana
Loss an army of 60,000 men---
please return to the owners---
sign and label them
Flash
Look, a Raintree County out in office
l entrust myself to the hands
of a gentleman
Where's your heart?
Take him over to the house
When l get caught, that's what comes
my leisure
Now move---move
Some ware is this?
l fought in 6 major engagements---
from Gettysburg to wilderness---
never been unhorsed
And then l get caught by 2 bummers
That's why l came to my leisure
You're right, Captain---
l'm ahead to turn you over to the army
Where's Susana?
Do you know where Susana is?
Susana Seanacy
l'm Johnny Seanacy---l'm her husband
Do you know where she is?
Do you know where the boy is?
l'm gonna find them
She---she's gone long time ago
Don't---go her way
Come on down
Jimmy?
Daddy
Jimmy
That's my hero
Jimmy, l don't believe it---
l don't believe it at all
Captain---when does this war go to end?
l guess l can't go on much longer
We'll see---Captain Lee will buy
a long shot
Suppose all southerners will take
that career, huh?
Am l right
when somebody will continue
to fight for his career?
Jack, l'll tell you the truth
lt's too sad to know l'd blow
his head off
l never thought if they'd know it
Now Captain, l didn't
Mr. Seanacy, where you take Jim?
Back to my house there---
l'm trying to get him to Dubana
You'd better go by a close cut with me---
l'll probably prove myself for
Probably much better talk to this
asshole donkey
And the war is over, you gonna get
Miss Susana?
Yes
Don't do this, Mr. Seanacy
l never should have told you
where she was
You don't know what she was like
when they took her away
You don't know, Mr. Seanacy---
she really got sickness
Nothing---
not all the loving care in this world
could get rid of it
l know Miss Susana---
me and old George upstairs
He saved her in the fire---
he carried her through the window
The smoke in his lungs, he has been
holding it ever since
And then she got sick
She talked most strange
about Henrietta who could be her mother
She said ovezr and over---
Where she was?
You crazy too?
l delivered Susana
And from that time on Mrs. Strait
could never take care of her
So Henrietta had a deal---
they were always together
Susana wanted Henrietta
to be her mother
0nly she hated the idea of democracy
Henrietta was---just like me
0nly then l knew what the child was---
then the war going on inside her
Alright, let's move
Thank you, Patsy
Jack
l believe he breathes bad
Let's make it quick
Flash, are you alright?
Flash
Stay where you are
You hit?
You need me?
l'd make it settled, the pitch one
Stay where you are
We got to get out of here
You want me to take the kid?
No, l'll take care of him
Don't wait by my side---
you got to race the run
lt's the only chance for the day---
prefer 2 of us
Alright, let's go
Hey you---come out
What's wrong you, bums?
Just want to see you still there
Here you're there?
Why don't you go and play
somewhere else?
You keep us out of beauty---sleep---
We gonna get you a good luck sheep
Shame it---you shoot that pretty close
That isn't friendly---you decide to call
Comer save yourself
Not just fast---the longer l gonna
save free
Pal, where are you coming?
Well, come on
0h, come on---what are you waiting for?
l came from Raintree County---
l can look at it---here
Another glorious victory
Hey, Joey---he's coming your way
He dead?
No, lucky dog---war is over by him
PEACE
LEE SURRENDERS T0 GRANT
Halt
Mrs. Roman?
Yeah
l'm glad---l'm Johnny Seanacy
Have l told you in my letter---
Mr. Seanacy,
that she hasn't changed
Mrs. Seanacy is mentally deranged---
suicidal
For the most part, she's normal
rather than rigid
Women are not very pretty, are they?
They're hungry mostly
We don't need to be on diet
We don't even have sanitary
Even with the war over, we're still
lack of everything
War or peace, nobody cares
Your wife is normal enough now
She's locked here because l thought
she might like privacy
Susana---l'm glad to see you
You shouldn't come
Mrs. Roman said you---
Normal?
l come to love this sound in that wood---
that beautiful holy sound of it
l'm afraid---even in my own happiness
with you here
l'm taking you home with me
Why?
l've always got in your way
No, you haven't
Now you might even find your raintree
Susana, there's no raintree
But l think there's---
and l say it over and over again
and l make both of us miserable
And then you begin to pity me
and l can't accept your pity
l'd rather be alone
l don't pity you---l love you
That's the foundation to build on
You don't think the foundation too
wicked after all this time?
We're in an incomplete kind of love---
Johnny
lt just wouldn't work
l like to try---l'd like to try
lNDlANAP0LlS & LAFAYETTE R.R.
SPEClAL TlME SCHEDULE
REMAlNS 0F ABRAHAM LlNC0LN
LATE PRESlDENT 0F THE U.S. AMD ESC0UT
Now Lincoln belongs to us all---
to all the men who died
Say goodbye, Jim ---
Jim says goodbye
Goodnight, Jim
We'd better say goodnight
Johnny
Yes?
l want to talk to you
What about?
You
Not tonight, Professor---
l got million compositions to correct
l thought the world of yours
is a larger issue
Compositions to correct---
that's a sublime vocation
l'm afraid so, Professor
You're quite right, Johnny---
it's not a laughing matter
Lincoln got a bullet in the brain---
our country is still rip apart
l for one take the most hopeful view
About what?
Lincoln's reconstruction policy
0h, it never got started---
it was too gentle for most people
Johnny
Galwood
l was just in the neighborhood and
down to railroad station
paying my last tribute to Lincoln
0h, that's wit of you
Good evening---ladies
l---l just tell you a few minutes
l'll be very brief, Johnny
l intend to run for Congress
l intend to see the barrier south gets
just it deserves
There's no longer a barrier, Galwood
lt's beaten---and it's bleeding now
You're sentimental, Johnny
Personally l'm a practical politician
What do you want from
the sentimentalist?
My election gets lead the big things---
for me, perhaps, the presidency
And for me?
You name it, Johnny
Let bygones be bygones---
forgive and forget
We each have a war to fight---
you in your way---
me in mine
Lincoln in his---but now---
Now Lincoln becomes a useful symbol
and you'd better cash in on it
l don't cash in on any man
Johnny, l'm organizing a new party
Galwood, you always belong to the same party---
the party of yourself
Get out
Well, how do you like that snob now?
Johnny, you'll run against him
Statesman, that's a splendid notion
You could do it, Johnny
l always said he'd be a great man
in the family
0h, Johnny, what do you say?
Not me
Why not you?
You wanna be burying yourself
in the books all your life?
l'm no politician
Some of the time you call yourself
natural attitude for it---
You run your actor choice---
He spends his days teaching his
half-form-mind children
So he spends his nights writing a book---
a great book to guide the lost
in the wilderness
The book somehow never got written
Well, what happened to it?
l don't know---the children got talk
That makes me wildly happy
Well, you really wouldn't understand---
you're such an awful teacher
l'm not my student adorable
You might make a good politician
Me?
Why not?
Right now, politics is on your brow
like a high fever
Hm ---
And the fever is mourning
Yes---if l could now leap out---
lie out promise to Galwood
best days ever seen in the back
of the train getting out steam
when l'm squatting back in my arms with
a boy lighting fire-crackers under me
Yes, l'm sorry l was so---
so big mouth---big mouth, huh?
Yes
Goodnight
Goodnight, Professor
My dear---perhaps even presidency
Goodnight, Johnny
Goodnight
Good evening, Nell
Goodnight, Mom
Johnny, l think you're a great book
of your own life
Don't spoil it
What you did just now was very clever---
but it doesn't solve anything
What are you talking about?
About the Professor---your candidate---
but he's not mine
Who would you choose?
You
Please
Johnny, who else could do with?
Who else could help you beat
the bleeding south?
0ne thing about the Professor---
he'll keep his word
Then he'll out lip and
out lie promise Galwood
What good he'll do with it?
Nell, l don't want to talk about it
Why?
Because l want you to do something
you're capable of doing?
Look---l'm out
l'm not going to run for Congress
Johnny, if you'd only just---
Look---it's final
Johnny, you can't escape responsibility
Nell---
Johnny, whatever you do,
l know you'll do it honorably well
Goodnight
l'm sorry, Susana---l talk too much
Nell
Nell, you still love him, don't you?
We grew up together
We love Raintree County
We went everywhere together
Yes, l still love him
lt's because of me---
because of me you can't run for Congress
Dear, it's not because of you
Because l'm sick
You're not sick---it's just the---
Well, l'd like to stay here in
Raintree County
0h, l wonder---l wonder things
would be different
better if you found your raintree
l bet Nell could find it for you
Susana, that was long time ago
l went looking for the raintree
l'm not even sure l expected to find
But at least l learned to see
the raintree
lt's not nearly important as
what you find looking for it
l'm happy with what l ‘ve found..-you
All my life, l want someone to love
and love me---
someone whose voice is touching my ear
in the night---
shut out the bad dreams---
someone who'll always be bound to me---
And that's him ---with such great barrier
Johnny, don't---
don't work too late, darling
Mommy, what are you doing?
Darling
Jim, l gonna do something for Daddy---
it's a surprise
What's it?
We mustn't tell him
or it won't be a surprise
l won't tell
You see l'm going to find the raintree
For Daddy?
Yes, darling---for Daddy---
then everything will be alright
l'll find the raintree and
hand it to him gently---
with all my love
Can l go with you?
No, darling---l take Jimmy
l don't understand
Jim, darling---someday when you're older---
ask Daddy about it
He'll be able to explain---
it's Daddy what's for
The thing---only happened to your father
because he can't stay one day to have his picture
Now l was there
Mr. Seanacy---
Susana
Susana---hear me?
Johnny---you'd better come with me
Jim
He hasn't been found yet
Johnny---
Jimmy
Jim
Daddy
Jimmy
Hello
Come on