Gentlemen
this is a corpse.
There is a tradition among medical
students that dealing with death humorously
makes things easier .
It doesn't.
There may be a successful Joke about death
in the abstract, but l have never heard it.
About death in the particular,
believe me there is nothing runny at all.
I have been a pathologist for over twenty-five years
I haven't been able to get a
Single laugh out of it yet.
For some of you this will be unpleasant;
for a few, perhaps - perhaps impossible.
Now fix firmly in your heads that
seven hours ago this was a living soul,
housed in an edifice constructed
by a supremely capable Architect.
You are about to violate it.
And when you do,
you will help yourselves
immeasurably as physicians and healers
if you do so - tenderly and with love.
Our purpose here today is to
determine the cause of death.
We will follow the method of Rokitansky,
which is to remove the visceral organs intact .
First, we will make a cruciate incision
from the suprasternal arch to the pubus,
and then, transversely as' well.
Thus!
''Seven hours ago this was a living soul ''
Well, that settles it.
I'm not leaving my body to Science!
You kiddin'? I may not even die!
ThatAarons puts on a
great show though, doesn't he?
Yeah - he doesn't get any laughs, though.
All right! So I'm nervous.
All right. You eating with us, Marsh?
No, I can't. I have to work the Lab tonight.
We got nurses -- we can get one for you.
Pretty? Who cares? They're alive, aren't they?
I'm saving myself until 'the right girl' comes along.
Be home later, Al . See you, Brundage.
It must be tough, living with both Mayo Brothers!
Luke's okay .. Do you know he's got
to clean up the Lab in order to eat?
Yeah .. but even so, y'know, there's
somethin' about him. What does he do for kicks?
He wants to be a doctor.
So what do we want to be? House painters?
He wants it more. A lot more than any of us.
How are you, Kristina?
My feet hurt.
Long operation?
It was a radical neck dissection... four hours.
Why that's not so long. Last week we
did an abdominal -- took over six hours;
we even had to replace the
assistant surgeon, because he ---
Is that your dinner?
Oh, I'm not very hungry.
You should eat.
You've got a lot to feed there.
I just don 't feel like eating.
Go on - take these. No thanks, Kris..
really... I' m not hungry.
I was looking for you upstairs this morning.
You were?
I'd like to ask you a favour...
You know that laminectomy that
Lettering is doing on Monday?
I wonder if you could fix it
for Alfred and me to watch ..
Well ... I'm really not supposed to do that.
Miss Hedwigson, report to Surgery B please!
It'll be alright for Monday. I'll fix it. Thanks, Kris.
All right - I'll ask. What happened?
Nothing. Nothing? Atiger like you?
This kid's very sick. She needs a lot of help.,
She's got an absolute obsession about virtue!
You mean she didn't go for you? Eh?
I think she's hyper-thyroid.
Well, there's plenty more fish in the sea.
Yeah - but this fish cost me
eighteen bucks in a night -club.
What is that?
Todd and Sanford - ''Laboratory Diagnosis''.
Oh yeah. I bought a synopsis today
from Brundage. I'll lend it to you.
You can't learn about blood
tests from an outline, Al.
If you don't watch it they're gonna drop you.
Yes, Dad...
Oh - you short of money again, Luke?
Why? From the Bursar.
What is it?
Trouble.
I'll have to see my father.
What did you do with it?.
Luke, I ...What did you do with the money?
Let me explain, won't ya? Is there any of it left?
Or did you blow it all?
Thatwas my mother's money
things she did without -- for me.
Please, Luke -- please don't
You -- drunk!
I know what I am...
Yes - I - I stole your money.
But l'm not Just an old man
you left alone in this place.
l'm a person -- a human being.
Your mother never understood that,
and you can't understand it.
You won't make it, Luke.
You want to be a doctor.
Ever since you were a kid
you went runnin' after them.
Just to carry their bags.
l'm sorry for you.
l don't think you'll ever make it.
There was something left out of you, Luke.
lt isn't enough to have a brain.
You have to have a heart!
and so please have your reports on the
intermediate enzymes
on my desk by tomorrow morning.
That will be all fortoday, gentlemen .
Hey, Al .
Yeah. Did you remember those slides?
l'd like to get 'em back.
l'll clean 'em up for you and
get 'em to you this afternoon. Allright.
Where you been? You missed three classes.
l've been trying to raise money.
l l'm out on my ear Monday.
Did you see your father? Forget it.
Oh... hey, how about the scholarship fund.
They've got dough in their..
l've been there. They only take
fourth-year men. l've been everyplace.
l got my allowance today. Here - take it.
lt won't help, Al. l need four hundred!
Take it. lt's a start.
Al!
Stop it, will ya? So for a
month l'll eat in the cafeteria.
You better hurry or you'll be late or class.
l'll see you.
Hey, Al...Yeah?
Could you ask your father?
Sure - l could ask him.
You know what he'd say?
He's the cliche expert of all time.
He'd say, ''My boy, you
know money don't grow on trees
the root of all evil -- lend a dollar; loose a friend
And besides, he hasn't got it...honest.
Go on - you'll be late.
Why me? Why'd you come to me?
You got me my job in the Lab,
you've encouraged me...
and you know l'll make a doctor.
Have you any idea of the kind of money l make?
l figure around eight - nine thousand.
That's exactly right.
And l've got three children, too.
They're going to throw me out.
Can't you at least get me
an advance on my salary?
l have no control over that.
Even if l did, how would you eat?
l don't know. l don't care.
But l have to have the money.
All right! Quit school,
go to work, come back again next year.
l can't waste a whole year.
l can't do anything else. l...
l just can't! Of course you can!
This isn' t the end of the world.
You're - you're over-reacting.
Marsh, you're wallowing in self-pity.
l want to tell you something.
l was a promising student, too.
l had to face the same problems
you're facing now - and a lot more.
You're not a jew.
l'm part of the five-percent they let in here
because they were ashamed
to keep us out entirely.
Now you've got me wallowing ..
Haven't you got a family?
Just my father.
Can't he help? He's a drunk.
All right- here's seventy-five dollars.
lt's all l can afford.
Give it to the Bursar on Monday.
Tell him you're going to hold up a gas station.
Pull out all the stops, lie to him!
Tell him anything. Get him to give you more time.
Here!
Sir - l don't know what to say.
l have a class.
This isn't a state institution.
We have to be very business-like about this.
l have to be very business-like about it.
Now l'll accept this payment,
but unless you have the balance in 30 days,
you won't be permitted to attend classes.
Yes, sir.
Marsh ...
do you think you can get it?.
l'll get it.
l was afraid you wouldn't get here.
How'd you make out?
l've got a thirty-day extension.
Then the rest of the money - or l' m out.
Okay -- now relax. She
arranged this for you, you know.
Gentlemen.
if we can remove the tumor
without injury to the spinal cord,
the patient may be able to walk again.
First operation? No, sir.
Used to it? Almost.
lf you faint, faint backwards.
He's not deep yet, is he? No, he isn't, Doctor.
Gentlemen, the patient is unconscious,
and normally should react to stimuli.
Sterile pin!
Miss Hagen?
Absolutely no response.
Now let's see whatwe can do.
Towel clips ....
Deeper!
Yes, sir.
Knife please.
Come over here, gentlemen, where you can see.
We'll make a vertical mid-line-incision.
That's it!
Put the dressings on. ls he light?
Stage two, Doctor. l want him almost awake.
Anatomically the operation was a success .
Now let's see if we've helped the patient.
Not too tight with that tape. How's the pressure?
120 over 80. Good.
High drama, ey gentlemen?
Men in white, acting swiftly against death,
flashing knives, flowing blood, mystery...
just like on television.
Don't be seduced by it. lt's mechanic's work.
A hundred years ago itwas
the physician who was important.
Surgery was left to the barbers.
He doesn' t mean a word of it.
You like Smorgasbord?
Not any more.
Next Saturday, at my friend Bruni's house,
l'm going to fix a big one.
You want to come? We'd love to come.
Saturday. Eight o'clock.
l'll meet you in front of the nurses dormitory.
You might regret this.
Now why shouldn't we be polite to her?
She did us a favor.
Don't say l didn'twarn you.
She looked at you like you were Smorgasbord .
Luke, are you sure l can't get
you something else? No, thanks.
No, thank you. l pass ..
l was thinking - couple smart
young doctors like you
maybe you could tell me?
At night l fall asleep,
dead to the world, just like a log.
And in the afternoon - after lunch - l feel so tired,
l'm Just no good for work .
Also - in the morning - l got gas on my stomach ..
Now what do you think is wrong?
l can't imagine.
Yah - well, l can!
Luke - whatwas that funny
joke you was going to tell us?
Yeah, Luke - how about that
funny joke you were going to tell us?
Please tell it, Luke.
Well -there's a honeymoon couple out riding.
The bride's horse rears up
and the husband goes ?over and grabs it
by the bridle and shakes his fist in its face
and says, ''Now that's one!''
What? That's one!
One, Oley...the first time. The first time what?
The first time the horse rears up!
Oley, that isn't the end of the joke!
Go on, Luke.
Well - after a little while the horse rears up again.
The husband goes over and he shakes
his fist in the horse's face again,
and he says: ''That's two ......Good. good.
The third time the horse rears
up the husband pulls out a big gun
Yah - a horse pistol.
Yah
He shoots the horse dead.
The wife says: ''Now why did you do that?
Killing a poor, dumb animal like that?''
The husband turns around. He looks her
right in the eye and he says: That's one!
You see, he warns his horse and then he shot him,
so now he warns his new wife in the same way.
Yah. Yah ... that's pretty funny!
Er - how about some more herring, Luke?
You like Svenskafood, Luke? Yeah.
Kristi fixed it.
All last night early this morning she worked.
She cooks good, hah? Wonderful .
She sews good, too. That dress - she made it.
Even her underwear she makes sometimes.
Believe me, she's got what it takes
to make some man a good...Bruni!
And a man would know where the money goes to.
And you know what she does?
Every month at least half her salary into the bank.
Please, Bruni!
How much you got now, Kristi?
Three-four thousand dollars, l think.
Kristi, you don't have to do that now.
We got plenty of time.
Hello - Mr. Revere, please.
Mr. Revere, this is Mr. Marsh.
How are we doing on that loan application?
Look, if l had a car and a hundred dollars a week,
would l be calling you ?
Okay - goodbye.
Do you mind if l walk with you?
No. Where're you going? Administration.
All right -- what's so funny?
You and that one with the horse's tail. O, what do
you know .. And a couple of others l've heard.
l worked in a hospital once where a student
copied the whole list of
seventy-five nurses from Ato Z.
He bet he could do it alphabetically.
Well, and what happened?
He flunked outwhile he was still in the ''G's''.
l .. eh. .. l wanted to thank you for the other night .
Oh, that's all right. No - l really mean it.
l had a wonderful time.
l thought, maybe, you'd have dinner with me.
Look - l know itwas pretty terrible.
They stuffed you 'til you could hardly move.
They bored you to death.
They didn't even laugh at your jokes.
Believe me, you don't have to take me to dinner.
But l want to take you to dinner.
You're taking a chance. You might be bored again.
You won't bore me.
Feel like something to eat?
No - let's walk a while. All right.
What are you thinking about?.
When l was small, l used to hate women like that.
Like what?
That girl in the movie. l used to think itwasn't fair.
lf things were arranged right
all women would be that pretty.
Well you're pretty, you've got a nice figure. Oh?
You know what l mean ...
you - you're put together right.
Everything fits - the way you move -
the way you walk - even the way you talk.
The other nurses call me
''The Swedish Nightingale''.
How did you ever happen to take up nursing?
Oh - l was six years old -and
l saw a nurse in a blue cape.
And l made up my mind right then.
So now l'm a nurse, but l still talk like Minnesota.
Well l like it and l'm not bored.
Aren't you? No, l'm not.
l thought you liked me, Kris. l'm not Dorothy, Luke.
Well now what's she got to do with it?
Oh, she goes out with the students all the time.
l'm not like that. l'm not
being catty - they don't ask me.
l'm Just not sexy the way she is.
You don't know what you are
- so stop talking like that.
What do you want with me?
Kris - l enjoy being with you... l like you.
l want to see you often. Luke .. l mean it. Okay?
All right.
And you don't have to run yourself into
the ground anymore, so you can cut that out.
l said all right.
Well, all right.
...and his right eye is swelling.
How often you see him? Who ? Who - she asks!
Three - four times. Since last Saturday? Uhm.
What do you do? We walk - talk. That's all?
He kisses you?
Well??
A little.
You like him, Kristi?
Oh Bruni, l love him - l loved him right away.
Weeks ago in the hospital when l first saw him.
And l don't know what to do. Do? Love him.
You don't understand, Bruni.
He wants to be a doctor!
Everything else is nothing next to that
Maybe that's why l love him so much.
Now what can l tell you you don't know yourself?
lf you find out he doesn't love you, don't see him.
But if he does, then what happens happens.
But - but l want ....You wantwhat all
women want. So l wanted.
So l got. . . . Oley, turn that thing down!
Cheer up, Kristi! Everything works out.
Yah - cheer up, Kristi! Everything works out ...
What is it Luke?
Mmmm? What do you mean?
Something's been bothering
you all evening. What is it?
Oh, just thinking ...
Kris, l've been trying to find a
right way to say this - or the right time.
Look, l love you, Kris.
l don't know when it happened,
or how - but l love you.
Now don't say any of those things about
students and nurses, or how bored l'll be
l wasn't going to,Luke.
Just tell me, tell me how you feel.
No .. l can't. Yes, you can.
Tell me. l can't. l don't know.
Do you know if you love me?
Of course l love you. l thought you knew.
l thought everyone knew. Can't you see it?
l loved you before you spoke two words to me.
That's what l wanted to hear.
And l want you to marry me.
But- right now l'm in such an awful mess,
l just don't know.
What is it? What mess?
They're gonna throw me out of school.
Have you done something wrong?
No. Well then - why?
Well - my tuition isn't paid
and l don't have any money.
Oh - is that all?
All? Only money?
l thought you'd done something wrong.
That you were in real trouble .
But they 're gonna throw me out!
Of course they 're not.. l have money.
You? Me. You heard Bruni the other night.
Well, it's true. l got plenty in the bank.
Oh, no ... Why not? Because it's yours!
You're so silly sometimes, Luke ... so proud.
Listen to me, Luke - and don't argue about it.
l love you so much ... l love you!
lt's my right to help you.
Kris ..
What's with you, Luke?
Three o'clock on a week night?
You're gonna have to get another roommate, Al.
Oh, cut it out!
You'll come up with the money somehow.
Tomorrow l'm getting married.
You're what? Getting married!
You're crazy. You can't...
Haven't you got enough trouble as it is?
Married to whom? Kristina.
Hedvigson? The OR? That's right.
Have you flipped your lid or somethin'?
l know what l'm doing.
You don't know what you're doin'.
This is not the kind of a dame you marry!
l'm marrying her!
Look -A Doctor's wife gets him patients.
She went to the right school -
her folks belong to the right country club.
She's charming. She was brought up that way.
This dame ought to marry a farmer!
Are you finished?
Don't l make any sense with you at all?
Oh, l get it ... you're doin' this to stay in school!
You're marrying her for her
money to pay for your tuition!
She's payin' for it, isn't she?
Well, isn't she?
Yes, she is.
Y'know the thing that kills me about you idealists,
is just how far you'll go.
l'm supposed to be the cynical type
but l could never do a thing like this.
Well, you've got a father to pay your way!
All right, then. You need the money -
take the money and blow.
Why do you have to marry her?
That's not the way it is, Al.
l want to marry her. lt's my part of the bargain.
You're cheatin' her right from the start, Luke.
You don't even love her.
Well she'll never know. She'll never find out.
l think it's a dirty, stinking, lousy thing to do.
You're taking advantage of a poor
square-head who's afraid of being an old maid.
You're lettin' yourself be kept!
l'm sorry. l'm sorry l said that.
You all right? Yeah - l'm all right.
Real civilized .... Doctors of medicine
What ... ? l was going to ask you to be best man.
Okay... l'm it, then.
lt's not all the way it sounds, Al - she's
well - nothing is just black or white
l know.
Goodnight, Luke.
Well, here we are! Yeah - here we are ..
And l imagine the neighbors know
that we've arrived, too.
Well - good night, Al. Good night, you two.
See you in the morning at eight.
A.M! Okay, Al. Don't forget to
look in the ice-box! Thanks, Oley.
Oh, my little darling!
Do you like it, Luke? Yeah - it's nice.
Oh, the kitchen's small,
but l found a place for everything.
And... l changed the bedroom around.
l think you've done a wonderful Job.
What's that on the pillow?
Oh - that's evergreen. ln the old country
they say that makes the babies healthy.
Olie and Bruni must have done it.
l wonder what Oley meant about the lce-box?
l'll go take a look.
Champagne! Oh - that was really sweet of them!
We probably don't have any champagne glasses.
l hope it tastes all right in these.
Do you feel different, Luke?
Different? l mean - do you feel married?
Sure l do.
l keep trying to realize it's really true.
lt is true. You're not sorry, are you, Luke?
Ha - of course not!
l guess every woman asks her
husband that in her wedding night.
You drink your champagne.
Oh, Luke - l love you . l love you so much.
l love you, Kris...
We have here a patient who swallowed his watch
and we got to find out what is ticking.
Scalpel, please! Ooh! A light one!
And now ve make a simple
incision from the xyphoid to the pubus
and then - sideways. Thus !
Now we take out the intestines.
He's a long fellow .. long fellow,
and we look at all the areas
to be sure we find the watch.
Two more seconds ... Ah-ha !
Such a cheap watch ... four seconds slow !
Okay, now we - we lock him up here.
We put all the intestines back again.
We got to get everything
put back in the right place.
We got to be very gentle
here with the patient, you know.
Thank you, Doctor.
Now that you have entered your
second year of medical school,
l had hoped that the humorous aspects
of surgery might have been exhausted.
lf you don't mind, gentlemen, l'll take over.
First slide, please.
Leukoplakia - this is the most
common danger signal of oral cancer.
Now when you see this, it is time
that is... it is sometimes time
to check for a consistent irritant.
Now this slide may one day help
you to save a life ... Remember it.
Use your microscopes. Study this series well.
There'll be no time for review.
Next slide, please!
They really throw it at you. Relax.
They only expect you to learn seventy percent.
Kill the slide!
Open it!
What page? Any page.
91 7? Subject? The abducent nerve.
The abducent nerve...
The abducent nerve. The abducent nerve.
The abducent nerve supplies
the rectus lateralis oculi.
lts fibers arise in the upper part of the
rhomboid fossa beneath the colliculus facialis.
They pass downward through the pons and
emerge in the furrow between the lower border
of the pons and the upper end of
the pyramid of the medulla oblongata.
The nerve pierces the dura mater.
ls that verbatim?
Just about, Sir. All right.
To graduate in medicine you will memorize
fifteen thousand pages exactly like that.
Gentlemen, if there is a single description
of a doctor, it is this: a doctor is memory!
Now the survivors of this course will
be members of the only group in modern society
privileged to commit manslaughter
with immunity from the law.
Therefore you will learn everything!
Not seventy percent - but everything!
Otherwise you will be dropped.
That will be all for today, gentlemen.
Anybody for law school?
Yeah - ''not seventy percent - but everything''!
What's he trying to do?
Scare us to death with that manslaughter bit?
l don't know.
He doesn't bother me with that
blood-and-guts stuff. l'm going in for skin.
Yeah? Listen to Boy Doctor :
Your patients never die, they never get well -
and they never get you up at night.
And they don't think skin is serious,
so they never pay their bills.
Obstetrics, that's the racket.
Everybody always pays for their kids!
But you never sleep. No woman ever had a
baby at three o'clock in the afternoon!
Personally l'm for surgery.
l just got a look at Dr. Dietrich's car,
parked outside. You know what he drives?
What? A bentley -- Seventeen thousand bucks.
That guy doesn't take out a
splinter for less than a thousand!
Well, l'll still take ''Ear-nose-and-throat''.
The common cold is the doctor's best friend.
Call it virus - you make more dough.
Now, look - if these kiddies are all through,
your old man here will really wise you up...
lt is notwhat you practice -- it is where!
What do you mean? l've been doing
a little research on this problem.
The average doctor's income is eleven G's,
in the South less - in the West more.
Pebble Beach, Colorado Springs, Beverly Hills ...
That's where the rich are crackin' up fast.
Well you're wasting your time here.
Why don't you both become bookies.
Come on! Hey, you know - l kinda like small town.
Ooh - stay out of them, man.
No neurotics and no dough.
Big cities. Cadillacs.
That's what my old man always says.
lt's just as easy to get up for a fifty
dollar-ulcer as it is to get up for a ten dollar ulcer.
Easier! ln other words -if they haven't
got fifty dollars, you Just let 'em die!
What's the matter, Marsh? Are we upsetting you?
No, you're not upsetting me.
You just make me want to vomit, that's all.
Well? Shall we join Dr. Kildare in surgery?
Closing suture!
l don't get it. Why didn't
Dietrich cut the vagus nerves?
Pipe down, he can hear you.
You can take your retractors out now ....
All right, Doctor - sew him up!
Yes, Sir . 3.0 silk. Yes, Sir.
Note that Dr. Radcliff will suture with extreme care.
This is a ward patient,
and there's no charge, of course.
But from my private patients l get as much
as a thousand dollars for this operation.
Forthat kind of money, gentlemen,
the patient has a right to a handsome scar.
As l have explained, the gastro-enterostomy
you have just seen is an operation of choice.
A gastrectomy -orthe
resection of almost the entire stomach
is another means of
dealing with the duodenal ulcer.
lt depends entirely on the individual case.
Now then - are there any questions?
He didn't cut the nerves.
l'm going to ask him. Let it lay, will ya?
Yes?
Dr. Dietrich, l noticed that you
did not severthe vagus nerves.
That's correct. l did not.
lsn't it true, Sir, that in this
operation the vagus nerves must be cut
to reduce the acid flow and
prevent the recurrence of ulcers?
What's your name? Marsh, Sir.
Well, Marsh, l've performed this
operation perhaps a hundred times.
l've never cut the vagus nerves.
l know there is some such new theory.
lt is not a theory, Sir.
The clinical evidence was
published over a year ago.
Now look here, Marsh, l have no intention...
Excuse me, Doctor, but may we
clear the instruments? Yes, yes.
You're arrogant, Mr. Marsh, and wrong!
l have the reports, Sir, if you'd care to read them.
When you come to your senses, Marsh,
and realize who you are and where you are,
l'll accept an apology.
How dare you, do anything like that?
Who do you think you are?
Just tell me one thing: He was wrong, wasn't he?
Will you listen to me? You apologize to
Dietrich or you won't be allowed to interne here.
Was he wrong? Yes, he was wrong.
Did you hear what l said? You won't interne here!
All right, then l won't! But l'm not
going to tell Dietrich he was right
when he was wrong
even if l have to go to another hospital.
There won't be a good hospital in the country
open to you. Dietrich's got influence.
Well l can't apologize.
You mean you won't.
All right, then l mean l won't.
Hello, Luke.
Hi.
Dinner'll take about ten minutes. Are you starved?
l'm not hungry.
Good - then l'll sit down for a few minutes.
l'm tired.
Allright. Let's not lead up to it gently.
Let's have it and get it over with.
l don'twant to fight with you, Luke.
Why not?. Everyone else has.
There's nothing for me to say. Dr. Aarons told you.
You mean he told you to work on me.
Well, you're wasting your time.
l'm not going to apologize.
Luke, he's right. They'll stop you from interning.
All right- then let them stop me! l'm sick of it!
Money! That's all they care about. All of them.
Brundage, even Al. And that pompous fool
who calls himself a surgeon is the worst.
He can't keep up with the new stuff.
He's too busy collecting thousand-dollar-bills!
l've seen Dietrich operate plenty of times.
He's a good surgeon.
Maybe a little old-fashioned, but..
Can't you understand? Didn't you hear today?
l know, l know. He didn't cut the nerves,
and there's a twenty percent chance
the patientwill get another ulcer.
You mean you know that? And you're on his side?
l'm not on his side.
l'm in the operating room
almost every day of my life.
Sometimes l see things
that make me want to scream.
But l don't. That's you ... that's not me!
l say when a doctor does something wrong,
he's got to be stopped!
Oh, Luke! You expect too much!
A doctor's an ordinary man, like everybody else.
l've told you a hundred times. A doctor can't
be like anybody else. He deals with human life.
Human Life! You're not too
stupid to understand that, are you?
l know l'm not very smart, and sometimes l make
you angry because l don't think the way you do.
l was going to give you this next week -
for our anniversary.
Maybe you better look at it now.
l promised Bruni l'd come over. l'll be back early.
Now, then, gentlemen, our subject for today
will be surgery of the gall bladder.
lnfection of the biliary system is believed
to play a large part in the formation of ....
Yes, Marsh?
Sir - l want to apologize - for yesterday.
That's all right, Marsh. We all make mistakes!
Well, gentlemen, this is where the books
come to life.
Anything l could say now you
should have learned a year ago.
Don't let the patients frighten you. Make friends
with the nurses. They run the hospital.
No fooling! Thompson, you and
Morgan take Ward B. Ward C is all yours.
Oh .. eh.. good luck.
Thank you, Doctor... thank you.
Well .. er ... see ya ...Well? Cheer up. Yeah.
Hey - how do l look?
Ah - you're a magnificent animal.
No-no .. l mean - do l look like a doctor?
You're acting like one of the patients.
We'll knock 'em dead in there.
Not a very happy phrase - Doctor.
Good morning, Doctor. l'm Miss Katz.
This is Miss Collier. Good morning. Good morning
Hiya, Doll.
All right, healer, read this, follow me,and let's
see how many you can kill on the first day.
Mr. Roberts is first for, you, Doctor. Chronic colitis.
Mr. Roberts - how do you feel, this morning?
Lousy.
Well, you'll feel bettertomorrow . You wanna bet?
Well, you're through with intravenous feeding,
Mr. Clyde. You're gonna have some solid food.
lf you don't mind, Doc, l'll get along with this.
That was wonderful, Mrs.
Dayton. You'll be leaving soon.
l'd like to stay here, Doctor. l have no place to go.
You're not gonna do it, do you hear me?
You're not gonna operate on me.
But you've already agreed.
Your bladder is obstructed.
l don't care. You're not gonna cut me.
Now listen, Mr. Burke. You'll be
given an ordinary sleeping pill.
Upstairs a doctorwho has done it hundreds
of times will give you a spinal anaesthetic;
We'll make a small incision two inches
below the navel and relieve the obstruction.
lt'll take less than ten minutes.
You'll be weak, it'll hurt a little bit but
you'll be back up on your feet by four o'clock.
You make it sound easy. lt is easy. Now relax!
You're not kidding anybody, Slocum.
We know you're selling your blood.
How much you get for it?
Just five dollars a pint. This is your
last transfusion. Aw, Doc..l mean it!
This is no filling station.
Come on, Heidi - come on
- you know you can make it.
Come on !
That's the girl.
See, Heidi? l told you you could do it.
Four minutes and thirty seconds. The embroidery
was beautiful - but the patient died.
Luke - you don't know what l've been through!
She had the baby right here -
so help me! Right here!
And can you do something about this mole,
Doctor? lt drives me crazy.
lt certainly doesn't look very good.
Can't you remove it?.
lt's best to leave this kind alone.
Well then, can't you do something about my leg?
Every time l move it it hurts my hip..
and l still have the headache and the gas pains.
And you know what happened yesterday?
l got so dizzy, l almost fell over.
We'll do the bestwe can, Mrs. Ferris.
Hey,Doc - you think she's got trouble?
Listen to this: l ...
They didn't tell us about this part of it, you know!
Babcock, Deaver, Goulet,
Retractor, Bailey Rib Approximator.
Volkman rake, Richardson, Kelly .
Curved Kelly. They'll just ask for Kelly.
That's sloppy. Ask for exactly what you want,
and you'll get it.
l just don't know what to do with him, Doctor.
lf he isn't running around like a wild lndian
getting ail dirty he's getting into trouble in
the kitchen or pestering his father on his day off
or bothering me to go to a movie, and on
top of that he keeps blinking blinking blinking,
it drives me crazy and there must be
something you can do about it, Doctor.
l have a feeling, Mrs. Field,
he'd stop blinking if you'd stop talking.
You can relax, Doc: this one is real dead!
Oh, Doctor? Here's his stuff. Slid under a bus.
Al! Do you want some coffee? No, thank you.
What's the matter with you?
There's something l have to tell you.
Well, what is it?.
Accident case just came in!
He died in the ambulance.
So ?
ltwas your father, Luke.
Maybe l - l'd better. Let him go, Al.
You know how Luke is..
He'll...he'll have to be by himself.
Oh, Dr. Marsh. l'm going home
- and l wanted to say goodbye.
Well you look fine, Mrs. Ferris. How do you feel?
l know this is going to be a surprise to you,
but l feel good. Nothing hurts. Fine.
What's that?. Why, that's where
they took the mole off, Doctor.
They? Who's they? The other Doctor - your friend.
Luke - we were so worried. We called everywhere.
You all right? Yes, l'm all right.
Did you remove that mole? Well, did you?
Yeah. Why?
ltwasn't Just a mole.
lt was a melanoma. What?. You heard me!
Were you asleep or hung-over
when we had melanomas in class?
Luke, you've been up all night, and...
Why didn't you send her to surgery?
You know when you cut it off like that
you may have released cancer
cells right into her bloodstream?
l don't think it was a melanoma.
You don't think. How would you know? You spend
all your time making passes at the nurses
That's a pretty lousy thing to say, and you know it!
Now listen, Al! Luke, listen -
this isn't the place for this.
You may have killed that woman! Luke!
Either you report this or l will -
and l hope they throw the book at you.
l'll report it myself.
l have to finish rounds.
l said l have to finish rounds.
How could you talk to Alfred
like that in front of everybody?
You don't understand, you'll never understand.
l understand this much:
there are two people in
this world who care about you.
That's one of them.
l remembered you were on tonight.
Yeah, l'm on. Al, look:
l didn't mean what l said today.
You were right, though.
And Aarons told me even worse later.
But l didn't have to blow my
top in front of the nurses.
Ahhh - what's the difference. We've only
got a couple of more weeks here anyway.
Though l keep thinking about that
woman walking around, not even knowing.
Forget it. Maybe l was wrong.
l don't think l'll ever feel
right again if anything happens.
l know... but l didn't have to
add to it by shooting my mouth off.
Y'know with anybody else
this would be it for keeps.
But l know you -- push a button and off you go.
l don't know what it is. Sometimes l just take off.
Sometimes l wish l had seventy-five
more pounds. l'd belt you one!
Hey! l know how tough it was
for you to come down here tonight.
Okay.
Okay. Charge!
Well, gentlemen, you've completed your
internships. You're practising physicians now.
This will be your last staff meeting.
You saw your first dissection on this very table -
and l think it's fitting that we say goodbye here.
Now a pathologist usually has the last word,
but in this particular case it's a
very hard word to find, because -
well, because if you don't know it by now...
if it isn't in your hearts -
it's too late for me to tell it to you.
Goodbye. God bless all of you.
And -- don't endorse any cigarettes!
Sit down ... sit down ...
l just came to say goodbye.
l hear you're going to Hicksville. Greenville!
Sounds pretty small.
lt's farm country -- where they
never saw a thousand-dollar bill.
You think that makes the air purer there?
That's the way l feel.
Yes, indeed.
l can see the picture you've got of yourself already.
A country road, and an old Ford,
only it's not an old Ford - it's a white horse.
And you are St. George,
complete in spotless armor.
You get to a farmhouse.
There's a man bleeding to death...
alone - without instruments, without assistance,
you perform an impossible operation.
And because your heart is pure, you save him.
l haven't any such ...
You're gonna go down that road
and when you get there,
do you know what you're going to find?
A man with a boil on his backside.
Do you hear me?
A boil on his backside.
You will lance it - and go home.
Goodbye, Doctor .
Marsh!
You're one of the most brilliant
students we've ever graduated here.
You'll be a great physician.
But stop living your life like a greek tragedy
or you'll muff it!
Thank you.
Goodbye Doctor.
Welcome to Greenville.
Dr. Runkleman - this is my wife.
l'm happy to meet you Doctor.
l've heard so much about you.
Lies, all lies.
ls that all? That's it.
Naked ye come into the world,
and naked ye shall leave it.
You're a country doctor now.
My car's right over here.
Well - there it is. Greenville.
Picturesque cafes - gaily costumed natives -
- ten below in the winter -
a hundred and ten in the summer.
Hi, Martha!
She doesn't talk to me. Thirty years
ago l said she'd be dead in two months.
Diagnosis is my specialty!
Sam! Oh - hello, Doc.
Get off that leg! You won't
have it next month if you don't!
Now you better watch your blood pressure, Dave.
You'll live longer!
ldiot!
These are crazy people.
Last week a man caught his arm in a cultivator,
walked a mile holding it together.
And what do you suppose is
the first thing he asked me?
How much is it going to cost?.
You're a point-killer.
You want to remember that about farmers.
They always want to know what it's going to cost.
She's pretty sharp. Oh, yes.
Well - this is where you're going to live.
Oh - it looks very nice.
lt's not bad.
Here's the car l got for you.
lf you drive anything newer, they'll take
one look and yell: ''There goes my appendix''!
Well, l hope you like it. l'm sure we will .
l had a handy man clean it up.
My contribution to gracious living.
How much did you pay him? Seventy-five cents
an hour. You were robbed, Doctor.
Well, l better get over to the office.
See you in the morning, Luke. Eh.. eight o'clock.
Ye-uh.
All right .. go ahead. l can manage.
Come on - before she changes her mind.
This is Dr. Marsh - Miss Snow.
Miss Snow doesn't care how much you
reduce the population of Greenville,
as long as you don't bollox up
her appointments? Right? Wrong!
Old Lady Schoenman called. Bed rest.
Cafergot pill every hour for five hours. Migraine.
Mr. Jergens called again.
Double up on the Amphojel ...
The gentleman has an ulcer.
What's in the mail? Drug samples and bills
and another love letter from Mrs. Henderson.
Very funny !
Surprised, eh?
lt's a pretty big library.
You mean for a country Doctor?
Well, these days you have to keep up.
Your patients buy Reader's Digest
and the first thing you know they
have diseases you never heard of.
Well, go on, go on.
Adam Jerner has more pain in his arm.
Remove the weight every hour for five minutes.
What else?
Nothing more for now.
All right. Roll 'em in, roll 'em in!
Mr. Parrish. please.
Use the salve morning and evening -
and don't sit down too much.
l'm a bus driver. l'll drive the bus standing up!
l had a professor who told me l'd wind
up treating boils on the backside ...
Well - here it is - first case.
Did he also tell you you
probably wouldn't get paid for it?
Say Ah!
Again.
Again
Again. OUCH! That hurt!
Ahhh - don't be such a cry-baby!
l don't care what happened to your frog!
But l tell you, Emma.. lt's impossible!
All right, Emma - it's impossible!
But you're pregnant!
You're kidding! Oh no we're not!,
As a great man once said: ''lt's no
worse than a broken leg!'' Yeah, but....
One after every meal, Gertrude.
Thanks, Doctor. l - l hope they'll help. They will.
There's nothing wrong with her.
Look - when they come in and
they've got a pain, treat it.
When they come in and they only think they've
got a pain, treat the pain they think they've got.
You 'can't practice medicine;
you have to treat people.
About another inch.
Easy now....
Now!
NOW! CLOSE!
This kid just swallowed over eight
hundred dollars worth of diamonds!
lt won't hurt him any.
lt won't hurt him! What about me?
Just follow him around, Harry,
don't let him out of your sight!
Dave - have l got what l think l have?
Now don't kid me! Yes, Ed.
Will it hurt? We can take care of that.
Just like that, eh?
You're sixty-seven years old, Ed.
You've lived it up like an international playboy.
Takes one to know one, Dave. No regrets!
Are you guys sure this operation'll fix me?
Absolutely. We'll make a new man of you.
Well, when you do - send him the bill, willya?
l told you we'd get paid Luke.
No money, but lots of chicken on the table!
Tired? Oh, l'm dead. Dinner will
be ready in a few minutes. Good.
You must have had another big day. Big?
Kris, you have no idea.
Those people just swarm into that office.
l don't know where they all come from
in a small town like this.
That Runkleman's a one-man clinic.
He handles everything:
adenoids, cardiacs,
pregnancies, ingrown toe-nails.
And he's good, too, Kris. He's a good physician.
But l'll bet we handled over
two hundred cases this week.
That's what you wanted, Luke.
Yeah - but this much - this fast..
The way we work there just isn't time!
l'm always afraid, that some patient
isn't going to get enough attention.
Oh - people don't expect the world.
You can'twork all day and worry all night.
No, l suppose not..
You don't realize it yourself- but
you're so wrapped up in it, you haven't...
we haven't had time to talk.
And there's some things l want to tell you.
l'm happierthan l've ever been in my whole life.
l thought maybe l'd miss working, but l don't.
l go around all day telling myself how -
how smart l am to be a woman
and your wife.
Only l love you so much.
l want it to be complete!
Don't you think that now we could...
l want to have a family, Luke.
What l mean to say is - well ..
Yes? Yes - Dr. Marsh is here. Yes, Mrs. Bassett.
No - don't move him. Yes, right away.
Just give me the directions.
The Lang Farm on the old North Road...
left. Thank you.
Nat Bassett, a stableman; horse kicked him.
Thanks, Kris. You go back to sleep.
He'll rest now, Mrs. Bassett.
He shouldn't wake up any
more tonight. But if he does,
be absolutely sure that he doesn't
get out of bed. Thank you, Doctor.
Oh, incidentally, Doctor, l almost forgot.
Mrs. Lang asked if you'd stop up
to see herwhen you get through.
At one o'clock? She's up.
Good evening - l'm Dr. Marsh.
l'm Harriet Lang. Come in,
Doctor Marsh. Thank you.
l was worried about Nat Bassett. How is he?
Well - l can't tell yet. lf his hip is
broken he'll be in bed for a month or two.
l warned him about that horse. Oh?
He's at stud here. l breed Jumpers. l see.
This is Ben Cosgrove...Dr. Marsh. Doctor!
Well, l've been leaving for several hours...
Ben's a baby-sitter...for adults. Yeah!
Good night, Doctor.
Excuse me.
Whatwill you have to drink?
Nothing, thank you.
l like that song. Sometimes l just let it play.
Dave Runkleman told me about you.
He did?
Aren't you going to ask me what he said?
All right - what did he say?
He said you were born to be a doctor!
l wanted to meet you...really!
l'm embarrassing you.
No - you're' not embarrassing me, Mrs. Lang.
l'm just tired.
l'm operating tomorrow morning at seven.
They always warn you about solitary drinking,
but they never tell you how to get
people to stay up and drink with you.
l'm sorry you're lonely, Mrs. Lang.
l didn't say l was lonely.
l haven't been sleeping, and...
Well - l think you'll sleep tonight.
That's a very polite way of
saying l've had too much to drink.
And you're right - l have.
Goodnight, Dr. Marsh.
Goodnight, Mrs. Lang.
Greenville Hospital - good-morning.
Just a moment, please.
Good morning, Mrs. Penrose,
and where are the medicine men?
Scrubbing. Toilet water,
Hormone cream - Lipstick - l love you.
l hear -- l hear you saw the Widow Lang last night.
Yeah - she was worried about
the stableman. What'd you think?
Well - the X-rays show that...
l don' t mean about the stableman ..Oh?
And don't tell me you didn't think.
Well, she seemed very nice .
Uh-huh...
Hiya, Doc. Lou! l haven't tried
last month's wonder drug yet.
Let's see - what do l need?
Four bottles of Zephirin -
twenty Procaine Penicillins -
about a thousand tongue blades - and a
couple of dozen ace bandages. Got that?
What l have is something real special.
Oh no! Just take a minute.
Say, Dave, who is Ben Cosgrove?
He's her lawyer -- and she hasn't done him
any good -- and watch out -- it's catching!
This is the first major improvement
in a stethoscope in thirty years.
You've never heard amplification like this.
Go ahead.
Should we buy it?. Yeah - it's pretty good, Dave.
How much? Two hundred and thirty.
Allright - drop it at the office. Now beat it.
Thanks, Dave. Dr. Marsh, see you next week.
We11? Well, what?
Come on .. come on! What'd you hear?
l didn't hear anything.
Don't lie ..Let's have it. All right
Systolic murmur, thrill, dullness in
the second interspace, unequal pulses.
Don't look so shocked. l've told it
to over a hundred people in my time.
How long have you known, Dave?
Couple of months - that's why you're here.
Well, you're gonna have to quit.
Look - l've already got old man's
kidneys and trouble in the prostate.
lt's not going to be so much fun from now on,
anyway...And if l don't keep busy..
But at least you could go East
- see Raermer - or Hamilton.
And have 'em try to sell me on surgery?
No thanks.
You've got to do something for yourself, Dave.
Look - when it ruptures, l'll go fast.
What more can you ask?
This is Dr. Snider - Dr. Marsh.
Dr. Snider is the Director of the Hospital.
Glad to know you. How do you do, Doctor?
ls Dr. Snider the anaesthetist?
You're a city boy - this is Greenville.
When a patient can 't afford a
regular man, Dr. Snider's it.
Ready, Clem? Ready.
Respiration's labored! What's her blood pressure?
Sixty over zero. She's cyanotic.
Clamp that Pentathol off! Give her straight saline.
Endotracheal tube - quick! You let her
go into spasm - she can't get any air!
She's closing. l can't get it down!
You'll have to cut her in the throat.
Knife! No - wait a minute, Dave ...
Curare. l don't think it'll work.
lf it doest relax her, we can still cut. Go ahead.
She seems to be responding.
Get that tube again!
Oxygen. Oxygen!
Fresh gown and gloves!
Her color's coming back. l guess, she'll be all right.
Thank you, Kris. You were wonderful.
Look at him - the weight of the world!
l know what it is.
He's been itching all day to
harangue me about Dr. Snider.
Well l have been trying to talk to you all day, Dave.
That business about the Pentathol was..
Please, Luke. Not tonight.
l've got to talk to him. All right...
you want me to say it?. l'll say it.
He's unsure of himself.
He wasn't the best to begin with,
but he's the head of the hospital!
And he's incompetent. All right!
l watch him. l try to keep him out of trouble,
but we're stuck with him.
He's a political appointment, Luke - and there's
nothing you, l, or anybody else can do about it.
Now can we forget it, and try to enjoy ourselves?
This is my night off, for the love of Mike.
Harriet! Hey!
Hiya, Dave. Dave Runkleman .
How are you, Dave?
Hello, Dr. Marsh.
Good evening Mrs. Lang.
My wife. Mrs. Lang - Mr. Cosgrove.
How do you do?
Pleased to meetcha.
Have another .. Oh-l've already
had too many. Have one more ...
Stop worrying. She's been dancing with Ben for
years now, and nothing's ever happened.
l'm not worrying!
But l wish she didn' t look
so beautiful in that dress.
lf l spent that much time and money,
l'd look beautiful myself.
You make a fine looking couple.
Hey, Kris. You ve had quite a few already.
l prescribed it. You stay out of this.
Watch out for him. He's a wicked old man.
l sure am ... here's a fresh drink.
Er - she doesn't drink. Her Doctor disapproves.
Er.. what's the Latin for
Gin and Vermouth, Doctor?
What? Here we go again.
Ben doesn't approve of Doctors.
He thinks we write our prescriptions
in Latin just to mystify the patients.
Oh- instead of the Simple way
the lawyers write contracts?
Listen - we're amateurs next to you.
You're a secret society. You've got
everything except the grip and the high sign.
Ben - you're drunk - and you
don't know what you're talking about.
l don't know? l'm just drunk
enough to tell you guys something!
When they getwise to how little you know,
you won't be able to kill
people and get away with it!
l've lost a few patients - l've saved many more.
Look, Cosgrove, we all know that occasionally..
Just what do you know, Doctor?
Ben - you're being very rude! And very stupid.
Am l? You don't know why the heart beats,
you don't know what thought is -
why the nerves feel.
You don't even know why a woman gives
birth in nine months instead of twelve.
You don't even know.. We don't know
all of it -- No. But we're learning.
Learning? You're not learning -
you're subdividing.,
One guy stakes out a claim on the lungs,
another on the stomach, another on the heart.
And if the territory overlaps a bit -
you divide up the take.
You've even got a name for it! Fee splitting.
Yeah - that's it. And the poor slob of a
patient pays both of you, without even realizing it.
ln nursing school they used to have a joke.
Doctors wear rubber gloves so
they won't leave fingerprints.
All right, Kris - that's not very funny.
That's right, shut her up.
The secret society at work. Why don't you
guys stop acting like a bunch of quacks?
Why don't you stop acting like a shyster lawyer?
Are you calling me a shyster?
Shut up - the both of you! This is a public place!
l'm sorry.... , l think we'd better go home.
l don't care what you say... you're supposed to be
a Doctor's wife. lf you can't drink, don't drink..
l never drink, Luke, you know that ..
that's why l .. At least be honest.
You drank too much and you talked too much
because you were annoyed at
my dancing with Harriet Lang.
You said that, Luke. l didn't.
Kris?
What?
l'm sorry.
lt's all right. ltwas my fault, too.
No. l was sore about Snider and then
Cosgrove - and l just took it all out on you.
We don't talk enough, Luke.
lt isn't that we fight.
We just don't seem to have
much to say to each other.
Sometimes l wish... Kris - look -
we just had a little argument, that's all.
l said l was sorry.
lt is not good fortwo people to be like this.
No - l guess not.
l tried to talk to you the
other night but you were so tired.
We're established here now. We have this house.
Some day soon we ought to
think about having a family.
lt's too early to talk about that.
l just started to practice here, really, we -
-we can't take on too much yet.
But itwouldn't have to cost a lot,
and l could always ..Kris!
Let's talk about it some other time.
Good night, Luke.
Good night, Kris.
Well - if it isn't the good Doctor. What are you
doing out here? Patient down the road.
Through for the day? Uh-huh.
Come on up to the house. l'll buy you a drink.
l'll freshen it up for you...
lt's no good. What do you mean - it's no good?
l mean it's no good...
for me!
l still don't understand what you...
You told me l was lonely. l am!
My life is horses and dinner
twice a week with Ben Cosgrove.
lt's not very exciting, but...but you just
don'twant to take a chance on anything more.
Not with you! Look- you spend
twenty-four hours a day on medicine
and you go thru the motions of a marriage...
you haven't got time for me.
Then why did you ask me up here?
Because l wanted to -- and itwas stupid.
l can't afford to fall in love with you.
Well, you're lucky you can turn
it on and off like that .. l can't!
Sucker!
Well, Al?
Well - your blood pressure's normal;
your hemoglobin's excellent;
you have no communicable diseases,
and congratulations on
being twelve weeks pregnant.
Thanks - that's aboutwhat l figured.
Lucas Marsh being a
father staggers my imagination.
Was he excited? What did he say?
l'll bet he's doing handstands. Al!
What's the matter, Kris?
l haven't told Luke.
You haven't told him? That's ridiculous!
This isn't the kind of a secret you keep, Kris.
Especially from a Doctor. Why?
What is it, Kris? He doest want a baby. Oh!
Most men don't...until they find out about it.
Then they rush out and buy electric
trains when there's still eight months to go.
Not Luke.
You know, we don't have that kind of marriage.
Thanks Al!
Kris! Tell him. No matter what. Tell him!
Anne, have l a light day this week?
Thursday! Good. Switch all the appointments,
l won't be in at all.
All right, Doctor.
He may have a slight fever after that shot,
but he'll be all right.
Goodnight, Mrs. Bassett. Goodnight, Doctor.
Good evening, O'Dell. Good evening, Doctor.
Who's this?
Aterminal - pneumonia.
Bettertake his temperature. He's burning up.
Can't be, Doctor. His pulse
has been very slow..Take it!
What's his name? Simmons, Carlisle Simmons.
There's nothing on here!
There was nothing to chart.
Has Dr. Snider seen him? Of course.
Well, what instructions did he give?
None. He never does in these cases.
These cases?
When their time comes Doctor always
lets the old ones cross over peacefully.
This one won't last until morning.
What is it?
A hundred and four. Here!
Were these spots on him when
Doctor Snider examined him? Yes, Sir.
Guide the bed! But Doctor... Guide the bed!
Dr. Marsh! This is my patient. What are you doing?
O'Dell - l want two ampules of
chloromycetin and some oxygen.
Doctor - l have my ward patients!
Don't argue with me, O'Dell, l want them.
And telephone my wife -
tell her to get here right away .-
This man has typhoid. We can't waste any time.
Now look here Marsh.. l don't know what..
Stay out of the way ... l've got to isolate him!
Go make that call, O'Dell .
Marsh, l'm head of this hospital,
and l'm ordering you to stop disrupting it!
Dr. Snider, you've exposed this whole
hospital to typhoid. That's bad enough.
But it's unbelievable that you
would deliberately let a patient die.
That's an old man. He's going. There's
nothing anybody can do about it. You're a doctor.
You've no right to make that decision.
You're supposed to keep him alive!
He's in shock. Where are the blocks?
We haven't any.
You're wasting your time. l can always tell.
He'll go before six o'clock tomorrow morning.
Get out of here, Snider, before l kill you!
You're insane ..
Get that tank of oxygen.
Alcohol, please.
And l need more blood.....
l'll do that ... here ... check his pressure.
He should be responding. Still no pressure.
Cortisone, a hundred milligrams.
Massage his legs ...
Well - he's out of shock.
Help me with the bed, will you?
We'll need more saline. l'll get it. Keep sponging.
He stopped breathing!
l think you've got him ... He's breathing now.
Better give him a shot of Coramine...
l'll take over.
That could have been the ball game.
l'll bet you're tired. A little.
Kris - there's something l want to tell you.
You were wonderful. l've always known it,
but l've never said it to you before.
You're great!
You're a great nurse.
All this talk we've had about
housework and families... that isn't for you.
You've got to come back here to the hospital.
You're needed here, Kris.
l am tired, Luke. l'm going home.
Ladies and gentlemen
the voice of Dr. David Runkleman.
Ladies and gentlemen: There is typhoid
in Greenville. Typhoid is highly contagious.
We can prevent an epidemic if you will all,
each and everyone of you,
do exactly as you are told.
Come to your county hospital
immediately for inoculation.
l repeat: Come to your county
hospital immediately for inoculation.
That's beautiful, Harry.
On the hour every hour, right? Right, Doctor.
Your next shot will be a week from today.
Your next shot is a week from today.
Dr. Runkleman, l presume?
Who are you? l'm Alfred Boone, Doctor.
l .. er... l was told you'd have a Cadillac.
lt's only a front - the Cadillac has me.
ls Luke around? He's out giving shots.
Then l'll go over and see Kristina.
Roll up your sleeve, first.
You're kidding! Roll up your sleeve!
Oh - fine.
Greenville Hospital - good evening.
Oh - hello, Mrs. Marsh.
Yes, Dr. Marsh just called in.
He has one more shot to give ..
at Mrs. Lang's place.
Thank you.
He has only one more call, he'll be home soon.
More coffee? No, l'm fine.
This is a kind of an awkward Silence, Kris.
What's happening?
l haven't told Luke about the baby, Al.
l think you'd better level with me.
l tried to tell him, but l couldn't.
You have to! l just couldn't.
Look, when Luke told me he was going to
marry you,l nearly flipped. You know that.
But l was never more wrong, and l want to help.
That's why l came down here.
l know, Al - and l appreciate it.
But l've got to work it out myself.
Yeah...
Look, l don'twant you to think
l'm starving to death, but ..er...
what have you got in the ice-box?
l'll see!
Goodnight, Mrs. Lang.
Thank you.. Goodnight, Clara.
What are you thinking?
Nothing. Be honest.
All right...l don't know..l just felt.. Guilty?
Maybe. l hate to say l told you so.
Yeah -
l do feel guilty and l don't like the feeling.
You're supposed to be a man
who doesn't care about his wife.
Yeah.
lt doesn't matter. But you don't feel
this guilty if you don't care, Luke..
What's the use of talking?
You want to go, why don't you? Come on!
Harriet, l really didn't figure it thatway...
l don't have any problems l didn't have before.
l told you once... horses... tomorrow night
dinner with Ben Cosgrove.. l'll live .
Goodnight, Harriet.
Hey!
Al.. What are you doin'...Get in!
What are you doing around
here in the middle of the night.
Waiting for you. Well come on inside.
l've been inside ... for six and a half hours.
Well - what goes?
lt's a good question .... you tell me.
Now Al, look ...Now save your breath if you're
gonna tell me to mind my own business.
She's pregnant.
She never said a word.
She tried to a couple of times.
Yes, she did.
Look- you're a doctor! Don't you ever look at her?
Well? Don't you?
l wish l had.
The time is now ... try it.
Al...Save it ... l'll see you, huh?
Kris ...
Kris, Al waited for me outside.
l had no idea .. if l'd only known...
Kris - l'm sorry. l'm really sorry.
Just let me try... l promise you...
Get up!
You're always sorry.
Every time you hurt me you're sorry.
You always try to fix it by
acting as though you love me.
lt doesn't work any more.
l know where you were tonight.
l can't forgive you. Kris - listen to me ..
you've got to listen to me!
l've been wrong - l know it.
But l swear to you ... l swear to you..No!
You listen to me and don't interrupt,
because nothing - nothing you can say will matter!
From the beginning you
never thought l was smart enough
or attractive enough,
or woman enough - to be yourwife.
You come crawling in here
now because your friend told you
l was going to have your child.
Stop pretending! l'm sick of it!
l don't need you to have this child!
Kris - you've got to listen to me! Don't!
You had to have money, so you married me.
Well, you made it ... you're a doctor!
You don't need me now!
And l don't need the little you got to give me.
l don'twant to live with you, Luke.
Please - get out of here!
Go away!
Get out of here, Luke!
Please!
What a day!
Any messages? Yes, Doctor.
Dr. Marsh - here are yours. Thank you.
Anything from Kris? No.
l saw her last night.
She's all right. l thought
you might have heard from her.
l think l must be losing my touch.
Well - thanks for trying anyway.
Good evening, Dr. Marsh. How are you, Felton?
Well, you're looking better, Mr. Parker.
Continue sedation!
How are you,Charlie? Fine, Doc.
Let's have a listen.
Marsh...
1t's - it's Dave Runkleman!
He just grabbed his chest and fell over.
Hit me - like a truck ..
Demarol - a hundred milligrams - quick!
He'll have to go in.
The aorta's tearing. He's hemorrhaging.
Don't you think we ought to try to get
hold of Stafford or some other heart man?
There's isn't time. You'll have to assist.
All right. l'll get someone
to handle the anaesthesia.
Don't take it so big Luke. lt happens to everybody.
Shut up, Dave.
Slow and regularly, holding nicely.
Right angle clamp please.
There it is ..There's the break.
Ductus clamp ... Retract.
l'll need more exposure ..
Steady this, please.
Suture. Four-O, Arterial... Large forceps.
Sponge...Tag the end...
Clear the field.
Suture scissors...How's the pressure, Doctor?
lt is okay... a hundred and ten over seventy ..
Check the suction.
Gill foam, please.
All right- that's it.
Better get out.
No, not yet. We'll need more oxygen...
Turn it up, please.
All right .. You've got it. You've stopped the leak.
Let's close. Thumb forceps!
.. l'm going to wrap the aorta.
l want to give him every chance l can.
You'll have to get under it. l intend to.
lt's very thin. l wouldn't try, Marsh.
Dissecting scissors ..
Take him deeper, Doctor...Plastic..
Better go easy. l've got to get underneath.
Careful, it's stretching.
You'll have to stop the lung action.
There, l've almost got it ...
Watch it! Marsh - 1t's rupturing!
Clamps - quickly!
Cut the ether! Oxygen only.
McCray - all the blood you can get, fast!
O'Dell - more blood!
Keep that suction going, Barker. Knife!
Leg transfusion! We'll have to
extend the incision...Bone cutters..
Retractor...Barker...Hemostat. No, the curved one.
Forceps - Rheinhoff- These won't hold...Cushing!
Hemostat...vein tubing ..
How many units have you got?
Six, Doctor. l'll need more than that- lots more.
Get them - all you can get.
Wait, put that scope where l can see it first.
Left aneurysm needle, Barker.
He's slipping! The pulse is weak!
Pressure bulbs! Come on, Barker.
Hard on that retractor.
Get this instrument out of my way.
Get rid of it. Take over here, Snider. .
More clamps! We've got to get that blood in faster.
His pulse is failing. l can hardly get it.
Heart is stopped, Doctor. Adrenalin - fast!
You give lt, l'll massage.
No response.
Still nothing...
Doctor ....
Doctor!
He's gone Marsh.
God help him, he made a mistake.
Kris!
Luke.
Kris - help me! For God's sake - help me!