- So how was it?
- Good.
- You're gonna go ahead?
- Full steam.
Anything I can do to change your mind?
Nope. No way.
You know, there's an old saying:
"No matter how hot it gets up there
during the day...
...there's not a..."
- "Not a damn thing to do at night."
What the hell are you gonna do
at night in the middle of nowhere?
Sleep like a winner.
Doug, you're a city boy with
a low threshold of boredom.
You'll be back in two weeks.
Come in the office for a minute.
I got people waiting upstairs.
I wanted to tell you...
...Senator Parker's coming
to the dedication tonight.
He's almost guaranteed
the urban renewal contract.
Do you know what that means?
Skyscrapers like this
all over the country.
You design them. I'll build them.
Jim, I think you suffer from
an edifice complex.
You'll never leave.
After the party, come on downstairs
and watch me burn my black tie.
Glad to see you back.
Doug, I can't understand it.
The dampers won't stay opened.
- Whatever happened to "hello"?
- Hello.
- How are you?
- Good.
You look like it took.
- Hi, Mr. Roberts.
- Just a second.
We'll miss you.
- Duncan know?
- He's all smiles.
- What electromagnets went in?
- Doug?
- Thompson G-4s.
- Don't you think they should be G-12s?
That's what comes from
last-minute panic. I'll fix it.
There's ground water
on that Atlanta job.
Bring the designs in today.
How about Chicago specs?
- Philadelphia?
- In a minute, guys.
Well, hello.
Welcome back.
Are you taking any calls?
Who's there?
No, I'm not taking any calls.
Are we gonna talk at all?
No. It's my lunch hour.
Well, I'm not a cheeseburger,
you know.
You're better.
All protein, no bread.
All I need to go with you
is about eight glasses of water.
is in that suitcase.
I got about a $ 140 worth of
vulgar underwear for you.
First things first.
That's nice.
Years from now, when they talk
about this, and they will...
...remember to tell them that
it was my idea.
Got change for a 50?
Sorry, it's the smallest I have.
Not a chance!
Let's see what we got here...
Twenty-five, 50, 60...
...70, 75...
...85, 95.
That's it exactly.
Catch your tip next time.
All your security squad's up there...
Hello, Mrs. Allbright.
Hi, Phillip.
We won't be so messy tomorrow.
We're gonna try charcoals.
Mommy wants to know if
you'll have dinner with us?
Thank you, but I'm going up
to the tower party.
Aren't you coming?
Mommy says thanks, but she doesn't
go to parties since Daddy died.
Here, let me take that paint off.
Bye.
How are you, Phillip?
- Sorry, Mrs. Mueller, what was that?
- I said how are you?
Okay.
Goodbye.
Okay, I'll get on it right now.
I'll have to check the panel.
Have to see if all those light up.
Mr. Callahan?
We still got any G-12 electrodes?
- Yeah, main storeroom.
- Right.
Okay, booster pump, zone one.
- One-ten.
- Check.
Main generator, zone one.
I don't get any reading.
Try the auxiliary generator.
What the hell?
Go ahead.
Here we are.
Are there offices on this floor,
as well as apartments?
I wouldn't like that at all!
The business offices only go up to 80.
From the 81 st floor, here...
...all the way up to 120,
it's exclusively residential.
Now, the apartment
I want to show you is 8145...
Say, Bill?
Tune in the main utility room.
Something's screwed up.
The sensor didn't trip
the fire alarm.
Why should it?
You can see for yourself.
There's no fire.
The sensor indicates there is.
Plus Wes just called.
He said they're having
wiring problems down there.
You better stay with it.
I want you up there with me.
We can do good things together.
What's the matter?
Hello?
Dave's leaving.
They've offered me managing editor.
That's nice.
I mean... I guess we've got ourselves
a situation.
It seems.
I want the kind of life
you're talking about. I want that.
I want a place where our kids can
run around and grow and be free.
But?
I want this job.
I wanted it for five years.
I've worked for it for five years.
Now suddenly it's there.
See, I have ideas, Doug.
I can do something with it
that hasn't been done before.
I guess I want both, and I
can't have both. Can I?
I don't know.
Where?
Be right there.
Let's hold this off till tonight.
What happened?
We kicked on the auxiliary,
and this shorted out.
Power off?
- What about that?
- It should've been conduit.
Give me a pair of dikes.
I know, I know.
Callahan called me.
Now just how bad is it?
Depends on how good
your imagination is.
Jesus Christ!
Specs called for
conduit safety covering.
How many fuse terminals
did you check?
How many do I have to?
Mr. Bigelow is here, sir.
Okay, send him in.
Now, Doug, one piece of
scorched wire...
...from a burned-out circuit breaker
isn't conclusive.
Maybe not. But now I'm worried about
what other shocks we're in for.
Will, Doug...
...J.D., wait till you see this.
What happened?
Was the wallpaper hung wrong?
We have an equipment problem.
- No problem in the tower, is there?
- Could be.
Come on.
You're just guessing.
I want to talk
to your son-in-law.
I wanna talk to him right away.
- Get Roger Simmons.
- Yes, sir.
I guarantee I'll check this out.
We're all going
to check it out.
I'm missing something.
We damn near had a fire.
Yeah, a fire.
In this building? Come on.
We haven't finished installing
the safety equipment.
- The party should've been put off...
- Hold it, Will!
Everybody's overreacting.
- Mr. Simmons is out, sir.
- Out where?
They don 't know, sir,
but I left word for him to call.
We'll talk to Roger tomorrow.
And then we'll decide what to do.
- That's okay, isn't it?
- Nope. Won't wait.
Try zone one again.
Damn it!
This is top priority.
We gotta get these
electrical systems on.
Our security program's
loused up without them.
Don't go away.
Doug!
Well, what a surprise!
Where's that electrical
genius of yours?
I called his office, the club,
the marina. No luck.
What's he done?
Come on, I'll get you a drink.
He must've done something.
My father called.
He hasn't been that upset in years.
Have any idea where he is?
Well my husband's territory
ranges rather widely.
It's like that of the timber wolf,
anywhere within a 50-mile radius.
But if you wanna wait,
he'll show up.
He has to.
His clothes are here.
- Can I get you a drink?
- No, thanks.
I guess you don't plan to tell me
what Roger's done.
Hi, Doug.
- Honey.
- Hello.
- What are you drinking these days?
- Nothing, right now.
Well, welcome back from
the wilderness.
To what do we owe the pleasure?
Callahan was
testing a backup generator.
There was a systems failure.
How can that be?
It can't be, theoretically.
Unless you screwed around
with the electrical specifications.
That's being rather blunt,
isn't it?
You betcha.
Then you'll understand my being
equally blunt.
What the hell business is it of yours?
I wonder what kickbacks were involved.
I don't have to take crap from you.
Listen. We had an electrical
flare-up in the main utility room.
Some of that wiring
wasn't exactly what I asked for.
All the wire I put in is up to code,
inspected and approved.
Code's not enough for that building!
And you know it!
I asked for installations
way above standard.
Buddy, you live in a dream world.
I deal in realities.
I want your wiring diagrams
and copies of your work orders.
That would take weeks
and a lot more clout than you have!
In my office! Tomorrow, 9:00.
They say he used to wrestle
grizzly bears in Montana.
Of course, he was younger then.
Probably in better condition.
You must have enjoyed
all this immensely.
No, I didn't.
Actually, I'm depressed
for both of us.
What did you expect me to do?
Punch him in the nose?
If you've done anything to
Dad's building, God help you.
Baby, I don't need God's help
or your old man's. Not anymore.
So don't expect me to shake
every time Daddy barks...
...even if that's
what you want me to do.
All I want is the man
I thought I married.
I guess we're running out of
reasons to stay married, aren't we?
It's getting late.
Mustn't miss the party.
Stand back, please!
Everybody, back of the ropes!
Stand back, please.
Hi.
7:30 sharp.
I hope you like your men prompt.
At my age?
I only care that they show up at all.
Nonsense.
Be a good girl, Elke.
I left you some milk in the kitchen.
See you later.
Did you find Simmons?
Yeah, I found him.
Did he or didn't he change your specs?
He didn't admit it,
but I bet you he did.
Payoffs and kickbacks.
The only way he could've swung it.
Here you are...
...your original specs.
Zone one only, but
we gotta start somewhere.
That son of a bitch
gave us an impossible job.
- Susan.
- Hello, Dan.
Good evening.
- How are you, dear?
- Congratulations. It's magnificent.
Thank you.
I'll meet you out front.
- I'd like to talk to Susan.
- Right.
Find me the architect
who designed you...
...and who needs Doug Roberts?
I do.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is a gala evening.
The entire city
is in a holiday mood.
The list of luminaries reads
like a Who's Who.
There are leaders
from society and government...
...stars of screen and television.
And now, just arriving,
the Honorable Gary Parker...
...chairman of the
Federal Urban Renewal Commission.
The senator's in from Washington
to be here for the dedication.
Senator Parker,
ladies and gentlemen.
We'll try to get him to the microphone
to say a few words for you.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you very much.
I'm honored to be here tonight.
This magnificent building
represents yet another landmark...
...in a long succession of landmarks
for this great city.
I think you've
got him in the bag, Jim.
- Being here at
this historic moment.
Thank you.
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
Mr. And Mrs. Roger Simmons.
Mrs. Simmons is the daughter
of the builder, Jim Duncan.
How are you?
Nice to see you, senator.
Shake hands with Mr. Duncan, please.
Where were you all day?
I wasn't aware
the leash was that tight.
Later, I wanna
ask you a few questions...
...and I expect
some straight answers.
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
Mayor and Mrs. Robert Ramsay.
I thank you very much.
I hereby dedicate
this magnificent glass tower...
...tallest building in the world!
We'll make it. That's it.
All right, Callahan?
Hit them.
This way.
It's really something, isn't it?
After you.
Come on, Dan.
I'm going by the office.
I'll be up in a few minutes.
I've never seen
the bridge look like that.
- It's unbelievable!
- Astonishing!
- How did it go down there, Mr. Bigelow?
- Fine, thank you. Good night.
Shall I leave you a night line?
No, you can disconnect.
I've had it with phones for today.
Lorrie...
Sorry, but I have
a letter that must go out.
See you Monday, Janet.
Gee, I never thought he'd
come back here before the party.
We almost missed him.
It's all right.
I'm not gonna do anything tonight.
Have a nice weekend.
Thanks. You too.
Hello.
Hi.
- Promise me something?
- What?
If I ever start taking you for granted,
do something about it.
And what do you suggest?
Cut off the phone lines.
Pour coffee down my neck.
Tweak my nose?
I promise.
- How's the family?
- Fine, thank you.
Good. Gary?
- Would you excuse us, gentlemen?
- Certainly.
- I've got a surprise for you.
- Politicians don't like surprises.
- Carlos?
- Yes, sir.
- What can I fix you?
- Meet Senator Parker.
- Great pleasure.
- It's an honor, senator.
Show him what you've been
hiding back there.
Yes, sir.
1929?
- That's all you'll drink tonight.
- A whole case?
What you don't drink,
we'll ship to Washington.
- Open a bottle, will you?
- Yes, sir.
How did you ever come by a whole case?
Come on, Jim.
It's nothing.
I guess you're looking for someone.
I am. Have you seen him?
I've ordered for Patty.
What can I get you?
- Nothing right now. Thank you, Roger.
- Susan, tell me...
What does a girl do in San Francisco
when her old man...
...decides to leave for two years?
Beats me, buddy.
No headhunting?
I've had a little trouble
making that work.
Could we discuss that
tomorrow at lunch?
No.
- You must miss your villa.
- Well, yes and no.
It gets rather dull
in the south of France.
Nothing but swimming and yachting,
partying and all that sort of thing.
And believe it or not, they fight
over the few eligible bachelors.
Even such old scraps as I.
- No false humility, please.
- Oh, shall we?
I decided to come back to
the reality of San Francisco...
...to regain my perspective
and my humility...
...and spend more time at the one
thing I'm really good at:
The stock market.
Monte Carlo's losses,
San Francisco's gains.
Thank you.
Do you believe in destiny?
I believe in all good things.
There must be a reason
for my coming back home.
Meeting you.
This can't be right.
It's too hot.
You better leave it off.
Utility. Wes.
Doug,
I'm up on 83 with Will.
We got a wiring problem.
Overloads could be trouble.
Shut down as many of
the zone one systems as you can.
I can't do that.
All the lights are on
for the dedication ceremony.
You mean the whole building?
We're taking
the overload just fine.
Well, shut it down right away.
I can't do that without an okay
from Mr. Duncan himself.
I'll accept the responsibility.
Just turn off the lights!
What about the lights
in the tower for the party?
- Not all the power, just the overload!
- Yes, sir, Mr. Roberts!
We better get down to 81
and check the relay systems.
They turned on everything
in the whole building.
There's something on 81.
Phone it in, in case the lines
to the fire department are out.
- I'll be in 81.
- You got it.
Get those drapes!
Smother it!
Try to smother it!
Pull it around over here.
Put it all over him. Come on!
Let's get some water onto that fire.
Turn it on!
Down, down! Stay low!
Call an ambulance for this man.
Get on the ball!
Call an ambulance!
I want everybody off this floor!
- The fire department?
- On their way.
Get that ambulance. Give me a hand.
Get him in the elevator.
All right, try not to touch him.
Try to get him by his belt.
This is 81. A man's been burned.
Get an ambulance.
Yes, right away.
Call Duncan in the tower.
He's got a lot of people up there.
- What?
- Do it now!
It's Mr. Roberts.
Yeah, Doug. We were
getting worried about you.
Susan's here, Senator Parker,
the mayor and his wife.
They're asking why
the greatest architect isn't here.
Never mind that.
Will Giddings has been badly burned.
Will Giddings burned? How?
An ambulance is coming,
but you better think about...
...getting those people down
on the ground floor.
What for?
We got a fire here!
Well, I think
it's under control, but...
Well, then why the urgency?
Urgency?
If fluky wiring in this building
caused that fire...
...fires could break out everywhere!
Doug, I think you're overreacting.
I feel sorry for Will Giddings,
but he'll be taken care of.
But I won't concern myself with
a fire in a storage room on 81...
...because it can't possibly
affect us up here...
...not in this building.
Now, have someone call me
when the fire department arrives.
Meanwhile, get in your dinner jacket
and come up and join the party!
What building's on the corner
of Montgomery and...
Oh, Jesus!
- The glass tower!
- What?
The glass tower!
I sure hope that fire's on
the first floor.
Did you ever fight one
in a high rise?
Is it as rough as I hear?
Like being inside a chimney.
Jesus!
How in the hell did they get here
before we did?
Don't anybody
ever stay home anymore?
- Mike, she's throwing a lot of smoke.
- Eighty-first floor, right?
We've got lobby control,
second alarm is in.
- Set up a Forward Command.
- Got it.
Chief...
...this is Roberts, the architect.
- What do we got here, Kappy?
- Fire started, 81 st floor, storage room.
It's bad. Smoke's so thick,
we can't tell how far it's spread.
- Exhaust system?
- Should've reversed automatically.
It must be a motor burnout.
- Sprinklers?
- They're not working on 81.
- Why not?
- I don't know.
- Jim?
- Yes, sir?
Give us a quick refresher on
your standpipe system.
- Floors have 3 and 1.5- inch outlets.
- GPM?
Fifteen hundred from ground to 68,
1000 from 68 to 100...
...and 500 from there to the roof.
Are these elevators
programmed for emergencies?
- What floor are your plans on?
- 79. My office.
That's two floors below the fire.
It'll be our Forward Command.
Men, take up the equipment.
Let's go.
Architects!
Yeah, it's all our fault.
You know we can't fight a fire
in anything over the 7th floor.
But you keep building them
as high as you can.
Are you here to take me on,
or the fire?
What about the 81 st floor?
You got everybody out of there?
I wanna see all floor plans,
81 through 85.
Gotcha.
This is what worries me.
Those beams and that glass.
Chief, 81 has been evacuated,
but it doesn't look too good up there.
Give me a list of your tenants.
Don't worry.
We're moving them out now.
Not live-ins. Businesses.
We lucked up.
Most of them haven't moved in yet.
Those that have are off at night.
I wanna know who they are, not where.
What's that got to do with anything?
Who they are?
Any wool or silk manufacturers?
In a fire, wool and silk
give off cyanide gas.
Any sporting-good manufacturers,
like table-tennis balls?
They give off toxic gases.
Now do you want me to keep going?
- One tenant list, coming up.
- Thank you.
What do we got?
Elevator bank, central core.
Service elevators here.
Air conditioning ducts, 6 inches.
- Pipe alleys here?
- One, two, three, four, five.
- This is south?
- South.
Have you got any construction on 81?
Anything that can blow up, like
gasoline, fabric cleaner?
I don't think so.
Good. I'll be up on 81.
For what it's worth, this is one
building I figured wouldn't burn.
Neither did I.
And they're celebrating.
A party.
What party? Where?
In the Promenade Room.
300 people.
Why didn't you get them out?
Why don't you go talk to Duncan?
He ain't listening to me.
I will.
Here he is now.
This is Duncan.
A battalion chief?
I'll watch out for him.
Thank you.
Ted, take your men down
to check that hallway.
Jack?
Jack, how bad?
I don't like the looks of it.
It's running the ceiling.
Work it around.
Up there.
- I'll be up topside.
- Right.
Jack...
...watch yourself.
Keep it high.
- Looking for me, chief?
- If you're Duncan.
I am.
Everything under control?
Gotta move these people out of here.
Now, just how bad is it?
It's a fire, mister, and
all fires are bad.
You're not familiar with
the many modern safety systems...
...we have designed into this building.
We've got them all.
It's your building, but it's our fire.
Now get out.
I don't think you're listening.
A fire on 81 can't reach up here,
not in this building.
- I'll do it.
- Hold it, hold it.
Do you want me to pull rank
with the mayor?
With a fire,
I outrank everybody here.
One thing we don't want is a panic.
I could tell them, but you ought to.
Just make a nice, cool announcement
to all your guests...
...that the party's being moved down
below the fire floor. Now.
Patty, you and Susan stay right here
where I can find you.
Now, don't leave this table.
You, I wanna talk to.
Did you change any of Doug's
electrical specifications?
- I most certainly did.
- For God's sake, why?
The reason should be obvious,
especially to you.
We've got a fire.
If it was caused by what you did,
I'll hang you out to dry.
And then I'm going to hang you!
Would you please stop playing?
Stop playing, will you?
Ladies and gentlemen...
Ladies and gentlemen,
may I have your attention?
It seems that we have a small fire...
...in one of our storage rooms...
...50 floors below.
I assure you there's no danger.
But in accordance with
the fire department's orders...
...a purely precautionary procedure...
...we're going to move the party
down to the lobby for a while.
And we'll be serving cocktails and
champagne in our Continental Room.
But I promise you,
dinner will not be delayed.
Now if we can all move
to the elevators...
Now, ladies and gentlemen...
...there's no reason to rush.
Senator Parker, you and your party.
It's really all right.
Stay here.
I'll be right back.
- Lisolette!
- Frank!
Lisolette!
- How's it going, chief?
- Better get ready.
Kappy, get the floor plans on 82.
We got problems.
Fire lapping?
- Are your com lines tested?
- Phone jacks on every floor.
- I'm plugging into your PA system.
- No sweat.
- Emergency setup?
- Battery-powered standby system.
Splice these lines into
our two-way communications van.
Sure.
- No problem?
- No problem.
- How long will this take?
- A minute.
Not bad.
Here's our problem.
The fire's lapping
up through the windows.
Get down! Get down!
What was that?
- Come on!
- The ceiling's going!
Men trapped! We need help!
Bring a line!
Pull them out, pull them out!
Pass the fire hose!
Pass it along!
Battalion Two to Forward Command.
Urgent!
Forward Command, go ahead.
Explosion on 81, fire headed
toward elevator banks!
We need more crews up here fast!
- They need relief on 81. Hit it.
- They're on their way.
Done!
Tell Duncan to stop those
Tower Room people...
...from using that express elevator,
or somebody'll get killed.
Ring in a third alarm.
I want some rescue squads
and some choppers here.
We may need them
to get those people down.
Come on, Park.
I'll be on 81.
The fire's moving toward
the main shaft.
Use the scenic elevator.
Don't overload.
I don't like how you talk to me.
- You drunk?
- Not yet.
- Then get out of my way!
- You didn't talk like this before.
Running over budget
and out of money.
Did you ask me then to shave
$2,000,000 off our electrical costs?
Shut up and help these people!
- Let me ask, father-in-law...
- Excuse me.
Did you encourage other
subcontractors to cut corners?
Where did you save the other
4,000,000 in Doug's original budget?
Please! Please!
Hold everything.
Ladies and gentlemen, I'm sorry.
Move back into the Promenade Room...
...and we'll take you down by
the scenic elevator.
Now these express elevators can be
activated by fire.
And with the probability
of short circuits...
...the cars might stop
on the floor where the fire is.
So please, we'll use
the scenic elevators over there.
For God's sake, get out of there!
Please, back!
It looks bad, Jack.
It is.
I got a couple of men hurt.
The fire's spreading.
I got a third alarm in.
What about this ceiling?
Must have just happened.
I'll check the other corridors.
Firemen, let's pull it down
before it falls down.
Bring it out! Take it down!
Empty all the water out.
Chief, it's out of control.
Bring in another line!
Get another tank!
Angela?
Phillip?
Phillip, open the door!
What ideas can I use upstairs...
...to explain where I've been
all this time?
Well, what you might do is just...
...walk right up to him and say,
"J.D., I'm sorry for the delay...
...but my secretary
had an urgent personal problem."
What happens if
he asks what the problem was?
He won't.
- You know what astonishes me?
- What?
You make love with a girl...
...and there's no visible evidence.
Nothing to mark the event.
Look at you. You look like you
could be going to church.
In this outfit?
I love you.
Did you leave a cigarette burning?
That's not a cigarette.
Jesus!
Get some towels.
Stuff them under the door.
Dan?
Right.
- What'd they say?
- Help's on the way.
There's nothing to worry about.
We'll just sit tight
and wait till they get here.
I won't panic.
Not to worry, baby.
Please, just join the end of the line.
Oh, no, ma'am.
Please.
But I can't find my daughter.
She's here somewhere.
- They're aware of that.
- She's wearing a purple dress.
- I've got to find her!
- I promise, they'll find her.
Now, only 12 at a time.
I'm sorry. That's it.
We'll be in the next group, maybe.
It won't be too long.
What's she doing on 87?
Forward Command?
I wanna speak to Jernigan.
Harry.
Jernigan.
What?
Damn it, man!
You should've sent a man up there!
How do you expect her to hear
a phone call? She's deaf!
Sure, the kids can hear!
I don't know, maybe they
were in the shower when you called.
You stay there.
I'll get them down!
All my men are committed.
I need fresh crews, damn it!
- We'll send them right up.
- Still got people on 87.
I'll get them down.
I'll give you a hand.
Turn your face away.
There never were any firemen,
were there?
I said that to make it easier on you.
I switched off the phones.
There's no way to call out.
Nobody knows we're up here.
Well, I always did want to die in bed.
Nobody's going to die.
At least they'll never find out
about us, will they?
I used to run the 100 in 10 flat.
Don't go!
I'll be back with
the whole fire department.
- You all right?
- The mother and children are in there.
- Don't worry. We'll get them out.
- Wait!
Please, Mrs. Mueller!
Please stay back.
- What do you think?
- I don't know. Give it a kick.
I'll take the back.
I got Mrs. Allbright.
Anybody in here?!
It's okay, kid. It's okay.
Come on.
He's okay.
- Mom, Mom!
- Your mom's all right.
Mr. Jernigan took her downstairs.
Anybody else?
My sister. Where's Angela?
He'll get her.
Angela?
Angela, where are you?
It's gonna be okay, Angela.
Thank God!
Hold it right here.
- All right!
- That's it.
Don't crush.
It'll take hours
to get everyone down.
Those of us with stout hearts and
trim waistlines should use the stairs.
- That's 135 floors.
- All downhill.
It's closer than they told us.
Let's try the south exit.
That might be clear.
Carlos!
- Yes, sir.
- Help us get this thing open.
Is it stuck?
Here, let me try to kick it.
- I'll call security.
- Yes, sir.
Battalion 38
responding to fourth alarm.
Where are those choppers, Kappy?
Navy's been alerted.
Why do they make these goddamn
things so heavy?
You want it easy, chief?
They should design a survival suit
for us like for football players.
Who pays to see us play?
Let's go to work.
I need two men up the stairwell
to the tower.
The door's jammed.
I want it cleared.
Okay, you got it.
Timmy, I want you with me.
Get two men with 30 minutes of air.
Kappy?
Glass will be sailing everywhere.
Tell the police to move
those barricades four blocks back.
- Got it.
- Let's hit it.
Yo! Security guard.
Anyone here?
Hello. Security.
Say, kitty, almost missed you.
Keep away from the walls.
There's fire on the other side.
Wait a minute.
It's a ruptured gas line.
Get back!
Oh, my God!
Is there any way you can get down?
I think I can.
Phillip!
Let him try.
There's no other way.
Come on, Phillip!
Come on.
That part's easy.
Come on, boy. Easy does it.
Get your foot over there.
Ease down.
Come on, Phillip.
Come on, Phillip!
It's just a couple of inches away now.
There you go.
Easy.
Don't look down!
Come on.
I gotcha. I gotcha.
We were supposed to have fire drills,
but nobody ever told me anything.
They said we would have fire drills.
But they never did.
It's going to be all right.
You all right?
You know, I had a...
I got up, but I'll have trouble
getting down. Can you help me?
Could you just hold on
around my neck, real tight?
Come on. Give it a try.
Just put your arms around me,
and you tell me what to do.
Put her legs down.
Hold on tight.
Hold on real tight, now.
Just hold on tight.
Hold on.
Hold on tight, now.
It's gonna be okay now.
Hold on!
Easy now.
- Hold on, Angela.
- I've got ahold of you!
Get your arms around my neck!
Thattagirl.
Nurse?
Mrs. Mueller, come on!
You gotta try!
Take it slowly, now.
You've got about a foot to go.
Feel around with your feet now.
Can you see it?
Hold on to that pole
and grab ahold of my belt.
Try to get your hand over there.
Come on, half a foot.
Six inches.
Try to swing now.
Just try to pendulum.
Can you swing?
Come on.
Just get to me over here.
Mrs. Mueller!
Are you all right?
All right, let's go.
Come on. Come on.
I'm coming.
You okay?
Nobody's gonna get down this way.
Oh, God! We're cut off.
Well, the only way is up.
Come on, let's go.
Chief O'Hallorhan?
Inside, security phone on the right.
- Get me Chief O'Hallorhan.
- I'm trying to get through now.
Can't we go down?
The fire's below us. We gotta go up,
underneath the Promenade Room.
Come on!
Tim, get that phone.
Check your ventilating
systems over here.
I'll send up another truck company.
Pull this ceiling,
and vent that other side.
It's the copter air-control officer.
Thank you. Jack, I know you've
been hitting it.
I'm getting relief
for you and your men.
Who am I speaking to?
Chief Flaker, sir.
U.S. Navy, Air Rescue.
It's about time.
We need your rescue choppers.
Right away. Our communications will
be near the Forward Command center.
No, too dangerous.
Stay out of those elevators.
Then, sir, we'll just trot
up the stairs.
You'll just trot right up to 79, huh?
Standing by in the lobby.
Thank you.
This ain't gonna help any!
They won't hear us in there.
There's 300 people!
It's a fire door. It's over
2.5 inches thick.
I could crawl through the duct.
Will we be able to go with you?
That leads to a pipe shaft
that's 135 floors straight down.
Phillip, take care of these ladies.
They're your responsibility now.
All right, I'll tell him.
- How is it on 65?
- They're containing it.
Well, it's still below us.
Let's take a look.
Okay, watch the electrics.
Come here!
The master generator's blown.
The backup should've kicked on.
See what's holding up our starters.
What happened?
Where the hell are we?
Security, this is Duncan.
Have the main breakers gone?
The whole system's failed.
What's the last report
on the firemen getting here?
Are they on their way?
Hold on to me a second.
Hold on!
Christ!
That's one of our men!
Oh, God!
Go down by rope.
Better get it.
Sir?
We'll rappel down to 65 and use
the top of that elevator as an exit.
Why not pry open the doors
at this level?
I don't think so.
I can't make it.
I'll fall.
I know I'll fall.
Then you better go first.
That way, when you fall,
you won't take any of us with you.
Let's go to work.
Check all rooms
in that corridor.
Check this room.
Tear it down.
See? Just like we
taught you in training.
Open it up.
Of course I read you!
I don't know where he is,
but if I see him, I'll tell him.
- Must be an easier way to get to a fire.
- Not for us.
- Where've you been?
- We had trouble getting here.
The Navy flight commander needs you.
Just walk 65 floors down?
Only five. A freight elevator
on 60's running auxiliary power.
- Got it controlled?
- Getting there.
You men stay here with the chief.
Tell him I'm on my way.
Oh, Mike...
This one of your men?
"Dan Bigelow."
Nope.
Must be a civilian.
Okay to O'Hallorhan.
He's on his way.
Look!
There's another one there!
Carlos, give me that security phone,
will you?
How'd you get in here?
I'll give it to you later.
Give me O'Hallorhan.
Anybody'll do.
Listen, the south stairwell is
blocked. Cement, for chrissake!
Can you send somebody up
to break it loose?
They're on their way?
How...?
Oh, my Lord, Elke.
My poor cat.
She's still in the apartment.
I'm sure the fire
didn't get up that high yet.
She'll be all right.
- Hello, ma'am.
- Hello.
- How're you doing?
- We're fine. Glad to see you.
That's the door right there.
It's blocked with cement.
We're gonna have to blow that thing.
Mrs. Mueller?
It's Mr. Roberts!
Mrs. Mueller! Phillip!
We hear you.
We're gonna blow this door.
Get everybody clear.
You've got about 30 seconds.
Understood?
Understood!
Okay, ma'am, let's get down there.
Out of the way.
Please go back.
They're gonna dynamite this door.
Step back, please.
We're blowing the door.
Okay, get down low.
- What kind of explosives are you using?
- It's plastic C-4.
Blow a hole in anything.
Here, shine this on the bag for me.
That's it. Keep it up here.
Is there gonna be a bang?
Nothing for you to worry about, baby.
You'll be safe.
Okay, everybody ready?
Good going, Brian.
You all right?
I'm James Duncan.
Can we get down that way?
No, not a chance, sir.
The stairway below is completely gone.
Everyone, listen!
- Hold it down!
- Listen!
I've been informed
that there's no possibility...
...of using this stairway to get out.
Now, I'm sorry.
Patty...
There's still a chance
we can get out of here.
Didn't you hear what my father said?
You can't get out that way.
Are you coming or not?
If you have to wait for permission
to save your own life, go ahead.
- I'm getting out.
- Roger, you...
Come on!
Let's go. You guys, hose the ceiling.
You two, in there!
- I guess you thought I stood you up.
- It crossed my mind.
You sure you're all right?
Those helicopters, they'll get
us out of here, won't they?
Sure they will
if there's not too much wind.
Some party.
Can I get you anything else?
The choppers are here, but the winds
make a landing attempt too risky.
Get some men on top of
the Peerless Building...
...and get a breeches buoy
to the Promenade Room.
We can't shoot a line that far
in this wind.
Why not shoot it from a chopper?
I'll get right on it.
- Doc?
- Chief, the ceiling fell in on him.
By the time I got to him,
he was covered with hot stuff.
Pretty ridiculous spectacle,
right?
- There's no way down.
- Thank God you're all right.
- Oh, Roger, what are we gonna go?
- I know what I'm gonna do.
Get quietly drunk.
If you're responsible for this,
I know what you must be feeling.
You don't know the meaning
of the word.
- Responsible?
- Feeling!
You know about responsibility.
It's a family trait.
Duncans are big in that department,
at least on the surface.
That's not fair! I don't think
it's wrong to feel a sense of duty.
Sometimes, when you turn
the exact same phrase...
...lift an eyebrow
in the exact same way...
...I see and I hear your father.
The two of you, one!
Like a big tree and a little tree
in its shade, where the acorn fell.
Roger, I came over here to you
because I thought you might need me.
Right now...
...what I need most...
...is this.
I promised myself if I ever saw you
again, I'd make a full confession.
No, but thank you.
- But you don't know anything about me.
- But I do.
You're penniless...
...you have no villa
in the south of France...
...no antiques coming, no paintings.
But, Harlee, I don't care.
I'm a cheap tinhorn.
A two-bit con man.
Not cheap.
Maybe unsuccessful.
But you see,
your heart isn't in it.
How can you cheat people
effectively...
...if you don't enjoy cheating them?
I came here to sell you 1000 shares
in Greater Anaheim Power and Light!
Is it a good investment?
There is no
Greater Anaheim Power and Light.
Only the certificate I had printed.
I think you'd have admired
the artwork. Beautiful engraving.
I'd like to see it.
It's in my jacket.
I took the jacket off.
It was needed elsewhere.
You see what I mean?
I can't even deliver
a phony stock certificate.
Did you hear what I said?
Every word.
Then tell me you're shocked...
...or at least disappointed.
- But I'm not.
- You must be!
Harlee, I'm not.
I'll be right back.
Give me a few minutes with Doug,
will you, dear?
Sure.
Will Giddings is dead.
He died 20 minutes ago.
Oh, boy.
I wonder how many more
will be dead tomorrow?
I thought we were
building something...
...where people could work,
live and be safe.
If you had to cut costs, why didn't
you cut floors instead of corners?
Now listen.
Any decisions that were made for the
use of alternate building materials...
...were made because I, as a builder,
have a right to make those decisions.
If I remain within the building code,
and goddamn it, I did!
Oh, here we go again!
The building code. Come on.
That's a standard cop-out
when you're in trouble!
I was crawling around up there.
The duct holes weren't fire-stopped!
Corridors without fire doors
and the sprinklers won't work.
And an electrical system
that's good for what?
I mean, it's good for starting fires!
Where was I
when all this was going on?
Because I'm just as guilty as you
and that goddamn son-in-law of yours!
What do they call it
when you kill people?
- Who is it?
- Chief O'Hallorhan.
- What happened?
- Part of the central corridor just blew.
We've got in the fifth alarm.
The helicopters?
It's too windy. We'll set up the
breeches buoy on the Peerless Building.
What can we do to help?
Move your combustible material
away from the window.
Okay, gotcha.
There's nobody on those drapes.
Let's get them.
Jake, give me a hand.
Did you reach her?
The phones are all out.
Just a little while longer,
and we'll all be home together.
If only I could have talked to her.
Let her know we were thinking of her.
Told her how precious she is to us.
She's still such a child.
She doesn't even know where I keep
the key to the safety deposit box.
How will she be able to get into it?
I mean...
...if she should have to.
The things you think of.
Do you wanna help me?
- Here he is.
- The wind's down a little.
We're gonna try for a landing.
Get Roberts.
Get 10 people on the roof.
Have the rest stand by.
We're gonna start airlifting.
Will do.
Put these over there.
Give me a pad of paper and a pencil.
Give me that brandy snifter too.
- Doug, are they going to land?
- They're gonna try.
We'll send the kids out first,
then the women.
Number these up to 100 or so.
High-rise roulette.
High-rise roulette. That's right.
- There may not be time to tell you...
- There will be.
I'll go tell everybody.
Pass those out when you're ready.
There'll be a lot of wind up there,
so everybody stay in one group.
Come on.
Stay back, stay back!
Look out!
Roberts! Roberts!
Chief O'Hallorhan
wants to speak to you.
All right, make way.
Coming through, coming through!
Here he is now.
Roberts, I know those pilots
are dead, and I...
God, it was just awful up there.
Listen, our best chance now
is the breeches buoy.
I told my two firemen
to knock out a window.
We'll try to shoot a line
from a chopper.
Hey, one of you guys
got a pair of clippers?
- Sure, what do you want them for?
- I want to try something.
Step back. The firemen
are gonna knock out the windows.
Step back and you won't get hurt.
May I have your attention, please?
We've activated a gravity brake on
that outside elevator.
There's no power to bring it back up,
but at least we can get 12 people out.
Which 12?
The same group that was
up on the roof and two additions.
The woman who saved the children's
lives and a fireman!
I want a trained man in there.
All right, let's move it out!
Marge!
Take this. Take it!
You can get out! Go on.
What are you doing?
I'm sorry.
I want you out of here.
So you can stop worrying about me?
What about me worrying about you?
It's the only way you can help me.
Help me.
If you asked me
to go to the North Pole...
...or even the cliffs of Mendocino,
I'd go.
What if I ask you tomorrow?
Please.
- Ma'am, I'll take her.
- Thank you.
Come on, Phillip.
I'll never let you go anywhere
without me again.
I don't want to.
Ever again.
- I'll meet you in the lobby.
- I'll be waiting.
We're still a lady short.
- You've gotta go.
- I don't want to leave you.
Honey, I'll make it.
I promise you.
Have I ever broken a promise to you?
Good luck, honey.
Please.
All set, everyone?
Okay, here we go.
Out of sight!
Yeah, it's coming.
Let's untie this, take it off,
pull in the rest of the line!
Okay, come on.
Let's get it through.
All right,
hold it right there!
Bring in another 20 feet
of that main line.
That's it.
All right, bring in a little more!
That's it. Hold it now.
Brace yourselves.
Watch your heads!
Grab it! Take it back and secure it!
All right, let it go!
Let it go!
All right, go on!
Take it out!
Okay, take ahold.
How about the main line?
Secured?
Good!
Chief!
Explosion above 110...
...blew the elevator off its track.
It's hanging by a cable.
- How many people in it?
- Loaded. I'd say about 12.
What're you gonna go?
Flaker.
- Flaker!
- Sir?
Can you give me a chopper
with a winch and some cable?
Have them pick me up on the
Peerless Building.
Got it.
Try and get a hitch on that elevator.
Drop it down to the deck
by the chopper.
Mommy, Mommy!
I won't cry if you won't cry.
It's all right.
Yeah, take it up out of there.
Pull it. Come on!
Tie it over there.
Okay, let her go!
Look out below!
Come on.
Okay, that's it.
All right!
There's one in there!
Come on! Pull it in!
All right, let's haul
that chair in! Come on!
That's it!
All right, keep it going!
All right, hold it right there.
Who's next in order?
I am. I am!
- Come ahead!
- I can't do that.
Yes, you can.
- I can't!
- Yes, you can.
Oh, God!
Don't let go of me!
Don't let me fall!
Don't let go!
Don't let go of me!
Get me out, please!
Hold it right there.
Okay, lower the cable.
Grab that hook!
Steady.
What about the torch?
Lash it tight.
- This is O'Hallorhan.
- We read you, chief.
Pick me up with the hook...
...and set me down on the
scenic elevator.
Then you'll pick up the elevator
and gently set it down on the street.
Can you handle the weight?
I think we can handle it.
We'll find out in a hurry.
Watch it!
Take it away!
How much time do we have?
I wish I knew.
Goddamn it, Jim,
you built the place!
I just don't think that
all of us are gonna make it.
Well, I guess I'm next.
I don't suppose you'll let me stay.
Come on. I'll see you soon.
I love you.
Let it go!
You think this'll hold it?
It'd better.
We have to cut the elevator cable.
- What's your number?
- 68.
47.
Here, Mrs. Ramsay,
you'll be all right now.
- You'll be all right.
- Tell my husband I'm all right.
- Tell him I'll be all right.
- I will.
- And I'll see him at home later.
Let's go.
Oh, my God, you're all right!
Thank God you're all right!
Watch the ladder.
Hey, Mike...
...deputy wants to see you.
Mike, we've been checking
the situation in the Promenade Room.
We figure they've got
17 or 18 minutes left, if that.
It'll take more than 3 hours
to get them down by breeches buoy.
They'll die up there
if something's not done.
We might have the answer.
Johnson's a structural engineer.
Tell the chief your calculations.
The structural strength
of the joists in that room...
...could definitely
withstand the explosion.
What explosion?
Chief, we've got the copter ready.
Wait a minute. We'll handle that.
Just get back to your job.
Yes, sir.
What explosion?
We can blow the tanks
two floors above the Promenade Room.
They hold 1,000,000 gallons of water.
That's enough to drown the fire.
- You're crazy.
- Mike, it's the only way.
You could kill everybody up there.
I don't think so.
You don't think?
When you take into account the stress
factors, the design...
Wait a minute. Just hold it.
We've already made the decision.
Someone has got to go up there,
rig the charges and blow them.
There's only two people qualified
for that. You and Conners.
They just brought Conners down.
He's on his way to the burn center.
Under the circumstances,
we can't order you to go up there.
I'm just laying it out for you.
But you...
You see how it is, don't you?
How do I get back down?
Oh, shit!
The women are gone.
We are going next.
You've all got numbers.
And you're gonna take your turn.
And if it's any consolation...
...I'll be the last one out of here
along with my son-in-law.
It's out of control.
And it's coming your way.
You got about 15 minutes.
Now, they want to try something.
They wanna blow those
water tanks above you.
They think it'll kill the fire.
How are they gonna get the
explosives up here?
They'll find some dumb
son of a bitch to bring it up.
Hang on, I'll tell them.
They want to put out the fire by
blowing the water tanks above us.
We'll eat a lot of water and concrete,
but if they don't try it, we'll burn.
The fire's out of control.
They think we got maybe 15 minutes.
This way, some of us might survive.
We got no options.
Come on. Let's go.
Get that line.
Get off!
- You crazy bastards! Drop this line!
- Let go of me!
Drop the line.
It's not gonna work.
It won't hold everybody!
Get off!
- Get the hell out of there!
- Go!
Get off.
Chief.
We lost the breeches buoy.
It was panic up here.
It's under control now.
I'll try and set down on the roof.
I'll need you up there.
I know where to place the charges,
but I don't know how.
I know how.
See you up there.
You'll have to tie yourselves down.
Ropes, tablecloths, belts...
...anything you can find!
- Carlos!
- Yes, sir.
Get some knives.
There we go.
For God's sakes, Carlos. Don't tie
yourself up to a lot of glass.
That's the '29.
Try it.
It's okay.
Doug...
...I never thought this could happen.
Sure.
- How much time you think we got?
- Ten minutes, maybe less.
We'll have to blow the floors
as well as the tanks, you know.
All right. This is your detonator.
You're running instantaneous.
I'm running delayed. Here you go.
This is your explosive.
This is the timer.
Later on,
after you throw the wire...
...we'll plug it and splice it into
the timer, set it, and it blows.
Set your explosive like this.
Take your detonator,
pull the plug.
Toss it.
- Got it?
- I got it.
- Good luck. See you later.
- Okay, thanks.
Here you go.
What will you set it for?
Five.
I think we can make that.
That's it.
Tie yourselves down, goddamn it!
You'll never make it through there.
How much time?
Three and a half.
Here.
I'm burning up!
Let's go!
Fireman?
Bob!
Excuse me.
She was in the elevator with you.
The fine-looking lady. Mrs. Mueller.
Have you seen her?
I'm sorry, she's dead.
Lisa!
- Claiborne!
- What?
I didn't want you to see him.
You know, there's nothing any of us
can do to bring back the dead.
All I can do now is pray to God...
...that I can stop this from
ever happening again.
I don't know.
Maybe they just ought to leave it
the way it is.
Kind of a shrine to all
the bullshit in the world.
You know, we were lucky tonight.
Body count's less than 200.
One of these days, they'll kill
10,000 in one of these firetraps.
And I'll keep eating smoke
and bringing out bodies...
...until somebody asks us...
...how to build them.
Okay. I'm asking.
You know where to reach me.
So long, architect.
Subtitles by
SDI Media Group
[ENGLISH]