When I came back from leave,
everything looked the same...
...except the countryside
was already green.
I saw the old church in a cup
in the hills...
...and the mountains beyond, brown
mountains with green on their slopes.
The war slowed down
during the winter...
...but the troops still marched
with heavy cartridge boxes...
...bulging under their capes...
...as though they were
six months gone with child.
Our unit was stationed in the town
where we had been since autumn.
I was glad the Austrians
seemed to want to come back.
They did not bombard it
to destroy it...
...but only a little, in a military way.
Lieutenant!
Frederico! We miss you.
- Hi, Bonello.
- Look who's back. Signore lieutenant.
- Car's in good shape? How's this one?
- It's okay.
- Okay, number one.
- Having any trouble with the war?
No. Here in Orsino, the ambulance
company has no trouble with the war.
But up there, the war is bad.
Always bad.
I know how you feel.
Give me my hat
to go play with the girls.
Show me the girls and I go play.
I see nothing's changed.
How are you, Passini?
And you, Aymo.
Still causing trouble?
I, signore lieutenant? It is Passini
who keeps moaning.
You know what he told me
about you yesterday? He said:
"The lieutenant,
he don't come back."
He's wrong. I said
you don't come back...
...because Americans,
they're too smart.
Not all of them, maybe.
Think I'll check in.
Looks like you get along
better without me.
It's better to have an officer
to complain about.
Here, take these things
in signore lieutenant's quarters.
Come in.
Lieutenant Henry
reporting for duty, sir.
You'll never learn. It's not like this.
Like this.
You're back in good time.
We expect to get a road
through the snow in a few weeks.
Then we move.
Glad you're back, lieutenant.
Thank you, Major Stampi.
Your chess has improved, doctor.
God must have heard
my prayers for you.
Check.
What do you say, Father, if after
you die you find out there is no God?
I shall keep the bad news
to myself, major.
The papi returns.
Did you have a nice permission?
You're looking well.
Lying is a sin, Father.
Lieutenant Henry looks terrible.
One more kiss and he'd fall apart.
What's new? I hear from Major Stampi
we're almost ready to go.
Yes. Soon we march up the Alps,
down the Alps...
...capture Austria and finish the war.
By God's mercy.
A stubborn fellow.
Two years in war...
...and he still pretends
there is a God of mercy. Coffee?
- No, thanks.
- Did you see much of interest?
- Well, I saw some fine churches.
- From the outside, I hope.
Perhaps someday when you have
the time, you'll enter one.
God is patient.
Tell me, did you go fishing in Abruzzi?
And did you see my family?
I'm sorry, Father.
I meant to go to the Abruzzi...
...but things came up in Naples and...
We'll go together someday.
Perhaps Rini will go with us.
Yes. Unbelievers are sometimes
devout fishermen.
- How are things at the hospital?
- Since you went away, nothing.
Jaundice, pneumonia,
self-inflicted wounds.
And of course, venereal diseases.
Always harder
to evade than enemy bullets.
But tell me, I can wait no longer.
What kind of a time did you have?
- Great.
- Many beautiful girls?
- Enough.
- At your age, I never spoke that word.
I think perhaps we should finish
our game tomorrow, major.
You are a good priest, but still a priest.
- I shall be happy to beat you tomorrow.
- See you tomorrow.
- Frederico.
- So long, Father.
Now, where did you go
and what did you do?
- Tell me everything at once.
- I went everywhere.
Milan, Florence, Rome,
Naples, Taormina.
You talk like a timetable. Where was
the most beautiful adventure?
- Milan.
- Maybe because it was first.
She played the piano beautifully.
There is nothing like talent.
I remember in Verona once,
a lady artist, a contortionist...
Oh, shut up.
I bore my friend, forgive me.
However, I have something of interest.
Here we have a big improvement
in the war situation.
- We have beautiful English girls.
- Wonderful.
Yes, the British have opened
a new hospital near Orsino.
I am now in love with one
of the nurses, Miss Barkley.
I have even thought
of marrying Miss Barkley...
...but I best confess,
she has one drawback:
Her attitude is uncooperative.
You must be slipping.
No, but she is very strange,
very moody.
Who knows, she might even
prefer you to me.
You will meet her tomorrow.
Have you any money?
- Fifty lire?
- In my wallet.
I must make the impression
of a man of sufficient wealth.
You are my great and good friend,
and financial protector.
- Don't overdo it.
- In case I change my mind...
...I will need this for the Villa Rosa.
Poor girls, they have missed me.
- You and 50 lire.
- And you...
Carmelina told me, "If Frederico
does not come back soon...
...we hang the Villa Rosa
in black bunting."
Oh, shut up about dames.
I can see you had
a successful vacation.
Two new ones.
England is a great country.
- Good morning.
I would like...
Excuse me.
- Miss Barkley? Good morning.
- Good morning, major.
May I present my young American
friend, Lieutenant Frederick Henry.
How do you do?
Hello.
Isn't it odd for an American
to be in the Italian army?
It's not the army, only the ambulance.
- The ambulance is important service...
- It's very odd, though.
Why did you do it?
Oh, I missed out on a job
as war correspondent.
I didn't want to kill anybody, so I
tried the Red Cross, to have a look.
- To have a look?
- Yes, I may want to do some writing.
They assigned me
to the auto ambulance.
- End of story.
- With me, it's a different story.
I am a lover of mankind...
- Major Rinaldi?
- Yes.
Dr. Gates would like to see you,
if you have time.
Yes, I have time. Will you pardon me?
Will you follow me please, doctor?
With pleasure.
What's the stick?
It belonged to a boy
who was killed last year.
Oh, I'm sorry. I...
He was a very nice boy.
He was going to marry me.
- He was killed in the Somme.
- That was a mean battle.
His mother sent me the little stick.
They returned it with his things.
- Were you engaged long?
- Eight years.
- We grew up together.
- Why didn't you marry him?
I don't know. I was a fool not to.
Have you ever loved anyone?
Off and on.
You have beautiful hair.
I was going to cut it all off
when he died.
That would've been a shame.
I wanted to do something for him.
He could've had anything
he wanted if I had known.
I would have married him, or anything.
I thought it would be worse for him
to go to war if we were lovers.
Then, of course, he was killed.
That was the end of it.
I don't know.
Oh, yes. That's the end of it.
It's very beautiful here.
- Is it true they'll have an offensive?
- So I've heard.
Then we'll have some work.
There's no work now.
- Done nursing long?
- Since the end of ' 15.
I started when he did.
I remember having a silly idea he might
come to the hospital where I was.
With a saber cut, I suppose,
and a bandage around his head.
- It doesn't happen like that.
- No, he didn't have a saber cut.
They blew him all to bits.
- Do you suppose it will always go on?
- No.
- What's to stop it?
- It'll crack somewhere.
It really doesn't matter.
We die anyway.
It takes a while.
You think so?
Will you excuse me?
I have to go now.
Miss Barkley...
I have been thinking
about Miss Barkley.
She has beauty and mystery,
but she is not for us.
Miss Barkley is not only a woman,
she is a problem.
- It is not a good mixture.
- Your lectures throw me off.
Well, gentlemen, I have news.
Tomorrow morning,
rain or shine, we advance.
We advance in the morning, and I am
wasting time with a billiard ball.
With this news,
it will be impossible...
...to get into Villa Rosa
with a shoehorn.
You go. I'm not in the mood.
This is madness. Tomorrow night,
you will be in the Alps, freezing.
You'll need a few warm memories.
I am stupid. The British.
You are going to call on Miss Barkley
in spite of my warnings.
- Father Galli, I need your help.
- Yes, major.
Tell our friend if he sees Miss Barkley
three times, he'll have to marry her.
Tell him. It is a British law.
And that is not all.
After marriage, children.
There is no end to the disasters
the British can bring down on Frederico.
I am hardly in a position
to discourage marriage.
Are you coming, papi?
I offer you a last reprieve.
I'll see you tomorrow in the parade.
All right.
But if all does not go well...
...you know where I am.
Good night, gentlemen.
- Good night, major.
- Miss Barkley will be down directly.
- Thank you very much.
- They look like a mausoleum.
- What did you say?
I said these busts
look like a cemetery.
- Bad for the patients, I should think.
- I think the busts are rather handsome.
By the way, you know
that our girls...
...are not permitted to leave
during the evening?
The Italians do not approve
of women being so near the front.
That's pretty silly of them, isn't it?
No.
I'm inclined to think they're right.
- Good evening.
- Hello, Miss Barkley.
Is there any place we can go?
Why?
Well, I'd... I'd like to see you.
Well, l... I suppose we could walk
in the garden, unless it rains.
Well, it's not raining now.
Thank you.
They certainly have difficult rules
for you nurses.
I'm not really a nurse.
I'm something called V.A.D.
- What's the difference?
- A nurse is like a doctor.
It takes a long time to be one.
A V.A.D. Is a shortcut. For war only.
Well, a lot of things are for war only.
Why did you want to see me?
Isn't that rather obvious?
You mean, to have a look?
You're nice looking at.
Frankly, I didn't like your attitude
about the war.
- Some people joined for other reasons.
- You mean a better world, and all that?
Yes. Seems rather foolish
to you, doesn't it?
You mustn't take things too hard.
It's a short life, at best.
- Yes, I think that too.
- Then why not enjoy it?
Let's drop the war.
- There's no place to drop it.
- Let's drop it anyway.
- Please.
- Why not?
- It's so meaningless.
- No, it's not.
People who don't even know each other.
I don't like it. I never have.
I'm sorry.
That's all right.
I'm dreadfully sorry.
I just couldn't stand
the "nurse's evening off" aspect of it.
I didn't mean to hurt you.
- I did hurt you, didn't I?
- No harm done.
It's happened before.
You poor man.
You mean girls usually slap you?
Well, not always.
You don't mind when they do?
It's more interesting when they don't.
Especially when they're
as beautiful as you.
You don't have to say
a lot of nonsense.
I said I was sorry.
I suppose I might have waited
until we knew each other.
- Lf only there'd been time.
- You're leaving?
We all are.
- When?
- In the morning.
It's raining.
This is closer.
- You're trembling.
- It's nothing.
- What is it?
- It's nothing, really.
Tell me.
It's only that l... I've always been
afraid of the rain.
Why?
- I don't know.
- Tell me.
Don't make me.
Tell me.
I'm afraid of the rain because
sometimes I see myself dead in it.
Hold me.
Say, "I've come back to Catherine
in the night."
"I've come back to Catherine
Oh, darling, you have come back,
haven't you?
- Yes.
- I love you so...
It's been awful.
It's very funny, really,
happening to me like this.
Not with someone I loved
for years and years.
With someone I've just met.
A stranger.
Your name is Frederick Henry,
isn't it?
Don't talk that way, please.
You're so sweet.
You don't have to play any games.
I'm not playing any games.
I'm in love with you.
I wasn't kissing you.
I thought...
It sounds mad.
I thought he'd come back to me
in the night.
Catherine, darling...
"Catherine."
You don't pronounce
it very much alike.
But you're a very nice boy.
I'm glad you're nice. But you
don't have to pretend you love me.
- That's over for the evening.
- I'm not pretending...
I'm not mad and I'm not gone off.
It's only a little sometimes.
Now you can go to war
and forget all about this.
- I'll come back to you.
- Please, you make it worse.
I hope the advance is not too difficult.
That you don't get hurt.
Please.
Don't go away like this.
Good night.
I'm sorry, papi, but we must leave.
Lieutenant Henry. Lieutenant Henry!
Lieutenant Henry!
Take the wheel.
- Do you love me, truly?
- I'm mad for you.
Come back. Promise you'll come back.
- I promise.
- Promise you won't leave me behind.
Goodbye, darling. I'll be waiting.
We're liable to be up in these hills
a long time.
Well, baby, it will seem longer
to you.
Do you think we have
to capture all the Alps?
You sound as if Miss Barkley
had been very cooperative.
- Shut up.
- Tell me. It will make you feel better.
- Did she...?
- Shut up.
- I am a man of extreme delicacy...
- lf you wanna be my friend, shut up.
I don't want to be your friend.
I am your friend.
An envious one.
It's a long time since I had anyone
to say goodbye to.
They slow down.
Maybe they changed their minds.
- You think they like to attack?
- Nobody likes to attack.
- I like to attack.
- Then you are stupid.
The great Passini reads books.
Knows everything.
- Better than knowing nothing.
- Everybody's stupid.
Fighting is stupid.
- War is stupid.
- He's right.
He's right. What are we doing here?
The field hospitals, lieutenant.
There's your sawmill, doctor.
Good luck up there.
See you again, major.
Bonello, I'll drive for a while.
Passini, you and Aymo hop in the back.
- Is good, the blessing, no?
- It can't hurt.
Turn the ambulances around before
you come in. Fill the gas tanks too.
- Hey, we ought to clean the plugs.
- Yes, that will win the war.
Very fine.
We sleep in the snow.
Beg your pardon, captain.
Thought I'd come up and have a look.
Our front lines are just below.
The enemy is on that ridge facing us.
Fire!
They're trying to get
our supply depot.
I better get down.
Looks like we'll be busy.
Take a cable car!
Fire!
Get the ambulances ready!
Passini, open those doors!
Take it easy, Passini.
Passini.
Shoot.
Stop it.
Lieutenant Henry, are you all right?
Passini.
- Mother of God, no!
- Shut up.
Give me a hand.
Put signore lieutenant on the bottom,
the other man on top.
- Does it hurt?
- No. Let's go!
Hold on, lieutenant.
Bonello? Hey, Bonello!
- What's the matter?
- The man over me has a hemorrhage.
Then I'll go fast, signore lieutenant.
We're not far from the hospital.
How's the man on top,
signore lieutenant?
He's dead, I think.
Almost there.
- How are you, baby?
- What do you think?
The pain hasn't started yet.
A good thing to know.
A present for you, papi.
The best cognac in Italy.
What's happening with the mountain?
Have we taken it yet?
Fifty thousand Italians are now
freezing triumphantly on its top.
Father Galli's here
with his breath of heaven.
- Hello, Frederico.
- Hello.
Our papi's going to be all right.
- I'm happy to hear that.
- I have other good news.
Lieutenant Henry will be moved
to the new American hospital in Milan.
No, Rini.
I wanna be sent to Orsino.
It is not in my hands.
All wounded Americans
have been ordered to Milan.
Why shouldn't you want to be?
I am very stupid.
It is not geography.
It is Miss Barkley.
- I'm going to Orsino.
- Relax.
I will see what can be done.
Between Father Galli and me,
we will move heaven and earth...
...to send Miss Barkley to Milan.
- Orderly.
- Yes, major.
Lieutenant Henry is the
illegitimate son of President Wilson.
Keep the bugs off him.
You are not in pain?
Feels better.
I will pray for your quick recovery.
I hope he hears you.
He hears if you love him.
Perhaps from Milan you'll go home.
You too...
...to the Abruzzi country.
Next time, I'll join you there.
Yes, we'll go fishing together
in a stream below our house.
- There's a river up in Wisconsin.
- There are fine rivers everywhere.
In Abruzzi, perhaps some of the best.
And the people...
...kind with a smile for God.
The springtime
is the most beautiful in Italy.
But the fall is even more lovely.
Sleep well, my friend...
...and may God bring you to your river.
Get the porter.
Where did he go?
- There you are.
- Yeah, big surprise.
That's my sore leg, you fool!
Excuse me.
- Watch what you're doing.
- Excuse me.
- Take him up.
- Go easy.
Don't worry, we get you upstairs.
Alive!
Easy, now.
He won't fit.
- You gotta put the leg down.
- I can't.
I help you.
No. No!
Hey, stop it.
He fits now.
Sorry, lieutenant, no room.
My leg. Put my leg up.
Americans, lots of trouble.
- You got any idea where you're going?
- I think we have some beds up here.
Nobody here. What do we do?
- I'll find somebody.
- Good idea.
Here she is.
- Lieutenant Henry?
- Yeah.
You're our first patient.
Your doctor in Orsino
notified me of your coming.
- I'm Miss Van Campen, superintendent.
- How do you do?
- This is Miss Ferguson.
The room at the end of the hall,
porter.
- Are there any other nurses here?
- Just Miss Ferguson and myself.
I think we're enough for one patient.
- Do you expect any other nurses?
- Just the two of us.
That bed.
You fool!
Come on.
Sorry, lieutenant.
Excuse me, lieutenant.
Sorry.
- Get out.
- I'm sorry...
Get out of here!
Undress and bathe him, Miss Ferguson.
And bring a nightgown.
- I'll undress and bathe myself.
- Nonsense.
- Would you like to use the bedpan?
- No!
- When does a doctor get here?
- When he gets back.
We've telephoned
to Lake Como for him.
I'm hungry. How's the food?
We find it quite satisfactory.
- Can I have wine with my meals?
- No!
Open your mouth.
- Let's see how sick you really are.
- I'm not sick, I'm wounded!
I need a drink.
Why can't I have one?
Because I said absolutely not.
That's rather infantile.
Turn him over, Miss Ferguson.
Let's see if he can break it that way.
- Did you get it?
- Yes, sir.
I ran the blockade.
- Now, turn away.
- I'm over 21.
- Here.
- It's a pity.
They were very becoming.
Don't let Van Campen catch
you guzzling. We'll both get life.
- Find out anything about Miss Barkley?
- Yes.
- Indeed.
- What'd you find out?
Oh, look at him.
The bedridden Romeo.
Miss Barkley is arriving
on the 8:00 train.
She's coming? You're not kidding?
Boy, she must be something.
That's the barber.
I figured you could use a shave.
Always helps a reunion.
Hello.
You sweet...
You're wonderful to come here.
Come here, please.
- Did they operate yet?
- No. Forget about that. Please, darling.
- You mustn't.
- I'm crazy about you.
Oh, darling.
You do love me?
I adore you.
Come on, please.
But do you really love me?
Don't keep saying that.
Please, Catherine.
Shut the door.
Don't talk. Please, Catherine.
I love you.
Darling.
Smooth.
Smooth as piano keys.
Smooth as emery paper.
- Is it rough?
- No, darling.
I was just making fun of you.
I have to go now, darling.
I'm crazy in love with you.
You're sure?
- You're sure you love me?
- Very sure.
- You'll be good to me, won't you?
- Of course I will.
You will, won't you?
Because we're going to
have a strange life.
Strange?
But it's the only life I want.
It is an honor to attend
a friend of Rinaldi.
I was his chief at the university.
From the start he revealed
a talent for female anatomy.
Tell me what the x-rays show, please.
The x-ray.
I think it'd be safer
if we don't open the knee...
...until the foreign bodies are encysted.
That will take five or six months.
I'm not lying around
like a dummy for six months.
Perhaps we will know a little more
about how long, after our examination.
Is she your girl, young man?
I'm her fella.
I thought so.
Injury and death. Death and injury.
I have been standing
over them for 30 years.
But the war changes
the picture a little.
Youth instead of age
requires my services.
What a shame to waste
young legs as targets.
What does the x-ray
of the right kneecap show?
- The kneecap is free.
- What?
No foreign substance
until we come to the calf.
You are mad. I can see
the shrapnel with my naked eye.
I'm sorry, colonel,
there is nothing there.
All the right leg needs
is a few minor probes to the calf.
- This is the x-ray of the left leg.
- Impossible.
To a medical genius,
nothing is impossible.
Now, kindly look at the leg
under discussion...
...the right one, please,
and describe its contents.
She is a lovely girl.
I'll do all your obstetrical work
free, up to the third baby.
After that there will be a small fee.
The ankle is curiously swollen
and full of foreign bodies.
- What ankle?
- The right one, here.
That is not an ankle.
- That's the knee in question.
- Of course.
- I was holding the plate upside down.
- Natural mistake.
Next time, hand me the plate
in the proper position.
- Right-side up.
- How about it, doctor?
Do I have to wait six months
for an operation?
Well, I think we can
get to you a little sooner.
- Say, tomorrow?
- Tomorrow?
- Yes.
- Good work.
- We'll meet at 10 in the morning.
- See you on the chopping block.
I leave you in good hands.
Love is the best medicine.
- Good evening, happy people.
- Good night.
Oh, doctor...
...thank you for your assistance.
If I can be of any further help to you,
doctor, don't hesitate to call on me.
I have duties.
I have to get you ready.
I don't want anyone else
to touch you.
I know I'm silly,
but I'll be furious if they touch you.
Now, just a little advice:
When you're going under ether,
don't think about us...
...because people get very blabby
under an anesthetic.
Think of something very unpleasant...
...or say your prayers.
That'll create a splendid impression.
I won't talk. Not a chance.
Don't brag. You're very sweet,
you don't have to brag.
You have such a lovely temperature.
I like yours better.
I'm awfully proud
of your temperature.
Maybe all our children
will have fine temperatures.
Our children will probably
have beastly temperatures.
Tonight? Please.
For tonight,
the chart indicates a few drugs...
...a bath...
...and an emetic.
Nothing else.
He'll be out of the ether soon.
Couldn't ask for a better operation.
Don't jiggle him.
Catherine.
Come here.
Van Campen is listening.
You better muzzle your Romeo.
Catherine, come here.
Our patient seems to have
a one-track mind.
If she hears him, you're sunk.
Catherine, come here...
Can you imagine anyone making wine
because it tastes like strawberries?
Why shouldn't they?
It sounds splendid.
But it doesn't even taste
like strawberries.
Next time, if I don't seem
too ungrateful, I'd like brandy.
Oh, no.
It's much too strong for you.
Tell you what I'll do, Cat.
Get me another bottle
of brandy and I'll marry you.
Just for a bottle of brandy
you'd make an honest woman of me?
No, as a matter of fact, I'll marry you
even if you do bring me this vile stuff.
No.
- We're not going to be married.
- Yes, we are.
Darling...
...I'd rather marry you
than do anything in the world.
- Lf we do, they'll send me away.
- Who says?
Wives are not allowed at the front.
Aren't you embarrassed
about not being married?
No.
See, darling...
...it would mean everything
to me if I had any religion.
But you're my only religion.
You're all I've got.
It's going to rain.
Cat, darling.
It's all nonsense.
I'm not afraid of the rain.
Dear God, I wish I weren't.
- Did you see the two new patients?
- No.
A head wound and a hernia.
- It's interesting.
- I'm grateful for them.
- I was terrified they'd send me back.
- How's your hero?
He walked down the corridor
three times...
...then he wanted to try running.
I had to stop him forcibly.
We're going boating next week.
- I think it'll be good for him, don't you?
- Dandy.
I went all over Milan
looking for American oatmeal.
It's really only gruel.
He insists it has to come out
of an American package.
Luckily he's much more
tolerant about bacon.
- They're all alike.
- What do you mean?
I mean they all got habits.
Chief one being,
they don't wanna get married.
- He's already proposed.
- Proposed what?
To marry me.
Well, well!
I take it all back...
...about his being a "love them
and leave them" boy. Congratulations.
Thank you, but getting married
would only mean separation.
- You know the regulations.
- Are you crazy?
No, don't answer. Listen:
In a couple months your Frederico
walks out on good legs...
...and leaves you behind.
- It won't be like that.
Listen, honey,
that's also regulations.
Every soldier feels the right
to walk out on any dame he captures...
...while serving his country.
- Stop, before you make me angry.
Get angry. It may pump
some sense into your head.
What is the noise about,
Miss Barkley?
Well, I was just saying that
the only thing that can help the Allies...
...is for the Americans to come over here
and come over quick.
Our English lady doesn't
approve of that statement.
I will not tolerate a disturbance
in this hospital of any kind.
Yes, Miss Van Campen.
If you don't like Americans,
Miss Barkley...
...you will please keep it to yourself.
- Yes, Miss Van Campen.
- Does Miss Barkley smoke?
- No, I don't.
I mean, no. No, she doesn't.
Hold your nose when you jump.
- How many people have you loved?
- Nobody.
- Except me, of course.
- You're the first and only.
Come.
- How many others, really?
- None.
You're lying to me.
A little.
It's all right.
That's what I want you to do.
Keep right on lying to me.
When does a girl say
how much it costs?
- I don't know.
- Of course not.
Does she say she loves him?
Tell me that. I want to know that.
Yes, if he wants her to.
Does he say he loves her?
Tell me, please. It's important.
He does if he wants to.
But you never did.
Tell me the truth, please.
No.
You wouldn't.
I knew you wouldn't.
I love you, darling.
The girl just says
what the man wants her to.
Well, not always. But...
But I will.
I'll say just what you wish,
and I'll do what you wish.
Then you'll never want
any other girls, will you?
Never.
I'll do and say what you want.
Then I'll be a great success.
- Won't I?
- You're lovely and wonderful.
There isn't any me anymore.
Just what you want.
- Ask for it.
- You.
Miss Barkley?
Where's Miss Barkley?
Have you seen Miss Barkley?
I've been looking everywhere.
- I'll... I'll tell her you want to see her.
- Where is she?
In the kitchen, I'm sure.
She always insists
on doing the dishes.
- Works like a truck horse.
- Thank you.
Van Campen's on the warpath.
I detoured her to the kitchen.
You've got about one minute.
Van Campen.
Give me the paper.
"With Babe Ruth in the box, the Red Sox
again clobbered the wilting Senators...
...5- 0.
A dreary session, except for
a triple play in the ninth stanza...
...that led to the groaning exodus from
the sweltering Washington bleachers."
Miss Barkley, the bedsteads
in Ward B need polishing.
Yes, ma'am.
I don't understand why you remain
in the room when the patient is asleep.
I didn't know he was asleep.
I was reading to him.
Reading to the patients
is not part of your duties, Miss Barkley.
- I'm very sorry. I thought...
- You may leave the paper here.
He can finish that important
dispatch by himself.
Come on, Black Feet!
Come on, Black Feet.
Make your move!
And I was counting on throwing
a party at the Grand'ltalia.
Let's see if we can pick
a winner in the next race.
- What's the matter, Cathy?
- Nothing, darling.
You're not depressed because
we lost the last race?
- Certainly not.
- Then what's wrong?
- Nothing, really.
- Yes, there is.
Tell me, please.
I don't want to.
I'm afraid it would make you
unhappy or worry you.
It won't, if it doesn't worry you.
All right.
I'm going to have a baby.
- That is news.
- You're not upset?
Please don't worry.
- I only worry about you.
- Please don't.
Everybody has babies.
It's a natural thing.
- You're pretty wonderful.
- No, I'm not.
But I won't be any trouble
after this one minute.
I've known for some time.
Haven't I been a good girl till now?
You never suspected.
Well, that settles one thing.
- We'll get married tomorrow.
- No, please.
That's why I didn't tell you before.
I didn't want you to feel trapped.
Tell me you don't feel trapped.
You always feel trapped, biologically.
Always isn't a pretty word.
- I'm sorry, Cat.
- It's all right.
You see, I've never had a baby.
I've tried to be the way you want.
And you talk about "always."
Cat, I could cut out my tongue.
Darling, I'm delighted.
Honestly, I am.
I'll dig up a minister, a mayor maybe.
No, no, please.
They'd ship me
straight back to England.
Maybe the war will be over
before you have to go back.
The important thing
is for us to be together now.
Just as long as we can.
Attention!
A special communique
from the Isonzo front.
In spite of desperate resistance...
...by the flower
of the Austrian army...
...our troops have reached the summit
of San Gabriele and San Marco.
Isn't that fine wedding music?
I, Catherine, take thee, Frederick,
for my wedded husband.
To have and to hold...
...till death do us part.
Till death do us part.
Nino.
Where did you get these bottles, Nino?
I demand an answer.
- They're Lieutenant Henry's, aren't they?
- Please, they are empty bottles.
I understand.
You won't ever leave me for
anybody else, will you?
I have plenty of faults, but I'm faithful.
I'll be so faithful you'll be sick of me.
Lieutenant, I've suspected you of using
this hospital as a place of diversion.
- Miss Barkley's no diversion...
- Are these yours?
Yes. One's brandy and
the other's kummel. They're empty.
One moment, Miss Barkley.
You know our rules.
Therefore you know what to expect.
As for you, you're obviously
no longer a convalescent.
I'm notifying headquarters you are
ready to return to active duty.
This very night.
Tonight...?
It's almost 11.
We still have a few hours.
They'll be skiing in
Saint Moritz soon.
We'll go sometime.
All right.
They're like us.
Nobody's like us.
I wish they had someplace to go.
- It might not do them any good.
- Oh, I don't know.
Everybody ought to have
someplace to go.
I feel better now.
I felt terrible when we started.
We always feel good
when we're together.
- We always will be together.
- Yes.
Except that,
I'm leaving a little after 2.
Don't think about it, darling.
- Do you have to go back for your things?
- No.
The porter's taking my bags
and saving me a place.
Good.
After you leave, I'll go back
and get my things.
- How's your leg? Getting tired?
- No.
But let's not walk too long.
Let's go somewhere.
Good.
Let's go in there.
All right.
I'd like a room.
A suite, if you have one.
- For how long?
- Catching a train in a few hours.
Oh, yes, I understand. We have
no suites, but we can give you...
...Number 15.
Our mirror room, very popular.
- With private bath.
- Fine.
- No luggage?
- No luggage.
Ten lire in advance, please.
Would you care for some wine?
We have some good French champagne.
All right. Some sandwiches too.
Your key. Arturo!
Shame on you.
Shame.
Just the right atmosphere, isn't it?
What's the matter, darling?
I never felt like a whore before.
You're not a whore.
I know it, darling,
but it isn't nice to feel like one.
Come here, please.
Come here. Please, darling.
I'm a good girl again.
You're my fine girl.
I'm certainly yours.
- And you're a fine, simple girl.
- Yes, I am a simple girl.
But no one ever
understood it except you.
I didn't think so at first.
I thought you were a crazy girl.
I was a little crazy. But I wasn't
crazy in any complicated way.
- I didn't confuse you, did I, darling?
- You did, a little.
Here.
Wine is a grand thing. It makes you
forget all the bad you do.
Then have some more.
Vice is a wonderful thing too.
People who go in for it have
good taste about it.
The red plush is really splendid.
Just the thing.
I don't know how a room like this would
be for waking up with a hangover.
But everything we do seems
so innocent and simple.
Wine is lovely.
But it's given
my father gout very badly.
- Have you a father?
- Yes. He has gout.
You won't ever have to meet him.
Haven't you a father?
- Stepfather.
- Will I like him?
You won't ever have to meet him.
But he's very generous. I can
draw drafts on him whenever I please.
That's good.
We have such a fine time together.
I don't take any interest
in anything else anymore.
I feel very married to you,
it makes me so happy.
But at my back I always hear
Time's winged chariot hurrying near
Is it time to go?
Don't worry, darling.
You were fine until now,
and now you're worrying.
I won't.
How often will you write?
Every day.
Do they read your letters?
- I'll make them very confusing.
- But not too confusing.
I'll just make them a little confusing.
- I hate to leave our fine house.
- So do I.
We're never settled
in our home very long.
We will be.
I'll have a fine home for you
when you come back.
For young Catherine.
- We have to go, darling. Really.
- All right.
You go first.
I'm sick with worry about you.
Where will you go? What will you do?
Please don't
worry about me, darling.
I've plenty of money,
and I'll find some nice place.
Maybe on the lakes.
It ought to be beautiful in the autumn.
Where will you have the baby?
That's a long way off.
You're not to worry about that one bit.
Anyway,
people have babies everywhere.
Yes, that's true.
Well.
This is it, kid.
- I'm going into the station with you.
- No, darling, I'd rather you didn't.
- Oh, darling, please.
- It'll be easier to say goodbye here.
Thank you.
- Thank you for everything.
- I love you.
I love you. I adore you.
Take good care of yourself
and young Catherine.
I will. And you...
...you promise
you'll come back to us.
I will.
Take the lady back
to the American hospital.
- Hello. How are you?
- All right, sir, thank you. And you?
You couldn't believe
how bad it's been.
But it will be worse.
We can expect the Germans
on this front...
...now that the Russians have made
a separate peace with them.
What about your countrymen?
Now that your country's in it,
will there be many Americans here?
They're training an army of 10 million.
The French front will get them all.
We'll never get any down here.
- We'll face the Germans alone.
- Many of them, you think?
Five, 10 divisions, who knows.
But I suppose we'll know soon enough.
- Heard the Germans are good.
- It isn't that they're better men.
They've got a better war machine.
Been building it gun by gun for years...
...while we Italians
have been practicing civilization.
Now, of course,
civilization is not very useful.
There's one of your
ambulances left in town.
The others I sent to Caporetto.
You know it?
Yes, sir. A nice little town
with a fountain in the square.
I doubt if the fountain is still there.
Better go see your friend Rinaldi.
Anything wrong?
He's had a summer and fall of it,
I can tell you.
Thank you, sir.
- Father Galli.
- Frederick, how are you?
- I am glad to see you.
- Hello, Father.
- Your wounds are healed?
- All healed.
- You have come back at a bad time.
- Sounds a little noisy.
- Hello, baby.
- Rini. How are you?
- How's the leg?
- Working.
Sit down. Let me look at it.
- Hello, Father.
- Hello, major.
Eighty percent mobility.
It's a crime to send you back.
Now, tell me
about everything, papi.
Nothing much to tell. How are you?
How am I? I dig bullets out of blood.
I cut off arms, legs, the side of a face.
I am becoming a remarkable surgeon.
We will celebrate my genius.
We'll get drunk, papi.
- No, I'm tired, Rini.
- We'll get drunk.
And go meet some girls with
loud voices, and then we'll feel fine.
Seven stars.
War booty from San Gabriele.
- Cognac, Father?
- No, thanks.
Saint Paul said, "Take a little wine
for your stomach's sake."
- Yes, I know.
- Father Galli knows.
Father Galli is better than Saint Paul.
Saint Paul was a rounder, a chaser.
- It's the truth, Frederico?
- I never discuss a saint after dark.
So you've gone over to the priests.
I have to bait this priest alone.
The priests always win.
Everyone ends up on their knees.
Except the miserable Rinaldi.
He remains true to the devil.
No, Rinaldi, you're all right.
To all of us.
You are changed. You drink differently.
Are you married?
- Not yet.
- Still in love?
- Yes.
- Same girl?
- Is she good to you?
Shut up.
All right. To hell with love.
He's been under a strain.
The Fifth Horseman of the Apocalypse.
It destroys the liver and
makes the hand shake.
A surgeon's hand shaking inside
a man's belly. Very fine.
- I drink to open bellies.
- You ought to have a leave.
He wants to get rid of me
because I have a disease.
- Is that true, Father?
- No. It's in his mind. His mind is sick.
It's true.
Everybody has it.
The whole world...
...has it.
He's been working too hard, day and
night. There are not enough doctors.
Tell me about Miss Barkley, papi.
I want to hear something pretty.
Tell me something pretty.
I'll speak to the general
about a leave for him.
- Good night, Frederico.
- Good night, Father.
Thank you, papi.
Turn around. Back to Orsino. Come on.
Turn around. Go back. Clear the road.
Come on, hurry up.
Clear the road.
- Sorry, lieutenant. Turn and go back.
- What for, sir?
Orders. We must clear
the road to Orsino, and fast.
- Right.
- Let's go.
I don't understand.
I don't either,
but I can make a pretty good guess.
Lieutenant! Orders from the division.
- Take your ambulance to the retreat line.
- Do I take any wounded?
- Where did you get that information?
- The division.
It's a lie. There is no retreat.
The division has orders to hold the line!
I'll go where I'm told, but please
get your orders straight.
Caporetto is lost. Fifteen German
divisions have broken through.
- All three of our armies are in retreat.
- I'm not surprised.
We are evacuating.
Doctors will go with the army.
- What about the wounded?
- It's better not to move them.
- The ambulances will carry equipment.
- I am not equipment.
I am a man. I'm staying.
I repeat division orders:
Every doctor is to go with the army.
Yes, sir.
Orders are a noble thing.
I must not disappoint the division.
- Better to disappoint...
- Come on, Rini, you're sick.
The wounded and the dying. They should
be abandoned without hesitation.
Excuse me, Father. The Germans
will be along in a few hours.
- Come with us in the ambulance.
- I remain here.
They'll pulverize the town
before they come in.
The dying need me.
What about the Abruzzi,
and the chestnut woods and the river?
Perhaps, if God permits.
You're someone
to remember, Father.
I am ordered to leave, Father Galli.
But you have better orders,
from God, to remain.
I salute your commanding officer.
May his blessing go with you.
Goodbye, Father.
A scene to remember.
Yes.
Make way for Rinaldi,
who is saving his skin.
Shut up, Rini. You're full of fever.
Get off!
Look.
Look, the German spy
is spitting on us.
The dead man spits on us.
That's what we deserve.
It's hopeless.
Bad luck, Rini. We're walking.
- Where's Bonello?
- I don't know. I was asleep.
Just deserted, huh?
- You stay close to us.
- Yes, lieutenant.
- Come, Rini, it's gonna be a long haul.
- Father Galli stayed.
The priest stayed, but Rinaldi runs.
Come on. No nonsense.
- Esmeralda!
- Aymo!
My only loves are untrue to me.
What's the use?
- What's the use?
- Stop, Rini.
What good are we to Italy?
- We are fit only for surrender.
- Shut up!
Let the Germans collect
the garbage with a shovel!
- You're under arrest.
- What are you talking about?
- You can't touch an officer.
- Shoot him if he resists.
- What is this? Who are you?
- Battle police.
- Why arrest Major Rinaldi?
- We heard him.
- A German infiltrator preaching defeat.
- He's just the opposite!
Take him away!
- What's your division?
- Nineteenth.
The 19th division was pulled out
10 days ago.
- You're a German in Italian uniform.
- He's a spy.
Guilty of preaching surrender.
I request he be sentenced to death.
I place the accused in the hands
of the court-martial.
In the name of His Majesty,
the court finds the prisoner guilty...
...and orders him shot.
- Wait.
Wait. I will talk. I will talk, wait!
Keep your hands off me.
I need no assistance.
Your name, rank and birthplace.
My name is Alessandro Rinaldi.
My rank is that of a coward.
My birthplace I will not
disgrace by naming it.
You have medical corps insignia.
Forgive me. I forgot to tear it off.
No, Rini, stop it.
Tell them the truth!
He was spreading disorder.
He called our army "garbage."
- He was telling our men to surrender.
- I ran.
I ran with them.
I am a doctor needed by
our dying men. And I ran.
Dispose of me, garbage inspector!
- Let me talk for him.
- Silence.
Come, you heroes.
Shoot the coward, and win the war.
You are a German infiltrator
or a confessed deserter.
In the name of His Majesty,
you're ordered to be shot.
You're mad. Major Rinaldi's sick.
He's sick, I tell you.
Colonel.
You must listen to me. He's one of
the best surgeons in your army.
Our army?
Give your name, rank and birthplace.
Goodbye, papi.
I am joining Father Galli.
No...
Answer the question.
You are not an Italian.
You're wearing an Italian uniform, but
you do not even know the Italian salute.
Ferguson! Ferguson?
Ferguson.
- Fred, what are you doing here?
- Don't ask questions.
- Look at you.
- Where's Catherine?
- Are you wounded?
- No.
- I hope it's a hole in your head.
- Where is she?
In the mess you got her into.
I can't stand here arguing with you.
Please, before they grab me.
Please, Ferguson, where is she?
Stresa. Hotel Valeria, room seven.
Lieutenant Henry.
Are you wounded? What are you
doing in those clothes?
Before you do anything, let me...
Don't tell me anything.
You're a deserter!
- Not the way you think. I had to...
- Of course. Cowards always run.
Will you give up,
or shall I do it for you?
No firing squad for me.
Darling...
Oh, darling.
What's wrong?
I'll tell you about it.
Darling, you're ill. I'll get a doctor.
I don't need a doctor. I'm not sick.
Not that way.
Then what is it? I don't understand.
It's just...
...I'm through.
I'm through with the war.
I've made a separate peace.
You mean, you...
You deserted?
Yes. I'm a deserter.
It's not your army, or your country.
Tell me what happened.
All kinds of hell.
Rinaldi's dead. They killed him.
A firing squad.
I'd better not tell you about it.
No, I want to hear.
He was sick. Talking like a madman.
And the firing squad blew his brains out.
I was next. You can't win an
argument with a firing squad.
No, of course you can't.
And you're not going to try.
You're not going back.
I'm not against them.
They're the good ones. The brave ones.
I wish them all the luck.
They deserve it.
But it's not my show anymore.
Of course it isn't.
We're together, that's all that matters.
The rest is something else.
Far away.
Just us. Us.
I must say, you look better.
I think I'll be hungry for a week.
I thought you were going
to sleep for a week.
The sleeves are a bit short.
But it was the best I could do.
You are a little tall for your age, darling.
It's a fine outfit.
We'll just stay right here.
It's practically deserted this
time of the year. And cheap.
- Couldn't be nicer.
- Now, let's see...
...shall I get you some papers?
No, I don't wanna read the papers.
I'm sorry. Was it so bad you don't
want even to read about it, darling?
Yes, it was bad.
I wish I had been with you
so I would know about it too.
Darling, what will happen
if they find you?
- I'll shoot them.
- You wouldn't.
And what would they do to you?
They'd shoot me, of course.
Then we can't stay here.
We can go to Switzerland.
- Please, I'm tired of thinking about it.
- The border's very near here.
Yes, and they have guards across it
like a picket fence.
We can go across the lake.
We'll borrow one of those boats.
They'd turn us in if we even asked.
Then we'll steal one.
We can send it back.
It's over 20 miles.
You can do it. I know you can.
And the patrol boats?
They'd spot us sure.
Not if we go at night.
Darling, don't you see?
We've got to get out of here, fast.
Tonight!
Please.
All right.
You're a grand girl.
I hope nobody saw us.
I'm more worried about the patrol boats.
Darling, not so fast. You'll get tired.
We have to get into Swiss waters
before it's daylight.
Here, I can do that.
It's no good. I can't put you
through this. I'm taking you back.
- You will not.
- I will. This is crazy, you and the baby.
If you take me ashore,
I'll swim after you.
A little rain won't hurt me or the baby.
What will hurt is waiting in that room,
not knowing...
...if they caught you
and stood you against the wall.
Now, start rowing!
All right. You win.
That's a good boy!
I could use a drink.
- Thanks.
- You're ever so welcome.
- Do you know something?
- What?
- I don't think this rain is going to last.
- I hope not.
- Do you know something else?
- What?
I don't care if it does!
Aren't you dead?
Oh, I'm all right.
My hands are sore, is all.
I think I hear something.
It's a patrol boat.
They're backing up.
They're turning.
We must be close to the border.
- Darling, I was terrified.
- So was I.
Are you all right?
Darling, I've never been more
all right in my whole life.
- Darling.
- We're in Switzerland.
Darling. It's a lovely country.
Yes. It feels good beneath my feet.
Can you realize we're
actually in Switzerland?
Darling, it's true, isn't it?
I don't have to go down to the station
with you to see you off.
I hope not.
Don't say that. It frightens me.
Your hands, your poor hands.
We'll buy some ointment.
Magic Swiss ointment.
- Forget about my hands. I'm still hungry.
- So are we.
Pardon me.
I'm Lieutenant Zimmerman.
- Is that your boat that just came in?
- Yes.
What nationality are you?
American, British.
Well, let me see your passports.
Why do you come to Switzerland?
We're tourists. My cousin and I
want to enjoy the winter sports.
You rowed here from Italy?
Rowing is my favorite sport.
I always row when I get a chance.
- Indeed. Your cousin too?
- Yes, I love it.
Cousins with the same tastes...
...of different nationalities...
...rowing all night across the lake...
Very interesting.
What have you been doing in Italy?
I've been doing some writing.
Picking up local color, you might say.
And you, Miss... Barkley?
She's been studying art.
Yes. Rubens, Raphael, Rembrandt...
You know, things like that.
- How much money have you?
- Twenty-five hundred lire.
Twenty-five hundred...?
As you're so interested in boating,
I can recommend an excellent place.
A very small, intimate hotel...
...overlooking the most romantic lake.
- That sounds enchanting.
It's owned by my mother.
Her name is Madame Zimmerman.
- How nice.
- I have one of my mother's cards here.
Take the luggage,
and get these tourists a cab.
Your passports will be kept
by the police.
I regret this, but it's necessary
under the circumstances.
- They'll be returned, after a time.
- But you're sure we can stay?
I'm certain you and your cousin will find
my mother's hotel very comfortable.
Thank you, lieutenant.
It's a great country.
And so practical.
You may come in now, Mr. Henry.
Your wife is an excellent
advertisement for Switzerland.
She's had only six weeks
of our fine air...
...but she couldn't be healthier
if she were born Swiss.
Not one wrong symptom.
A beautiful expectant mother.
- You should be very pleased.
- I am.
I prescribe a little sleep
and, of course, some exercise.
No scaling Alpine peaks.
Your husband's knee is fine now,
but he must be careful.
We want the child
to have a healthy father.
We want him able to walk the baby.
Well, he will be.
You'll have the baby in spring,
the season for beginning.
Thank you, doctor.
We'll see you regularly?
Of course, but do not be concerned.
We have babies quite often
in Switzerland.
- Goodbye, Mrs. Henry.
- Goodbye, doctor, and thank you.
I'm so excited to be healthy!
Darling, stop fussing
with that silly pipe...
What's that?
Little Catherine.
She's turning a cartwheel.
Want to feel her?
- Doesn't it hurt?
- No, you idiot. It feels wonderful.
I got our passports back from the
police. Now we can get married.
No.
I'm sure it would be
the proper thing to do.
Unless you're crazy.
Not as crazy as you think. I'm not
going to let you off the hook, ever.
I won't startle the whole countryside
now, letting them know I'm not married.
We could go to some other village.
Wherever we went, it would be too
embarrassing. I show too plainly.
I can't be married
in this splendid matronly shape.
You'd make a beautiful bride
in any shape.
We'll get married as soon as
I'm thin again.
Everyone will say,
"What a handsome couple."
We'll have orange blossoms, organ
music, and somebody to mind the baby.
Come in.
How nice, Mrs. Zimmerman.
I got to tell you a joke.
When my son told me you were
coming, he made a mistake.
He thought you were cousins.
Here's beer and breakfast
for the gentleman...
...and hot wine and spices for madam.
- Thank you.
- Happy evening, lady and gentleman.
- Happy evening, Mrs. Zimmerman.
- I think I may marry Mrs. Zimmerman.
- She's too good for you.
- Here, drink this while it's hot.
Darling, I'm going to cut
my hair short. Very short.
- Now?
- No. When I'm thin again.
I'll be thin and I'll have short hair.
- You're not going to say no, are you?
- You can cut it.
- Why? I thought you liked my hair long.
- I love it long.
- You said you prefer it short.
- I did not.
- You hinted it.
- I didn't. I'm just trying to agree.
I wish you wouldn't try to confuse me.
I know why you're bored with me.
- Because I love you too much.
- You're mad.
- Please don't shout at me.
- I'm just trying to say, you don't bore me.
Everything else bores me but you.
Darling, you mustn't mind me.
We really are the same.
We mustn't misunderstand on purpose.
- We won't.
- But people do.
They love each other,
and misunderstand on purpose.
They fight, then suddenly
they aren't the same.
- We won't fight.
- We mustn't.
Because there's only us two.
In the world,
there's all the rest of them.
Anything comes between us,
we're gone. They have us.
They won't get us...
...because you're too brave.
Nothing ever happens to the brave.
They die, of course.
A coward dies a thousand deaths,
the brave but once.
The brave die thousands of times,
if they're intelligent.
You're an authority. You're brave.
No, I'm not.
But anyway...
...I won't cut my hair until after
Catherine is born, and I'm thin.
I'll cut it off and be a fine new girl
for you. And you'll fall in love again.
I love you enough now.
What are you
trying to do, ruin me?
- Yes. I want to ruin you.
- Good, that's what I want too.
Say, you know how they go courting
in the Alps? They yodel.
If the lady's interested, she yodels back.
Really?
That's it. Checkmate.
I don't care, I've got your queen.
Darling, the game's over. It's checkmate.
But why? I still have more of these
silly pieces than you have.
I wish you liked rummy.
It's much more fun.
Happy New Year, darling.
To all three of us.
- Here's to 1918.
- Little Catherine's year.
Do you mind? Our being alone, just us,
on New Year's Eve?
I never feel alone when we're together.
But sometimes a man
wants to be alone.
I imagine sometimes a girl
wants to be alone too.
If they love each other,
they're jealous of that.
- I don't want to be away from you, ever.
- Me too.
My life used to be full
of all sorts of things.
Now, if you're not with me,
I haven't a thing in the world.
But I'm not fun for you anymore.
I'm just like a big flour barrel.
You're not. You're more
beautiful all the time.
Just the same,
you're going to town tomorrow...
...and find some gay, young playmate.
- I don't want to be with anybody else.
- Yes, you do.
I'll start the New Year by buying
Catherine's first wardrobe.
I'll find what's necessary.
I'll do it tomorrow.
You should know, you were a nurse.
But so few soldiers had babies
in the hospital.
I did.
Where are you?
I'm right here. I've got a sled.
You sound like a ventriloquist.
- You look like a spook in fairy land.
- Spook for yourself, darling.
All aboard.
I don't think I want to ride.
I want to walk. It's good for the baby.
The baby does what I say.
- Well, may I steer?
- Sure, you can steer.
Ready?
Hello.
- Will it take much longer?
- No.
Don't be impatient.
She's doing a beautiful job.
I must look my best
when I meet little Catherine.
She'll be very impressed.
- Is this your first child, madame?
- No. We have two boys.
That is wonderful.
And two girls.
Oh, monsieur!
Hurry up.
She won't come between us,
will she? The little brat?
No, we'll keep her in a tree.
Won't it be fun?
There'll be three of us.
- Hello, Cat.
- Hello.
- How are you?
- I'm fine, darling.
I brought your things.
- Isn't the doctor here yet?
- In a few minutes.
- How is it?
- The pains are coming quite often now.
This is a real one.
You go away, darling.
- Go out and get some dinner.
- I couldn't.
I may do this for a long time,
the nurse says.
The first labor is usually protracted.
I'd rather stay.
Please go, darling. I think you're
just making me self-conscious.
I want to be a good wife, and have
this child without any foolishness.
You have time, if you would
like to get dinner.
No, I'll be just outside.
Can I go into the delivery room?
Yes, I'm sure it will be all right.
Thank you.
Bear down as hard as you can.
I'm having fine pains.
That was a very big one.
It will be soon, now. I can tell.
Yes, my dear. We'll give you some
gas, to ease the pain.
I don't want to make any fuss.
- Darling?
- Yes.
I just wanted to be sure
you were here.
I won't leave.
That's a good boy.
Darling, I have the most
wonderful doctor.
He's been telling me
the most wonderful story.
When the pain came too badly,
he put me out. He's wonderful.
- You're wonderful, doctor.
- You're drunk.
I know it. But you shouldn't say it.
Give it to me!
I'm sorry I go on so long.
I thought I would do it so easily.
I try as hard as I can.
I push down but it goes away.
Here it comes!
Give it to...
Please, doctor, give me enough
to do some good.
It doesn't work.
It doesn't work!
I don't care if I die, if it will only stop.
Please!
Please make it stop!
Can't they give me something?
- Doctor...
- lf they could only give me something.
It doesn't work.
Nothing works.
Oh, darling...
I'm just a fool.
I wanted so to have this baby and not
make trouble. And now I'm all gone.
- All gone to pieces. It doesn't work.
- My brave darling.
I'm not brave anymore...
...I'm all broken.
- In a little while...
- They just keep it up till they break you.
It'll be over in a little while.
I won't die, will I, darling?
No. I promise you won't.
I don't want to die
and leave you, but I...
...I get so tired of it...
...and I feel I'm going to die.
Nonsense. Everybody feels that.
I always knew I was going to die.
You can't. You won't.
I won't let you.
You wouldn't do any such foolishness.
You wouldn't die
and leave your husband.
Don't mind me, darling.
I've just gone all to pieces.
I love you so.
I'll be good again.
You'll be all right, Cat.
You'll be all right.
You're so good to me.
You will go, please, for a few minutes.
I will make an examination.
You can come back
afterward, darling.
- Can't he, doctor?
- I'll send word when he can come back.
Poor Catherine.
Mr. Henry.
The doctor wants to see you.
Is anything wrong?
How does it go, doctor?
It doesn't go.
But she was so healthy.
You said yourself she was.
Yes, I know. But somehow,
sometimes nature fails itself.
- What do you advise?
- There are two things.
Either a high-forceps delivery,
which can tear and is dangerous...
...besides being bad for the child,
or a cesarean.
- What's the danger of a cesarean?
- No greater than an ordinary delivery.
If it were my wife,
I would do a cesarean.
- What are the aftereffects?
- None. There is only the scar.
What if you just went on
and did nothing?
We would have to do something
eventually.
Mrs. Henry is already losing
much of her strength.
The sooner we operate, the safer.
- Operate as soon as you can.
- I'll go and give the instructions.
- Did you tell him he could do it?
- Yes.
Isn't that grand?
Now it will all be over in no time.
- Darling?
- Yes, Cat?
Is it raining?
No, I don't think so.
I think it's raining.
It's a boy. Congratulations.
Aren't you proud?
He nearly killed his mother.
You may come in now,
for a moment.
I love you, sweetie.
What sort of a baby is it?
It's a boy. Long and wide and dark.
- Is he all right?
- Yes, he's fine.
I'm awfully tired. I hurt like hell.
Madame Henry mustn't talk too much.
You haven't eaten all day, darling.
Go and eat something. I'll be
all right when you come back.
I'll be back in 15 minutes.
Have a nice dinner.
- Mr. Henry.
- Yes, doctor.
I'm sorry about the baby.
What about the baby?
The terrible labor, the whole ordeal,
it was too much for him.
We couldn't start him breathing.
So he's dead.
Yes. We tried everything.
- What about her?
- She'll be all right, my boy.
Come, have a cup of coffee with me.
I assure you, she'll be all right.
Yes, coffee and brioche.
The alcove, please.
- It will be free in two minutes.
- We'll wait.
It's true, even the German
communique admits it.
A month ago they said only a miracle
could save the Italians.
Well, the miracle has happened.
The Italians are holding the Piave River.
Poor Cat. She wanted this baby
so much.
The table is ready, doctor.
I don't understand it. I felt him kick.
He was alive inside Catherine.
Except the last week.
The last week he was quiet.
Maybe he was dead all the time.
- Drink your coffee, my boy.
- Poor kid.
Never even had a chance.
Maybe it's just as well.
They kill you in the end.
Maybe it's better that way than
to wind up dead on a muddy road.
You don't know what it's about.
You never have time to learn.
They throw you in
and tell you the rules...
...and the first time they catch you
off base, they kill you.
You can count on that.
Stay around and they'll kill you.
Poor Cat.
Poor, dear Cat.
This is the price you pay
for sleeping together.
She didn't have a bad time
when she was pregnant.
She was hardly ever sick.
She wasn't even very uncomfortable,
until towards the last.
But you never get away with anything.
Get away? Hell!
They get you in the end.
Maybe they're gonna get her too.
She's not gonna die, is she?
No, my boy. I'm sure.
You were sure about the baby too.
What if she should die?
She's coming along fine.
Don't you worry.
Dr. Emerich.
Excuse me, Mr. Henry. I'm wanted.
Finish your coffee, I'll meet you
later at the hospital.
She said she felt like hell.
What if she should die?
No, she won't die. People don't die
in childbirth nowadays.
Yes, but that's what
all husbands think.
What if she should die?
No. She's just having a bad time.
That's it.
Afterwards, we'll say,
"What a bad time."
And Catherine will say,
"Oh, it really wasn't so bad."
But what if she should die?
But what if she should?
Oh, Mr. Henry.
I just tried to telephone you.
- What's wrong?
- Madame Henry has had a hemorrhage.
- Can I go in?
- Not yet.
- Is it dangerous?
- It is very dangerous.
Oh, God.
Please don't let her die.
I'll do anything,
if you won't let her die.
Whatever wrong I've done...
Please, dear God, don't let her die.
You took our baby,
but don't let her die.
Please. Please, dear God.
Don't...
Mr. Henry.
Cat.
You're all right.
You're going to be all right.
Our baby's dead, isn't he?
I'm going to die too.
I hate it.
Don't touch me.
Poor darling.
You touch me all you want.
You'll be all right, Catherine.
I know you'll be all right.
I meant to write you a letter to have...
...if anything happened.
I didn't do it.
Do you want me to do anything?
Do you want me to... send for anybody?
Just you.
I'm not afraid.
I just hate it.
It's been sweet.
Darling.
You won't do our things
with another girl...
...or say the same things, will you?
No.
I want you to have girls, though.
I don't want to.
I'll come and stay with you nights.
I'm not a bit afraid, darling.
It's just a dirty trick.
Can I do anything?
No, just leave us alone.
- I think it might be better if...
- Get out. Both of you.
Darling.
My wonderful darling.
You'll never leave me.
You're with me till I die.
My darling.
Till I die.
Cold.
You're so cold, Cat.
Like a statue.
Won 't it be fun?
There'll be three of us.
I'm not a bit afraid, darling.
I just hate it.
Darling. You will be good to me,
won't you?
You will, won't you?
Because we're going to have
a strange life.
But it's the only life I want.
Subtitles by
SDI Media Group