Greece and the islands
of the Aegean Sea...
...have given birth to many myths
and legends of war and adventure.
And these once-proud stones,
these ruined and shattered temples...
...bear witness to the civilization
that flourished and then died here.
And of the demigods and heroes
who inspired those legends...
...on this sea and these islands.
But though the stage is the same,
ours is a legend of our own times...
...and its heroes are not demigods,
but ordinary people.
In 1943, so the story goes...
...2000 British soldiers lay
marooned on the island of Kheros...
...exhausted and helpless.
They had exactly one week to live.
In Berlin, the Axis had determined...
...on a show of strength
in the Aegean Sea...
...to bully neutral Turkey into
coming into the war on their side.
The scene of that demonstration
was to be Kheros...
...itself of no military value,
but only miles off the coast of Turkey.
The cream of the German war machine,
rested and ready...
...was to spearhead the attack.
The men on Kheros were doomed...
...unless they could be evacuated
before the blitz.
But the only passage
to and from Kheros...
...was guarded and blocked
by two great...
...newly designed,
radar-controlled guns...
...on the nearby island of Navarone.
Guns too powerful and accurate...
...for any Allied ship then
in the Aegean to challenge.
Allied Intelligence learned
of the projected blitz...
...only one week before
the appointed date.
What took place in the next six days
became the legend of Navarone.
Yes?
I'm looking for
Commodore Jensen.
I'm Jensen.
Come in, Mallory.
You're late.
I'm sorry. Our plane was attacked
an hour out of Crete.
- We got into Alex on one engine, sir.
- The Germans have a price on you...
...and Andrea Stavros
of 10,000 pounds apiece.
How did you know that?
I should do. I'm your boss.
You've been working for me
the past 18 months.
I'm delighted to make
your acquaintance.
Did they say
you were going on leave?
Yes, sir. They did.
Well, I'm sorry.
I'm afraid that's not true.
Not yet, at any rate.
Here's your old chum.
Come and say hello to him.
You haven't changed since Athens.
Hello, Roy.
Come along, gentlemen, will you?
Barnsby...
...these gentlemen have
an interest in Navarone.
We've heard you on radio, but
perhaps you'll be more specific now.
I'll be specific.
As you can plainly see,
it was bloody awful!
Squadron Leader
Barnsby's Australian.
But we'd love to go back,
wouldn't we boys?
- Sure! Right!
- Just as soon as we can! But...
...only on one condition.
We want the joker who thought
of this to come with us...
...and when we get there...
...we're gonna shove him
out at 10,000 feet...
...without a parachute.
Bloody right.
- It was bad as that?
- Bad?!
It can't be done.
Not from the air, anyway.
You're sure about that,
squadron leader? This is important.
So's my life!
To me, anyway. And the lives
of these jokers here...
...and the 18 men we lost tonight!
Look, sir...
...first...
...you've got that old fortress
on top of that bloody cliff.
Then you've got
the bloody cliff overhang.
You can't even see the bloody cave,
let alone the guns.
And anyway, we haven't got
a bloody bomb big enough...
...to smash that bloody rock.
And that's the bloody truth, sir.
I know how to hit those guns.
Yes?
Yes, sir.
You fill a plane full of TNT...
...and then you do a suicide
dive right into that cave.
There's just one problem, sir:
Getting someone to pilot the plane.
I see. Perhaps you might
consider it yourself.
Thank you, squadron leader,
and all of you.
I know you've done your best,
and nobody could have done more.
And I'm sorry.
As you've probably surmised, I'm the
joker they'd heave out at 10,000 feet.
And I can't say I blame them.
I knew it was hopeless from the start,
but it had to be tried.
Anyway, this is why you
were hauled out of Crete.
And don't mislay this, will you?
No, sir.
We're pressed for time.
Let's go, gentlemen, shall we?
- Any questions?
- Only one.
Why me?
What you want is
a seagoing taxi driver.
Other men know these waters
as well as I do.
Yes, but you've got
special qualifications.
Franklin'll explain it.
It's his idea, anyway.
First, you speak Greek and German.
Second, you've kept alive in occupied
territory for a year and a half.
And before the war, you were the
greatest mountain climber in the world.
"Keith Mallory, the human fly."
Come to the point, Roy.
The point is that our Resistance
contacts on Navarone...
...say there's only one spot on
the coast the Germans don't watch:
The South Cliff.
It's 400 feet straight up...
...and it can't be climbed
by man or beast.
And that's where you come in.
That was your idea too?
That's right.
I want you to get me and my team
over there and on top of that cliff.
When you've done that, you can
take a richly deserved leave...
...and a long-overdue promotion.
I see.
Can you do it?
No.
With all due respect,
I think the operation is insane.
But that's not my business.
My business is to climb
and I haven't climbed in five years.
That's a long time.
It's too long for this cliff.
And you're asking me
to do it at night.
I wouldn't try it in broad daylight.
I'll have a go myself, then.
I've climbed a bit.
Don't be a fool. You'd get yourself
killed and your team along with you.
- Then it's scrubbed?
- No, it's not scrubbed!
It can't be.
Not now.
Mallory...
...this is our last hope.
The Germans won't expect
a team of saboteurs at this late date.
Those 2000 men on Kheros will
die next Wednesday morning...
...unless somebody climbs the cliff.
There's nobody else
we can get in time.
If there were,
you wouldn't be here now.
I suppose it's too late to get
Andrea Stavros to help me.
On the contrary.
I think you'll find him waiting
for you in your hotel.
You think of everything.
I have to. It's part of my job.
- Thanks, Keith.
- It's my pleasure.
Nothing I like better
than a well-organized setup.
You'll want to know about the team.
Sydney, would you get us
some more coffee, please?
Franklin considers it the best team
in the business. I agree.
He himself is ideal for the job. He's
experienced and extremely capable.
Don't blush, Roy.
And best of all, he's lucky.
Aren't you lucky?
- If you say so, sir.
- I do, indeed.
Napoleon said once, when somebody
was up for promotion to general:
"Yes, I know he's brilliant.
But is he lucky?"
The emperor knew the value of luck.
Our Roy seems to have it.
- Then make me a general, sir.
- Patience, my dear boy, patience.
Now this is our Corporal Miller.
A chemistry professor in private life.
An absolute genius
with high explosives.
He blew up Rommel's headquarters...
...with no damage
to the orphanage next door.
They don't come any better. We tried
to make him an officer. He refused.
This is "Butcher" Brown,
our mechanical marvel.
He's a genius with engines,
machinery, radios, et cetera.
And the best man with a knife
I've ever met.
He got his training in Spain. The boys
call him the Butcher of Barcelona.
Private Spyro Pappadimos.
What's his particular genius?
He's a born killer. A useful man
to have along on a job like this.
His father happens to be our chief
resistance contact on Navarone.
The boy went to America
to get an education.
I'm afraid he got the wrong kind.
Well, there's the team.
Pirates and cutthroats,
every one of them.
And of course, there's Lucky here.
And the redoubtable Mr. Stavros
and yourself.
With every one of us a genius,
how can we fail?
You can't.
We're sending six destroyers through
the Navarone Channel next Tuesday...
...to take the men off Kheros.
If those guns aren't spiked by then...
...there'll be six more ships
at the bottom of the Aegean.
There's your car, gentlemen.
Surprised?
I didn't think I'd see you again
so soon.
You thought you'd have
to look for me?
When the time came,
I would find you.
What is this?
We have to ferry some operators
to an island called Navarone.
- Do you know it?
- I know it.
I also know I have
work to do on Crete.
- Who's responsible for this?
- A major I used to know.
Name of Franklin.
He's a man who still has to prove
to himself he's a hero.
I'll speak to Franklin.
Where do I find him?
That's the man.
You can speak with him on the way.
Think they've got a chance?
Frankly, no.
Not a chance in the world.
I'll be surprised if they
get halfway to Navarone.
It's just a waste of six good men.
However, it doesn't matter, considering
how many have been wasted already.
I'm glad it's not my decision.
I'm only the middleman.
Still, they may get there
and they may pull it off.
Anything can happen in a war.
In the middle of absolute insanity...
...people pull out
extraordinary resources.
Ingenuity, courage, self-sacrifice.
Pity we can't beat the problems
of peace in the same way.
It would be so much cheaper.
I never thought of it
in just that way.
- You're a philosopher.
- No.
I'm just the man who has to send
people out on jobs like this one.
Must have been delayed.
I'm sure he'll be here soon.
- Major Franklin?
- Right.
My name's Baker. Sorry I was delayed.
Come with me, please.
It's been so comfortable,
I hate to leave.
When you're all quite ready...
Charming.
Just like an English country hotel.
Where does everybody else sleep?
Nobody sleeps. On your feet,
professor. We've got homework to do.
If you insist, major.
What are you doing, friend?
Looking for dust?
No, friend. Microphones.
This is the British Army Post.
Don't you trust anyone?
No. That is why I have lived so long.
Mr. Stavros is Colonel Stavros
of the Greek 19th Motorized Regiment.
- He outranks us all.
- It is of no moment.
The 19th Regiment no longer exists,
for the time being.
- I beg your pardon, colonel.
- Andrea.
Please continue.
Right. If you're ready, corporal.
Yes, sir. Ready, sir.
Ready, willing and able, sir.
Champing at the bit.
Captain Mallory and Andrea...
...are responsible for getting us
to where we're going.
I'll tell you where it is,
and why we're going.
That is, if you really want
to know, professor.
I'm all ears, sir. All ears.
We must avoid the coast road.
That means a 12-mile trek...
...to St. Alexis, where Resistance
people from the town of Mandrakos...
...will come and meet us
if they can make it.
Any questions?
I have an alternative route
to that place.
May I borrow your pencil, please?
Does the major think
this is possible?
I see.
That's a thought, isn't it?
Well, let's re-examine the plan
and see if we have any alternative.
Watch out!
- How long has he been there?
- I heard something 10 minutes ago.
I thought my ears were playing tricks.
Then I heard it again.
Ten minutes?
Brown, go and get Major Baker.
Yes, sir.
What's your name?
What are you doing here?
The major asked you a question!
Answer the major.
Sounds like Kurdish.
I don't understand it.
I'll try Greek.
- Translation, please.
- He doesn't speak English.
Why was he listening?
- What are you doing to that man?
- You know him?
That's Nicolai, our laundry boy.
Is he the reason I've been disturbed?
I've had a hard day!
Does his job involve
listening at keyholes?
- I don't believe it.
- We caught him at it.
It was just idle curiosity.
He doesn't speak English.
Why does he listen?
And why did he try to stab this man?
I presume he was trying
to defend himself.
In this part of the world, carrying a
knife doesn't make you a criminal.
Let him go.
Major Baker, arrest this man and
hold him incommunicado for a week.
After that, my advice is you
kick him out of Castelrosso.
Who the hell are you to give
me advice, major?
Then I'm asking you as a favor.
I'll consider it.
All this cloak-and-dagger stuff.
I said, let him go!
Pappadimos,
have you got your silencer?
- Yes, sir.
- Then use it. Shoot the laundry boy!
Are you crazy?
And if the major gets
in your way, shoot him too.
That's an order.
Captain, he's insane!
Surely you won't let him do this.
I can't stop him, he's in charge.
Anyway, I agree with him.
Of course, he doesn't have
to shoot you.
He can just call our HQ and you'll
be on a troopship home, as a private...
...unless you give him your word that
you'll do exactly as he says.
All right.
If it means that much to you,
you have my word.
Take him, sergeant!
Stupid theatricals.
You're entitled to your opinion...
...but I just saved your life.
I'm desperately sorry, gentlemen.
Really, I am.
It's embarrassing.
Just look at it!
No, it's exactly what we want.
They said you wanted a boat no one
would notice, but that's a disgrace!
Give me 36 hours,
and I know I can lay my hands...
...on a German E-boat
in absolutely perfect condition.
I promise you,
only one careful owner.
I can pop over to Rhodes
and get it for you.
Won't the Germans have
something to say about that?
I suppose so, if they knew.
But I've got good connections there.
What do you say?
- No, thanks. We can't wait.
- Pity.
I'll get my chaps
to help with your gear.
No, that's all right, thank you.
Right. I get it.
Special cargo and all that, what?
Well, good luck to you.
Brown?
Yes, sir?
What do you think?
Well, she's a bit of a monster, sir.
But I think I've got her worried.
- Comfortable, professor?
- Yes, thank you.
Matter of fact,
the boys have almost finished.
Permission to speak?
- What about?
- Well, the condition of this vessel.
Talk to Captain Mallory.
He's in charge of transportation.
Very good, sir.
I've inspected this boat
and I think you ought to know...
...I can't swim.
I'll keep it in mind.
Dead on 10, sir.
Hello, Lucky. Hello, Lucky.
Report my signal. Report my signal.
Hello, George-Mike-William.
George-Mike-William.
Strength three. Strength three, over.
Hello, Lucky.
High Flight reports Indians on warpath
in your territory.
So please be careful.
Also, severe storms expected
throughout your area tonight.
Repeat. High Flight reports
Indians on warpath...
Hey.
Ship ahoy!
Go on working.
They'll have glasses.
Lower your sails!
We are coming aboard!
It's knee-deep in the hold,
but I think we'll manage.
You want a breather?
Wouldn't mind.
Funny the way that German officer
spoke English to us back there...
...almost as if he knew who we were.
I had the same thought.
I think our friend Baker
may have some explaining to do.
I shouldn't have done it.
What's that?
Dragged you into this.
I'm sorry.
Forget it. I was getting tired
of Crete food anyway.
No, I'm stupid sometimes.
Even as a kid, I'd expect
people to play the games I liked.
Then I'd get furious when they didn't.
Well, now they have to,
so why worry?
Hot coffee!
That's good.
I'm sorry, captain.
There's a serious shortage of cups
aboard this ship.
I pointed out deficiencies
in this vessel.
I remember.
- Thanks.
- My pleasure.
Any time you want another chat,
about this boat, I mean, I'm available.
All right.
And I still can't swim.
Don't mind him.
He doesn't mean anything.
I don't mind him as much
as he seems to mind me.
Have you been together long?
Since the beginning out here.
He's the best friend I have
in this part of the world.
That's a pretty good partner
you've got there yourself.
Yes.
- We've been together a long time too.
- You're lucky.
He's going to kill me
when the war's over.
- You're not serious.
- Yes, I am.
So's he.
About a year ago, I gave
a German patrol a safe conduct...
...to get their wounded into hospital.
I still had some romantic notions
about fighting a civilized war.
Anyway, they wanted Andrea
pretty badly even then.
They shot their casualties,
went to his house and blew it up.
He was out on a job, but his wife
and three children were in the house.
They were all killed.
I helped him to bury them.
He didn't say a word to me.
Never looked at me.
But after it was over, he said that
as far as he was concerned...
...it wasn't the Germans who were
responsible, but me.
Me and my stupid
Anglo-Saxon decency.
He said what he
was going to do, and when.
Do you think he still means to do it?
He's from Crete.
Those people don't make idle threats.
I thought I was getting leave.
I was going to ask for
transfer to another area.
Take some time to think,
get ready for him.
And I messed that up.
I'm sorry.
That's all right.
It's gonna be a long war.
What makes you sure
he's gonna wait that long?
I'm not. Not if he gets
the right opportunity.
What I'm banking on is, that now
all he wants to do is to kill Germans.
As long as I can be useful to him
in that department...
...he'll do his best to keep me alive.
I hope.
That's nice of him.
Well, I can see his point.
The only way to win a war is to be
just as nasty as the enemy.
I'm only worried we'll find out
we're even nastier than they are.
I can't say that worries me.
Well, you're lucky.
Think I better
have a look at the hold.
Before Miller tells me to!
Help!
We've saved the explosives...
...the guns...
...and most of the ammunition.
I'm afraid we've lost the food
and the medical supplies.
But if we rendezvous with
the Resistance...
...at St. Alexis,
they'll supply us with both.
Let's get out of this place
as quickly as we can.
Pappadimos and Miller, you'll have
the first shift with the stretcher.
You're officially
taking command, sir?
Yes, I suppose I am. Why?
Just for the record.
This afternoon on the boat...
...you fumbled your job.
How'd that happen?
I don't know, sir.
The man was a foot away from you.
You only wounded him.
How could you miss?
I must have hesitated, sir.
You hesitated?
A man of your experience?
The Butcher of Barcelona?
How could you hesitate?
Well, I was tired.
I'm tired and I'm fed up.
I've been fighting this war
a long time.
I've been killing Germans since 1937.
There's no end to them.
Shoot a man at 200 yards,
he's just a target.
You kill him with a knife...
...you're close enough to smell him.
I smell them in my sleep.
After the last time, I made a pact
with myself: I'd do my job.
But I wouldn't do the other anymore.
Not if I could help it.
And who gave you the right
to make a private peace?
You think you're
the only one who's tired?
I do my job, sir!
Your job is to kill enemy soldiers.
There will, of course,
be a code word.
If we don't answer, a patrol
will be here in no time.
Let's pack and get out.
Let's go.
Well?
The major's leg is broken
in two places.
He could be hurt inside too.
He needs medical attention.
What do you suggest?
- Leave him for the Germans.
- They'd get him to a hospital.
If he doesn't get sulphanilamide,
he doesn't stand a chance.
Naturally, you all think a lot
of Major Franklin. So do I.
We have two choices.
We can take him,
and if he doesn't get help, he'll die.
Or we can leave him here,
and he'll tell the Germans everything.
Roy? Never!
He might not be able to help himself.
They have other drugs
besides sulpha.
All they have to do is use scopolamine,
and he'll tell them our whole plan.
There is, of course, a third choice.
One bullet now. Better for him.
Better for us.
You take that man along,
you endanger us all.
Why not drop him off the cliff
and save a bullet?
And why don't you shut up?
Yes, there's a third choice.
We'll make it if necessary...
...when it's necessary...
...and not before!
Now let's move!
Brown, from now on your job is
to look after Major Franklin.
I said, move!
Morning!
I'm sorry.
Don't be silly. It's just bad luck.
Well, what do we do now?
Where are we?
We're on our way.
- I'm going to hold you up.
- No, you won't.
Anyway, the professor won the toss
and he's dying to carry you.
That's right. You're not
nearly as heavy as I thought.
Now look...
...you've got to leave me.
You're out of your mind.
It's radio time.
Well, it's all on your plate now.
You'll never be able
to thank me enough.
I wanted the job all the time.
Hello, Lucky. Hello, Lucky.
Report my signal.
Hello, George-Mike-William.
George-Mike-William.
Strength four. Strength four, over.
Hello, Lucky. This is most urgent.
Paddington Station will close
at midnight, X minus one.
Do you understand?
X minus one, over.
We've lost a full day.
Germans are gonna hit Kheros
a day ahead of time.
Gives us until midnight,
the day after tomorrow.
Message understood.
Message understood. Over and out.
I'd like to be alone with the major.
Roy, that was foolish.
You almost ruined everything.
We've just heard, we're canceled out.
Scrubbed.
What?
They're going for an amphibious
landing the day after tomorrow...
...on the east coast.
The Turkish side.
The Turkish side?
And they're coming in force.
As far as we're concerned,
the pressure's off.
All we have to do is
make as much trouble as we can.
By tonight, we'll have you
in the hands of the underground.
We'll have you taken care of.
Try this again, I'll have Andrea
break your other leg.
Good luck.
Do not worry.
I shall see you tonight at St. Alexis.
Good evening, gentlemen.
Obviously, this place
has been used before.
Any food around?
I regret to say no.
Weren't you careless?
We might have been anyone.
I heard you coming five minutes ago.
No.
No!
Pappadimos,
it's time to relieve Andrea.
I'll take it.
No.
Pappadimos...
...you go.
- Maybe he brought food.
- Hold it.
He might be faking.
Saved!
Don't move!
Raise your hands!
Raise your hands high!
All of you!
You there, with the food, speak!
You are not Germans.
Which of you is Major Franklin?
The man on the stretcher.
Who are you?
My name is Maria Pappadimos.
You may put your hands
down now, gentlemen.
Pappadimos?
They said Pappadimos was a man.
My father.
He was taken two days ago.
He was taken?
He told them nothing.
He will die first.
- You have sisters or brothers?
- A brother, Spyro, in America.
Oh, he's not as far away as all that.
He's that handsome devil
right over there.
Spyro!
Why did you do that for?
To remind you to write letters
occasionally.
- There's a war on!
- I mean before the war!
I promised myself I would do this
the first time I saw you again.
Well, I'm sorry, brother.
Which of you did this?
Well...
I'm afraid it was me.
- Who is she?
- My friend, Anna. She's one of us.
It's bad that this happened to her.
Before the Germans came, she was
a schoolteacher in Mandrakos.
Last year, she was caught. They
tortured her to make her betray us.
They whipped her until
the white of her bones showed.
Some nights, we could
hear her screaming.
Then they kept her in
the fortress for six months.
When they let her go...
...she could not speak.
She has never spoken since.
Not even in her dreams.
Even I have never been allowed
to see the scars on her back.
But she's a good fighter.
As good as any of you!
Like a ghost, she goes anywhere!
She got us these guns.
And she kills without mercy.
You are very lucky, brother.
No, they are the friends! Our friends!
It's gangrene, sir.
If the leg doesn't come off, he'll die.
Does he know?
I don't think so.
Sir...
...I beg your pardon, but I haven't
had a chance to talk to you alone.
I don't want to be left out anymore.
I want to be part of the team again.
Please give me a chance.
You can trust me.
I'll think it over.
That's gangrene! What choice
do we have now, captain?
- Who relieved you?
- She did.
- In future, take orders only from me.
- I asked you a question, sir!
And I heard you, corporal.
Get yourself something to eat.
That's an order.
Thank you, sir.
There's a lot of activity down there.
I can hear it.
They're turning Mandrakos
inside out.
As soon as they move out,
we'll move in.
We're gonna get you to a doctor.
Brown says that you are doing well.
Brown is a liar. And so are you.
I haven't lost my sense of smell,
you know.
I just hope the doctor's
a good surgeon.
I wonder what old Jensen would say?
My luck seems to have changed,
doesn't it?
I don't suppose I'll ever
be a general now.
This Franklin...
...he's not a bad fellow.
No, not bad at all.
- You're sure there's a tunnel there?
- They'll never find us.
Well, they found us here.
Let's go. Let's go!
Oh, excuse me.
- Where is this tunnel?
- Up here, sir.
Where does this lead to?
We'll come out
just behind Mandrakos.
All right.
Let's keep going.
Anna?
You're limping. Are you hurt?
Do you need help?
Thank you, old bean.
Get off your behinds.
Think there's a fire escape?
These are fine people.
Give up quietly, gentlemen.
Unless you want many innocent
people killed, as well as yourselves.
Turn around, please.
Captain Mallory, you've made
a remarkable effort.
Unfortunately, it was
doomed from the beginning.
Will you tell me where you've
hidden your explosives?
No.
As your commanding officer, Captain
Mallory must play a heroic role.
You needn't carry such a burden.
You've all suffered a great deal.
Why prolong that suffering?
For you, the war is over.
Another officer is coming
to question you. A captain in the SS.
His methods, quite frankly,
are most severe.
None of you are in uniform.
Therefore, you're considered spies.
You know the penalty for espionage.
But if any one of you has the courage
to tell me where the explosives are...
...I promise, you will not only
save your own life...
...but the lives of your comrades.
This will be your only chance.
I do advise you to take it.
Please, sir! I am no spy!
I am not one of them!
You yellow--
Go on.
Sir, I swear to you, sir...
...I'm just a poor fisherman.
Two days ago these men killed
my sailors and stole my boat.
They forced me to join them.
Sir, I am their prisoner!
Where did you learn
your English, fisherman?
In Cyprus, sir.
I swear to you, it's true.
Aren't you Andrea Stavros?
Colonel Stavros?
Oh, no. No, sir.
My name is Nondus Salonikus.
I told you,
I'm a fisherman from Cyprus.
Then how do you happen to wear
a shoulder holster?
They forced me to wear it...
...and made it a kind of joke.
Where are the explosives?
I swear, sir...
...I would tell you if I knew.
But, see, they didn't say.
The truth is, sir, they don't trust me.
I don't blame them.
The commandant will telephone
to congratulate you, Muesel.
Thank you.
I've questioned them about the
explosives, but they refuse to answer.
The Greek claims
he is not one of them.
Now you! You are not
of this company, you say?
No, sir, I'm not.
You are a liar!
- But Your Excellency--
- A liar!
Come, come. That didn't hurt.
- Where are the explosives?
- I don't know, Your Excellency.
Your Excellency,
I swear I do not know!
I am not one of these men!
They forced me to join them.
As I explained to the captain...
...I'm just a...
...poor fisherman from Cyprus.
My name is...
...Nondus Salonikus.
I swear to you.
These men stole my boat and then
they forced me to join them.
Your Excellency--
Your Excellency, I am their prisoner!
Where are the explosives?
I want an answer now, or I'll personally
rearrange this officer's splints.
Very well.
I can't!
Please, I can't!
- Get up!
- I'm sick! I'm sick!
- Please! Oh, I'm sick!
But I'm sick! No, please!
Please, I'm sick!
I'm sick! I'm sick!
Call the sentry in.
Now, Oberleutnant...
...get on the phone.
Tell them you're not to be disturbed
until you give further orders.
Remember...
...I speak German...
...perfect.
Not very hygienic, I must say.
Shocking taste in undies too.
Ah, well...
Heil, everybody!
Roy...
...we're gonna leave you here.
I understand.
We're gonna let them
chase us around for a while.
But the one thing
they mustn't know...
...is about the landing
tomorrow night.
Of course.
Don't worry.
Oh, thanks.
Good luck.
Hold it.
We'll leave Major Franklin behind.
He's a wounded officer.
I expect him to get medical attention.
We don't make war on wounded men.
We're not all like Hauptmann Sessler.
Now, where's the camp radio station?
I will not tell you.
You wouldn't hesitate to kill me
for any number of reasons.
But not this one.
In any event, I will not tell you.
- So long, Roy.
- Good luck, Keith.
Well, Lucky, I shall miss you.
Try to be a bad patient, will you?
Keep on asking for bedpans.
Drives them mad.
I'll keep it in mind.
When this is over,
you'll buy me a lunch.
Roast beef, Yorkshire pudding,
a nice little red wine...
Steak and kidney pie.
Anything you say.
You'll be paying for it.
And you, colonel,
what a performance.
All right.
I hope you were right to leave
Franklin with the Germans.
Sir?
- Yes?
- No, not you, sir. Mr. Stavros.
Tell me about yourself.
- What do you want to know?
- Are you married?
I have been married.
My wife and children were killed.
Have you killed many people?
Only Germans.
Oh, some Italians too.
- Captain Mallory?
- Yes?
You are a lucky man.
Yes, I know.
- Mr. Stavros?
- Yes?
I like you.
I like you too.
I don't know.
Well, baby face,
I never would have known you.
You better get rid of that
fuzz under your nose.
No, I'm an officer, remember?
You just picked the wrong uniform.
Lights out in five minutes.
I want you as well-rested as possible.
Now, first thing in the morning...
...we'll ditch the truck
and get hold of another car.
Then we'll pick up the explosives
and go into Navarone.
We've got to be inside the fortress
by 10:00 tomorrow night.
Might one inquire how?
We're gonna walk in.
Simply because of this masquerade?
No.
Because I told Franklin
our orders had been changed.
That we weren't after the guns.
That we were just to create
a diversion for an assault...
...tomorrow night
on the Turkish side.
Now, if my hunch is right, the Germans
will give him scopolamine...
...and that's what he'll tell them.
They may not believe it, but they'll
be faced with the fact that he does.
Now I'm gambling that
they'll clear out of Navarone...
...and take up positions on the coast.
Very clever.
But that still leaves the garrison
inside the fortress...
...and we get them out by having
Andrea, Pappadimos and Brown...
...start up diversions
all over Navarone.
If there's enough confusion going...
...Miller and I should have
a chance to break in.
At the same time, the girls will steal
the fastest boat they can find...
...so we all have a chance of
getting out when this thing is over.
Very clever, indeed.
Suppose they don't have any
scopolamine? What happens then?
Suppose they use the
old-fashioned methods?
Suppose your ventriloquist's dummy
just won't talk...
...because he's a good man?
He won't be easy to break!
He may take a lot of punishment
before he tells them our plan!
He may even die on them
and tell them nothing at all!
Have you considered that?
Yes, I have.
I'll bet you have!
I'll bet you've considered that
as far back as the cliff!
You and your...
...three choices.
I'll bet that's why you dragged him
around with us all this time!
If he lives,
he'll never be the same again!
Do you know what you've done?
You've used up
an important human being!
Oh, I misjudged you.
You're rather a ruthless character,
Captain Mallory.
I didn't think of it back on the cliff.
But if I had...
...I'd have done the same thing.
It's our only chance!
Well, right now I say
to hell with the job!
I've been on 100 jobs,
none of which altered the war.
There've been 1000 wars and there'll
be 1000 more, until we're all dead.
I don't care about the war anymore.
I care about Roy!
And if Turkey enters
on the wrong side?
So what? Let the world blow itself
to pieces, as it deserves!
What about the 2000 men on Kheros?
I don't know them.
But I do know the man on Navarone!
Mr. Miller, the man was
finished when he fell.
That's easy for you to say,
sitting there, drinking coffee!
It's funny. I was grateful
when you left him behind today.
I just hope before this job's over...
...that I get the chance to use you
the way you've used him.
I'm sorry, but I couldn't think
of any other way.
Everybody get a good night's sleep.
No matter how it goes tomorrow...
...you're gonna need it.
I'll take the first watch.
Hello.
Tell me, schoolteacher...
...from a purely moral point of view...
...bearing in mind that we represent
goodness and civilization...
...do you think that what I did
was a civilized thing to do?
Scopolamine.
They are burning Mandrakos...
...in punishment.
This part of town
has been evacuated...
...because the guns' vibrations
has weakened the houses.
Where will the attacks come?
On the Turkish side.
What time?
Is the timetable clear?
Any questions?
Good luck.
I won't be needing this. You take it.
Spyro.
Andrea.
Everybody stay where you are.
The party's over.
Somebody's stepped on the cake.
Exhibit A: A clockwork fuse.
Elementary and archaic,
but they work.
This one won't work anymore.
Know why?
The clock's okay,
but the contact arm's broken off.
It could tick until Christmas
and not even set off a firecracker!
Exhibit B:
Exhibit B is missing.
All my slow burning fuses are gone.
Disappeared! Vanished!
Exhibit C: My time pencils.
75 grains of fulminate of mercury
in each of them.
Enough to blow my hand off.
And very unstable, very delicate.
Which means there's
a traitor in this room.
You're crazy.
It happened at base.
No, I'm not that crazy!
I checked it all before I left base.
No, here.
Here!
Someone here.
But who?
Who?
This stuff's only been
out of my sight two times.
Once was when Andrea and Maria
took it away to hide it.
But it was all right
when we picked it up again.
The only other time was
when we left it in the truck...
...and we scouted the gates.
All of us!
Except her.
We left her on guard in the truck...
...alone.
You are crazy, sir!
Let me just think for a moment.
Since we got here, we've jumped
out of one frying pan into another.
Just think...
We were hiding in the carob grove...
...and she's up in a tree. Remember?
Anybody can signal an airplane
with tin or a mirror.
And they found us there,
didn't they?
And then in the tunnel.
In the tunnel she lagged far behind,
with a shocking limp.
Seen her limping lately?
But being behind us,
she could leave some messages.
So when you take Roy to the doctor,
the Germans are waiting for you.
When she takes us to her place,
they come there.
But she got us out.
Of course! That house would be a
shambles and she'd be dead with us.
So, what does she do?
She disappears into the bedroom
to change her clothes...
...and to leave a little note.
She takes us to the wedding
and we're caught...
...because we can't get to our guns!
But even if we can, we slaughter
half of Mandrakos!
You are an insane man!
Am I?
Maybe I am.
Nothing surprises me anymore.
We can settle this thing very easily.
Let's see those scars
the Germans made on her back...
...those terrible scars.
How about it, Maria?
Don't you want to see those scars?
Q.E.D.
You cannot believe it?
Believe it.
I cannot stand pain.
It's easy to be brave when you're free,
when you're with friends.
But I was caught.
The others were free but they didn't
help me. I was alone.
I was alone in their hands.
They said they would put me
into their brothels.
They said they would torture me.
I saw what they did to other people.
I'm sorry.
I cannot stand pain.
When we got here...
...why didn't you put in with us?
You could have come with us!
It was your only chance
to get free of them!
There was never any chance.
You never had any chance!
It was hopeless from the beginning.
You'll never get out of here!
Never!
I tried to tell you last night.
Can you do anything at all?
I don't know.
There's always some way
to blow up explosives.
The trick is not to be around
when they go off.
But aren't you forgetting
something, captain?
The lady.
As I see it,
we have three choices:
One, we can leave her here.
But she might be found.
And in her case
they won't need a truth drug.
Two, we take her with us.
But that makes things more difficult.
And three...
Well, that's Andrea's choice.
Remember?
You really want
your pound of flesh.
Yes.
Yes, I do.
I just couldn't manage to get
to sleep last night.
- If you're anxious to kill her, do it!
- I'm not anxious to kill her.
I'm not anxious to kill anyone.
See, I'm not a born soldier.
I got trapped.
You may find me facetious...
...but if I didn't make some bad jokes,
I'd go out of my mind.
No, I prefer
to leave the killing to you.
An officer and a gentleman.
A leader of men, a hero.
If you think I enjoy this, you're mad!
I never wanted it.
I was trapped like you,
or anybody in uniform.
You wanted it.
You're an officer, aren't you?
I'll never want the responsibility
of an officer.
Then you've had a free ride
all this time.
Someone's got to be responsible.
Do you think it's easy?
I don't know!
I'm beginning to wonder who is
responsible to do the dirty work.
Is the man who gives the orders guilty,
or the one who has to do it?
- We've no time for this.
- Now just a minute!
If we're gonna get this job done,
she has got to be killed!
And we all know how keen you are
on getting the job done.
I've never killed a woman before,
traitor or not...
...and I'm finicky.
So why don't you do it?
Why don't you let us off for once?
Come on, be a pal.
Be a father to your men.
Come down off your cross,
close your eyes and pull the trigger!
What do you say, sir?
You all know what you
have to do. Get started.
Brown, you go with Maria.
Now, you know when you put on
a uniform and learn how to do it...
...it's not hard to kill anyone.
Sometimes it's harder not to.
You think you've been getting away
with it all this time, standing by.
Well, son...
...your "bystanding" days are over.
You're in it now, up to your neck!
They say you're a genius with
explosives. Start proving it!
You got me in the mood
to use this thing...
...and by God, if you don't think
of something, I'll use it on you!
I mean it.
Go on.
You stay here.
I'll call you if I need you.
Whatever you say, sir.
Spyro!
Detonators, sir, please.
I'll be finished here in about
30 seconds.
Miller?
Miller!
- Miller!
- Yes, what is it?
What are you doing?
They'll search those guns first
and find my stuff.
They're not stupid.
But if they remove it carelessly,
they could have the same result.
But I'm banking on this job
being our insurance.
- What happens?
- Would you bring down the hoist?
Whoa, that's enough!
See this bottom runner?
When they send this hoist down for
shells or charges, it'll come here.
It'll hit these
two wires and we get a circuit...
...that'll send up
all my plastic explosives here...
...plus this little item...
...that I borrowed here.
They won't see these wires
under the grease.
Are you sure it'll work?
No guarantee, but the theory's
perfectly feasible.
But if this stuff goes up...
...everything else in this place
will go up with it.
Suppose you don't get a contact?
Then I'll be responsible for sinking
one of the destroyers...
...maybe the whole lot of them.
I'm sorry, sir. it's the only way
I know to get the job done.
As you said, I'm in it now...
...up to my neck.
Hurry up.
- Go ahead.
- After you.
Remember? I can't swim.
You won't let me drown, will you?
I can't make it.
My arm...
Come on, man. Take it!
Grab it!
Spyro's dead, isn't he?
What happened?
He forgot why we came here.
And now you're going back to Crete?
Yes.
Come with us.
With us?
With me.
I must go back.
You saw what the Germans did
to Mandrakos.
Navarone will pay heavily for
your success tonight.
Come on,
I'll give you a hand.
I'm going back.
The job is finished.
Your job is finished.
What chance do you think you have
of staying alive back there?
I'm not so easy to kill.
Hey.
Well, the boys on Kheros
will be happy soon.
It'll be crowded, but
there's nothing like an ocean voyage:
Fresh air, good food,
deck sports, pretty girls...
I'd like to offer you
my apologies...
...and my congratulations.
The truth is,
I didn't think we could do it.
To tell you the truth,
neither did I.