[Thunder]
...circling northeast
of Kingfisher Canyon,
moving northeast.
A little bit earlier...
The tornado warning
continues now
and has been extended
officially--
I gave this
to you earlier--
It's been extended over into
Oklahoma County, to--let's call it--
They're calling all
of Oklahoma County,
but right now maybe
we can...
[Wind Roars]
[Thunder Cracks]
[House Creaking]
Jo, come on.
What is it, Mommy?
Come on, sweetie.
Let's get up. Come on.
It's O.K.
We need to get down
to the storm cellar right now!
Come on!
Take Jo! Let's go!
Come on, sweetie.
Don't be scared, Jo.
Mama's got you.
[Wind Roars]
[House Creaking]
TV says it's big.
Might be an F-5.
O.K., we're going
to the storm cellar.
Toby! Toby! Toby!
Toby! Toby!
Hurry, we gotta move!
Hand her to me!
Come on, let's move!
Toby!
[Arf Arf]
If you don't have
a cellar or basement,
go to the center part
of your house.
Aah!
We're almost there!
Take her! Take her!
I gotta get the door!
Hurry! Hurry!
[Arf Arf]
Daddy, Daddy,
Toby's still outside!
[Arf]
Come on, Toby!
Come on, boy!
It's O.K., Toby.
Grab Jo, honey!
Daddy!
[Arf Arf]
Take Jo.
Aah!
I can't!
I can't hold it!
Dear God!
I can't hold it anymore!
Oh, God!
I can't hold it down!
Aah!
Daddy!
Jo!
Daddy! Daddy!
Stay with me, Jo!
My daddy!
Jo!
[Birds Twitter]
[Satellite Telemetry]
At 7 a.m.
in Oklahoma City,
the temperature
is 75 degrees.
Across the state,
skies are partly cloudy.
Dry line is mostly
in western Oklahoma.
Visible satellite pictures
indicate thunderstorms developing
along and ahead of
the dry line.
Temperatures over the state
were in the mid-70s to low 80s.
Chris, take a look.
The caps are already
starting to break.
All the models are forecasting
lifted indices
from minus 6
to minus 10.
If these cells
keep building like this,
there could be a record
outbreak of tornadoes.
This is going
to be a long day.
Honey, are you sure
she's going to be there?
If I know Jo,
she's already dragged her entire
department into the field.
Aw, hell. Day like today,
it's to be expected.
She forgets everything
except her work.
You're nervous
about seeing her, aren't you?
Nervous? No.
Why, do I look
nervous?
No.
Well, yeah,
you do a little.
I just want
to get it over with.
But she said she'd
sign the papers, right?
That's what she said.
You don't think so?
No, I think so.
Give me a kiss.
[Rock Music Plays]
[Knocking]
O.K., Professor,
hang on there!
I think I fixed it!
[Music Continues]
I got it
Ow! Fuck!
This thing is useless!
Sorry, Jo.
Wait, wait, wait, Beltzer,
that's good!
Give me a reading!
O.K., boss lady.
Hold your horses.
Which way
do you want it, Jo?
Looks like the dry line
has stalled.
Give me a sector scan
west northwest.
Look at midlevels
for rotation
and increase the PRF.
♪ If I mistreat you,
girl ♪
♪ Sho' don't
mean no harm ♪
♪ If I mistreat you, girl ♪
♪ Sho' don't mean
no harm... ♪
All I'm saying is
don't fold the maps.
I didn't fold
the map.
Yeah, well,
Kansas is a mess.
There's a big crease
right through Wichita.
Roll the maps.
What do you know?
The storm chasers.
♪ Honey, where'd you stay
last night J♪
Hey!
I don't believe it!
Who is that
handsome devil?
Gentlemen.
The Extreme!
It's The Extreme!
Ha ha ha!
Oh, man, don't
start that shit.
Ha ha!
Oh, manly
handshakin' Zeus.
How you doing, man?
I'm doing great.
Doing great.
Oh, man!
Dusty, I'd like you
to meet Melissa.
Melissa,
this is Dusty.
Dustman has been
chasing with us
ever since
we started.
Listen, man.
Where's Jo?
She's over by the Doppler.
It broke down again.
Running out of grant money.
Honey, why don't you hang out
here for a little while?
I'll--I'll be
right back.
Dusty, why don't you
explain to Melissa
why you are
the way you are.
Ha ha ha!
Come on.
Man, Jo's going to wig
when she sees he's back.
I'm not back.
The prodigal son returns.
J" Time to go away I
♪ Darlin', could it be? ♪
Hiya, Joey.
Hey, Bill.
♪ Heal me
with a smile ♪
J" Darlin', stay... ♪
Hiya, Jo.
♪ Heal me with a smile... ♪
Hey, Bill.
I'm happy
you found us.
How you doing?
It's going good.
Hear the sky today?
Yeah, she's, uh...
she's really talking.
Catch.
It's the biggest series
of storms in 12 years.
One lined up
right after another.
NSSL says they've never seen
anything like it.
Is that right?
So, Jo, about
the divorce papers.
Hey, Jo!
Got a second?
Whoops.
Excuse me.
Yeah, sure.
Hi, Bill. Hey, this thing's
acting up again.
The focus mount's
jammed.
Where's
the focus mount?
There's grass
in the autofocus.
Did you check this?
You have to check it.
You want me
to clean that out'?
Not unless you want
to sketch the tornadoes.
Hey, welcome back, huh?
I'm not back.
[Thunder]
So you want the papers?
I did drive all the way
out here for them.
They're signed
and ready.
Good. Good.
Let's see them.
Do you need them
right this second?
It'd be nice.
What's the urgent
urgency?
You act like
you're getting married.
I am.
Wow.
Yeah.
Is it Melinda?
Melissa.
Wasn't there a Melinda
in there somewhere?
No, there's only been
Melissa since you.
Boy, not much
for browsing, are you?
No, I guess I'm not.
There you go.
Thank you.
♪ Love will find a road ♪
♪ Love will ♪
♪ Find a heaven
for you to go J♪
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
You missed a page.
What?
Right here.
Where did this
come from?
What are you doing?
Can I read it first?
No.
It's the same as
it was in December.
I didn't read it
in December.
Christ. Would you just sign it
so we can get out of here?
Please?
We? She's here?
Yes, she's here.
She's over with Dusty.
Now would you please
sign the document?
You left her with Dusty?
What's the matter with you?
What are you doing?
I want to meet her.
No, you don't.
Christ.
The suck zone.
It's the point...
basically,
at which the twister
sucks you up.
That's not the technical term
for it obviously,
but--
Hi!
I'm Jo Harding.
Oh, hello.
Nice to meet you.
Bill just told me
the happy news.
Which?
Us. Marriage.
Jo, Melissa.
It's happy news.
I guess it probably
seems kind of sudden.
Seems sudden?
Dude, you taking the vows?
That's sweet.
Well, we--we just
wanted to get it done
before Billy started
his new job.
That's right.
Right, right, right. Weatherman.
- What?
Say it.
I said weatherman.
I think it's great.
You had that tone.
There was no tone. If you have
a problem being a weatherman--
I don't have a problem
being a weatherman.
[Cellular Phone Rings]
Excuse me.
[Ring]
Dr. Melissa Reeves here.
I just wanted
to say hello.
Hello.
Very nice
to meet you.
You, too. Billy.
What? No.
Uh-huh.
New truck?
That's right.
Boy, oh, boy...
New job, new truck,
new wife.
It's like
a whole new you.
Jo.
This is very awkward.
I know. Tell me about it.
I thought you'd be
coming out here alone.
I wasn't expecting
on coming out here at all.
You said you'd meet me--
It's about Dorothy.
Dorothy? What about her?
She's here.
Show me.
I can't believe
you did it.
We built four of them.
Does she work?
Thought you'd want to be here
for her first time out.
It wouldn't be right
if you weren't here.
Whoo-hoo! This is
going to be good.
[Thunder]
How sweet is that?
Bill's concept, man.
Ooh, The Extreme.
It came from his brain.
Ohh, The Extreme.
I had a hand in it.
Wow, it is great.
What is it?
It's an instrument pack
for studying tornadoes.
The first one in history.
It's very exciting.
Scientists have been studying
tornadoes forever,
but still nobody knows
how a tornado works.
We've no idea what
is going on inside
because nobody's
ever been able
to take scientific measurements
from inside the funnel.
That's what she's
going to do.
How?
We put her up
inside a tornado.
She opens...
and releases hundreds
of these sensors
that measure all parts of
the tornado simultaneously.
You see, Melissa,
it's like this.
These sensors
go up the funnel
and radio back information
about the internal structure,
wind velocities,
flow, asymmetries.
We can learn more
in 30 seconds
than they have in
the past 30 years,
get a profile of a tornado
for the first time.
And what will that do?
If we knew how
a tornado really worked,
we could design
an advance warning system.
Aren't there already
tornado warnings?
Well--
They're not good enough.
They're nowhere near
good enough.
Right now,
it's three minutes.
If we can get
this new information,
we can increase warning time
to 15 minutes.
Give people a chance
to get to safety.
At least, that's what
these guys are trying to do.
- Whoo-hoo!
- That's right!
Oh, yeah!
I can't believe
you actually did it.
Well, we did it.
All right.
How do you get it
in the tornado?
You got to get
in front of the tornado
and put it
in the damage path
and then get out again
before it picks you up, too.
It's the suck zone.
Oh.
Excellent!
Jo, we got major action!
NSSL says
the cap is breaking.
Tower's going up
30 miles up the dry line.
All right. Let's go.
All right.
We're moving!
It's fatty time.
Jo, we got it.
Rabbit, you're up.
Let's go. Let's go!
Joey, Haynes,
a little help.
Yes, sir.
Right behind you.
Smooth.
There it is!
Come on, Dusty!
You're always last to go!
All right, Beltzer.
Preacher, follow!
Brian, don't forget
the camera.
I got it!
They can handle this.
They know what
they're doing.
This is what they do.
They--They live for this.
Uh-huh.
Dorothy ll and Ill ready.
Dorothy IV ready!
Are you sure you don't
want to go along?
No. Go with them,
you mean?
Yeah.
No, they'll be fine.
Did she sign the papers?
Oh, shit!
She didn't?
Come on. If we hurry,
we can still catch her!
Hey, Bill,
glad you're back!
I'm not back!
Rabbit.
Yeah, boss?
Can we do better
than the 30?
No.
Not for a while.
It's best to stay on it
until we pass Roger's Creek.
Copy that.
Once we catch up
with her,
you take the truck
and head home.
I'll get the papers signed
and see you tonight, O.K.?
No!
You know what, honey?
I find this
kind of interesting.
I'm going to tag along.
Jonas.
Son of a bitch.
Who is that, honey?
Jonas Miller.
He's a night crawler.
We all started out
in the same lab,
but Jonas went and got himself
some corporate sponsors.
He's in it for the money,
not the science.
He's got a lot
of high-tech gadgets,
but he's got
no instincts.
And he doesn't
have Dorothy.
Jo, I think we got fleas.
Jo, come back.
Hey there.
You change your mind?
Yeah, what's Jonas
doing here?
I'm not sure, but I bet
he's asking himself
the same question
about you.
[Honk Honk]
Oh, shit, hold on!
Damn son of a bitch!
Hey-
How long do you think
it'll take to get it fixed?
Maybe 10 minutes.
15 tops.
Sounds good.
[Jonas]
What drives me is the unknown.
What if we could predict
the tornado's path?
How many lives
would be spared
with the creation
of an early warning system?
And D.O.T. 3 is the answer--
the first digital
orthographic telemeter.
And inside, she holds
hundreds of these little sensors,
which, when released
in the tornado,
will transmit back data
on windspeed, pressure,
and dew-point temperature.
- Bill.
- Why didn't you tell me'?
Bill, don't!
And what will soon be
the center of all studi--
Hey!
You son of a bitch!
What'd you think-- I wasn't going
to find out about this?
Get this loser off me!
Back off!
It's not worth it!
What's the matter with you?
You stole my design,
you son of a bitch!
What the hell are
you talking about?
Dorothy.
You took her,
you damn thief.
Oh, I get it.
You want to take credit
for my design.
You're a liar.
She was our idea,
and you know it.
Unrealized idea.
Unrealized.
That ain't worth shit!
Bill!
Hey, hey! Guys, guys!
All my guys,
get a grip on yourself.
We both know he'll never get
that thing up in the air.
Well, let me enlighten
you people.
This baby has
satellite comlink.
We got on-board
pulse Doppler.
We got NEXRAD real time.
Today we're going
to make history.
So stick around...
'cause the days of
sniffing the dirt are over.
Better than what
you sniff.
We'll see who gets
there first, pal.
Oh, and by the way,
I really enjoy
your weather reports.
You slime!
I'm not through
with you yet! Come on!
Come here! Come on! Come on!
Get your hands
off of me!
I'm all right!
O.K.!
He's a corporate
kiss-butt, man.
I'm sorry.
I should've told you.
One day.
I'll give you
one day.
Whether she flies
or not, I'm gone.
Honey, honey,
is everything O.K.?
It's O.K.
Everything's fine.
Are you sure?
Yeah, yeah.
Everything's O.K.
Listen, I'm going to hang out
here and get some air.
Why don't you go get us
some cold drinks?
O.K., sweetheart.
O.K.
[Distant Thunder]
You know, Jo,
I don't know what the matter is
with Bill.
He's wacko.
He's crazy.
You ought to keep
a leash on him.
He's not my problem.
He's yours.
Oh, by the way.
This storm's going to be
a lot bigger than we anticipated.
I got reports of mesos from Grand
County all the way to Logan.
You're sharing
information with me'?
No.
I was just, uh, curious
as to which way
you're going to head.
Southeast, I think...
to the counter.
Two lemonades to go, please.
Nothing changes.
Pardon me'?
He's going to wait
and see what Bill does.
Can I have a coffee
to go, please?
That man is waiting
for Billy? Why?
[Distant Thunder]
So you're telling me
that Billy knows
what a storm
is thinking?
Something like that.
Gum?
My Aunt Meg used to call him
a human barometer.
Well, he hasn't really
told me about all this.
If you have to pee,
you should do it now,
'cause there's not
very many places to stop
once we get on the road.
You're still in love
with him, aren't you?
Check, please.
Not that I blame you.
I just hope this isn't
some desperate attempt
to keep him in your life.
We're together.
Hey, man...
what's up?
Goin' green.
Greenage.
Saddle 'em up.
You got it, boss.
Charles, I need
a sector scan on that cell.
Keep looking for a hook.
Will do, sir.
Flanders, what are
my dew points doing?
Points up to 70, sir.
Honey, I got you
a lemonade--
We got to move out.
Listen, follow us
in the truck.
Stay behind Dusty's van.
You'll be safe back there.
I got to go with Jo.
O.K., let's move out,
people! Let's go!
Where are we going?
Thanks. I'll drive.
All right, people.
Let's pack it up. Let's go.
Ha ha! It's the wonder
of nature, baby!
[Rock 'n' Roll Blares]
Ha ha!
Whoo!
[Music Blaring]
Whoo-hoo!
Hey, you guys!
[William Tell Overture
Plays]
[Cellular Phone Rings]
[Ring]
Dr. Melissa Reeves here.
Oh.
Oh, hello, Donald.
Yes, you got me in my car.
J" Oklahoma! J
♪ Where the wind comes
sweeping down the plains ♪
♪ And the waving wheat... J♪
This feeling of inadequacy
is coming from you.
Julia doesn't resent you.
We've talked about this before.
She did not marry your penis.
Oh, O.K.
She didn't only
marry your penis.
♪ L-A ♪
♪ H-O ♪
- ♪ M-A, Oklahoma ♪
- ♪ Oklahoma J♪
So...
Amazing coloring
there, isn't it?
Yeah, look at those mammatus.
Bet those tops have got
to be spiking above 40,000.
That's a good thing.
That's a very good thing.
She work at the station?
Is that where you met her?
Jo, I don't want to fight.
I'm not fighting.
I'm talking.
I don't want to fight.
She's nice.
Hag
Uh-oh.
She's not nice?
I know what
you meant.
You do?
Yes, so don't do this.
O.K. I'm making
extremely civilized conversation.
You're biting my head off.
Jesus.
Yes, she's very nice.
No, she does not
work at the station.
She's a...
She's a therapist.
Oh.
Yours?
Christ! You couldn't
resist, could you?
What? I'm not saying
you need therapy.
- What?
- I'm not.
I need therapy?
I didn't say that.
I need a therapist?
What could I possibly need
a therapist for?
You're the doctor.
Tell me.
I don't know...
An inability
to finish things.
I don't finish things?
Rushing into things you
can't quite commit to.
Commitment?
You asked me.
No, that is bullshit.
Look, I may have walked out,
but at least I showed up
in the first place.
O.K., there's
a whole road thing goi--
You never had
the slightest idea about commitment,
what being
married means,
like stability,
supportiveness, the house,
and all kinds
of neat stuff like that.
- Can I drive?
- No!
Then would you?
Whoa!
Damn.
Somebody should warn her
about your temper.
Jo, I swear
if you don't--
She obviously has no idea
what she's getting herself into.
Stay the hell out of it.
I know exactly what
I'm doing.
What am I doing?
I think they're
getting better at this.
You know what?
As long as you're happy...
Thank you.
I am happy-
I'm a happy person.
I'm happy with my life.
I'm happy with the way
things are going in my life.
I'm happy
with--with--with--
Melissa.
I know her name.
Yes, I'm happy
with Melissa.
O.K. You look happy.
I am,
Shit! Shit!
Hey, are you guys going to
wrap this up pretty soon?
What?
Oh, nothing.
I was just wondering
if we were going to
chase this tornado,
or if you just want
to catch the next one.
Shit!
Beltzer, is it
on the ground?
I got it!
Easy, easy, easy.
We have to bear right.
It's on an easterly course.
The national weather service
has issued a tornado warning,
effective until 11 a.m.,
for north and western...
Uh, Dr. Miller.
Yes?
I think they turned left here.
Do it.
We're moving
to intercept, guys.
Get ready to set up.
You got it.
You've got to get
further ahead of it.
I know
what I'm doing.
Cut across
the field, Bill.
I know I have to
get ahead of it.
You're going to have to
get into that field.
- Do you want to drive?
- I'm just saying--
Would you like to drive?
Yes, I'd love to.
Listen, it's about
3 miles southeast.
Let's see what she does.
Go in there!
Just wait.
You're going to miss it.
Just hold on a second.
Have you lost your nerve?
Tighten your seat belt.
Bill, Jo, where are you?
We lost visual.
Are we having fun yet?
We got to get out of this.
Really?
2 miles now.
Picking up speed.
Bill, sometime this week
would be good.
I'm trying to get it out.
Are you mad?
I'll be mad later.
Right now I'm trying
not to kill us.
Funnel getting thicker.
It's moving fast.
Corning towards you, Jo.
It's starting to turn.
Where? I can't see.
You will.
Jo, you're too close!
It's not going to work!
Get out of there!
Oh, shit!
I can't get out.
It's too steep.
This was a great idea.
See? That wasn't so bad.
Let's get her out!
Let's go!
Why can't we spend
a normal day together?
We're right in
the damage path!
Jo, this is crazy!
Let me go!
There's no time!
We can still do this!
Come on! Come on!
Find something
to grab ahold of!
I know!
What are you doing?
I want to see it!
Bill!
Look out! Look out!
Oh, my God.
It's gone.
Where's my truck?
Aah!
- There it is.
- Melissa?
Oh, God!
Are you O.K.?
Melissa! Melissa!
Aah!
You--You just
missed that truck!
That's awesome!
[Laughing]
Melissa!
On, Billy!
Billy!
Are you O.K.?
Oh, God. I'm O.K.
Are you sure?
Bill,
she just missed the truck.
God, what happened to you?
Nothing. We're O.K.
We were perfectly safe.
Gone.
It's trashed.
We'll take a look at it.
It's gone.
It's over. It's over.
It's all over.
O.K.
Are you O.K.?
She's O.K.
[Laughing]
Well, there's
some good news.
I mean, it did fly.
What was it like?
It was windy.
Windy.
That's intense.
All right,
move it, Dusty.
That's intense.
Hey, the auto club's here.
Maybe we should stop,
see if they need some help.
Tornado warnings through
central Oklahoma...
They're fine.
Pay attention to the road.
Hey, you fashionably
late again, Jonas?
Fashionably late, huh?
Give me a kiss, baby.
Get out of here!
Loser!
Why don't you go find
your own twister, buddy?
Loser! Move on!
Let's go.
Don't worry.
I'll get them clean.
Come on, guys.
let's get Dorothy ll ready.
Have you got full coverage
on that truck?
Liability only.
It's a very pretty truck.
Thank you.
Don't even think about it.
No way.
This is the caboose.
I'm waiting for orders, boss.
Go ahead.
It's your truck.
You really should.
Dusty, the battle zone
should be northeast of 81.
Wait a minute.
The battle zone?
Billy, what are we doing?
We're going again.
Again? But back there you
almost got yourself killed.
No, no.
Just a close call.
You're going to cross 15
at Oklahoma 412.
412.
O.K., copy that.
Haynes, what's on the mesonet?
Winds continuing
to back.
VILs are at, uh...60.
O.K., guys.
Let's go get it.
Ohh.
Mobile lab.
Yeah, Tony, is it me,
or has the main
updraft shifted?
Upper level winds
are veering, sir.
Uh-huh. This thing
might dissipate.
We have enough time
to get in front of it?
Murphy, rotation
is increasing.
Shear is 90 knots--
50 outbound,
40 inbound.
Yeah, yeah, we see it.
We see a very
pronounced hook.
Checking for you now, sir.
Dr. Miller, good southeast gusts
at 40 miles per hour,
approaching 150
in the funnel.
Storm motion is 225 degrees
straight out of the southwest.
We're in perfect position.
Let's proceed.
Oh, howdy.
Got to admire
their spirit.
There's your pal.
What are you doing?
Look at the updraft,
the angle.
It's going to
shift its track.
Are you sure?
Oh, yes. Definitely a sidewinder.
It'll move left.
- Is that bad?
- Wasn't there a road back there?
You're right.
Go. 90. so. 90. so!
[Cellular Phone Rings]
[Ring]
Hello.
Donald, now's not a very
good time for me, O.K.'?
All right,
put Julia on. O.K.
Looking good.
Looking very good.
All right, about 4 miles up,
hang a right.
Let's deploy,
and we'll be done.
Uh, Dr. Miller.
Shit, shit!
It's moving away!
Looks like they're
going to intercept.
Damn it, Tony!
I thought you told me
this thing was going to
stay on the same heading!
[Melissa]
Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
Yeah. I know.
We're close.
Yeah, I know. O.K.
Rabbit, tell me
what road we're on.
Where does this take us?
I know it feels unnatural,
but with Donald's motility,
you're not going to have this
baby the old-fashioned way,
even if you stand
on your head.
She's a reproductive
therapist.
Laurence.
Laurence, come in.
We got to get ahead
of this storm.
What's on the satellite?
I can't talk to you
right now.
I have to call you back.
Shifting due south,
shifting due south.
We have an F-2,
ladies and gentlemen,
possibly F-3, O.K.'?
Read me'?
There's very, very large rope
on the ground.
Very large.
It looks like it's turning.
The atmosphere
is very unstable.
I repeat--unstable.
This is Rabbit.
It's at 2:00.
It's heading this way.
This is Sanders.
We are driving due east
on a country road.
We've been on it
for about 6 miles.
We've got an F-3, too,
sitting on the ground,
and she's a beauty.
Whoo-hoo!
Jo, it's barn burner.
Barn burner.
It's not going to
hang out long.
It's not hanging out long.
We got it! We got it!
We see it!
We're getting slammed
in here, guys.
You better hang back.
This thing loaded?
Yeah. Go for it.
Rain bands.
What?
Look at the surf
coming off those fields.
Shit. Horizontal rain.
Hang on.
Jesus, Bill. I've never seen it
clouded like this.
I don't think
anybody has.
Bill, we're in the core.
O.K.,
we got sisters.
Oh, my God.
[Cellular Phone Rings]
Yes? Julia, I can't talk
to you right now.
We're right under
the flanking line.
I realize that.
We can't attack this thing
from the south.
We're going to get rolled.
Watch me.
Julia, I know you're upset.
You just got to breathe.
The both of us
just got to breathe.
[Mooing]
Cow.
I got to go, Julia.
We got cows.
Another cow.
Actually, I think
that was the same one.
Damn it! We've got
drunkards here.
We got no path.
This is not good.
Get us out of here.
I'm trying.
Floor it!
“Ans on!
[Melissa Screaming]
[Melissa Gasping]
Whoo!
Was that incredible?
Whoo-hoo!
God, did you see that?
It was incredible.
Oh, honey. Honey.
[Rock 'n' Roll Blaring]
Did you see that?
It's all right.
Oh, God. It's O.K.
Oh, God. It's OK.
No, I'm not O.K.
This is not O.K.
O.K.?
Oh, Christ. I'm sorry.
Honey, I didn't think.
You know, when
you used to tell me
that you chased tornadoes,
deep down I always just
thought it was a metaphor.
Shh...
It's O.K. It's O.K.
Three times a lady!
Did you see the inflow
jets on those fatties?
Did you see? I was sitting
in the middle of it.
I was thinking it might not be
too bad of an idea
if we just got
the hell out of here
'cause there were
too many tornadoes back there.
Are you kidding?
This thing's not over.
We've only seen
the start of it.
Hey, you know what, Jo?
Some of us couldn't help but notice
how close we are to Wakita.
No.
Aunt Meg wouldn't mind
a pit stop, right?
No.
Red meat.
We crave sustenance.
Guys, we are not
invading my aunt.
Food.
Food!
Hey! We are absolutely
not going.
[Wind Mobiles Chime Softly]
There's the spot.
Just do it.
O.K. Great.
Billy!
Meg!
Come on, honey.
He)', Meg. How are you?
Oh, it is so good
to see you.
It's good to see you.
Day before yesterday
I was telling Jo
how much I miss you.
You haven't seen
any of my new work.
Jo, oh, honey.
Looks like you've seen
some action.
You should have seen it.
Meg.
Boys!
Give me some
of that lovin'.
Steak and eggs!
No. In a severe
lightning storm,
you want to grab
your ankles
and stick your butt
in the air.
He's right. If you're
going to get hit,
it's the safest orifice.
Yeah, I'd like to get hit
by lightning once.
You know,
see what it's like.
Hey, this is
real lemonade.
Hey, Meg,
I'm moving in here.
You guys, look out.
Make a space.
Look out, look out,
Look out.
God, Meg.
You got a lot of beef.
Where did you get
all this beef?
Did you see my cows
out front?
- No.
- Oh. Oh.
Oh!
Cool.
You slaughter
your own cows, Meg. Nice.
Potatoes.
Better grab some
while you can.
Meg's gravy
is famous.
It's practically
a food group.
Shower's free.
I'm next.
Oops.
Oh, I want that.
How can you watch
this garbage?
Oh, pardon me, gentlemen.
You guys got to see this.
Careful, buddy.
He'll steal your microphone.
Well, for me,
It's the thrill of the hunt.
[Boeing]
You know,
man against nature,
doing battle
with the elements.
Well, as a scientist,
can you actually predict
tornadoes now?
Well, no. they are very,
very unpredictable,
as some of my more unfortunate
colleagues found out
earlier on today.
But we hope
to change all that
with a system
that I have devised.
God, he sucks.
Shut up!
- Boo!
- Turn him off!
What a wiener.
He really is
in love with himself.
I thought it was
just a summer thing.
Dude, he's going to
rue the day.
He's going to rue the day
he came up against
The Extreme, baby.
Hear, hear!
Bill, I'm talking
imminent rueage.
Imminent rueage.
I was just wondering,
why do you call Billy
The Extreme?
Because Billy...
is the extreme.
Bill is the most out-of-control
son of a bitch
in the game.
No, I think
I came in second.
I've seen The Extreme
in high gear.
You guys got to get
some new stories.
I'm going to go clean up.
So, we get this one
near Daleton, right?
Oh, God.
We're way too close,
and Jo's got the vid on it,
and she's filming it, right?
Then all of the sudden
out of nowhere,
this shitty-looking
green Valiant
comes pulling up
right in the way.
She starts yelling,
and this loser stumbles
out of the car.
He's got a bottle
of Jack Daniels in his hand.
He's naked.
He is butt naked.
Naked.
Not naked.
I was not naked.
He was without apparel.
Half naked.
Naked.
So Jo's yelling at him
to get out of the way, right?
So, he just...
He strolls up
to the twister,
and he says,
"Have a drink."
And he chucks the bottle
into the twister,
and it never
hits the ground.
Twister caught it
and sucked it right up.
Honey, this is
a tissue of lies.
See, there was another Bill,
an evil Bill,
and I killed him.
I love him!
No, that was
a good-size twister.
What was that, an F-3?
Solid F-2.
See, now you've
lost me again.
It's the Fujita scale.
It measures the intensity
of a tornado
- by how much it eats.
- Eats?
Destroys.
The little encounter
we had back there
was a strong F-2,
F-3 maybe.
Maybe we'll see
some F-4s today.
That would be sweet.
4 is good.
4 will relocate your house
fairly efficiently.
Is there an F-5?
What would that be like?
The finger of God.
None of you have
ever seen an F-5?
Just one of us.
Forget it.
Doesn't matter what you do.
You'll still be beautiful.
You're biased.
Yes, I am.
Sounds like old times down there.
Yes, it does.
He didn't keep his part
of the bargain.
Which part?
To spend his life
pining for you
and die miserable
and alone.
Is that so much to ask?
I don't know.
Bill always went
his own way,
which was usually the same way
you were going.
Seems like a long time ago.
Not so long, Jo.
He's here, isn't he?
[Wind Mobiles Chiming]
That is so beautiful.
We have a serious
weather situation...
We got one, baby!
F-3! Mile outside of Parlaine!
This is for Garfield County
including the city of Enid.
This is a storm
that has developed
within the last
15 minutes.
First-alert
Doppler radar shows
that this is
a very intense storm.
You ride along with Dusty, O.K.?
Is that cool?
- What's the word from SELS?
- The word is big.
All right, let's go, people!
We know where Jonas is?
Yeah, he's still in Milston.
More than 30 miles from it.
Can we beat him?
I'm working on it.
Thanks for stopping by.
I'm sorry to eat and run.
It's what you live for.
Bye.
Good to see you, Bill.
Honey, I--
It's O.K.
Tasty cow, Aunt Meg.
It's for you, Dusty.
Thank you, sweetheart.
You and me, right'?
Yes.
Sweet, sweet.
Well, I...it was
a pleasure meeting you.
Likewise.
You better run.
Keys.
Please.
You're welcome.
Rabbit.
Hang on.
Let's go right
through Wakita.
We'll take Meyers Road
right past the fire station.
We'll take 132
to 44 East.
Rabbit, you know
any shortcuts, let us know.
We need every second.
O.K., Rabbit.
Time to impress me.
O.K. About a mile up,
there's a little detour.
We're going to take a walk
in the woods.
It gets bumpy here, folks.
O.K., let's get you wired.
Uh, excuse me.
O.K., you're up.
Whoo-hoo!
See, kids? An ordinary person
spends his life
avoiding tense situations.
Repo Man spends his life
getting into tense
situations, Beltzer!
Whoo!
O.K., Rabbit.
What have you got?
O.K., Bill, turn left here
toward that farm.
You sure about that?
Uh...yeah. Trust rne.
Rabbit is good.
Rabbit is wise.
Mother of God.
Jesus Christ.
This is a field, Rabbit.
I know.
Keep going, beyond it,
right through that brush.
You see that brush
right in front of you?
Yeah, we see the brush.
What's beyond that?
- Beyond what?
- "Beyond what"?
The brush!
A brick wall?
A bearded lady? What?
Oh, urn, it's the highway.
It's the highway.
Where's the road, Rabbit?
Yeah, where's the road, man?
It should be any moment.
[Horn Blares]
Hello.
Shit.
She's insane.
You're insane, Jo.
What are you trying to do,
get somebody killed?
Oh, really, Jonas?
It was so nice of you
to stop back there
and make sure we were all right.
It was very considerate
to see 10 people
on the side of the road
and not stop!
Let's keep this channel clear.
Dirtbag.
We're going to have to
get off of this road.
This is no time to guess.
I'm not guessing. Just make
a right turn. Trust me.
Do you want to drive?
Just turn!
Do we follow?
We do not.
What's he doing, man?
Oh...
[Chuckles]
I don't know.
Find this road.
It's like "Bob's Road."
Ha ha ha ha.
[Beeping]
We've got a touchdown.
We have touchdown. Touchdown.
Tornado is on the ground.
Listen to this.
Looks like it's
coming down Route 33.
Jo, we're on 33.
What's the path?
Uh, it's going about
35 miles an hour.
Do you see this?
I cannot see this.
Where is it? Hello?
Where you guys looking?
- Where, where, where?
- Direction, Rabbit.
North northeast.
- You see it?
- No.
You got anything out there?
North northeast--
You copy?
Shit, it's coming
right at us.
Uh, axis gone vertical--
Gone vertical.
Sucker's really
gaining strength.
[Jo]
You see it?
No, but I can...
Beltzer,
we don't have a visual.
Repeat--we do not have
a visual. Help us out.
Where is it?
I got it, Billy.
It's the best motion
we've ever seen.
It's like the base
of this fatty's
over a half a mile wide.
[Bill]
Rabbit.
If you're going
east on 7,
it should be coming over that hill
in a matter of minutes.
[Sanders]
This is the one, man. I feel it.
[Sanders] This is the one man.
I feel it.
It's got to be there.
Maybe it stalled.
No, I think Rabbit's right.
It's going to show its ugly face
right over that hill.
Jo, what do you think?
Are you going
to go for it, Jo?
Jo?
Time for deployment, guys.
Let's do it.
Oh, man.
This is the fun part,
sweetheart.
O.K., we got hail.
Hail. We got hail.
Sanders, pull it over
anywhere in here.
Here is good.
That's good.
We got a big one, guys.
Upflow, Beltzer.
We have upflow. Copy?
Yeah, Jo,
I'm checking.
I'm checking it.
She's almost up.
Bill, right now.
This is it.
I'll get her ready.
Ow!
Did you see him?
What?
The red truck going
right towards the core.
No.
He's not talking
about Billy, is he?
Are you O.K.?
I'm all right.
Keep going!
[Beep Beep Beep]
Hey, Beltzer,
we got a view!
Yeah, I can see it.
All right...
I got it.
That's no moon.
It's a space station!
Whoo!
Debris.
We have debris!
[Bill]
Ow! Come on! Come on!
O.K.!
They're in the birdcage!
Oh, my God.
Melissa, look at this!
Take a peek!
You can really feel it
with a telephoto lens.
No!
Come on! What's the matter?
What's wrong?
You people are all crazy.
Do you know that?
What?
[Jo]
Dusty, are you set up?
We're not leaving
till we get this.
She's the craziest one
of them all.
[Grunting]
O.K., she's almost ready.
Hold on!
We're almost there.
We're almost there!
Whoa!
Stop! This is fine.
It could shift.
We got to get closer,
a little closer!
All right,
that's close enough.
Aah! Aw, fuck!
O.K., hurry!
Get the tailgate.
You got it?
Yeah, she's all set.
Help me get her down.
Hurry!
Let's move!
Bill, hurry!
Damn. We got to go!
Now! Come on!
We can do this!
Come on! Come on!
Shit, it's stuck!
Ah!
Watch it!
God!
Bill!
Get down! Look out!
Come on! Hurry!
Aah!
Look out! Damn.
[Bill]
Where'd it go?
Where is it?
What's going on?
Aw, I don't believe this.
What the hell?
What does
the Doppler say?
The cone of silence.
Bill, Jo, it's over.
The thing was stable,
and--and th-then it's--
It's gone.
It's backbuilding.
It's not through yet.
You're right.
It's backbuilding.
We got a jumper here.
Beltzer, it's backbuilding.
You got to track it.
Yeah, Jo, we know.
Data's incomplete.
I think you guys should
get out of there. You copy?
Bill, help.
Bill, help me!
Jo, we should leave.
No, no, no.
- Help me!
- Forget the sensors.
- We got to get out of here now.
Beltzer will see it
if it drops anywhere near us.
It's not going
to drop near us.
It's going to drop
right on us.
Bill, turn this--
Wait, wait, wait. No, Bill.
No, no, no, no, no.
No, no, no. Go back!
Forget it, Jo. Forget it.
Go back. It's not too late.
Go back!
Forget it!
It's too late.
Help me!
Help me.
What are you doing?
Jo, the pack's wasted.
It's over.
What is wrong with you?
We can still do this.
Jesus Christ, listen to yourself.
You're obsessed!
You've never seen what that
thing can do, so don't tell me--
I just saw it!
You've never seen it!
You've never seen it miss
this house and miss that house
and come after you.
Christ, Jo, is that
what you think it did?
I don't know.
Jesus, Jo, why can't
you just forget it?
You don't understand, O.K.?
You'll never know.
When's it going to
be enough, huh?
How close do you have
to get? Talk to me.
Jo, things go wrong.
You can't explain it.
You can't predict it.
Killing yourself won't
bring your dad back.
I'm sorry he died,
but it was a long time ago.
You got to move on.
Stop living in the past.
Look at what you got
right in front of you.
What are you saying?
Me, Jo.
Excuse me, Doctor,
here's your activity report.
Hey, Bryce.
What?
You better get over here.
Take a look at this.
The gate--
The gate velocities are maxed out.
If those two cells
converge...
lnbounds and outbounds
have doubled.
[Thunder]
[Truck Radio Plays]
This afternoon,
a dry line pushed backward
into central Oklahoma
has backed
into western Oklahoma
in response to another approaching
upper level disturbance.
As the disturbance interacts
with the dry line,
thunderstorms are likely
to continue to develop.
Some of these storms
will likely be severe
with tornadoes, large hail,
and damaging winds.
Due to significant
vertical shear,
damaging tornadoes
are possible.
The threat
for severe weather
is expected to continue
through tomorrow morning
when the dry line
should clear the area.
Persons in
the listening area
should remain alert
throughout the night
for changing
weather conditions
and listen for weather statements
and possible warnings.
...for several counties.
And there have been
tornado sightings,
the latest reported just
to the northeast of Canton.
That was
a few minutes ago.
Hold on a second.
I've just been handed this.
O.K., this is official now.
A tornado has been reported
moving through Canton
just a few minutes ago.
♪ Skies ♪
♪ Without stars... ♪
Excuse me.
Can I have eight
coffees to go, please.
Eight?
Yeah.
♪ I ♪
♪ Watched the world ♪
♪ From a room ♪
♪ Without a view ♪
♪ For you left me ♪
♪ With so few memories ♪
♪ That I could
close my eyes ♪
♪ And cling to... ♪
Two coffees, please.
Long day.
Mm-hmm.
You know, I been thinking
about the sensors--
the way they scattered
out there today
on the highway.
I'm starting to wonder
whether the funnel
will carry them
like we thought.
Too light?
I don't know.
Maybe the whole thing's too light.
What can we do about that?
I'm not sure.
This is a tremendous situation,
a very dangerous situation.
If you have loved ones
in the Canton area,
do not try to help them
at this point.
You'll only be
more of a hindrance--
Thank you.
[Thunder]
[Beep Beep Beep]
Jesus, it's coming.
Jo, Bill, it's coming!
It's headed right for us!
It's already here.
Everybody underground now!
Billy!
Honey!
Come on!
What's going--
[Bill] Jo! Jo!
Jo, come on!
Get underground!
Take cover right now! Go!
[Screaming]
The doors! Close the doors!
Doors! Doors!
Bill!
Get inside!
Jo, come on!
What are you doing?
Come back!
Come on! Take my hand.
I can't.
Take my hand!
Come on! Hurry!
Come on.
Here, get in here.
Go, go, go. Come on!
Everybody down in the pit!
Get down!
Let's go, everybody down!
Go. Move. Come on.
[Bill]
Stay calm.
I got it. I got it! Aha!
It's O.K. It's O.K.
My head...
You're O.K.
[Melissa]
No, it is not O.K.!
It'll be over soon!
This is insane!
- Stay calm!
- I don't like this!
This is driving me crazy!
I don't want to
do this anymore!
Aah! Aah!
It's O.K., honey.
It's going to be O.K.
Chewed my lips off wondering if he'd
come staggering back home again.
I've never been so frightened
in my-- Knees were shaking--
Was I on key?
I couldn't hear a thing.
[Wind Mobile Chiming Softly]
You were on pitch all the way.
It's a wonder to me that
Mr. Norman Maine is still in pictures.
Absolutely correct,
miss, uh...
Blodgett.
Esther Blodgett.
Ha ha ha ha.
[Wind Mobiles Chiming Ever Faster]
[siren]
[Man] Oh, look at the truck.
It's trashed!
How...
...happening with
the weather in Oklahoma
where tornado activity
continues.
Uh, reports coming in
from Fairview
indicate a drive-in movie
there was blown away.
We know there's injuries.
We know the damage is massive.
Is that what it was like
up on that hill?
That? No.
We were lucky.
Those were just downdrafts
and microbursts.
[Sirens]
Tornado just sideswiped us.
Can you tell
which way it's headed?
It's, uh,
it's backing northeast.
A huge tornado on radar.
It also indicates a storm...
It looks to hit
Wakita head-on.
And it looks like a--
directly--
directly toward the Wakita area.
And, uh,
it's very, very powerful.
I'm going.
I'm going. Let's go.
We're going!
Where's Beltzer?
Will you get me
a route around the storm?
Jo, wait.
Where's the phone?
The lines are down, Jo.
I already tried.
Damn it.
Hang on, I'll drive.
Jo, we can jump on the 38
exchange and cross Highway 132.
Honey, it's Meg.
I got to go.
I'm going back.
Good. Good. You'll be safe
at the motel.
I'll see you
in the morning.
I won't be there.
What?
Why?
What are you saying?
I'm saying good-bye-
No.
You know, I can't
compete with this.
I wouldn't even know
where to start.
Wait. Don't do this
now, please.
Sooner or later,
it would've ended.
We both know that.
[sighs]
The funny thing is...
I'm not that upset.
What does that mean?
We can do it.
Come on, let's move!
I never meant for
any of this to happen.
Oh, Billy, I know.
It's O.K.
Bill...
Come on.
[siren]
You go ahead.
She needs you.
I hope that Aunt Meg's O.K.
What about you?
Oh...don't worry about me.
I know my way home.
[Rabbit] We can be in Wakita
in about an hour.
[Dusty]
Bill, come on.
Oh, my God.
They had no warning.
[Child Crying]
[Jo]
Oh, my God.
Jo, wait!
[Jo] Meg!
Meg!
Jo, wait.
Careful. Careful.
This house could go any second.
Meg!
[Bill]
Jo, take a flashlight.
The whole place
is ready to go. Meg!
Careful.
Meg!
[Creaking]
[Dog Whimpers]
Meg!
Shh! Did you hear that?
What?
I think I heard something.
Easy does it.
Careful.
O.K.
[Dog Yelping]
Meg.
[Barking]
Mose, boy.
Mose--
She's down here.
Meg, we're here.
We're coming down.
Meg!
We got to get this
off of her. Hang on.
Don't move. Don't move.
O.K., ready?
Watch your hand.
Go. Go.
[Grunts]
I got it.
Easy. Easy, easy, easy.
Are you O.K.?
I'm all right.
I'm fine.
Get down!
Oh, God.
[Creaking]
We got to hurry.
Let's go.
- I'm fine.
- Think you can walk?
Watch out!
Meg!
Meg! Bill!
Someone take my wa--
Joey, take my watch.
Go, go. Careful.
Bill!
Meg! Bill!
We're O.K.
We're coming out.
Get an ambulance over here!
Get an ambulance!
Laurence, now! Go!
All right.
Here we go, Meg.
O.K. My go--
How about some
steak and eggs?
Ha ha ha.
How nice,
you all came over.
There you go.
Nice and slow.
O.K.
Bill!
Grab Mose for me.
I think he's
a little shaken up.
Don't worry.
I'll get him.
Mose!
Is she O.K.?
We'll probably keep her
overnight just to be safe.
Overnight? Forget it.
I'm all right.
You're going
to the hospital.
O.K., I'll go,
but I'm going to drive myself.
Honey, your car's in a tree
around the corner.
Ohh!
It's O.K.
Whoa!
Oh!
The F-4 that hit Wakita
has now moved on
to the northeast.
I've just gotten word in
that an even stronger tornado
has now started to form
25 miles south of Wakita
right where
the two storm systems
have finally met
and combined forces.
The weather service is saying
that this is highly unusual,
and they are saying that this
latest funnel, this latest tornado
could be the strongest
F-5 tornado
that this state has seen
in more than 30 years.
Let's break it down, folks.
We're talking winds
in excess of 300 mph.
Hey, what are you doing?
I want to see how you are.
- All right.
- How is she?
I was worried about you.
Look at this.
It's nothing.
He says I have
a bump on the head
and maybe
a broken wrist.
Let me see that.
There's nothing to see.
See? It doesn't even hurt.
I'm sorry I wasn't there.
Stop blaming yourself.
You got me out of the house.
Jo, it's got to stop.
I didn't have any warning.
The sirens went off
a few seconds before it hit.
I didn't even get downstairs.
Jo.
I'm sorry. Uh...
I was listening to the radio,
and I don't even know if you want
to know, but it's happening.
NSSL's predicting an F-5.
Jo...
it's going to happen
to somebody else.
You...You go stop it.
I don't know how.
Well, I think you do.
You've been chasing these things
since you were a little kid.
It's what you do.
Go. Do it.
And let's see here.
NSSL severe storm staff
now confirms...
You all right?
I thought you were
going to go
to the hospital with Meg.
Jo?
What is it?
It's been an absolutely
incredible day.
We know Wakita
has just been leveled.
What is it?
I know how to make Dorothy fly.
Uh, it's just
an unparalleled display
of the savage power
of nature.
There's going
to be more tornadoes.
Let me just say to you,
Let me just say to yo",
if you're in the path
of any of these storms,
just stay alert,
and news 89
will keep you advised.
Of course.
I need every aluminum can
you can find.
We need cutters
and duct tape.
Haynes, Beltzer, I want to get
the last Dorothy
on the back of my truck,
and I want to get them
both on there right now.
We're gone.
Dusty, you ready for us?
Yeah, yeah. We're good.
- We're good?
- Mm-hmm, yeah.
We're good.
We're very good.
Let's go. Come on!
Did you get them done?
I think so.
Beautiful!
O.K., O.K.
Good?
Yeah.
Great job, you guys.
- Just be ready to record.
- Right.
Be careful, all right?
Don't follow too close.
All right.
You got it, boss.
O.K.
We're back in business.
Come on, let's go.
[Jo]
Half a mile more?
[Bill]
Sounds right.
I figure--put her right
in the middle of the road.
Unless you think
somebody will hit it.
Nobody will be there.
Hurry!
Let's go! Come on!
[Beep Beep Beep]
O.K., that's good!
You got it?
Let's go!
Dusty, you in position?
Yeah, we're prime.
Ready for contact.
[Tires Screech]
This is it.
It's going to work.
Just another minute,
Dusty.
We're ready for it!
Come on, come on, take her!
- It's too light.
- No, it's not.
We're losing it.
No, we're not.
She can still fly.
Get in!
Let's go!
[Tires Screech]
[Bill]
My God.
[Jo]
Oh, my God.
Come on!
Get us off this thing!
Bill, punch it!
- She's stuck!
- Bill!
Bill, go right now!
Hurry!
What is that?
Bill, hurry.
Hurry! Hurry!
This is not good.
Hurry!
Hold on!
Let's go!
Son of a bitch.
Jo, Bill,
are you all right?
Hey, can you guys hear me'?
You O.K.'?
We're O.K.
Jo, Bill, did you see
that explosion?
We saw it.
This monster's still moving
northeast on 80.
You copy?
This is it.
Last one.
Last time.
Mobile lab to mobile one,
Groundspeed is increasing.
The base must be
at least a mile wide.
We can't see it anymore.
What is your location?
We're right alongside her.
She's beautiful.
All right, we're
getting ready to play,
So pull back
and prepare to monitor.
They had to be there
somewhere.
[Jonas]
O.K., path is stable.
Copy that.
Men, this is it.
This is the one.
Stay sharp back there.
They have position.
They could make it.
Not unless
they anchor the pack.
Jonas, this is Jo.
Can you hear me'?
Not now, Harding.
Jonas, listen to me.
The pack is too light.
The twister will toss it
before it reaches the core.
You have to anchor it.
Oh, sharing valuable
information, Jo.
O.K., I'll consider that.
Thank you.
Jonas, listen to me.
Don't be a--
What?
Can you see them?
Jonas, what's your position?
Oh, howdy, Bill.
We're heading northeast,
running parallel,
and about to pull ahead
of it on the left. Why?
Hang back a minute.
We got a pretty good view
from back here.
She could shift her track,
and if she does,
she's going to come
right at you.
Do you COPY?
Maybe we should do
what he says.
He'd never put us
in harm's way.
When I want your opinion,
I'll give it to you.
Keep your mouth shut,
put your foot on the gas,
and stay on this heading.
It's unbelievable.
What is it?
What's wrong?
The base is so huge.
It must be at least
a mile wide.
Do you copy,
Dr. Miller?
Jonas, listen to me.
This is not a game!
Get off this
frequency, Bill.
She's shifting.
[Bill]
Oh, my God.
Jonas,
I'm telling you.
Eddie, I know you can hear me.
Turn around now!
Get out of there!
Look out!
Damn it!
Stupid!
We tried.
There's nothing we can do.
Yes, there is.
Bill, Jo,
groundspeed is increasing.
Get out of it
as fast as you can,
or she's going to bury you.
Debris, Dusty.
We have debris!
Debris!
Right!
Left!
Duck!
What now?
I have no idea.
Bill, Jo,
you still with us?
Oh, my God.
I think we're going in!
Maybe we should get off
of this road.
I think
you may be right.
Jo, Bill,
are you all right?
Dusty, you guys Set "P?
Jo, we're set.
You going in?
We're going in.
You ready?
I'm on it.
Be careful.
[Beep Beep Beep]
She's up.
O.K.
Where are they?
I can't see them.
Doppler tracking is great.
Windspeed still increasing.
I've never seen
anything like this.
They're going
to punch the core.
You ready?
Yeah. Let me just set
the cruise control.
O.K., we're good.
On 3?
On 3.
Go.
Ready?
Ready!
1- 2, a!
Go.
Go. Go.
Go! Go!
- Yes!
We did it!
Dorothy's flying!
Baby, she's flying, man!
Look at that!
We're in! We're in!
I don't believe it!
We made it inside!
We're going to be
very popular!
Baby, she's flying!
Look at that.
Hey, it's working, man!
It's Christmastime.
We're inside! It's working!
We did it!
I'm already getting readings!
This is it! We did it!
We just made history.
Hey, you guys,
it's about to shift northeast.
Bill, I think you guys
should get out of there!
You copy?
Bill, Jo! Do you copy?
Oh, no!
Run!
Hurry!
The barn! Come on!
Look out!
Bill, here, here!
Come on, hurry!
To the barn!
Stay down!
Oh, my God.
Who are these people?
I don't think so.
Whoa! Let's get out!
Quick!
Oh, my God!
Come on!
Run for it!
Run!
Look out!
Come on!
Get down! Come on!
Open up!
Jo, get in!
Here!
These pipes go down
at least 30 feet!
We anchor to them,
we might have a chance!
Bill!
No good!
This one!
Come on!
Get in!
Hold on!
“Ans on!
[Horses Whinny]
[Panting]
You all right?
Are you all right?
Wow, look at that.
It didn't take the house.
♪ Shine on ♪
♪ Shine on JJ"
We did it.
Yeah, we did.
Dorothy really flew.
It was a good idea.
Yeah.
Well, I...
- We've got so much to do.
- Yeah.
I got to get grant approval
for a new warning system,
we need a bigger lab,
you got to start analysis
on all that data.
I do?
Yeah. We got to generate models
out of all this data,
and I need
to run the lab.
No, no. You're doing
the analysis.
I'm running the lab.
You're running the lab?
I don't think so.
G--
Do you always have
to do things the hard way?
You got it, guys!
The sensors worked!
The computers went crazy!
We got data coming
out of our ears!
The biggest twister on record!
Awesome, man!
Hey, Jo and Bill,
check out that sky.
You know what?
I think we've seen enough.