"I will praise the Lord,
"and so shall be saved
from mine enemies!"
"The waves of death
have closed about me!
"The cords of hell
have encompassed me about,
"and the snares of death
have overtaken me. "
"... have encompassed me about,
"and the snares of death
have overtaken me!
"In my tribulation,
"I called to the Lord,
and cried to my God.
"And he heard my voice
cry at his temple. "
Get back.
Clear the way.
Move back.
Keep in line, woman!
By order of Their Gracious
Majesties, Queen Mary and King Philip,
we are come to witness the burning
of these Protestant heretics,
who have denied the authority
of the one, true Catholic church
and of His Holiness, the Pope.
Let them burn for all eternity
in the flames of hell.
"I called to the Lord,
"and cried to my God.
And he heard my voice... "
God bless you, Master Ridley!
For the love of God!
Friends! Help me!
I burn too slowly!
Help them!
For God's sake, help them!
"And so shall be saved
from mine enemies... "
Your Grace.
Grace.
Your Grace,
the Queen is with child.
They should have consulted me
before they rang the bells.
Is it true?
There are symptoms.
She has ceased to bleed,
her breasts have some milk,
and her stomach is swollen.
Is it true?
The King has not shared
her bed for many months.
He has a repugnance for it,
as lately Your Grace
has for mine.
Hmm.
Norfolk.
Your Majesties,
this is most wondrous news.
Indeed. We do thank God for
this, our most happy condition.
We must also thank His Majesty
for this blessed event,
which is nothing
short of a miracle.
What news, my lords, of the
rebellion against our authority?
Sussex?
Madam,
it is safely dispatched,
thanks to His Grace.
Sir Thomas Wyatt and the other
leaders are already dealt with.
But if they had succeeded,
these Protestants and heretics meant
to place your sister upon the throne.
There is no proof
against the Lady Elizabeth.
She's plainly guilty.
What need is there of proof?
As long as she remains alive,
there will be plots
to raise her to the throne.
Ambassador?
I agree with His Grace.
She is a heretic.
She must never be
allowed to succeed.
But if she...
If she were
brought properly to trial,
she would not be found guilty,
and we would all be condemned.
She has many friends
in Parliament...
My sister was born
of that whore, Anne Boleyn!
She was born a bastard.
She will never rule England.
Your Grace will find
some proof of her treachery.
I am most sure of it.
It was so fast.
May I join you, my lady?
If it please you, sir.
My lady! My lady!
Princess Elizabeth!
You are accused of conspiring
with Sir Thomas Wyatt and others
against Her Sovereign Majesty
and are arrested for treason.
I am commanded to take you hence
from this place to the Tower.
Remember who you are.
Do not be afraid of them.
My lady.
Prisoner to the steps.
I cannot confess to something
I did not do!
Your denials are all in vain!
You knew of the rebellion,
madam. You were party to it!
It is plain enough.
Where is your proof?
It was to your advantage.
You must let me
see the Queen. I must...
You despise the Queen
and the Catholic faith!
I am a true
and faithful subject.
I attend Mass...
You pretend,
but in your heart...
What's that?
What say you, madam?
Speak up!
Madam, if there is some
small truth in these charges,
however innocently or
unknowingly you did proceed,
you had best confess.
I ask you why we must
tear ourselves apart
for this small question
of religion,
- Catholic and Protestant...
- Small?
You think it small,
though it killed your mother?
We all...
We all believe in God,
my lords.
No, madam. There is only
one true belief. The other,
heresy.
Madam, you are cold.
I do not need your pity.
Accept it, then.
For my sake.
Thank you.
I shall not forget
this kindness.
Tonight I think I die.
Madam.
No!
Where do you take her?
Please! What's going on?
Save me! Save me!
Save me!
You...
Oh, no!
I am Your Majesty's
most humble servant.
Come here.
Closer,
so I might see your face.
When I look at you,
I see nothing of the King,
only that whore, your mother.
Hmm.
My father never did anything
so well as to cut off her head.
Your Majesty forgets
he was also my father.
Why will you not confess
your crimes against me?
Because, Your Majesty,
I have committed none.
You speak with such sincerity.
I see you're still
a consummate actress.
My husband is gone.
They have poisoned my child.
They say it is a tumor.
Madam, you are not well.
They say this cancer will make
you Queen, but they are wrong!
Look there!
It is your death warrant.
All I need do is sign it.
Mary.
If you sign that paper, you will
be murdering your own sister.
You will promise me something?
When I am gone,
you will do everything in your
power to uphold the Catholic faith.
Do not take away from the people the
consolations of the Blessed Virgin,
their Holy Mother.
When I am Queen,
I promise
to act
as my conscience dictates.
Well, do not think
to be Queen at all!
You may return
to your own house at Hatfield,
but you will remain there under
arrest until I am recovered.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
No.
Feed her to the wolves.
Let her see
what they are like.
She's just a child. And yet
still you piss yourselves!
Your Grace, Protestants are
already returning from abroad.
Yes, and have made plans to
massacre every Catholic in England.
There would be butchery, indeed, if
such a plan were even conceivable.
They say Walsingham
will return from France.
Walsingham is nothing!
Be sure he does not.
There's so little beauty in this
world. And so much suffering.
Do you suppose
that is what God had in mind?
That is to say,
if there is a God at all.
Perhaps there is nothing
in this universe but ourselves
and our thoughts.
Think before you do this.
If you must do it,
then do it now.
And without regret.
But first think carefully.
And be certain
why it needs to be done.
Look out there.
There is a whole world
waiting for you.
Innocence is the most
precious thing you possess.
Lose that
and you lose your soul.
Amen.
Father... Sir William!
My lady.
There was nowhere else
we could meet in safety.
Listen to me carefully.
All things move in our favor.
Many of our friends are, even
now, returning from exile, but...
These are most uncertain times
and your life
remains in danger.
You must therefore say nothing
and meet no one whose
visit may compromise you.
No one?
No one. Not even Lord Robert.
But he is a trusted friend!
Child. Listen to me.
Please.
You are most innocent
in the ways of this world,
and we must do all we may to
guarantee the security of your throne.
But there is someone
I do wish you to meet.
Monsignor Alvaro de la Quadra,
the Spanish ambassador.
Sir William, why would...
My lady, I bring a message.
The King of Spain
is enraptured,
and offers you
his hand in marriage.
My sister is not yet dead.
Her bed is still warm.
His Majesty finds it
already cold.
You must sign it.
For the love of God, sign it.
Will you leave
your kingdom to a heretic?
He then said
that this King would marry me,
but would not expect to share my bed
more than two or three times a year.
As much as that?
Well, if he...
He is enraptured...
Naturally.
But his affairs would
otherwise keep him in Spain.
Then the King is a fool.
For what affairs could ever be important
enough to keep him from your bed?
Robert, you should not say
such things.
Then I shall only think them.
Oh, everything's
still so uncertain.
Sir William says that
my life is still in danger.
Do not listen to everything
Sir William tells you.
Do not listen to any of them.
None of them are of consequence.
When you are Queen...
I am not...
I am not Queen yet.
You will be.
Elizabeth, Queen of England.
A court to worship you,
a country to obey you,
poems written
celebrating your beauty,
music composed in your honor,
and they will be nothing to you.
I will mean nothing to you.
Oh, how could you ever
be nothing to me?
Robert, you know
you are everything to me.
All that I am,
it is you.
Is she dead?
Give it to her.
My lady.
The Earl of Sussex is here.
The Queen is dead.
Long live the Queen!
"This is the Lord's doing,
"and it is marvelous
in our eyes. "
To the north, I present unto you
Elizabeth, your undoubted Queen.
To the south, I present to you
I crown thee Elizabeth,
Queen of England,
Ireland and France.
God save Your Majesty.
Your Majesty should know
that you have inherited a most
powerless and degenerate state.
It's threatened from abroad by
the ambitions of France and Spain
and is weaker in strength,
in men, moneys, and riches
than I have ever known it.
What are you saying?
Madam, your treasury is empty.
The navy is run down,
there is no standing army,
and we are bare of munitions.
There isn't a fortress left in England
that could withstand a single shot.
I have no desire
to go to war, sir.
But that is not the end of it.
Apart from abroad, here at home there
are those who wish Your Majesty ill.
Mary of Scots has already
laid claim to your throne.
And Norfolk. Norfolk
covets it relentlessly.
Madam.
Until you marry and produce an
heir, you will find no security.
Sir Christopher Hatton.
There is...
Oh, I do not see...
Lord Ainsley, Your Majesty.
I do not see why
a woman need marry at all.
Come on, come on!
This is Mistress Quickly.
Majesty.
Your Majesty.
You will recall His Excellency,
the Spanish ambassador, ma'am.
How could I forget?
Excellency.
Your Majesty.
He's French.
You'll have to speak up.
Do I know that gentleman?
That is
Sir Francis Walsingham, madam.
He is returned from exile now
and I have appointed him to have
a care for Your Majesty's person.
Excellency.
Majesty.
Hey!
May I present the French ambassador,
His Excellency, Monsieur de Foix.
Your Excellency.
I suppose the French do offer
some suitor to her.
Naturally.
Everything now depends upon
the husband that woman takes.
King Henry of Anjou sends you
his brotherly love.
He trusts that
with your accession,
the relationship between our
countries may be much improved.
That is also my hope.
With such consideration,
the King expects
that you will consider the suit
of his brother, the Duke of Anjou.
Well, naturally, Her Majesty will
consider the proposal most carefully.
It is unfortunate, however, that at
this time the Duke's aunt, Mary of Guise,
chooses to garrison Scotland
with French troops.
Ladies?
The marriage of a Queen,
Excellency,
is born of politics,
not of childish passion.
Your Grace.
Walsingham.
Welcome to England.
Your Grace is surprised?
No,
only a little disappointed.
Play a volta!
When may I see you in private?
In private?
Have you forgot, my lord?
I am Queen now.
He's coming.
My ladies.
My Lord.
You blush, Lady Knollys.
Are you in love?
No, my lord.
Then you should be,
or waste all that beauty.
Does Her Majesty sleep?
Not yet, Sir William.
She is overwrought.
Hmm.
I wish you to show me Her
Majesty's sheets every morning.
I must know
all her proper functions.
Proper functions, Sir William?
Indeed.
Her Majesty's body and person
are no longer her own property.
They belong to the State.
Yes, sir.
Your Grace.
Your Grace,
Her Majesty is not risen.
Your Grace.
Please, Your Grace.
Her Majesty is not yet ready
to receive visitors.
Madam.
You had best get up.
There is some grave news.
My Lady, I'm sorry.
Mary of Guise has increased
the French garrison in Scotland
by 4,000 men.
Perhaps more.
Madam, I'm afraid
the French mean to attack
while we are still weak and while Your
Majesty's reign is still uncertain.
What is your counsel?
Madam, we must, with all haste,
raise an army to march upon Scotland.
Can... Can...
Can we not send emissaries?
There is no time for that!
As Queen,
we look to you for action,
unless you are content to wait for
the French to send more reinforcements.
Here.
Are you all in agreement?
I say there's never been a better time
or occasion to abate the French pride.
Arundel?
War is a sin,
but sometimes a necessary one.
I...
Lord Robert, you were
appointed to the council
to protect the interests
of England.
Now it appears you do not have
the stomach for it.
I'm in agreement, Your Grace.
If Your Majesty's throne
is at risk.
What say you, Walsingham?
Your Majesty!
I say a prince should rather
be slow to take action
and should watch that he does not
come to be afraid of his own shadow.
Now, madam...
With your permission, madam.
You are not, Sir Francis,
a member of council,
nor are you in the majority.
I do not like wars.
They have uncertain outcomes.
Go back to England,
and take this to your Queen.
Hmm?
Where are my counselors?
I know not, madam.
Where is Lord Robert?
Lord Robert, madam,
has gone hunting.
Leave me. Go! Go!
I regret to inform Your Majesty of
our miserable defeat in Scotland.
The bishops do demand
Your Majesty's removal.
Defiance afoot
in every quarter.
Alas, madam, we are
come already to catastrophe.
How dare you
come into my presence?
Why do you follow me here?
It is my business
to protect Your Majesty.
Against all things.
I do not need protection.
I need to be left alone.
Majesty.
They should never have been
sent to Scotland.
My father would not have made
such a mistake.
I have been proved
unfit to rule.
Well, that is what you all
think, is it not, Walsingham?
It is not for me to judge you.
Why did they send
such children?
Why did they not send
proper reinforcements?
Because the bishops
would not let them.
They spoke against it
in the pulpits.
Then they are speaking
against their Queen.
Madam, the bishops are against
you and have no fear of you.
They do not expect you
to survive.
My lord, the Queen.
Where have you been?
You were not at court.
Majesty. Monsieur de Foix.
Mary of Guise, ma'am, promises to make
no further threat against Your Majesty,
but on one condition.
What condition?
That Your Majesty considers the proposal
of her nephew, the Duke of Anjou.
The Duke is most eager
to meet Your Majesty.
He has heard a great deal
of your beauty.
For the love of God, ma'am,
let not the care of your diseased
estate hang in the balance any longer.
In marriage and
in the production of an heir
lies your only surety.
The Duke is also
most handsome.
Very well.
Invite the Duke of Anjou.
We shall see him in the flesh.
Robert!
Go away!
The Duke will not take kindly
to a rival for his suit.
He is a traitor
and his father before him.
Lord Robert's head
will end up on a spike,
not on the pillow of a Queen.
Do you think you understand
what you just did? Do you?
Must you leave?
I would not miss this
for the world.
Today I shall watch
the fall of that heretic girl.
I have been placed here
as your sovereign...
I am your sovereign.
I have been placed here...
I...
God has...
God has placed me here.
I am your anointed sovereign.
I am your Queen and, like
my father, I mean to rule.
There is one thing higher
than royalty, my lords,
and that is religion.
I pass this Act of...
I ask you to...
I ask you to pass
this Act of Uniformity.
It's not for myself.
It's for my people.
They're my people.
My lords, there is one God.
We have a common...
There is one God.
This is for my people.
My people are my care...
Only care.
The truth be, my lords, your votes
are nothing without my consent.
If there is no uniformity
of religious belief here,
then there can only be
fragmentation,
Dispute, and quarrel.
Surely, my lords, it is better to
have a single Church of England.
A single Church of England
with a common prayer book...
And a...
And a common purpose.
Now, I ask you to pass
this Act of Uniformity not...
Not for myself,
but for my people,
who are my only care.
Madam, by this act...
By this act, you force us to relinquish
our allegiance to the Holy Father.
How can I force you,
Your Grace?
I am a woman.
I have no desire to make
windows into men's souls.
I simply ask,
can any man, in truth, serve two
masters and be faithful to both?
Madam, this... This is heresy!
Heresy indeed!
No, Your Grace.
This is common sense,
which is a most
English virtue.
Where is Gardiner?
Where are the others?
Let us out!
Open the door!
This is Walsingham's doing.
It is the devil's work.
It will not serve her
in any case.
The bishops will pass no measure
which severs us from Rome.
Your Majesty would
improve all these matters
if you would agree to marry.
Aye. Marry, then.
Aye.
But marry who, Your Grace?
Will you give me
some suggestion?
For some say France,
and others Spain,
and some cannot
abide foreigners at all.
So I'm not sure how best to please
you unless I married one of each.
Now Your Majesty does make fun
of the sanctity of marriage.
I do not think you should
lecture me on that, my lord,
since you yourself
have been twice divorced
and are now upon
your third wife.
Each of you must vote
according to your conscience.
But remember this.
In your hands,
upon this moment,
lies the future happiness
of my people
and the peace of this realm.
Let that be upon
your conscience also.
My lords,
the house will divide.
Walsingham.
I would know on what authority
you have kept us locked up here.
Your Graces must forgive me,
but you're now free to go.
I am sure this infernal work
has not saved your bastard Queen.
Her Majesty has won
the argument.
By what count?
By five, Your Grace.
Five.
You will be damned for this
and I pray God your wretched
soul will burn in hell!
No...
Because I am Anjou!
Yes, I am Anjou, yes.
I am Anjou.
Yes.
And I can't wait.
Would you like that?
Remove your hand.
Perhaps, Your Grace.
We shall think on it.
But I am deeply religious.
But I am very religious,
too, huh?
Very religious, yes.
Your Holiness, the priest
from England is here.
Tell me, my son,
what is the news of our
brothers and sisters in England?
Do they still support the sovereignty
of that illegitimate whore?
No, Holy Father.
They pray ceaselessly that England
may be recovered from heresy.
Prayers may not be sufficient.
I will ask for guidance in
this matter, but do not despair.
Was it not truly said that the
righteous shall inherit the earth?
"My true love has my heart,
and I have hers
"My heart in me
keeps her and me in one
"My heart in her
her thoughts and senses guide
"She loves my heart
"for once it was her own
"I cherish hers
because in me it bides
"My true love has my heart,
and I have hers. "
Marry me.
On a night such as this,
could any woman say no?
could a Queen say no?
Does not a Queen sit under the
same stars as any other woman?
Monsignor Alvaro!
Monsignor Alvaro, tell me.
As well as ambassador,
are you not also a bishop?
I am, my lord.
Then you can marry us!
Marry you?
Or perhaps he does not know enough
English to perform the ceremony.
Alas, madam, in this matter,
I can be of no help to you.
Madam!
Protect her!
Protect the Queen!
Help her! Help her!
Quickly, form a guard!
Hurry, man!
The Queen! The Queen!
Look to the Queen!
Make way.
It's Her Majesty. Make way.
Isabel, see that the ladies
are prepared. Isabel, go!
Where were you,
Sir Francis?
I only hope that Her Majesty may be
safely delivered from this present danger.
Get the bedchamber ready,
ladies, quickly! We come.
I am perfectly well.
Please do not... Do not fuss.
No one is to enter.
Yes, Sir William.
Stay near now, and keep watch.
Yes, Sir Francis.
Sorry, Lord Robert.
I said no one.
My lord.
A word.
To whose advantage was this?
De Foix?
No. Not with Anjou in play.
Then some madman.
There is always madness,
Master Elyot.
This was devised.
There is reason behind it.
Then Alvaro,
for he has most cause.
Yes, yes, yes.
But he was present.
He's too subtle for that.
But Norfolk. He's not so
subtle, and has even more cause.
Indeed.
So then he's not in league
with the Spanish.
Perhaps. Stay close to him.
The Duke has some other game.
I must find where he plays.
I see it is true that the Queen
favors you above all others.
But you have many
enemies here. Is it not so?
That is no concern of yours.
It may be.
If you would be
prepared in secret
to renounce heresy
and embrace the true faith,
then you might find
many new and powerful friends,
and keep your Queen.
You are most mistaken,
Monsignor,
if you think I might
so easily be persuaded
to act against my conscience
and my love.
Ah.
My lord.
What will a man not do
for love?
Madam, if only
you would heed my advice.
I narrowly escaped
with my life, sir.
I... I cannot now
discuss marriage.
Forgive me.
The one cannot be
separated from the other.
Have I not told you?
Yes! And I am sick of it.
This entire conversation
is ill-timed.
My patience, Sir William,
is not infinite.
It is a great joy to see
Your Majesty is not hurt.
It was a terrible affair.
The Duke would still know
the answer to his suit.
You may tell the Duke that he
shall have his answer shortly.
Oh, madam!
The point is pressing.
The Duke cannot love me so much if
he demands my answer so precipitously.
Perhaps Her Majesty
will not answer
because her heart is
already set upon another.
Do not presume, monsieur, to
know the secrets of my heart.
Monsieur de Foix may leave.
S'il vous platt, Excellency.
Secrets, madam?
You have no secrets!
The world knows that Lord Robert
visits your chambers at night,
and that you fornicate
with him!
It's even said that
you already carry his child.
Yes, Sir William,
I live my life in the open!
I am surrounded by people!
I do not understand how so bad
a judgment is being formed of me.
Madam, you cannot
marry Lord Robert.
He's already married.
A married man.
Lord Dudley.
Lord Dudley...
Imagine being discovered
in another woman's bed.
You mean
his wife's bed.
Lord Robert, we are amazed
you show your face at court.
The Queen!
Spanish!
Spanish! Spanish!
English pirate!
It's not enough that English
pirates attack and rob our ships,
but we have to be made
fools of in this court.
The King, my master, has become
impatient for Your Grace to act.
If you will not,
then others may.
You must reassure His Majesty
that the time is close at hand.
He must not act
precipitously.
English pirate!
His Majesty has also
heard a rumor.
The world is filled
with rumors, Monsignor.
That Your Grace has made
contact with Mary of Scots
to promote your ambitions.
Even that you mean
to marry her.
Do you suppose me an idiot?
Your master is the most
powerful man in the world.
I would not cross him
for my life.
Did the Duke
not come to dance?
Madam, His Grace is
unfortunately indisposed.
He has some pains
of the stomach.
Oh. I am very sorry for it.
We wish to give
the Duke this ring
as a token of our love.
Madam, allow me...
No.
I shall give it to him myself.
Madam, I should not...
Sir William.
Come along.
What?
What? What?
You stare, madame.
What is it? Do you see
something strange, perhaps?
You are wearing a dress,
Your Grace.
Oh.
Yes, I am wearing a dress.
Yes, yes, I am wearing a dress.
I wear a dress like this,
my mother, and you.
But I only dress like this when I'm
alone, in private with my friends.
Your Grace.
Although my affection for you
is undiminished,
I have, after
an agonizing struggle,
determined to sacrifice my own
happiness for the welfare of my people.
Oh! My God.
Madam, I will explain.
Madam, is the Duke...
There will be
no more talk of marriage.
Lord Robert!
Your Majesty.
Will you dance?
If it please you.
Play a volta.
Why will you not see me?
You must let me explain. Others
will take advantage of this.
You must not believe
what they tell you.
They are jealous.
And envious.
Because I am nothing to them,
and everything to you.
Do you love her?
No. I love you.
I have always loved you.
I was afraid of losing you,
because I was not free.
For God's sake,
you are still my Elizabeth.
No. I am not your Elizabeth!
I am no man's Elizabeth.
And if you think to rule her,
you are mistaken.
I will have one mistress here!
And no master!
It matters nothing to me.
I can live without her.
Most happily.
Better than I could
live with her.
I have no need of her love.
Have not I
suffered enough already,
for loving her and showing it?
I envy you, my lord,
to love a woman so deeply.
Monsignor,
envy no man for that.
Such love is hateful.
It tears the soul apart.
Envy a man who has
never known such love.
Perhaps there may still be a
way to reclaim her affections.
Why should I want to?
And to save her life.
You jest with me.
No. Indeed, I do not.
For she will be
dead soon enough,
perhaps even at Norfolk's
hand, if you do not help her.
How can I help her?
She will not even see me.
His Holiness
has issued the bull.
It deprives Elizabeth, the
pretended Queen of England,
servant of wickedness,
of her throne,
and declares that henceforth her subjects
are absolved of their allegiance to her.
His Holiness also
decrees that any man
who should undertake
her assassination
will be welcomed by angels
into the kingdom of heaven.
Give these letters of blessing
and hope to our friends in England.
Your Grace.
Monsignor.
And Thomas Elyot.
You serve
your master well, Elyot.
As good as I can, in truth.
I mean your real master.
What's this?
What master?
Walsingham.
The priest is mistaken,
my lord.
I am Your Grace's servant,
as God is my witness.
Isabel, they are...
Don't fuss.
You should not try them on, Isabel.
They are the Queen's dresses.
Why not?
I must see the Queen.
I am Queen of England.
Tell her I must see her.
Say you're mine.
You're my Elizabeth.
Say you are my Elizabeth.
I am your Elizabeth.
I am your Queen.
Kat!
Kat?
Who are you?
You will declare yourself
to me.
Madam!
Come quickly. Something has
happened. You must come quickly.
Who was with her?
One of the guards found her.
No one was with her.
He said he saw
Lord Robert leave.
No. No, no, madam, no.
The dress was poisoned.
Uncover her.
No! That dress was a gift.
For me.
French silk.
Sir Francis.
You and I, we must be
honest with each other.
Your Queen is weak.
She has no army,
no friends, only...
Enemies.
Mmm-hmm.
What terms can she propose?
Madam, Her Majesty was,
I believe,
too hasty at rejecting the
Duke's proposal of marriage.
But how can I marry such a
woman? Huh? She is frigid.
Yes.
They even say
she's really a man.
Oh, you must
forgive my nephew.
He speaks when
he should not. It's terrible.
I hear you are a wise man,
Sir Francis,
and a creature of the world.
Like me.
Yes.
I have no illusions.
I know it is only
a matter of time
before my Queen is overthrown.
Her Majesty rules
with the heart.
Not with the head.
I understand.
It is hard for a woman
to forget her heart.
But what of you,
Walsingham?
A wise man would be careful not
to put himself in the way of harm.
Hmm.
And how would
a wise man do that?
He would, as I said,
change allegiance.
There are but two choices.
He would get into bed
with either Spain or France.
And whose bed
would you prefer?
Your Majesty,
may I speak with you
in private?
Speak.
You are
in the greatest danger.
You must believe me.
But you have a friend, someone
who can guarantee your safety
and your throne.
A friend?
The King of Spain.
Leave us.
How would he guarantee it?
He would marry you.
Only to make an alliance,
nothing more.
He would not expect to...
He would live in Spain.
Why do you do this, Robert?
Because I love you,
and though you will not see me, I am
the only one who would care for you.
You love me so much, you
would have me be your whore?
For God's sake,
I do this for us.
I ask you to save
some part of us!
Lord Robert, you may make
whores of my ladies,
but you shall not
make one of me.
Your Majesty.
Of course, I shall deny it!
But Your Majesty must
publicly dissociate herself
from this most bloody act.
I never ordered it.
Of course, madam, of course.
You must also make conciliatory
gestures towards the Spanish.
Your dependence upon their
goodwill is even greater than ever.
I really must insist... The word
"must" is not used to princes.
I have followed your advice in
all the affairs of my kingdom,
but your policies would make
England nothing
but either part of France
or Spain.
From this moment, I am going
to follow my own opinion,
and see if I do any better.
Forgive me, madam,
but you're only a woman.
I may be a woman, Sir William, but if
I choose, I have the heart of a man.
I am my father's daughter.
I am not afraid of anything.
I...
I deeply regret, madam,
if I have caused you
such offense.
Though God knows all my advice
has only ever been
to secure
Your Majesty's throne.
And I am grateful for it.
I have decided to
create you Lord Burghley,
so you may enjoy your
retirement in greater ease.
Madam...
That will be all,
Lord Burghley.
Majesty.
Madam, if I may.
A prince should never flinch
from being blamed
for acts of ruthlessness
which are necessary
for safeguarding the state
and their own person.
You must take these things
so much to heart
that you do not fear
to strike.
Even the very nearest
that you have.
If they be implicated.
It has been made known to me
there is a priest abroad in the
land carrying letters from Rome
to those who mean to harm you.
Norfolk's power in court
is growing.
It is said that he and his
foreign allies are raising
an army that will
outnumber your own.
If Your Majesty does not
act soon, then he will.
Find the priest
and those who harbor him.
All right! Search
every room! You, upstairs!
I will see everybody
in this house!
Where is Lord Arundel?
He's not here, sir.
Do you know
where your father is?
You were carrying
letters from the Pope.
To whom were you
told to give them?
Tell me,
what is God to you?
Has he abandoned you?
Is he such a worldly God
that he must play at politics
and the filth of conspiracy?
Is he not divine?
Tell me the truth
as if you were face to face
with him now.
I'm a patient man, Father.
Sussex, Gardiner, Arundel.
A man will confess to anything
under torture.
And Lord Robert Dudley,
Earl of Leicester.
Madam, this document was also found
among the priest's possessions.
"From His Holiness, the Pope,
"to His Grace,
the Duke of Norfolk.
"To legitimize your claim
to the throne of England,
"His Holiness proposes that Your
Grace should take as your bride
"Mary, Queen of Scots,
"and overthrow Elizabeth... "
"The illegitimate
and heretical whore
"who now sits
upon the throne. "
All Norfolk need do
is sign this paper,
and treason would have
been committed.
Then let him sign it.
And let it all be done.
In the future,
when England is safe
again and faithful,
they will thank me for this
act and forget the manner of it.
Is it not true?
Deliver this most carefully.
What is the meaning of this?
Your Grace is arrested.
You must go with these men
to the Tower.
I must do nothing
by your orders. I am Norfolk.
You were Norfolk.
The dead have no titles.
You were the most powerful man
in England.
And could have been
greater still,
but you had not the courage
to be loyal.
Only the conviction
of your own vanity.
I think, Walsingham, a man's courage
is in the manner of his death.
I'm content to die
for my beliefs.
So cut off my head
and make me a martyr.
The people will always
remember it.
No.
They will forget.
Your Majesty knows that...
That I did it
only for my faith.
Nothing more.
All your many kindnesses
are remembered.
You must not think
we care not for your children.
Your Majesty is merciful
and forgiving.
What kept you, Walsingham?
I've been waiting.
Your Majesty.
They're all gone to the Tower,
your friends.
Tell me,
how should I serve thee,
Robert?
My course is run.
Just tell me why.
Why?
Madam.
Is it not plain enough to you?
It is no easy thing
to be loved by the Queen.
It would corrupt
the soul of any man.
Now, for God's sake, kill me.
No.
I think rather
to let you live.
Madam, that is not wise.
Lord Robert has
committed treason.
He must be made example of.
And I will make
an example of him.
He shall be kept alive
to always remind me
of how close I came to danger.
I have rid England
of her enemies.
What do I do now?
Am I to be made of stone?
Must I be touched by nothing?
Aye, madam. To reign supreme.
All men need something
greater than themselves
to look up to and worship.
They must be able
to touch the divine...
Here on earth.
She had such power
over men's hearts.
They died for her.
They have found nothing
to replace her.
You will be damned for this.
Tonight I think I die.
Speak up!
Kat.
I have become a virgin.
Observe, Lord Burghley.
I am married.
To England.