Let us tell an old story anew,
and we will see how well you know it.
Once upon a time,
there were two kingdoms
that were the worst of neighbors.
So vast was the discord between them
that it was said only a great hero
or a terrible villain
might bring them together.
In one kingdom
lived folk like you and me,
with a vain and greedy king
to rule over them.
They were forever discontent,
and envious of the wealth
and beauty of their neighbors.
For in the other kingdom, the Moors,
lived every manner of strange
and wonderful creature.
And they needed
neither king nor queen,
but trusted in one another.
In a great tree
on a great cliff in the Moors
lived one such spirit.
You might take her for a girl,
but she was not just any girl.
She was a fairy.
There you go.
And her name
was Maleficent.
Good morning, Mr. Chanterelle!
I love your cap!
No. No, don't do it!
You missed me!
- Good morning.
Lovely work, girls!
What's all the fuss about?
The border guards have discov...
Why do you get to tell her?
I want to tell her!
I want to!
There are rules, Flittle.
I tell this time, you tell next time.
No, you told last time,
so I should tell this time,
and Thistlewit next time.
Tell me what?
Fine!
Thank you.
Maleficent, the border guard...
The border guards have found
a human thief at the pool of jewels.
I'm sorry.
She's always in a hurry,
with her big wings.
Humans, here.
I hope there's not another war.
I'm not afraid.
Besides,
I have never seen a human up close.
Come out!
No. They mean to kill me.
And besides, they're hideous to look at.
That's extremely rude.
Don't listen to him, Balthazar.
You're classically handsome.
It's not right to steal,
but we don't kill people for it.
Come out.
Come out this instant!
Are you fully grown?
No.
I believe he's just a boy.
And you're just a girl.
I think.
Who are you?
I'm called Stefan.
I'm Maleficent.
Yes, right.
You have to give it back.
Give what back?
If I knew you would throw it away,
I would have kept it.
I didn't throw it away.
I delivered it home,
as I'm going to do for you.
Someday, you know, I'll live there.
In the castle.
Where do you live now?
In a barn.
So your parents are farmers, then?
My parents are dead.
Mine, too.
We'll see each other again.
You really shouldn't
come back here, you know.
It's not safe.
And if I made that choice,
if I came back, would you be here?
Perhaps.
- What's wrong?
- Your ring.
Iron burns fairies.
I'm sorry.
I like your wings.
Maleficent thought of how
Stefan cast away his ring,
he who had so little in the world,
so that their hands might touch again,
and her heart was moved.
Thus did the young thief
who had hoped to steal a jewel...
Maleficent!
...steal something far more precious.
Maleficent?
Maleficent!
After all these weeks,
look who came back.
I thought it worth the risk.
So, what do you do for fun?
Stefan and Maleficent became
the most unlikely of friends.
And for a time it seemed as if,
in them at least,
the old hatred between men and fairies
had been forgotten.
As it will, friendship slowly
turned into something else.
And on her 16th birthday,
Stefan gave Maleficent a gift.
He told her it was true love's kiss.
But it was not to be.
As the years passed, Stefan's ambition
pulled him away from Maleficent,
and towards the temptations
of the human kingdom.
While Maleficent,
the strongest of the fairies,
rose to become
the protector of the Moors.
Maleficent often wandered alone
and sometimes wondered
where Stefan might be,
for she had never understood
the greed and envy of men.
But she was to learn.
For the human king had heard
of a growing power in the Moors,
and he sought to strike it down.
Guard, halt!
There they are,
the mysterious Moors
where no one dares to venture
for fear of the magical creatures
that lurk within.
Well, I say crush them!
Go no further!
A king
does not take orders from a winged elf.
You are no king to me.
- Bring me her head.
- Battalion!
Advance!
Arise and stand with me!
Hold the line!
- It's the dark creatures!
Charge!
You!
To the king!
You will not have the Moors!
Not now, nor ever!
You...
When I ascended to the throne,
I promised the people
one day we would take
the Moors and its treasures.
Each of you
swore allegiance to me
and to that cause.
Your Majesty.
Defeated in battle.
Is this to be my legacy?
I see you waiting for me to die.
It won't be long. But what then?
I will choose a successor
to take the throne
and care for my daughter.
Who among you
is worthy?
Kill the winged creature.
Avenge me,
and upon my death
you will take the crown.
Maleficent.
Maleficent!
So, how is life with the humans?
Maleficent, I've come to warn you.
They mean to kill you.
King Henry will stop at nothing.
Please, you have to trust me.
They spoke of many things,
and the years faded away.
And she forgave Stefan
his folly and his ambition,
and all was as it had been long ago.
You thirsty?
Maleficent?
What is this?
I have avenged you, sire.
She is vanquished?
You have done well, my son.
You have done
what others feared to do.
You will be rewarded.
I shall do my best
to be a worthy successor,
Your Majesty.
I've got you!
- You wicked bird!
- lnto a man.
It's a...
It's a demon!
What have you done
to my beautiful self?
Would you
rather I let them beat you to death?
I'm not certain.
Stop complaining.
I saved your life.
Forgive me.
What do I call you?
Diaval.
And in return for saving my life,
I am your servant.
Whatever you need.
Wings.
I need you to be my wings.
I present to you the first of his line,
His Royal Highness King Stefan.
He did this to me so he would be king.
Now what, Mistress?
Her wings!
It's a girl!
It's a girl! It's a girl!
Well?
Well, I saw nothing.
But there's been a...
What?
Child.
King Stefan and the Queen
have had a child.
There will be a christening.
They say it's to be a grand celebration.
A grand celebration for a baby.
How wonderful.
All manner of folk
came to the christening,
even a trio of fairies who sought
to foster peace and goodwill.
Look, there's the baby!
I love babies!
Can you just concentrate, please?
I'm not telling you again.
Greetings, Your Majesty.
I am Knotgrass
of the Moorland Fair Folk.
I'm Flittle, Your Kingship.
And I'm Thistlewit, Your Royalnesses.
They bring gifts for our daughter.
These are not just any old gifts,
for, you see, we're magic!
And very good with children.
Very well.
Sweet Aurora, I wish for you
the gift of beauty.
My wish is that you will never be blue,
only happy, all the days of your life.
Sweet baby,
my wish for you is that you find...
- Maleficent!
Well, well.
What a glittering assemblage,
King Stefan.
Royalty, nobility, the gentry, and...
How quaint.
Even the rabble.
I must say
I really felt quite distressed
at not receiving an invitation.
You're not welcome here.
Oh, dear.
What an awkward situation.
You're not offended?
Why, no.
And to show I bear no ill will,
I, too, shall bestow a gift on the child.
No! We don't want your gift!
Stay away from the princess!
Yes, stay away!
Listen well, all of you.
The princess shall indeed
grow in grace and beauty,
beloved by all who meet her.
That's a lovely gift.
Don't do this.
But
before the sun sets
on her 16th birthday,
she will prick her finger
on the spindle of a spinning wheel
and fall into a sleep like death,
a sleep from which
she will never awaken.
Maleficent, please don't do this,
I'm begging you.
I like you begging.
Do it again.
I beg you.
All right.
The princess can be woken
from her death sleep,
but only by
true love's kiss.
This curse will last till the end of time!
No power on Earth can change it.
King Stefan ordered his men
to seize every spinning wheel
in the kingdom.
The wheels were broken and burned,
that they might never be used,
and thrown into the deepest dungeon
in the castle.
Secretly, he entrusted
the safety of the child
to the magic of the pixies,
who would take her to a remote
hideaway for 16 years and a day.
Stefan shut himself behind
the walls of his castle
while his soldiers rode far and wide
to hunt Maleficent down.
But she made walls of her own,
that the Moors might
never again suffer the touch
of any human.
And she reveled in the sorrow
that her curse had brought.
The fairies began their charge
to raise Aurora in a snug little cottage
in the woods.
No! Is this it?
Looks dreadful.
Come on.
We need a smaller...
Baby-
Or bigger bodies.
No, what we need is a proper disguise.
What do you mean?
Well, we have to blend in, don't we?
We have to be big enough
to look after this baby.
So, gather around, ladies.
Get ready. One, two, three, grow!
That's worked quite well.
That's very nice.
Now, there will be no questions asked.
We are no longer fairies.
We are three peasant women
raising our orphan child in the woods.
- Yes.
- So, no more flying.
- No flying?
- No, no, and no magic.
- No magic?
- Yes, you heard.
It's in the middle of nowhere.
At least no one will find us here.
There you are.
Why are you always hiding?
Come on. There you go.
It's so ugly, you could
almost feel sorry for it.
I hate you. Beasty.
The fairies were
perhaps unequal to their task.
Why is she crying?
I think she might be hungry.
Then feed her!
There you are.
There you go.
It's going to starve
with those three looking after it.
It tickles.
- What?
- You're cheating.
I saw that!
- We're starting again.
- Suit yourself.
Greedy, bloated goat!
"Bloated goat."
Stop doing that.
I'm not doing anything.
Well, someone is.
It's not me.
You two are having a go at me,
and I will not tolerate...
Stop it!
Why...
No!
This is all your fault!
Come on. That's funny.
As the days went on, Stefan darkened,
further consumed
by paranoia and vengeance.
- Burn it all down!
- Yes, sir!
Flame!
Release!
Run!
You failed me.
The wall cannot be burned.
It is indestructible.
Nothing is indestructible!
Not the wall! Not Maleficent!
Not even her curse!
Bring me the iron workers.
You!
Look.
The little beast is about
to fall off the cliff.
What?
Hello.
Go away.
Go.
I don't like children.
Up, UP-
Go along. Go, go, go.
As Maleficent had said,
Aurora did grow in grace and beauty.
Pretty bird.
Far away from the lofty palace
that she remembered not.
And as the seasons changed
and the flowers grew,
so did she.
Hello.
That's it.
There you go.
She wondered at the world about her,
and at what lay beyond
the fearsome wall of thorns.
Curious little beasty.
But she was not the only one
who wished to get through.
Look.
- Is that her? Is that Maleficent?
- I don't know.
Bring them to me.
No, it's just a silly peasant girl.
Steady.
- It's her!
How could you do that to me?
You said anything I need.
Yeah, but not a dog.
It was a wolf, not a dog.
It's the same thing.
They're dirty, vicious,
and they hunt birds.
Fine. Next time I'll turn you
into a mealy worm.
Well, I'll be a mealy worm, gladly.
Anything but a filthy, stinking...
I wonder.
I know you're there.
Don't be afraid.
I am not afraid.
Then come out.
Then you'll be afraid.
No, I won't.
I know who you are.
Do you?
You're my Fairy Godmother.
What?
Fairy Godmother.
You've been watching over me
my whole life.
I've always known you were close by.
How?
Your shadow. It's been following me
ever since I was small.
Wherever I went,
your shadow was always with me.
I remember you.
Pretty bird.
This is Diaval.
Hello, Aurora.
I have known you
since you were a little one.
It's everything I imagined it would be.
It's just so beautiful!
I've always wanted to come...
Good night, beasty.
You mock me.
I know what you're doing.
I know exactly what you're doing.
Sire?
Your presence has been
requested by the Queen.
Leave me.
Sire, she is not well.
The nurses are fearful
that she won't make it through the night.
Can you not see
we're having a conversation?
When the curse fails,
Maleficent will come for me.
And on that day, I will be ready.
They're so beautiful.
I revoke the curse.
Let it be no more.
I revoke my curse!
Let it be no more!
This curse will last till the end of time.
No power on Earth can change it.
Do all the Fair People have wings?
Most do.
Then why don't you?
All the other fairies fly.
I had wings once.
They were stolen from me.
That's all I wish to say about it.
What color were they?
Were they big?
So big
they dragged behind me when I walked.
And they were strong.
They could carry me above the clouds
and into the headwinds.
And they never faltered, not even once.
I could trust them.
She's coming. She's coming.
Where are your workers?
In their beds, Majesty.
Get them back to work without delay.
They're exhausted, sire.
But I'll have them
back to work at first light.
I need them back to work now.
It's the wee hours.
Aye.
It is the wee hours.
So wake them up.
Sire?
So wake them up,
and get them back to work now!
We're running out of time! Go, now!
Aurora?
Come here.
Sit.
There's something I need to tell you.
What is it?
There is an evil in this world,
and I cannot keep you from it.
I'm almost 16, Godmother.
I can take care of myself.
I understand.
- But that's not what I have to tell you.
- I have a plan.
When I'm older,
I'm going to live here
in the Moors with you.
Then we can look after each other.
You don't have to wait until you're older.
You could live here now.
Then I Will.
I'll sleep in a tree
and eat berries and black nuts
and all the Fair People
will be my friends.
I'll be happy here for the rest of my life.
I'm going to tell my aunties tomorrow.
Until tomorrow.
I'm so excited!
Aunties, I'm almost 16.
I need a life of my own.
No. I love you very much,
but it's time to say goodbye.
You've been very good to me,
except the time
you accidentally fed me spiders.
Hello.
I'm sorry to bother you,
but I'm on my way
to King Stefan's castle
and I've become hopelessly lost.
Can you help me?
I'm sorry. That was my fault.
I rushed in too...
Forgive me.
It's that way.
The castle.
What's your name?
It's Philip.
Hello, Philip.
What's yours?
Aurora.
Hello, Aurora.
Well, it was nice meeting you.
And once again, my apologies
for being such a clumsy fool.
You're forgiven.
That's good.
I'd best be off, then.
Good bye.
Will you be back this way?
Nothing could stop me.
Then I'll see you soon.
Very soon.
- Goodbye, Philip.
- Goodbye, for now.
Stop doing that.
Well?
That boy's the answer.
- No, Diaval.
- Yes!
True love's kiss, remember?
It can break the spell.
True love's kiss?
Have you not worked it out yet?
I cursed her that way
because there is no such thing.
Well, that might be how you feel,
but what about Aurora?
That boy could be her only chance.
It's her fate, anyway.
Go ahead.
Turn me into whatever you want.
A bird, a worm.
I don't care anymore.
I'm so happy we're leaving tomorrow.
We are not leaving tomorrow.
Tomorrow is Aurora's 16th birthday.
And Stefan told us to take her back
the day after her birthday.
No. He said on her birthday.
No. The day after her birthday.
- On.
- After.
- On, on, on!
- After, after, after!
Stop it!
What?
How could you?
I need to talk to you about something.
Yes, sweetie, what is it?
I'm sorry to have to tell you this,
but I'll be 16 tomorrow.
Yes.
I'm leaving home.
See here, young lady.
I did not spend 16 years
in this miserable hovel
with these two imbeciles...
So that you could ruin it on the last day.
We are taking you back
to your father with...
My father?
You told me my parents were dead.
I think you better come and sit down.
Fairy Godmother!
I'm here.
When were you going to tell me
that I'm cursed?
Is it true?
It is.
My aunts said it was an evil fairy.
I... I can't remember her name.
They said
it was...
Maleficent.
Is that you?
Are you Maleficent?
No!
Don't touch me.
You're the evil that's in the world.
It's you!
Find the boy!
I need every available man
on the east wing now.
There should be no guards at the gate.
I want her to walk right in.
Sorry to disturb, Your Majesty.
We found this urchin at the gate.
She claims to be the princess.
Father.
It's me, Aurora!
You look just like your mother.
They brought you back a day too soon.
I told those three idiots!
Lock her up in her room.
Go.
Prepare the men. Maleficent's coming.
It's so good to be small again!
Look at my feet!
I love my tiny little feet!
Pay attention! We have to find Aurora,
or the king will have our heads!
Aurora.
Wait!
Princess?
I'm looking for a girl.
Of course you are.
I need a horse.
...into a sleep like death.
Aurora.
Come on, Diaval!
Faster, Diaval, faster!
She will prick her finger
on the spindle of a spinning wheel
and fall into a sleep like death.
No power on Earth...
A sleep like death.
It's done.
They pulled the guards.
He's waiting for you in there.
If we go inside those walls,
we'll never come out alive.
Then don't come. It's not your fight.
Thank you very much.
"I need you, Diaval.
I can't do this without you, Diaval."
I can hear you.
Look at her.
Look at what you've done.
She's only sleeping.
She's only sleeping, you say?
She's only sleeping forever!
- What about the kiss?
- Yes! True love's kiss!
True love does not exist.
But it's her only chance, Your Majesty.
Mistress.
What are we going to do?
We can't give up, can we?
Come on, girls.
But we don't even know where to start.
True love doesn't just fall
from trees, you know.
Pardon me.
I'm embarrassed to say
I don't know where I am.
In King Stefan's castle.
This is where I'm meant to be.
Odd that I can't recall how I got here.
Why have you come?
My father sent me to see the King.
Who is your father?
King John of Ulstead.
A Prince!
Aurora.
He knows her.
Why is she sleeping?
She's trapped in an enchantment.
Isn't she beautiful?
The most beautiful girl I've ever seen.
Do you want to kiss her?
Very much.
Go on, then.
I wouldn't feel right about it.
I barely know her. We've only met once.
Haven't you ever heard
of love at first sight?
Kiss her!
Go on.
An enchantment, you say?
Kiss her!
You didn't do it properly!
It's supposed to be true love's kiss!
I was certain he was the one.
- What are you doing?
- We have to keep looking.
I told you.
I will not ask your forgiveness
because what I have done to you
is unforgivable.
I was so lost
in hatred and revenge.
Sweet Aurora,
you stole what was left of my heart.
And now I have lost you forever.
I swear, no harm will come to you
as long as I live.
And not a day shall pass
that I don't miss your smile.
Hello, Godmother.
Hello, beasty.
No truer love.
She's here, sire.
Are we going back to the Moors now?
If that is what you wish.
We've got her!
- Stop!
- Get back!
No!
Into a dragon.
To the other side.
Run, Aurora!
Get back! Hold it steady!
Pull to the left! Pull!
Hold the line!
Look out. Hold your line.
- Close in.
- Bring it down!
Enough!
How does it feel?
To be a fairy creature without wings
in a world where you don't belong?
Kill her!
Shoot!
Shoot her!
Take aim!
It's over.
Maleficent brought down
her wall of thorns
and took off her crown.
And she invited Aurora to see
how the Moors had been once,
long ago, when Maleficent
was but a child
and her heart was bright.
For now, it was again.
But that was not all.
There she is. Hurry up. They're waiting.
Wait for me!
We present this crown
to our little Aurora,
for whom we have sacrificed
the best years of our...
Never mind.
Our kingdoms have been unified.
You have your queen.
So you see,
the story is not quite as you were told,
and I should know,
for I was the one
they called Sleeping Beauty.
In the end, my kingdom was united
not by a hero or a villain,
as legend had predicted,
but by one who was
both hero and villain.
And her name was Maleficent.