Calling Cape Com. Cape Com?
This is Jupiter 16.
Can you give a go for fourth orbit?
Cape Com to Jupiter 16.
Can you confirm 02 pressure
is within limit?
Roger. It all looks good
in the environmental control system.
OK. Everything looks good from here.
You have a go for fourth orbit.
Jupiter 16. Roger.
You're stowing all loose gear.
Ready for the EVA.
Jupiter 16, this is Cape Com.
Start your EVA when you're ready.
You have time in the other EVAs
for experiments.
So don't stay out too long, Chris.
OK, flight.
- Don't worry. We'll stick to plan.
- Roger.
Cape Com to Jupiter 16. On my mark
it will be fourplus three seven.
Four, three, two
one, mark.
Cape Com, this is Chris.
I'm out.
Everything looks OK.
Good.
The manoeuvring unit works this time.
I used it to get out.
It makes things a lot easier.
Cape Com to Hawaii,
this is flight control, come in.
Hawaii, roger.
Hawaii, we expect to start EVA
over your station on this pass.
Hawaii to Jupiter 16.
An unidentified object is closing on you
fast from astern.
Can you see it?
Hawaii, we have nothing here.
Hold while we check the space track.
Hawaii to Jupiter 16.
Repeat, Hawaii to Jupiter 16.
An unidentified object is on our scope.
We see nothing.
Can you give me a bearing?
Appears to be coming up fast,
from astern.
Hey, now I see it.
It's another spacecraft!
Repeat, it's another spacecraft!
Does it looks like a close pass?
You're breaking up. Say again.
- Does it look like a close pass?
- Chris, what's happening?
It's coming right at us.
The front is opening up!
I repeat, the front is opening up!
- It's coming right at us.
- Chris, get back in, get back in!
Do you read me? You're breaking up.
- Repeat, you're breaking up.
- What's happening?
Hawaii to Jupiter 16.
Hawaii to Jupiter 16. Are you receiving?
You're breaking up. Come in, please.
Jupiter 16!
You're breaking up...
My lead line! It's cu...
Hawaii to Jupiter 16, Hawaii to Jupiter 16.
Are you receiving me?
Come in, please. Over.
Hello, Houston.
We've lost radio contact.
We've also lost him on the scope.
Unidentified object is still orbiting.
Alert all stations and track him closely.
It is ridiculous for the Soviet government
to deny responsibility.
The Soviet government denies
all knowledge of this affair.
The world knows
we are a peace-loving people.
I hereby give notice that in 20 days
the United States
will launch her next spaceship.
My government has instructed me
to inform you
that any interference with it
will be regarded as an act of war.
May I ask what motive
our Russian friends would have
for wishing to destroy
American spacecraft?
My government sees this
as a blatant attempt
to gain complete and absolute control
of space itself for military purposes.
We don't agree.
Her Majesty's Government
is not convinced
that this intruder missile
originated from Soviet Russia.
Our tracking station in Singapore
reported faint echoes of this craft
coming down in the Sea of Japan area.
Might I suggest
that this is where you should
concentrate your intelligence forces?
The prime minister asked me to assure
you this is what we propose to do.
As a matter of fact, our man in Hong Kong
is working on it now.
Why do Chinese girls taste different
from all other girls?
You think we better?
No, just different.
Like Peking duck is different from
Russian caviar, but I love 'em both.
Darling, I give you very best duck.
That would be lovely.
We've had some interesting times
together, Ling. I'll be sorry to go.
Take that door.
The bed!
- We're too late.
- At least he died on the job.
He'd have wanted it this way.
We shall not all sleep,
but we shall all be changed
in a moment,
in the twinkling of an eye,
at the last trump.
For the trumpet shall sound and
the dead shall be raised incorruptible,
and we shall all be changed.
We therefore commit his body to the deep
to be turned into corruption,
Iooking for the resurrection of the body
when the sea shall give up her dead.
Present!
Fire!
- Carry on.
- Aye aye, sir.
Permission to come aboard?
- Permission granted.
- Thank you.
- Take this officer aft.
- Yes, sir.
Number One, take her up to 90ft.
Course zero four five.
Aye aye, sir.
- Hello, Penny.
- You'd better go right in.
You're late as usual,
even from your own funeral.
We corpses have no sense of timing.
In you go... sir.
Thank you... ma'am.
- Sit down, 007.
- Thank you, sir.
- No ill effects?
- None at all, sir.
Now you're dead, perhaps some of your
old friends will pay less attention to you.
Give you more elbow room.
You'll need it, too.
This is the big one, 007. That's why
I'm out here. You're fully briefed?
Yes, but there's one thing
I don't understand.
If our Singapore tracking
station is correct
about the rocket not landing
in Russia, where did it land?
We assume it's Japan.
All this is guesswork,
but the PM wants us to play it
with everything we've got.
- And the aerial reconnaissance?
- All photographed. Nothing.
Are the Japanese equipped
to launch such a rocket?
- We don't think so.
- Then who else is?
That's what you've got to
find out, and fast.
Before the real shooting starts.
This damn thing could blow up
into a full-scale war.
When you get to Tokyo,
go to that name and address.
Our man Henderson
will contact you there.
- Henderson.
- Captain here. Full ahead.
Right.
- That's all.
- Thank you, sir.
- 007.
- Sir?
We've only three weeks
to the next American launch.
- You know that?
- Yes, sir.
My sources tell me the Russians
are planning one even earlier.
- So move fast, 007.
- Yes, sir.
By the way, how was the girl?
Which girl?
The Chinese one we fixed you up with.
Another five minutes, I'd have found out.
She'll never know what she missed.
Miss Moneypenny,
give 007 the password we've agreed
- with Japanese SIS.
- Yes, sir.
We tried to think of something
you wouldn't forget.
Yes?
I... Iove... you.
Repeat it, please,
to make sure you get it.
Don't worry, I get it.
Sayonara.
James... good luck.
Instant Japanese. You may need it.
You forget, I took a first
in oriental languages at Cambridge.
Stand by to load.
Lift to the launch!
Tube loaded.
Hubcap open.
Fire.
This is your ticket.
Thank you.
Dozo.
I love you.
I have a car nearby.
- Where do you suggest we go?
- I know a quiet hotel.
- And?
- Where your friend is waiting.
Mr Henderson.
Wasn't Mr Henderson
able to come himself?
- I suppose not.
- Why?
He didn't say.
I think it's about hotel-time.
How long have you
worked for Henderson?
Long enough to learn not to discuss
such matters with strangers.
- Mr Henderson's waiting for you.
- You're not coming in with me?
Mr Henderson would like
to see you alone.
Do come in.
Mr Henderson?
At your service.
I believe you wanted to
ask me some questions.
Yes. Excuse me.
- Thank you.
- I'm glad you got it right.
I lost that in Singapore in '42.
You must excuse
this rather odd mixture of styles,
but I refuse to go entirely Japanese.
Very fond of some of these old things.
- You've never been to Japan before?
- No, never.
I myself have lived here for...
28 years.
And I'm just beginning
to know my way about.
- Your most vital contact will be Tanaka.
- Tanaka?
He's head of the Japanese secret service.
And his identity is the most
closely guarded secret in Japan.
When can I see him?
- You can see Tiger tonight.
- Tiger?
His closest friends
are permitted to call him that.
- Do you have any leads of your own?
- Yes, I do.
That's stirred not shaken.
That was right?
Perfect.
Cheers.
Russian vodka. Well done.
Yes, I get it from the doorman
at the Russian embassy.
Amongst certain other things.
Now, look. I think London's theory
about the missile being fired
from this country is right.
I don't know how or where.
And don't ask me who's doing it either.
But I have a fairly shrewd idea
that a major foreign power is behind it all.
You mean, apart from Russia and Japan?
It's not Russia, old boy, I'm sure of that.
It's not Japan either.
Although a large Japanese
industrial concern is...
Good evening.
Cheers.
Siamese vodka?
There he is!
Freeze!
Get in, quick!
What the hell's the score?
What do you mean?
My job is to help you.
Like you helped Henderson?
I'm taking you to a place of safety.
No, this time I'm taking you.
I want some information now.
- I have no information to give you.
- We'll see about that. Slow down.
Welcome.
Welcome to Japan, Mr Bond.
It is a great pleasure to meet you at last.
And how do you like our country so far?
I am a trifle disappointed at the ease
with which I could pull you in.
The one thing my honourable mother
taught me long ago
was never to get into a car
with a strange girl.
But you, I'm afraid,
will get into anything with any girl!
You have a lot of energy
for a dead man, Mr Bond.
You are James Bond, aren't you?
I am so very pleased to meet you,
Bond-san. I really am.
Permit me to introduce myself.
My name is Tanaka. Please call me Tiger.
If you're Tanaka,
how do you feel about me?
I... Iove you.
I'm glad we got that out of the way.
I'd like you to examine these
as soon as possible.
They're from Osato's safe.
This is an order for naval stores.
500 kilos of butter, 50 containers of lox.
What is lox?
An American name for smoked salmon.
But it's also the technical name
for liquid oxygen.
Which makes rocket fuel.
- Very interesting.
- Yes.
We must go.
The journey out will be more dignified
than the journey in.
That wouldn't be difficult.
I'd like that negative enlarged.
OK.
My private train.
I never travel in the streets of Tokyo.
In my position, it would be most unwise.
Very convenient.
I imagine that your Mr M in London
has a similar arrangement.
M? Oh yes, but of course.
Then the girl in the white
sports car's one of us.
- Aki? Yes.
- Very competent.
- Domo arigato.
- Dozo.
Do you like Japanese sake,
or would you prefer vodka martini?
Oh, no. I like sake.
Especially when it's served
at the correct temperature.
98.4° Fahrenheit, like this is.
For a European,
you are exceptionally cultivated.
- We'll see the photograph you found.
- Good.
A ship and a strip of land.
It could be anywhere.
My men found a microdot on the paper.
Enlarge!
It says, 'Photograph taken by female
American tourist from coastal vessel.'
'The woman has been liquidated
as a routine precaution.'
- Can we see the photograph again?
- Of course.
They killed an innocent tourist
for taking this?
Can you make it bigger?
Ning-Po.
Check motor vessel Ning-Po. Full details.
All recent movements
and present whereabouts.
- What's that on the left?
- Focus on the left!
Ama. Diving girls.
Can you identify that coastline?
Given time, yes.
- Who is the head of Osato Chemicals?
- Mr Osato.
Can you arrange an appointment
with him tomorrow?
Of course.
But tonight, consider my house yours.
Including all of my possessions,
naturally.
My friend, now you take
your first civilised bath.
Really? Well, I like the plumbing.
Place yourself entirely in their hands,
my dear Bond-san.
Rule number one...
is never do anything for yourself
when someone else can do it for you.
- And number two?
- Rule number two:
in Japan, men always come first.
Women come second.
I might just retire to here.
Your English girls would never perform
this simple service.
I know one or two
who might get round to it.
Miss Moneypenny, perhaps?
We have our sources,
Bond-san, just like you.
Don't get the soap in my eye, will you?
I suppose you know what it is about you
that fascinates them.
It's the hair on your chest.
Japanese men have beautiful bare skin.
Japanese proverb say,
'Bird never make nest in bare tree.'
If Henderson's theory is right,
why would a foreign power
want to launch missiles from Japan?
Because if they were discovered,
they could deny responsibility.
Especially if some private organisation's
doing the work.
- Osato?
- Perhaps.
Mr Osato is one of
our greatest industrialists.
No, he's merely a front.
- Who is big enough?
- SPECTRE.
Could be.
Now, massage. Which girl do you select?
I'll settle for this little old lady here.
Good choice.
She's very sexyful.
The last time someone gave me
a massage was in Hong Kong.
But unfortunately...
we had to cut it short.
We were rudely interrupted
by a couple of gunmen.
So, we never got around to finishing it.
This time, you shall finish it.
Aki.
No one will disturb you tonight.
I think I will enjoy very much
serving under you.
- Mr Fisher?
- Yes.
- This way, please.
- Thank you.
Please come in, Mr Fisher.
- Mr Osato is expecting you.
- Thank you.
You are three and a half minutes early.
Please be seated.
- How do you do, Mr Fisher?
- How do you do?
Miss Grant, my confidential secretary.
- Hello.
- May we offer you some champagne?
- No, thank you, it's too early for me.
- You're quite sure?
- Quite sure.
I always take a glass in the morning.
- You should try it.
- It's bad for your liver.
- Nonsense, it adds a sparkle to the day.
- I'm sure it does.
A Dom Pérignon '59, Mr Fisher.
- Sure you won't change your mind?
- Well, if you insist.
- Please be seated, Mr Fisher.
- Thank you.
So, you are the new managing director
- of Empire Chemicals?
- Yes.
- What happened to Williamson?
- Williamson?
He died rather suddenly, poor chap.
Ah, so. From what?
He fell into a pulveriser at the works.
Ah, so.
How shocking.
- A very honourable death, all the same.
- Very.
He gained great face with the company.
I hope you are not taking
any risks yourself, Mr Fisher.
Me? I never take any risks.
You forgive me for saying so, but...
I think you are taking one now.
I am?
You should give up smoking.
Cigarettes are very bad for your chest.
Mr Osato believes in a healthy chest.
Really?
You must tell me what I can do for you.
We're interested in the bulk-buying
of fermentation chemicals.
Monosodium glutamate
and ascorbic acid.
- Would you like a manufacturing licence?
- Yes, very much.
I'll have my sales manager
get the quotations
and delivery dates for you
as soon as possible.
We'll contact you later today
at your hotel.
- Which hotel are you staying at?
- The Hilton.
Goodbye, Mr Fisher.
- A pleasure to meet you.
- A pleasure to meet you, too.
- Goodbye, Miss Brandt.
- Goodbye, Mr Fisher.
Kill him.
Get down!
294 here. Tiger, immediate.
Come in, 294.
Zero-zero is with me. We are being
chased by gunmen, in black sedan.
I'm heading south for Highway Two.
Arrange usual reception, please.
- How's that for Japanese efficiency?
- Just a drop in the ocean.
- Zero-zero?
- Yes, Tiger.
Ning-Po is owned by Osato Chemicals.
- That fits. Go on.
- Vessel now loading in Kobe docks.
Sailing for Shanghai
at 5pm this afternoon.
Suggest you proceed Kobe immediately
to look her over.
- Can we make it?
- Yes, just.
Proceeding immediately, Kobe docks.
Tiger, contact M.
Tell him to send Little Nellie.
Repeat, Little Nellie.
Suggest she be accompanied
by her father.
Most urgent. Understood?
Understood.
Condensation: ice-cold. Liquid oxygen.
Get out of here. Contact Tanaka.
I'm not leaving you.
Tell him to keep that ship shadowed.
Go now.
Take him to Number 11.
- Wake him up.
- Are you finished?
Where am l?
You're in my cabin on the Ning-Po.
Leave him to me now. Wait in there.
And shut the door.
I've got you now.
Enjoy yourself.
- Who are you working for?
- Empire Chemicals, you know that.
- Do all their people carry guns?
- When they're abroad, yes.
And why were you
snooping around the docks?
I like ships. And I used to be a sailor.
You are a liar.
- Do you know what this is?
- I'd rather not.
Plastic surgeons call it a dermatome.
They use it to slice off skin.
I hope you won't force me to use it.
Now, what's a nice girl like you
doing in a place like this?
I have a confession to make.
What?
Actually, I'm a spy.
I know that.
I suppose you know that
industrial secrets are big business?
I've stolen Osato's new process
for making monosodium glutamate.
And...
Well, it's worth
$300,000.
So?
I'll split it with you if you'll get me
out of here and back to Tokyo.
That's a nice offer.
- How about it?
- I'm afraid not.
Why?
Osato would kill me.
We could fly to Europe tomorrow,
you and l.
The things I do for England.
Now, you are going to need some
very close... protection tonight in Tokyo
because... well, that's when
they'll try and get at you.
You'll need the best man we've got.
And who do you suggest?
Well,
me.
I'm afraid I have another appointment
tonight, Mr Fisher.
I'm awfully sorry to leave you...
but I have to get off.
Chasing girls will be the end of you,
Bond-san, I have told you before.
He didn't chase her.
He did it so I could get away.
He wouldn't touch that horrible girl.
- Would you?
- Heaven forbid.
Any progress?
Yes. We identified
the coastline in the photograph.
It is an island called Matsu, on the direct
route between Kobe and Shanghai.
We shadowed the Ning-Po in a helicopter.
- Did it stop at the island?
- I think so.
It was a very dark night.
Impossible to see her all the time.
But we know she stopped somewhere.
Look at these.
That one we took last night.
And that one, early this morning.
- Notice, please, the water line.
- You're right.
Fully laden here and empty here.
I want to take a fast look
at the island now.
- Has Little Nellie arrived yet?
- Yes, and her father.
Ah, welcome to Japan, Dad.
Is my little girl hot and ready?
Look, 007, I've had a long and tiring
journey, probably to no purpose.
I'm in no mood for your juvenile quips.
I have much curiosity, Bond-san.
What is Little Nellie?
She's a wonderful girl.
Very small, quite fast.
Can do anything. Just your type.
A toy helicopter?
No, it's certainly not a toy! You'll see.
We've made some improvements
since you used her last.
- I'll give you the drill.
- This is only for children. Don't use it!
Take my helicopter instead.
Right. Now pay attention.
- Two machine guns, fixed.
- Synchronised to what?
100 yards, using incendiaries
and high explosives.
Two rocket launchers,
- forward-firing on either side.
- Fine.
Now, these fire heat-seeking
air-to-air missiles. 60 a minute.
Good.
Flame guns. Two of 'em. Firing astern.
- What range?
- 80 yards. Two smoke ejectors next door.
Aerial mines. Now remember,
use them only
when directly above target.
- That's about the lot. You know the rest.
- Yes.
Cine camera.
- Tanaka, listen in on 410 megacycles.
- Good luck!
I'll contact you when I get over the island.
Be careful, Bond-san!
Hello, Base One.
I'm over the island and the fishing village.
Nothing to report.
We'll keep listening.
Hello, Base One.
There's nothing here but volcanoes.
Understood. Carry on.
- Hello, Base One.
- Listening.
Little Nellie got a hot reception.
Four big-shots made
improper advances,
but she defended her honour
with great success.
- Heading for home.
- Do not come home.
Russian space shot imminent.
Proceed vector4-6 degrees
and await instructions.
- Understood?
- Roger and out.
Clear the area. Clear the area.
Prepare for reception.
Radar blackout is now complete.
Moscow radio's already saying we did it.
The president's called
a press conference for 2pm.
He'll deny emphatically we were involved.
- But can we prove it?
- Of course not.
No one will believe the Russians did it.
Now they'll use the excuse
to shoot down our next Jupiter.
Houston to Washington. We followed him
for one orbit, now he's offthe screen.
That means he's coming down.
- Yeah, but where?
- Some place in Russia. It has to be.
The British theory about Japan
is nonsense.
- Forget Japan.
- I agree.
We've re-photographed
every square inch.
Ventilator fans to full power.
Open all air ducts.
Area safe to enter.
All crews to stations.
All air ducts to normal.
Air ducts opened.
- Close crater.
- Closing crater.
Fire guards to station.
Ventilator fans to normal. Open shutters.
Reception complete.
Withdraw captive spaceship.
Guards to stations.
Remove the prisoners.
I shall be in my apartment.
I may send for you later.
I must congratulate you, gentlemen,
upon your superb equipment.
We congratulate you, sir,
upon the way you handle it.
Our clients are satisfied
with the progress so far?
- My government is quite satisfied.
- Good.
Hans!
You will see that my piranha fish
get very hungry.
They can strip a man to the bone
in 30 seconds.
I have decided to ask for
a little money in advance.
I want the sum of 100 million dollars,
in gold bullion,
deposited in our account in Buenos Aires.
Our agreement states
no money should be paid
until war has broken out
between Russia and the United States.
- This is extortion.
- Extortion is my business.
Go and think it over, gentlemen. I'm busy.
Osato and Number 11, report now.
An unknown Englishman
was in your office the other day.
Correct, Number One.
- Do you know what gun this is?
- Walther PPK.
Only one person we know
uses this sort of gun.
James Bond.
- But Bond is dead.
- It was in all the newspapers.
Rubbish.
Bond is alive.
Unless you killed him, Mr Osato?
Don't tell me you let him go.
I gave Number 11
the strictest orders to eliminate him.
And did she?
She failed.
You should have killed him.
You had plenty of opportunity.
This organisation
does not tolerate failure.
- I know, but you see, l...
- Go!
Well?
Osato!
Kill Bond! Now!
Yes, Number One. Yes. Yes, yes.
- Hello.
- Bad news from outer space.
Yes, I heard it. Now the Russians
are accusing the Americans.
Next time it will be war.
- We'll have to get down to the volcanoes.
- I agree.
We'll also need
a company of first-rate men.
Do you have any commandos here?
I have much, much better.
Ninjas. Top-secret, Bond-san.
This is my ninja training school.
- Ninjas?
- The art of concealment and surprise.
This must develop
very fast reflex actions.
And spiritual strength.
Now, we will see some modern ninjas.
My plan is this.
I make a base on the Ama island.
100 of my ninjas will slide in unseen.
They will be workers and fishermen.
- What about me?
- Later.
But for the moment,
these will interest you. Rocket guns.
Very powerful.
See the holes in the back
for jet propulsion.
- It's a fine gun.
- All rocket guns.
This is our special baby rocket.
Very useful for people who smoke
too many cigarettes, like you.
- Accurate up to 30 yards.
- Very neat.
- It can save your life.
- You sound like a commercial.
- What's the plan for me?
- First, you become a Japanese.
Second, you train hard and quickly
to become a ninja like us.
And third, to give you extra-special cover,
you take a wife.
Regretfully impossible.
You must marry Ama girl.
One who is known on the island.
- Is she pretty?
- She has a face like a pig.
- To hell with that idea.
- But this is duty.
The girl I have chosen
is an agent of mine.
But first, you must become Japanese.
Eyepieces to Hera.
Why don't you just
dye the parts that show?
- Konbanwa.
Tiger said, from now on,
you must do everything Japanese-style.
Everything?
Good for Tiger.
I'm...
I... I...
Aki!
I'm...
She's dead.
Poisoned.
Tiger, we must get to that island.
You're almost ready.
Just two more days' training.
- You killed him.
- Yeah, he tried to kill me.
This man is a stranger from outside.
It's lucky we're getting out of here.
Tomorrow you will be a poor Japanese
worker, with humble Japanese wife.
Yeah, with a face like a pig.
My men are already ashore.
All over the island.
We have four days left.
It is not much time.
This is my house.
My friend has made us some food.
Do you live here alone?
Yes. My parents are dead.
Sit down, please.
Oysters.
Is this the only room there is?
Yes.
That is your bed.
I shall sleep over there.
- We're supposed to be married.
- Think again, please.
You gave false name to priest.
But we must keep up appearances!
We're on our honeymoon.
No honeymoon. This is business.
I won't need these.
- Bond-san.
- What's wrong?
The Americans have changed
the launching date.
The countdown has already started.
The president has given
a last warning to the Russians.
- When does it go up?
- Tonight, midnight. Our time.
- Did your men search the island?
- Yes. There is nothing but volcanoes.
Everything is so normal around here.
- Nothing happens.
- One thing has happened.
Yesterday an Ama girl
rowed her boat into Ryuzaki.
- Ryuzaki?
- It is a big cave on the mainland.
And when her boat floated out again,
she was dead.
- Was that the funeral we saw yesterday?
- Yes.
- How did she die?
- Nobody knows.
- Can you take me to this cave?
- Yes.
We'll slip away from the fishing fleet
in the morning.
All right?
Now, where is this cave?
It's straight across.
The cave is over there.
Gas. Get over the side.
Quick!
Phosgene gas, to keep the visitors away.
Did you notice the sulphur on the walls?
- The yellow?
- Yes.
It was once an underground outlet
for the volcanic lava.
- There must be a long tunnel.
- Miles of it.
It leads all the way,
right up to the top.
That's where we have to go.
Can you make it?
Of course. It's business.
Good.
May I rest a moment?
Surely.
It's hard work.
Some honeymoon!
It's going down! lnto the volcano!
Heliport to position.
The honeymoon's over. Come on.
This volcano isn't active, is it?
It never has been. Not in my lifetime.
There's been some
terrific heat here recently.
What happened to the helicopter?
It's down there somewhere.
Come on.
Stand by. Mark.
Stand by for ten-second countdown.
10, 9, 8...
All units worldwide
will remain at readiness
so long as the spacecraft is in orbit.
..3, 2, 1.
Ignition.
This is it, gentlemen.
All we can do now is wait and pray.
Is that deep?
They usually are - very.
It's metal!
Wait here.
Heliport to takeoffposition.
Open crater.
Emergency crews to stations.
Go to Tanaka.
Tell him to come with every man he's got.
Yes.
Heliport to standbyposition.
Astronauts to dressing rooms.
Attention, attention.
American target vehicle is now in orbit.
Interception will take place
in two hours' time.
Washington, this is Houston.
Houston to Washington.
Our vehicle is now
120 nautical miles altitude,
170 miles downrange.
Jupiter to Houston,
we now have second phase.
Roger, Jupiter.
Four hours 36 minutes into the mission.
- Can you give us a time?
- Roger.
Connect igniter cable.
Radar technicians, report to control room.
T minus 100 minutes and counting.
Did you volunteer for astronaut training?
In our country, we say cosmonaut.
Yes, both of us...
Yes, since six months we started training.
Good evening.
Who the hell are you?
Stand back, I'm gonna blow the lock.
Stand back.
Get into their uniforms.
Astronauts have two minutes.
Repeat, two minutes.
Reserve astronaut to stand by.
- Lock on target.
- Lock on target vehicle.
Check secondary guidance.
Launch time is now
T minus 90 minutes and counting.
Astronauts to launching pad.
Repeat, astronauts
to launching pad immediately.
Crews, stand by on gantry.
- Stop that astronaut. Bring him to me.
- Stop that astronaut!
- Summon the reserve astronaut!
- Reserve astronaut!
Reserve astronaut
to launching pad, immediately.
Re-coordinate with target vehicle.
A new update
with target vehicle
has been received from computers.
We now have T minus seven minutes
and counting.
You made a mistake, my friend.
No astronaut enters the capsule
with his air conditioner.
Remove his helmet!
James Bond.
Allow me to introduce myself.
I am Ernst Stavro Blofeld.
They told me
you were assassinated in Hong Kong.
Yes, this is my second life.
You only live twice, Mr Bond.
Target vehicle
passing over central Russia.
Approaching Mongolia.
Track is as predicted. All computers...
As you see,
I am about to inaugurate a little war.
In a matter of hours, when America
and Russia have annihilated each other,
we shall see a new power
dominating the world.
- Target vehicle on scope.
- Brief check on target vehicle.
Remove his suit and search him.
Reserve astronaut ready on Bird 1.
Prepare for firing.
Clear the area.
Emergency services to stand by.
Area now clear.
T minus one minute,
30 seconds and counting.
Re-coordinate with target vehicle.
Bird 1 now in readiness.
Astronauts ready on Bird.
All systems are go.
Close shutters.
- Radar blackout commence.
- Radar blackout in operation.
Effective range, kilometres 800.
- Open crater.
- Opening crater.
Crater opening.
Bird 1 to liftoffposition.
Gimbal the engines.
Pressurised tanks open.
Ventilator fans to full power.
10 seconds.
9, 8,
7, 6,
5, 4,
3, 2,
1, 0.
Ignition.
Close crater!
Closing crater.
Open shutters!
Bird 1 to base. Separation complete.
Confirm acquisition.
Calling Bird 1.
You are 70 nautical miles downrange.
200 miles altitude.
Hans, our job will soon be done.
Blow them up as soon as they have
captured the Americans. Here is the key
to operate the exploder button.
There are men in the crater!
Crater guns, fire.
Crater guns, open fire.
The firing power inside my crater
is enough to annihilate a small army.
You can watch it all on TV.
It's the last programme
you're likely to see.
If I'm going to be forced
to watch television, may I smoke?
Yes. Give him his cigarettes.
It won't be the nicotine
that kills you, Mr Bond.
Armed guards to control room.
- Close the crater.
- Close crater!
I shall look forward personally
to exterminating you, Mr Bond.
Close the shutters.
We are now impregnable.
Interception takes place in eight minutes.
Nothing can prevent that.
Impregnable?
- Come with me, Mr Bond.
- Bird 1 to base. Locked on target.
- Osato?
- Yes, Number One?
Base calling Bird 1.
You are to assume full control
of operation from now on.
Seven minutes to interception.
Roger, Base One.
Houston, this is Hawaii.
We have an unidentified object on scope.
Order first alert. Arm all weapons.
Interception will occur in six minutes.
This is the price of failure, Mr Bond.
Come on.
Goodbye, Mr Bond.
There's an exploder button in the
control room. We've got to get up there.
Impossible. Too well defended.
Evacuate the control!
Control room technicians.
There must be another way up there.
Give me cover till I get to the staircase.
Bon appétit.
Closing fast on our vehicle.
Orbit identical.
All units stand by for codeword.
Codeword is imminent.
I repeat, closing fast on our vehicle.
It's blown up! The enemy!
I repeat, the enemy has blown up.
All units will return to first alert.
Codeword is not -
I say again, not - imminent.
Tiger,
we've done it.
Down the tunnel!
Steady.
Now... about that honeymoon.
Why not?
But they'll never let you stay.
But they'll never find us.
- Dinghy's on board, sir.
- Tell him to come below and report.
It'll be a pleasure, sir.