♪ We're just two little girls
From Little Rock ♪
♪ We lived on the wrong side
Of the tracks ♪
♪ But the gentlemen friends
Who used to call ♪
♪ They never did seem to mind at all ♪
♪ They came to the wrong side
Of the tracks ♪
♪ Then someone broke my heart
In Little Rock ♪
♪ So I up and left the pieces there ♪
♪ Like a little lost lamb I roamed about ♪
♪ I came to New York and I found out ♪
♪ That men are the same way everywhere ♪
♪ I was young and determined
To be wined and dined and ermined ♪
♪ And I worked at it
All around the clock ♪
♪ Now one of these days
In my fancy clothes ♪
♪ I'm goin' back home and punch the nose
Of the one who broke my heart ♪
♪ The one who broke my heart ♪
♪ The one who broke my heart
In Little Rock ♪
♪ Little Rock, Little Rock
Little Rock ♪
♪ I learned an awful lot in Little Rock ♪
♪ And here's some advice
I'd like to share ♪
♪ Find a gentleman ♪
♪ Who is shy or bold ♪
♪ Or short or tall ♪
♪ Or young or old ♪
♪ As long as the guy's a millionaire ♪
♪ For a kid from a small street
I did very well on Wall Street ♪
♪ Though I never owned a share of stock ♪
♪ And now that I'm known
In the biggest banks ♪
♪ I'm a-goin' back home
And give my thanks ♪
♪ To the one who broke my heart ♪
♪ The one who broke my heart ♪
♪ In Little Rock ♪
Dorothy, wait a minute.
Louie, will you ask Mr. Esmond
to come back to our dressing room.
He's sitting in his usual place.
Right away, Miss Blake.
What's the rush?
He's not gonna run away.
- I know, but I just can't wait.
- For what?
Didn't you notice?
His pocket was bulging.
That could be a bag of gumdrops.
No, it was square bulge,
like a box for a ring.
I think he's got a
present for me.
You know, you're the only
girl in the world...
...that can stand on a stage with a
spotlight in your eye...
...and still see a diamond
inside a man's pocket.
Thank you, Louie.
Good evening, Mr. Esmond.
- Won't you, pray, come in.
- Thank you, I'd love to.
- Hi, Gus.
- Good evening Dorothy.
You were wonderful tonight, darling.
- Simply wonderful! You were magnificent!
- Thank you.
You were good too.
Gee, thanks, 'cause that
makes me feel all warm inside.
- Mr. Esmond!
- Is it the right size?
It can never be too big.
Do you think it's too small, Dorothy?
It looks like it ought to
have a highball around it.
I mean,
does it fit your finger?
Yes, it fits perfect.
Daddy, I'll bet you made me
the happiest girl in the world.
I don't know what you do, honey...
...unless you use Novocaine
on your lipstick?
Daddy? Daddy?
May I tell Dorothy?
If you wish.
Dorothy, Mr. Esmond and I
are going to be married.
To each other?
Of course to each other.
Who else to?
I don't know about you Gus.
I always sort of figured Lorelei would
end up with the Secretary of the Treasury.
Dorothy, guess what.
On Saturday we're sailing
on the Isle de Paris.
- "Ile" de Paris.
- We're going to be married in Europe.
Why not getting married in
America and then go to Europe?
- Well...
- Or is that old-fashioned way?
Well, we've made our plans.
Come in.
Mr. Esmond, a long
distance call for you.
Oh dear. From Dayton, Ohio.
Thank you very much,
I'll be right there.
It must be Father.
I hope nothing's happened.
I'll meet you at my table, dear.
Father! Never misses, Gus' old man.
Right on cue. Too bad, honey.
Nothing's going wrong this time.
Lorelei,
...the old boy is not about to let
you commit matrimony with his son.
I think he'd rather shove him
down an elevator shaft.
Dorothy, I'm sailing on Saturday,
with or without Mr. Esmond.
And I'm not coming back from Europe
until he comes and gets me.
When we're in France...
...where his father can't phone
him twice a day...
Well, Gus will never let you go alone.
Sometimes Mr. Esmond finds it
very difficult to say no to me.
Well, that's very possible.
Come on, guys, we can't check the roll
if you don't stick together.
Peters? Randall?
Sanford? Sims?
- Stevens?
- Look at that.
Stevens? Willard J. Stevens?
- Why don't you answer...?
- I'm busy.
Boy, oh, boy!
Check your passport
right over there.
Thank you.
Pardon please...
...is this the way
to Europe, France?
To where?
Not Europe, France, honey.
- France is in Europe.
- Who said it wasn't?
Well, you wouldn't say...
"is this the way to North America, Mexico"?
Would you?
- If that's where I want to go, I would.
- The dealer passes.
- This ship goes to Cherbourg, France.
- Thank you ever so. See?
Say, what's all the talent
in the blue jackets?
It's not a band, is it?
No, no, Miss, that's the Olympic team.
They're sailing with you on this ship.
- The Olympic team?
- Yes.
For me! Now wasn't that
thoughtful of somebody?
- Dibs on the shot-putter.
- Dorothy Shaw!
I want you to remember...
...you're supposed to be
the chaperon on this trip.
Now, let's get
this straight, Gus:
The chaperon job's is to see that
nobody else has any fun.
But nobody
chaperons the chaperon.
- Dorothy...
- That's why I'm so right for this job.
Passports, please.
I thought you were going to be late.
Here's your ticket.
They're all over there,
at the passport desk.
I want you after the blond.
The brunette's her
friend, Dorothy Shaw.
I never mind about her.
We don't care what she does.
I care.
Have fun, son.
Come on, please you guys, move along.
- Let's get on board.
- Have a nice trip.
Steve, suppose the ship
hit an iceberg and sank.
Which one would you
save from drowning?
Those girls couldn't drown.
- Right in here, mademoiselle.
- Thank you.
My, it's just like a room, isn't it?
Oh, look!
Round windows!
Yes, dear.
- Just put that there, Frisbee.
- Yes, Sir.
And, Frisbee,
wait for me on the pier.
- Yes, Sir.
- Lorelei.
- Where's Dorothy?
- I don't know.
Someone whistled at her
and she disappeared.
I hope she's not gonna be
a bad influence on you?
Oh no, lover.
Dorothy's not bad, honest.
She's just dumb.
Always falling in love
with some man...
...just because
he's good-looking.
Oh dear, that's not...
I keep telling her...
...it's just as easy to fall in
love with a rich man...
...as a poor man.
But she says, yes, but...
If they're tall, dark and handsome...
...she never gets around to
vital statistics, until it's too late.
That's why I'm her
best friend, I guess.
She really needs somebody
like I to educate her.
Yes, dear, but very few girls have
your wonderful willingness to learn.
I suppose that's true.
I want you to put
this in a safe place.
- What is it?
- A letter of credit.
Oh, that's real sweet!
You started writing me even
before I went away.
No, no, dear, you see a
letter of credit is like money.
Money?
Yes, just take it to a bank
in Paris when you get there.
Oh, that's wonderful!
Be sure and write me every day.
I'll be so lonesome.
I bought you
a little going-away present, dear.
Daddy! Daddy!
Sometimes I think there's only one
of you in the whole wide world.
Oh, sorry, wrong room.
- Who is that?
- A stranger. He had the wrong room.
Yeah, but he's good-looking.
Hope he isn't just seeing someone off.
- Dorothy...
- Well, quite a little place we have here.
Oh, look, fellas, come on in.
Folks, meet the relay team.
- How do you do? Nice to know you?
- How do you do?
We're gonna have ourselves
a little bon voyage party.
Skeeter, put the
phonograph in there.
Come on in, everybody.
Use that door, come on in here.
Make yourselves at home.
I'll get the glasses.
Hallo... Hi... You're welcome...
Who's got the champagne?
There it is.
Dorothy Shaw, I'm counting on you
to keep those athletes to yourself.
What a coincidence!
That's my plan too.
Gangway! Pardon me. Who needs a glass?
- Lorelei, I want to talk to you.
- Sure.
Dear, I want to tell you...
I want to remind you
of something very...
Stop that, please.
It's most distracting.
Dear, a lot depends on how
you conduct yourself on this trip.
As you know, Dad is dead set
against our marriage.
And well...
...even the slightest hint
of any scandal...
...even the slightest.
I don't know what I could do about it.
My goodness, lover.
You don't have to tell me that.
Oh, I'd give anything in the world
if I were sailing with you, baby.
Me too. I don't know
what I'll do in Europe without you.
I don't know what I'll do
without you, either.
I'm not so sure about that.
You can be a pretty
naughty boy sometimes.
Oh, Lee, you don't have to
worry about trusting me.
I do, though.
All visitors ashore! First call.
All visitors ashore!
♪ Bye-bye, baby ♪
♪ Remember you're my baby
When they give you the eye ♪
♪ Although I know that you care
Won't you write and declare ♪
♪ That though on the loose
You are still on the square? ♪
♪ I'll be gloomy
But send that rainbow to me ♪
♪ Then my shadows will fly ♪
♪ Though you'll be gone for a while ♪
♪ I know that I'll be smilin'
With my baby by and by and by ♪
♪ - With my baby by and by
- In the sweet by and by ♪
♪ Bye-bye, baby, bye-bye ♪
♪ - We'll go meet on the beautiful shore
- Baby, bye, goodbye ♪
♪ Bye-bye, pretty baby ♪
♪ You better remember you're my baby ♪
♪ When they give you the eye
My, my! ♪
♪ Although I know that you care
Won't you write and declare ♪
♪ Declare that though on the loose
You are still staying on the square ♪
♪ I'll be gloomy ♪
♪ But send that rainbow to me ♪
♪ Then my shadow will fly ♪
♪ Though you'll be gone for a while ♪
♪ I know that I'll be smilin'
With my baby by and by and by ♪
♪ With my baby by and by ♪
♪ I'll be in my room alone ♪
♪ Every postmeridian ♪
♪ And I'll be with my diary ♪
♪ And that book by Mr. Gideon ♪
♪ Bye-bye, baby ♪
♪ Remember you're my baby ♪
♪ When they give you the eye ♪
♪ And just to show that I care ♪
♪ I will write and declare ♪
♪ That I'm on the loose ♪
♪ But I'll stay on the square ♪
♪ I'll be lonely ♪
♪ But even though I'm lonely ♪
♪ There'll be no other guy ♪
♪ Though I'll be gone for a while ♪
♪ I know that I'll be smilin' ♪
♪ With my baby by and by and by ♪
♪ With my baby by and by ♪
♪ I'll be gloomy
But send that rainbow to me ♪
All ashore! Last call!
♪ I know that I'll be smilin'
With my baby by and by ♪
♪ Bye-bye, baby
Remember you're my baby ♪
♪ When they give you the eye ♪
♪ Although I know that you care
Won't you write and declare ♪
♪ That though on the loose
You are still on the square ♪
♪ I'll be gloomy
But send that rainbow to me ♪
♪ Then my shadow will fly ♪
- You'd better go.
- Don't go.
- Step back, please.
- Bye, lover!
♪ I know that I'll be smilin'
With my baby by and by ♪
♪ And by ♪
♪ With my wonderful baby ♪
♪ By and by ♪
- Hi.
- Hi, Miss Shaw. What are you going to be doing?
- All right, guys, keep moving.
- "Mr. Amos Jones and valet."
- What are you doing?
I'm checking the passenger list.
"Mr. Alfred Loman and valet."
"Mr. Eugene Martin and valet."
Why the sudden interest in valets?
When a man has "and
valet" after his name...
...he's definitely
worthwhile.
I'm simply trying to find
a suitable gentleman escort for you.
Well, don't bother. I just
provided myself with about 20.
Dorothy, did you ever hear
of a rich pole-vaulter?
Maybe not, but who cares? I like a man
who can run faster than I can.
I hate to think where you'll wind up.
You're wasting all your time on
unrefined persons without any money.
Honey, did it ever
occur to you...
...that some people just don't
care about money?
Please, don't be silly.
We're talking serious.
You don't want to wind up with
a loveless marriage, do you?
Me, loveless?
That's right!
Because if a girl's
spending all of her time...
...worrying about the money
she doesn't have...
...how is she going to have
any time for being in love?
I want you to find happiness
and stop having fun.
- That baffles me.
- You'll thank me some day.
Here's a good one:
"Henry Spofford III and valet."
I remember reading.
The Spofford family owns
practically a whole state.
A big one too.
I think it's Pennsylvania.
I guess I could settle
for Pennsylvania.
Hello, there!
Mrs.Henry Spofford III.
Mrs. Henry Spofford
III and valet...
...not going to have
anything I don't have.
I'll see you later.
Don't forget the cocktail party.
- All right.
- 5:30.
- The whole team?
- Until after the games.
You mean to tell me you eat at 6
and have to be in bed at 9?
That's right. Coach is strict
and check up on everybody.
Holy smoke, 9:00!
That's just when life begins.
- All right you guys.
- All right you guys
One, two, three, four.
Honey, you'll hurt yourself.
♪ I can't play tennis
My golf's a menace ♪
♪ I just can't do the Australian crawl ♪
♪ And I'm no better at volleyball
Ain't there anyone here for love? ♪
♪ Sweet love
♪ I'm apathetic and non-athletic
Can't keep up in a marathon ♪
♪ I need some shoulder to lean upon
And a couple of arms to hold me ♪
♪ Ain't there anyone here for love? ♪
♪ I'm not in condition to wrestle ♪
♪ I've never trained in a gym ♪
♪ Show me a man who can nestle ♪
♪ And I'll pin a medal on him ♪
♪ Need some chappie to make me happy
And he don't have to be Hercules ♪
♪ Don't anyone know
about birds and bees? ♪
♪ Ain't there
anyone here for love? ♪
♪ Sweet love ♪
♪ Ain't there anyone... ♪
♪ ...here for love? ♪
Doubles, anyone?
Court's free.
Two out of three, anyone?
Doesn't anyone want to play?
♪ I like big muscles
And red corpuscles ♪
♪ I like a beautiful hunk of man ♪
♪ But I'm no physical culture fan ♪
♪ Ain't there anyone here for love? ♪
♪ Sweet love
Ain't there anyone ♪
♪ Ain't there anyone ♪
♪ Ain't there anyone, anyone
Anyone, anyone ♪
♪ For love? ♪
- Did you say $50?
- Mai oui, monsieur.
That's a fairly tidy sum
just to get a seat at a table.
That's the law of supply
and demand, monsieur.
I get many requests for a seat at
Miss Lee and Miss Shaw's table.
And the price goes
up and up and up.
That's inevitable.
Je regrette, monsieur.
Je regrette it more than vous.
However, the name's Malone.
- Better get it down there while I can still afford it.
- Merci monsieur Malone.
- Bonjour, mademoiselle.
- Are you the headwaiter?
- At your service, mademoiselle.
- I'm Miss Lee.
Oh, Miss Lee. Well, now I understand.
What can I do for you, Miss Lee?
Put a certain gentleman at my table.
There's nothing I can do for you.
All seating arrangements are
completed, final., finished, compris?
That's too bad.
Once I was in Atlantic City
and all the gentlemen in the hotel...
...wanted to sit at my table.
Oh well, I can
understand that.
Some of them even went to the
headwaiter to give him money.
That happens. What can one do?
One takes it. Why not?
- That headwaiter had to give it back.
- Indeed? Why?
Because I had all my
meals in my room.
I mean, I didn't even
come to the table at all.
So, naturally,
the men wanted their money back.
Oh, mademoiselle, I beg you...
Do you want me to have
all my meals in my room?
- That must not be, mademoiselle.
- Of course.
If Mr. Henry Spofford III
is seated at my table...
- It shall be, mademoiselle.
- Thank you ever so.
Oh, mademoiselle.
Hi.
Oh! Hi, Miss Shaw.
Well, it's nice to see you.
In case you don't
remember, my name is Watson.
- Mr. Watson.
- Here we are, all ready for you.
- Thanks, I need it.
- What's the matter?
Can you imagine? The entire Olympic
team has to be in bed by 9:00.
What can you do about
a thing like that?
- Send a letter to your congressman.
- Catch me a pigeon, I'll be glad to.
Er, Miss Shaw, may I present Sir
Francis Beekman?
- How do you do?
- How do you do.
A pigeon, if there
ever was one.
Note the blood red ruby eyes.
I see, there is no reason
to run a fellow down.
He's jealous, because I have a way
with the ladies. - How do you do it?
What makes it different with the
ladies it's that diamond mine of yours.
Diamond mine?
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I'll go on being the host.
- Cheeky fellow. Good sort, though.
- Is it true?
What say we sit down
and make ourselves comfortable? What?
I understand that you're
an entertainer, Miss Shaw.
- I... why, but sure a good one, though.
- Thanks.
Say, is that on the level?
Do you own a diamond mine?
Well, I am happy to say I do, my dear.
Are you interested in diamonds?
No, no, not particularly, but...
Really, you must be a very quite...
extraordinary girl.
- Will you do me a favor, sir?
- Piggy, just call me Piggy.
- Will you do me a favor, Piggy?
- Anything, my dear, name it.
Would you be careful not to spread
it around about your diamond mine.
I wouldn't want my girlfriend
to hear about that.
Oh, she doesn't care
for diamonds either, huh?
Believe me, Piggy. I'm only trying
to save everybody trouble.
Do not tell her
about the diamonds.
Did you say "diamonds"?
Well, well, well!
By George, I must say!
No doubt about it, no sirree.
My judge. No doubt about it at all.
- Miss Lee, meet Piggy.
- Delighted! Delighted!
You did say "diamonds." I can tell.
Yes, my dear.
You see my firm controls the second largest
diamond diggings in South Africa.
But it seems we mustn't
say anything about it.
This young lady has a friend,
she doesn't want to know about me.
- I wonder why.
- Oh, no, you don't.
Pardon me saying so.
But having heard so much about you,
and all, I expected you'd be much older.
Me? Oh my, you don't say. By George!
Older than what?
The Pyramids.
Of course, I always say if
a man isn't a certain age...
...he just isn't interesting.
Oh, honey, lay off!
Bless my soul. Bless my s...
Would you care to dance?
I'd enjoy to dance.
Thank you ever so.
- Could you use another drink?
- No, thanks.
Can't tell the players
without a program.
Well, I certainly want to
know who the players are.
For instance, Sir...
...who's the young man who just
tried to steal second base?
My name's Malone.
Mine's Shaw, Dorothy.
Well, Mr. Malone?
You're the most attractive girl in
the room so I came over to tell you.
Do you mind?
No, I might as well warn you,
flattery will get you anywhere.
In that case,
we haven't any problems.
As a matter of fact...
...I've been wondering why
you hadn't shown up before this.
Well, I... I...
had some business to attend to.
Then this isn't a vacation?
Not entirely.
There's still a telephone.
- In fact, I just had some bad news.
- Oh?
My best 2-year-old
will never run again.
Bowed a tendon.
He's worth $30,000 or $40,000.
Not that I care about the money.
This might've been a good one.
Oh no, you're not one
of those, are you?
One of what?
The kind who thinks he has to tell
a girl how much money he has.
What's the matter with having money?
Yes, I'm afraid you are.
Do me a favor.
Will you Malone go
whistle up a rope?
No, wait a minute...
You might as well know
I can't stand rich playboys...
- ...who think all they have to is start...
- Now wait a minute!
I'm not that bad all the time.
Sometimes I'm very nice.
Sometimes I just speak
without thinking.
I get the picture.
You're half sweet, half acid.
- Please, Miss Shaw, I made a mistake.
- Yes, you did.
Honestly, someone gave
me some bad information.
Now that I've put
my foot in it...
...it seems to me I remember that
it wasn't you they were talking about,
...but your girlfriend.
- Oh, Lorelei.
- Or am I wrong again?
No, money is rather
a hobby of Lorelei's.
Oh, Piggy.
You're kind of worried
about her, aren't you.
You're very observing.
Am I forgiven?
Considering the man shortage
on this craft...
Good. We'll start all over again.
And I promise that I...
We're gonna be interrupted.
We just had a jolly time. What?
Oh, Mr. Malone, Miss Lee and Piggy,
...there I go again.
- Sir Francis Beekman...
- How do you do? How do you do? Hi.
Oh Dorothy, Piggy is
a super-best dancer.
So light on his feet,
you'll never believe it.
I was sure he would be.
No, no, say, you're
trying to flatter me, that...
- What's the matter?
- Lady Beekman, my wife.
I thought it was
his diamond mine.
There you are my dear.
Won't you come and join us?
- I just have.
- Quite so, my dear.
- Oh, may I present Miss Lee?
- How do you do?
- Miss Shaw...
- Hi.
- Mr...
- Malone. How do you do?
- How do you do.
- A pleasure, I'm ever so sure.
- Thank you.
Come sit down my dear,
we're having a jolly time.
Lady Beekman...
...that's the most beautiful jewelry
I've ever seen in my whole life.
Oh, hmmm, I'm quite
proud of the earrings.
Heirlooms, you know.
Been in the family for ages.
You'd never know it.
They look just like new.
Oh, quite...
You might be interested in my tiara.
I always carry it with me.
Afraid to leave it in the state room.
And you're not afraid
to show it to Lorelei?
Yes, stop. Lady Beekman
won't know you're teasing.
Look! Did you ever?
Anywhere, anything like it?
All blue stones.
Cozy little job, what?
- May I just hold it for a minute?
- Of course.
How do you put
it around you neck
You don't, lovie,
it goes on your head.
You must think I
was born yesterday.
Oh, sometimes, there's no
other possible explanation.
No, no, my dear. She's quite right.
Like so. It's a tiara.
You do wear it on your head!
I just love finding new
places to wear diamonds.
There's the music.
You'll excuse me, my dear.
Miss Lee has promised
me this next dance.
We've got to dress
for dinner now.
- But it's only...
- We must go, Francis.
Oh, well, all right. Au revoir.
A very pleasant au revoir to you.
My tiara. Thank you.
Poor fella.
Two-to-one she keeps him locked
in her closet, for the rest of the trip.
- Listen, I'd be grateful if she did.
- I think he's cute.
Except the point, you know very well
what I mean. You and that..
What are you doing?
Just testing.
Wonder what I'll wear
it with when I...
How does it look?
Exactly like trouble.
I told the coalition leader.
That we need a man who can
do something about...
Finish your story, dear.
Your table, madame.
Good evening!
Miss Lee and Miss Shaw.
This is Mr. Crossley.
Mr. Franklin. Mr...
- Mason. How do you do?
- Mr. Brooks. How do you do?
How do you do?
Isn't Mr. Henry
Spofford III here?
Not yet, but I believe
this is his chair.
You're here, Miss Lee.
Miss Shaw,
you're over here.
Thank you.
Pardon me,
my girlfriend's to shy to ask.
- But could she please have your seat?
- But of course.
She gets sick if she rides backwards.
- I'm sorry.
- Not at all.
How's it happened that
we are at the same table?
This is the seat they
assigned me, Lady.
How much said it cost you?
I can't tell you.
You'd get too conceited.
You're Mr. Franklin, aren't you?
Are you enjoying your trip?
- How many times have you crossed?
- This is my...
- Don't you feel a loner on a big ocean?
- Well I...
I just adore conversation,
don't you?
- I certainly...
- Pardon, monsieur.
- Mademoiselle, Mr. Spofford is here.
- Oh.
Dorothy.
Pardon me for whispering.
Now, please, try to
make a good impression.
Okay.
Right this way, Sir.
Mr. Henry Spofford.
- Hello.
Hello. Hello.
Well, Mr. Spofford,
are you traveling by yourself?
No, I've got a valet,
a tutor and a trainer.
Well...
...pardon my saying so
and all...
.. but having heard
so much about you...
...I expected you to be much older.
I'm old enough to appreciate
a good-looking girl, when I see one.
This promises to be quite a trip.
Personally, I don't intend
to miss a meal.
How am I doing?
Hey, there's a place over there.
Oh, Ernie, will you
get us some cigarettes?
Sure.
I can't get over that passenger list.
Calling a young boy "mister."
A girl could waste a whole trip to Europe,
if she trusted that passenger list.
Think we'd better give up
the whole idea, huh?
Believe if 16 or 17,
you could marry him in Tennessee.
Seemed a good idea
to bring some drinks.
- Here your cigarettes.
- You're a dear good boy.
I've been wondering,
what's your line, Mr. Malone?
My line?
Well, my most effective one...
...is to tell a girl that she has hair
like a tortured midnight...
...lips like a red couch
in an ivory palace...
...and I'm lonely and
starved for affection.
Then I generally
burst into tears.
- Very seldom works.
- You idiot.
No, I mean, what do
you do for a living?
Oh, that kind of a line.
Nothing, I'm afraid.
Just clip coupons and live
off the fat of the land.
- Coupons. That's like money, isn't it?
- Very similar.
I'm so pleased Dorothy's
taken an interest in you.
I mean she's never been
interested in anyone worthwhile.
No taste, hey?
No, I'm a hobo collector.
I might find room for you.
- She's joking, Mr. Malone.
- I hope not, I'm kind of counting on it.
Some people don't catch
on to Dorothy's jokes.
- I'm gonna try.
- That's good.
Dorothy is the best and loyalest
friend a girl ever had.
She'll make some man a wonderful wife.
You'll find out.
- Well, I've got to be going.
- Going? Where?
Don't worry about me.
I'm only concerned about you two.
There's a wonderful moon out tonight.
Well, well, well, there you are.
I say, Miss Lee,
will you dance with me?
I should be jolly well
pleased if you will.
Thank you ever so, I'd love to.
That is, if you hadn't asked me,
I was going to ask you.
Really? Well, by Jove!
I just say...
I say, will you excuse us?
Oh Ernie, do you
remember last night?
Very well.
No, I mean when we were talking
about the moon.
You said it reminded you of a moon
you've seen in Coney Island.
Ah. Could have been the same one. Why?
I remember then I was wondering...
...what a rich young man like you
were doing in Coney Island.
Oh, well...
I rather thought you'd be
in Bermuda or Palm Beach.
Wonder if I go in and break that up.
They're just dancing... out in public.
Can't make much of a case out of that.
You sound like a detective.
C'mon. Let's go find our moon
and forget about your girlfriend.
Anyway I'd probably get in trouble
if I pushed Piggy overboard.
Not with me.
Anyway, why blame Piggy?
It's not all his fault.
No, I...
Just what did you mean
by that remark?
Let's say I can't figure out
how two girls can be so different...
...and be such good friends.
Now listen, Malone.
Let's get this straight.
Nobody talks about
Lorelei but me.
She's quite a girl.
You just don't know her.
You don't mind
if I like you better, do you?
- We settled that quarrel in a hurry.
- Now what do we talk about?
Let's talk about you.
For the past hour I've been thinking.
Thinking about doing something.
What have you been
thinking, Mr. Malone?
...Basha.
Aren't you clever, Piggy!
You see, that means:
"Come to my Bashaand I'll give you
my all coconut shells."
And you see, the natives believe...
...coconut shells ward off the
snakes, ever what.
Africa must be fascinating.
Gee, Piggy.
A girl like I
almost never gets to meet
a really interesting man.
- Sometimes my brain gets real starved.
- Poor little thing.
It's a terrible thing to be lonesome,
especially in the middle of a crowd.
Do you know what I mean?
You'll never be lonesome again.
You leave it to Piggy.
Excuse me Piggy, I've
got to see Lorelei alone.
Certainly, certainly, shall
I wait in the next room?
If you like. We're expecting
Lady Beekman for tea.
- Lady Beekman? Here?
- Yes.
Oh, I just remembered,
I have another appointment.
I'd better pop off. Well, toodle-loo,
chin-chin and all that rot, you know?
That was very mean of you!
I would never inter...
Now, you shut up and
sit down and listen to me...
...because you're
in a jam, honey.
Me? Why?
What were you and
Piggy doing in here...
...before he started
barking like a seal?
He wasn't barking,
that's Swahili.
No, no, before that.
Now, think hard.
Was there anything that would look
incriminating in a photograph?
Something you wouldn't
want Mr. Esmond to see?
- Why, no... My goodness, yes!
- What?
Piggy was telling me
about South Africa.
It's very dangerous there.
Practically, full of
snakes called pythons.
And it seems a python
can grab a goat...
...and kill it
by just squeezing it to death.
- Get to the point.
- That's all.
What's incriminating about that?
Well, Piggy was being the python,
and I was a goat.
Oh, Lorelei!
Don't worry!
Piggy won't tell anyone
he was being the python!
He won't have to.
Because just about the time
Piggy was squeezing the goat...
...Mr. Ernie Malone was taking
pictures right through that porthole.
- Whatever for?
- The National Geographic magazine.
Oh, wake up, honey.
Mr. Malone has foxed us.
He's been shining up to me
so he can keep tabs on you.
I'll bet you anything he's a private
detective hired by Mr. Esmond.
Oh, Gus is jealous
without pictures.
If he sees that one, he will
be absolutely unreasonable.
Yes, he will.
I was going to crack Malone's head in,
but I thought better of it.
What do you mean, better?
We'll have a better chance of
getting those pictures back...
...if he doesn't know
we're on to him.
I'll get them.
- How?
- He's a man, isn't he?
No, charm won't work.
He's too smart for that.
- And he was such a doll last night.
- Oh, Dorothy!
Boy, will I tell that stinker off
when we get those pictures back!
- The question is, how do we do that?
- Well...
The simplest way
is to swipe them.
C'mon, we'll get our
warpaint on and go to work.
- By the way, where's Lorelei tonight?
- You sound interested.
I am, but not in her.
If you are interested,
I know where we could find her.
I was just asking a question.
That's all.
Hello.
Mr. Spofford, will you
please give me a hand.
I'm sort of stuck.
- Are you a burglar?
- Heavens, no!
The steward locked me in.
I was waiting for a friend.
Why didn't you ring for him?
I didn't think of it.
Isn't that silly?
If you're a burglar
and I helped you escape.
Please, help me
before somebody comes along.
I'm thinking.
All right.
I'll help you.
I'll help you for two reasons.
Never mind the reasons. Just help me.
The first reason is, I'm too young
to be sent to jail.
The second reason is, you've got
a lot of animal magnetism.
Look, someone's coming.
Oh dear, what'll I do?
Quick, hold this
around your neck, tight.
Good evening.
I say, whatever are you
doing up there?
I just want to see the view
from here, it's better.
Quite so.
Are you feeling well, my dear?
Yes, thank you ever so,
except for being so cold...
...I must have caught a chill.
- What say we get a spot of sherry?
- Oh, no, I can't.
Sherry's the best thing
if a cold is coming on.
Honest, I couldn't.
Well, you do look a little
bit flushed, my dear.
Let me feel your pulse.
No, no, please, don't...
No cause for alarm, my dear.
It's purely medical.
- There's no fever, at any rate.
- I'm all right, I'm fine.
- Such a little flowery hand.
- Please, put that back.
So sweet, so tiny,
and yet it can hold a human heart.
- Stop that!
- Beg your pardon?
Well I... Why...
- Laryngitis, I guess.
- There's no doubt about it.
Piggy, I'd better have
some of that sherry.
Will you get me some?
I fly on the wings of Mercury.
- Just hurry up.
- All right, my dear.
How can you stand that
doddering old wolf?
Can't you see his intentions
are not honorable.
For heaven's sakes,
get me out of here!
Help me over here.
Wait a minute.
What do you mean
you're all bruised?
Malone's been here with
me the whole time.
Mr. Spofford pulled me too hard.
Mr. Spofford?
Look, honey, never mind the game.
Did you get the pictures?
- No they weren't there.
- Are you sure?
Absolutely, I looked everywhere.
And they are in the camera shop either...
...'cause I went in and asked.
- Then he's got them in his pockets.
- He must have, darn it!
Of course,
he wouldn't bother to hide them...
...as long as he thinks
we're buying his act...
Well, there's only one thing to do.
Listen...
...order dinner for three
in our cabin and get some drinks.
I'll have him here in about 10 minutes.
If we can't empty his pockets
between us...
...we're not worthy
of the name women.
I'll have everything ready.
He'll be here in a minute.
I sent him for some cigarettes.
You have the drinks ready?
Almost ready.
This room's like an oven.
I know.
Let's turn some of the heat off.
Leave it alone, dear.
But it's hot, why don't...
Oh, for him. You know,
sometimes your brain amazes me.
Thank you. Remember, our drink
is just water and bitters, so...
...don't make any remarks.
What are you doing with that one?
This is his. Do you think three
sleeping pills are enough?
Three's quite a lot.
That's pretty potent stuff.
If a thing's worth doing,
it's worth doing well.
Here we go.
Come in.
- Here are your cigarettes.
- Thanks.
- Hi, Miss Lee.
- Good evening, Mr. Malone.
- I got cocktails all ready.
- Good.
Make yourself at home.
Say, you girls know
it's hot in here.
Must be 110.
Yes, it is a little warm, but
Lorelei's afraid of catching cold.
Got a touch of laryngitis.
Here your are Mr. Malone,
specialty of the house.
- Thank you!
- That's quite a cocktail.
It's very mild. Let's drink a toast.
Do you know this one?
There was an old fellow named Sidney
Who drank till he ruined a kidney
It shriveled and shrank
But he drank and he drank
He had fun doing it, didn't he?
- It's appetizing.
- I know another one. Bottoms up.
He looks like he's going to explode.
What are you girls made of?
What was that?
Just equal parts of scotch,
vodka, brandy and gin.
Here, try this.
- That wasn't water!
- No, it was straight vodka.
Do you want some more?
No.
What's the matter?
Don't you feel well?
I'm burning up.
I know what.
Let's take off your coat.
Yes, you'll feel a lot better.
You'll cool off. Here I'll help.
Now, you just sit down there.
Excuse me a minute.
- Any luck?
- Not so far.
Be sure you check the inside pocket.
- It's not in here.
- It's not in his coat.
Darn it.
There's one other
place it could be.
- Where?
- His pants.
- We'll only have to get those too.
- Do I have to get it alone?
No, I think two heads
are better than one.
I suppose so.
It's ticklish business anyway.
I'll look at it.
C'mon, we'll stick together.
Say, you know, I nearly went
to sleep, sitting here.
You suppose you could
turn that heat down?
You know what I think he needs,
a good glass of water.
- Don't you, honey?
- Yes, indeed.
I'd like some water,
but it's this heat, I can't...
Nice glass of water, yes...
Look out!
Your pants are soaked!
We can't leave him here
in wet pants, can we?
I'll put them up
under the hair dryer.
No, no, no, like I'm alright,
I'll just go and change.
Don't be silly.
We wouldn't take many...
No, oh no, no!
Look this is not...
I am not gonna catch a cold!
There is not...
What kind of a dinner party is this?
Pardonnez moi!
Francois, you're just in time.
Get something to put on him.
Mr. Malone doesn't feel very well.
You know I think you'd better
go to you room and lie down.
I feel like lying
down for a month.
- Qu'est-ce qu'il y a, monsieur?
- Here, put this on.
Francois'll help you.
It's not fair, you know.
Two against one...
- Oui, monsieur
- ...to take a man's pants...
Je suis d'accord, monsieur...
- I don't think it's here.
- It must be.
I've got it! I've got it!
Here. $2.20.
Your negatives and positive prints.
And may I say, in the immortal words
of my countrymen, "Ooh, la, la!"
- Thank you ever so.
- Ah, plaisir, mademoiselle Lorelei.
Hi. Remember me?
Why, yes. You're one of
the Olympic athletes, aren't you?
One of them? Sister, I'm the only
4-letter man on the team.
I should think you'd
be ashamed to admit it.
- What...
- No, don't say another word.
My word! By George! I must say...
This is the most contemptible bit
of impudence I've ever encountered.
The idea of photographing innocent
people through a porthole!
Why, it's absolute
invasion of privacy.
Just imagine, some newspaper
getting a hold of it.
Lady Beekman would never believe
you were just being a snake.
I think I'd better
sit down a moment.
Are you sure, my dear, there's
no more of these things about?
Positive, Piggy. Do you feel better?
You little angel,
you don't even know that...
...there is a certain
type of girl who would...
...take advantage
of a thing like this.
Gee, you'd have to be
a terrible girl to be mean...
...to a sweet, intelligent,
generous man like you, Piggy.
My dear, my dear...
...you must let me do something
for you to show my gratitude.
- Oh, thank you ever so!
- May I, may I kiss your hand?
I always say, a kiss on the hand
might feel very good...
...but a diamond tiara lasts forever.
A diamond tiara?
Yes, Lady Beekman's.
I'd just love to have it.
- Good gracious.
- What's the matter?
Oh nothing, nothing, but,
wouldn't you rather have some furs...
Or a race horse?
Or a motor-board?
No, thank you.
Well, it should be very difficult
for me to explain to Lady Beekman...
...that I'd given it away her jewels.
You're so clever, Piggy.
You could, if you put your mind to it.
- Do you really think so?
- Of course I do.
And besides, it's only fair
I should have her tiara.
Because after all, she has you.
- My dear, my dear, my very dear!
- Let's get it right now.
Anything you say,
my dear, anything you say.
- Keep an eye on the door.
- Oui, monsieur.
All right, Pierre.
Take this thing back to my cabin.
I'm gonna stay here.
Here's the microphone and a dividend.
Merci, monsieur.
- And leave the door open, Pierre.
- Oui, monsieur.
Lorelei, they're coming...
How did you get in here?
Came in through that door.
- I've been waiting...
- Still snooping around, huh?
That's right.
But it has nothing
to do with you.
I'm being paid to watch
that blond bandit...
I'd sure hate to have your job.
Maybe you're right.
Checking up on people is
messy work sometimes...
...but only when those people
are doing things that...
Doing things like
pretending to make love to a girl...
...while you spy on her friend?
That part of it is not true.
And I waited here to tell you so.
I wouldn't believe anything you said
if you had it tattooed on your forehead.
- Now wait a minute, listen to me...
- Go away Sherlock, you're a wrong guy.
I'm not wrong about you
and you're gonna listen to me...
You're only making things worse.
All right, don't listen.
But whether you listen or not...
...I'm gonna tell you.
Come on in, honey,
you can hear better in here.
- Oh, am I intruding or is he leaving.
- One hopes.
I'm leaving. But, Miss Lee,
before I go, I'm gonna tell you this.
Because once in a while,
even a mercenary nitwit like you...
...has a decent impulse.
Don't let your friend here get
mixed up in any of your schemes.
Because I'm gonna
rub your nose in them...
,
...and I don't want
this character to get hurt on the way.
If you've nothing more to say,
pray, scat!
That's about all.
Honey, except for telling you
I had money, which I haven't...
...everything else I
said to you, I meant.
And it wasn't part
of my job either.
Think about it.
Why did you just stand there
and let him kiss you?
You want to hear something crazy?
I think I'm falling in
love with that slob.
Oh, you just feel that way
because he's poor.
I hope so. Come on, let's change.
We dock in an hour.
Pierre, we want to buy some clothes.
You know, hats, dresses.
...des chapeaux...
You know some good places?
Oh, oui, autour du quai là.
That's where we want to go first.
- This has been fun, hasn't it?
- Yes.
It's the first time I've been
shopping without a man along.
Well Pierre, you
certainly were a big help.
Merci, mademoiselle!
I've never spent so
much money so fast.
- It was a pleasure.
- There. Is that enough?
Oh, thank you, thank you.
Merci, mademoiselle.
- We'll be seeing you.
- Au revoir, au revoir, bon soir!
Bonjour, mesdames.
Bonjour mesdames. How do you do?
I am the manager. May I help you?
Certainly, may you show me
a place to take my shoes off.
My feet are killing me.
Dorothy, please, a lady never
admits her feet hurt.
"VANDIOR"
Bonjour mademoiselles.
Have your reservations?
Yes we do. It's in the name
of Mr. Augustus Esmond.
- This is Miss Shaw, I'm Miss Lee.
- Hi.
Oh, yes. We have been expecting you.
This way.
Well!
Miss Lee, Miss Shaw.
I thought surely in all
Paris we could lose you.
Madame, are these the persons
you were talking about?
Yes, these are the persons.
Oh, Lady Piggy. I mean Beekman!
What a pleasant surprise.
Mmh, I dare say.
You may proceed, Pritchard.
This person is Miss Lee.
Miss Lee...
...I represent the Suffolk and
Greater London Insurance Company.
Well, did you ever so!
I never buy insurance.
So, it's Mr. Malone.
He needs it in the business he's in.
What is all this?
Young woman...
...if you return the tiara...
...I'm willing to forget
this squalid incident.
Allow me to clarify, Milady.
A Lady Beekman's tiara,
which is insured to my company,
has been reported as stolen.
What's that got to do with us?
We've been informed,
it's in your possession.
Is that true?
Absolutely not!
Honey, why don't you let Lorelei
talk for herself.
She'll do better than that,
she'll sue you for slander!
Honey, tell them, go on.
- Well...
- We're waiting.
None of your business.
Well, I'm afraid it's very much
our business.
Honey, just tell them you
haven't got it. Tell...
Oh, Lorelei, you didn't!
I did not steal Lady Beekman's tiara.
Then perhaps you'll explain
how it happens to be in your possession?
Suppose we say that's my affair.
Well, that's one explanation.
Lord Beekman knows it wasn't stolen.
Ask him.
We've already done so, Miss Lee.
And...
He denied knowing
anything about it...
...and departed
for the interior of Africa.
Piggy wouldn't do that!
Miss Lee, are you or are you not
going to give back the tiara?
I wouldn't dream of doing it.
It's mine and I'm going to keep it.
That remains to be seen.
Come, Pritchard.
You'll find that
I mean business.
Oh, really?
Then why are you wearing that hat?
- Honey, I want to talk to you.
- I made up my mind.
Look Lorelei.
The simplest way to get out of
this whole thing...
...is just to give it back.
I do not care to converse
with you, Mr. Malone.
We will not be in to this man,
as long as we stay in this hotel.
I regret, madame, you
will not stay here at all.
Oh, oh, what now?
The jig's up, Lorelei.
Esmond canceled your reservation
and your letter of credit.
- After hearing from you.
- That's right.
I don't believe it.
Mr. Esmond wouldn't do that.
- Did he?
- Exactly.
Mr. Esmond refuses
responsibility for your bills.
It's very inconvenient, because
we've just spent all of our money.
I'm sorry, madame.
That's not our concern.
C'mon, honey,
let's get out of here.
Anyway, I hear your plumbing is noisy.
Dorothy, if you need help,
I'm at the Elysée Hotel.
You hold your breath till I call.
Mademoiselle?
Café.
♪ When love goes wrong ♪
♪ Nothing goes right ♪
♪ This one thing I know ♪
♪ When love goes wrong ♪
♪ A man takes flight ♪
♪ And women get uppity-oh ♪
♪ The sun don't beam ♪
♪ The moon don't shine ♪
♪ The tide don't ebb and flow ♪
♪ The clock won't strike ♪
♪ A match won't light ♪
♪ When love goes wrong ♪
♪ Nothing goes right ♪
♪ The blues all gather round you ♪
Crazy, mademoiselle!
♪ And day is dark as night ♪
♪ A man ain't fit... ♪
♪ ...to live with ♪
Dites moi, mademoiselle...
♪ And a woman's a sorry sight ♪
C'est la guerre...
♪ When love goes wrong ♪
♪ Nothing goes right ♪
♪ When love goes wrong
Nothing goes right ♪
Do it, honey! Do it!
♪ When love goes wrong ♪
♪ Nothing goes, nothing goes right ♪
♪ When love goes wrong
Nothing goes right ♪
♪ Bees don't buzz, fish don't bite
Clock won't strike, a match won't light ♪
♪ When love goes wrong ♪
♪ Nothing goes right ♪
C'est vrai, c'est vrai,
touché, touché...
♪ A woman's a fright, a terrible sight ♪
♪ Man goes out, gets high as a kite
Love is something you just can't fight ♪
You can't fight it, honey,
you can't fight it.
♪ When love goes wrong, nothing ♪
No bows, honey,
just eight bars and off.
♪ Nothing goes right ♪
Crazy, crazy!
Pierre, you're just in time.
♪ It's like we said
You're better off dead ♪
♪ When love has lost its glow ♪
♪ So take this down ♪
♪ In black and white ♪
♪ When love goes wrong ♪
♪ Nothing goes right ♪
♪ Nothing goes right
...nothing goes right ♪
Oh, dear.
- Right over there, monsieur.
- Oh, thank you.
Merci.
Lorelei?
- Oh, hello, there.
- Hello.
You remember Mr. Esmond,
don't you dear?
Perfectly.
Why not say hello, then?
After all,
he used to be a friend of ours.
Nice to see you again.
- Nice to see you.
- Yes, indeed.
Lorelei, Lorelei wait!
Look!
Lorelei, I've flown
the entire Atlantic Ocean...
...just to talk to you,
and now you...
Well, you might come in for a minute.
That's, if you don't mind?
Oh, I don't mind if you don't mind.
- Mr. Esmond?
- Thank you.
Lorelei, aren't you even gonna
say you're sorry?
I won't let myself.
I won't let myself fall
in love with a man...
...who won't trust me, no
matter what I might do.
"No matter what you..."?
Lorelei, that's being unreasonable.
Well, goodbye, then.
How can I trust you after all
Father's found out about you?
We're ready to dress
you, mademoiselle.
Be right there.
Lorelei, I...
It's men like you who have made me
the way I am.
And if you loved me at all...
...you'd feel sorry for the
terrible troubles I've been through...
...instead of holding
them against me.
No, no,
don't say another word.
I wasn't gonna say anything.
Poor Gus, you have
a pretty tough time.
You know, if you really
want to get upset...
...go out and see the number
she's gonna do next.
You mean...
Oh, oh, dear.
Thank you.
No!
♪ No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no ♪
♪ No ♪
♪ No, no, no, no, no, no ♪
♪ No, no ♪
♪ No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no ♪
♪ No! ♪
♪ The French are glad to die for love ♪
♪ They delight in fighting duels ♪
♪ But I prefer a man who lives ♪
♪ And gives expensive jewels ♪
♪ A kiss on the hand
May be quite continental ♪
♪ But diamonds are a girl's best friend ♪
♪ A kiss may be grand ♪
♪ But it won't pay the rental
On your humble flat ♪
♪ Or help you at the auto-mat ♪
♪ Men grow cold as girls grow old ♪
♪ And we all lose our charms in the end ♪
♪ But square-cut or pear-shaped
These rocks don't lose their shape ♪
♪ Diamonds are a girl's best friend ♪
♪ Tiffany's! ♪
♪ Cartier! ♪
♪ Black, Starr, Frost, Gorham ♪
♪ Talk to me, Harry Winston
Tell me all about it! ♪
♪ There may come the time
When a lass needs a lawyer ♪
♪ But diamonds are a girl's best friend ♪
♪ There may come a time ♪
♪ When a hard-boiled employer
Thinks you're awful nice ♪
♪ But get that ice
Or else no dice ♪
♪ He's your guy when stocks are high ♪
♪ But beware when they start to descend ♪
♪ It's then that those louses
Go back to their spouses ♪
♪ Diamonds are a girl's best friend ♪
♪ I've heard of affairs
That are strictly platonic ♪
♪ But diamonds are a girl's best friend ♪
♪ And I think affairs that
You must keep liaisonic ♪
♪ Are better bets
If little pets get big baguettes ♪
♪ Time rolls on
And youth is gone ♪
♪ And you can't straighten up
When you bend ♪
♪ But stiff back or stiff knees
You stand straight at... ♪
♪ ...Tiffany's ♪
♪ Diamonds ♪
♪ I don't mean rhinestones ♪
♪ But diamonds ♪
♪ Are a girl's best ♪
♪ Best friend ♪
Hi, honey.
How'd Gus like your number?
He didn't applaud.
He looked kind of grim.
Hand me my hat there
would you please.
He is sweet, isn't he?
I really do love Gus.
You do, really?
There's no other millionaire in
the world with such a gentle disposition.
He never wins an argument,
always does anything I ask...
...and he's got
the money to do it with.
How can I help
loving a man like that?
Oh, I guess so.
Let's don't talk about love.
It reminds me of my friend Malone,
the human ferret.
Deshabillé?
Quelle catastrophe!
Les gendarmes!
The police are here!
They asked for you!
They have a warrant for your arrest.
They are coming now.
It will get in all the newspapers.
It will hurt my business.
Quelle scandal!
Now will you get rid of
that jinxed tiara.
But Piggy gave it me...
if I give it back,
it's like admitting I stole it.
Oh, keep still, honey.
You're in a strange country.
You can't prove
that you didn't steal it.
Do you want to take the chance
of a couple of years in the Bastille?
- I guess I've got to give it back.
- Where is it?
- In there.
- Oh, come on, let's get it.
- Oh, Dorothy. It's just not fair.
- No, of course not.
Dorothy, it's gone!
What? Are you sure
this is where you left it?
Yes. It's been stolen!
It's been stolen!
The cops!
Oh, sister, we really are in a jam.
Come on.
Maybe you can get out
here if I give you a boost.
Lorelei? It's me, Gus.
- Gus.
- I come to say goodbye.
He's your best chance.
Why, if he can't boost me
any higher than you can.
Lorelei?
Just a minute Gus.
Listen!
Either you hock some of that stuff...
...or get the price of the
diamond tiara out of him.
How much do you think a
diamond tiara'll cost?
$15,000 at least.
Gee, that'll take an
hour and 45 minutes.
All right, you get the money
and I'll take care of the gendarmes.
How?
Never mind how. You're not the only one
around here with hidden talents.
- Lorelei?
- Coming!
You can come in now, Daddy darling.
Lorelei, I've made up my mind.
We're through. Through forever.
Oh, but first I want
to kiss you goodbye.
Very well.
No, no. Not in front of everybody.
Come on in, Daddy darling.
"American vols sont ici."
"Venant de New York
maintenant à la porte douze."
This is your flight
coming now, monsieur.
Oh, thanks very much.
"Now Ici, monsieur."
Pardonnne, monsieur.
Until you finish customs you cannot...
I know, I just wish to speak
with this gentleman.
- Bien, monsieur.
- Well Malone?
How are you, Mr. Esmond.
Have a nice trip?
My son, where is he?
A few minutes ago, he was in the café
where the girls are working.
I explicitly told you on my cable
to stay with him until I arrived.
- Well, he...
- Don't you know he can't be left alone...
...in the same city
with that blond man-trap.
Oh, he's perfectly safe for a while.
Right now, the blond man-trap is in the
quatrième arrondissment night-court...
...getting ready to explain
a few things to the police.
That's much better.
We'll go over there as soon as
you get through this customs thing.
I'll be right with you.
I beg your pardon.
Well, Sir Francis Beekman.
I heard you'd gone to Africa.
What? What'd you say? Beekman?
No, Sir, my name is not Beekman,
my name's Amos Finch.
All right, if that's how you want it.
I say, don't be in such
a confounded rush.
Aren't you're the
chap on the boat?
- I am.
- I thought so.
Er, I was just having a bit of a joke.
Of course I'm Beekman.
- You're sure?
- Well, rather.
My plane leaves in an hour..
Do you know where to find Miss Lee?
I think so.
Would mind giving her a message for me,
but not until after I've gone.
Glad to.
Tell her... tell her that
I had no choice in the matter.
What I did, I had to do,
and all that sort of rot, you know.
She'll understand
if she knew my wife.
And tell her... tell her I know
that money means nothing to her.
But I'll make it up to
her someday, somehow.
I'll tell her.
Thanks awfully, old boy.
Well, toodle-loo.
It'll be a great favor,
by George, a great favor.
All right, Malone, take
me to see this young lady.
Yes, sir.
"Reprenter sentiments et si
honorablement à monsieur le president."
"Le mettez un terme
par un châtiment exemplaire."
"Faites entrer I'accusé."
"Faite entrer mademoiselle Lee."
"Mademoiselle Lorelei Lee."
"Mademoiselle Lee."
"Je veux dire la verité,
toute la verité, rien que la verité."
You will please swear, Miss Lee.
Oh, judge,
I never swear.
You've been asked...
...to swear to tell the truth,
the whole truth, nothing but the truth.
Will you do that?
Well, yeah. Thank you ever so.
Sit down, mademoiselle.
Mademoiselle Lee,
I've been requested...
.. to hold you for trial,
for a charge of grand larceny.
The complainer attest
that you have stolen...
...how do you say it...
a headpiece of diamond, a tiara?
My goodness, judge,
a girl needs a little time to think.
You're so much more intelligent
than poor little me.
Won't you tell me what I ought to say?
- Please, answer the charge, Miss Lee.
- Yes, judge, I was going to.
I was just thinking. It was
all a terrible misunderstanding.
You see, judge, sometimes life is
very hard for a girl like I.
Especially if she happens to be pretty
like I and have blond hair.
We can do without the philosophy.
We have interest in the facts, only.
"Monsieur le President, qu'il plaît
au tribunal..."
Mr. Pritchard is a
little confused...
...and would like to bring
up a question.
I can hardly blame him.
What is the question?
Mr. Pritchard doesn't see
very well...
...and would like to look at
mademoiselle Lee, more closely.
Permission granted.
- Now Miss Lee, I should like ..
- Why, Mr. Pritchard, how nice to see you!
Yes, Miss Lee...
You are Miss Lee, aren't you?
That's just who I am, all right.
But my friends call me Lorelei.
I do hope you're my friend, because...
...I just love to have
handsome gentlemen be my friends.
Well, my eyes are not
what they might be.
- Have you ever heard me sing?
- No.
- Are you sure?
- Oh, I've not had the pleasure.
Thank you ever so!
♪ A kiss on the hand
May be quite continental ♪
♪ But diamonds are a girl's best friend ♪
♪ A kiss may be grand ♪
♪ But it won't pay the rental
On your humble flat ♪
♪ Or help you at the auto-mat ♪
♪ Men grow cold as girls grow old ♪
♪ And we all lose our charms in the end ♪
Sister!
♪ Square-cut or pear-shaped
These rocks don't lose their shape ♪
♪ Diamonds are a girl's best friend ♪
This is not a cabaret!
Stop that woman!
♪ Tiffany's! ♪
♪ Cartier! ♪
♪ Black, Starr, Frost, Gorham ♪
♪ Talk to me, Harry Winston
Talk to me ♪
Did you hear me? Stop her!
Take her to the witness stand!
The rest of you take your places.
You are fired!
How could my son get mixed up
with that type of girl?
"Asseyz vous!"
Now, young lady,
we're here to dispense justice.
Not to watch a cabaret show.
You understand me?
- Yes, judge.
- All right.
Did you or did you not steal
the diamond tiara?
Oh, no, sir. I did not steal it.
The fact is, Lady Beekman's
husband gave it to me.
Your Honor, I'd like to
give some information!
The defendant here is not...
"Silence!"
You have evidence
that affects this case?
- Yes, Sir, I have.
- Well, by all means.
Your Honor, before he talks,
could I explain something?
Go ahead, Miss Lee.
Well, I have a friend named Dorothy,
and she's a really good friend.
And Dorothy knows I would never do
anything that was really wrong.
- Miss Lee, do you have to say this?
- Yes, sir, I do.
There's a certain young
man that Dorothy likes.
In fact, she's very fond of him.
And, Dorothy would never speak
to this man again...
...if he ever did anything
to hurt me, Lorelei.
So I think this young man had
just better know that...
...well, well, Dorothy thinks
she's in love with him.
- Mr. Esmond, I resign.
- What?
I just quit the case,
you don't owe me a dime.
What's got into you?
Are you out of your mind?
Hmmm,
but I like it that way.
- Judge, I've changed my mind.
- What?
I haven't anything to say.
Oh, this becomes more
and more confusing.
But the solution is simple.
My decision is this:
The property in question will be
placed in custody of this court...
...until its rightful owner can be
established by an affidavit...
...from Lord Beekman himself.
Now, Miss Lee, you will
give me the tiara.
But, judge, I can't.
If you refuse,
I must put you in prison.
Well, I don't refuse,
I just haven't got it. It was stolen.
Your Honor...
...I think I know where that thing
is and think I know who's got it.
- Who are you, by the way?
- I'm a private detective, your honor.
If you'll give me a couple of
policemen and wait about half an hour...
...I can bring the tiara
back and settle this thing.
Anything would be better than this.
Go with him.
"Accompagnez-le. Oui!"
"L'audience est supendue"
There he is.
"Pardon, monsieur.
Vous allez nous suivre."
- What's that?
- "Vous allez nous suivre."
What's he saying?
"Question d'arrêt, monsiuer. Allez!
Speak English! I don't speak...
This is outrageous! -"Mais avec nous."
I'm a British subject!
You'll hear about this!
This is positively outrageous!
Your Honor, I demand a lawyer.
"Que se decouvre!"
"Decouvrez vous!"
What?
What did you say?
- Good evening, your Lordship.
- Pritchard!
The policemen want you
to remove your hat.
Well, why doesn't he say so?
What are you doing, send
for the British consulate.
- Meantime, I'll take this.
- Hey, give that back. - In just a second.
Your Honor, this is
Sir Francis Beekman.
And this, I believe,
is the missing tiara.
That's private property!
I'm sure Miss Lee will
be glad to return it.
I certainly would.
But before that happens, I believe...
His Honor asked
Miss Lee to give him the tiara.
- I did!
- I say, that isn't...
I wouldn't go into that,
if I were you, Mr. Finch.
Finch?
- Miss Lee.
- Thank you.
- Your Honor.
"Maitre Courtier..."
Thank you.
- Monsieur Pritchard.
- Thank you. Your Lordship.
Thank you.
Case dismissed!
But, five minutes ago
you said you would marry me.
But that's before Dorothy phoned me.
But what on earth could she say
to make you change your mind?
She just said everything's okay now.
I don't quite understand...
- Oh, dear.
- Well.
- Hello, Father.
- Hello, son.
I know what you're here for Father,
and I don't care.
I've made up my mind.
I'm gonna make her marry me.
Oh, bless you heart, that's wonderful.
- I presume this is the young lady?
- Well, yes.
Such a pretty little girl!
American?
Yes, except on my father and mother
side. They're Irish.
Believe me, son.
I'm delighted about this.
I've wanted to see you
married for a long time.
Anybody but that monster,
Lorelei Lee.
- What?
- Mr. Esmond, I am Lorelei Lee!
Hah, hah. Pretty early in the game
to start teasing your father-in-law.
- What's the matter with you, Father?
- Nothing. I can take a joke.
What joke?
This is Lorelei.
Father, this is not the sort
of thing one would joke about.
I don't have my
driver's license with me...
...but you can take my word for it.
Honest!
Look, that's I.
See my name?
Oh...
I'm too old for this sort of thing.
- Father, I don't understand.
- You don't understand?
How do you think I feel...
with thousands of Lorelei Lees
coming at me from everywhere?
But believe me, son, you're not
going to marry any one of them!
Father, I love her.
I love her very much.
I've never had a feeling...
Oh, shut up! Young lady,
you don't fool me one bit.
I'm not trying to.
But I bet I could, though.
No, you might convince this...
...jackass that you love him,
but you'll never convince me.
That's too bad.
Because I do love him.
Certainly. For his money.
No!
Honestly.
Have you got the nerve stand there
and you expect me to believe...
...that you don't want to marry
my son for his money?
It's true.
Then what do you
want to marry him for?
- I want to marry him for your money.
- There!
Oh, Lorelei!
Don't you see that's why
we have to have his consent, silly.
Well, at least we're getting
down to brass tacks.
You admit that all
you're after is money.
No, I don't.
Aren't you funny?
Don't you know that a man being rich
is like a girl being pretty?
You might not marry a girl
just because she's pretty.
But my goodness,
doesn't it help?
And if you had a daughter...
...wouldn't you rather
she didn't marry a poor man?
- But I was just...
- You'd want her to have the most...
...wonderful things in the world,
and to be very happy.
Why is it wrong for me
to want those things?
Well, I concede that...
Say, they told me you were stupid.
You don't sound stupid to me.
I can be smart when it's important.
But most men don't like it.
Except Gus.
He's always been
interested in my brains.
No, no, that much
of a fool he's not.
Father, you've
changed your mind?
I don't know, son, I just
don't know what to tell you.
Daddy?
No, Daddy, not you.
I guess I mean "Sonny."
I'd like to spend about
three minutes alone with your father.
- Three minutes alone.
- Run along, darling.
Yes, dear.
Now, Mr. Esmond,
about what we were speaking.
Well, there's a great deal
to consider. I just can't imagine...
Please,
take your places.
Remember honey...
...on your wedding day,
it's all right to say yes.
♪ We're just two little girls
From Little Rock ♪
♪ And we lived on the wrong side
Of the tracks ♪
♪ But at last we won the big crusade ♪
♪ Looks like we finally made the grade ♪
♪ But square-cut or pear-shaped
These rocks don't lose their shape? ♪
♪ Diamonds
Diamonds ♪
♪ Diamonds are a girl's...
Diamonds are a girl's... ♪
♪ ...best friend ♪