Well, Thomas Becket,
are you satisfied?
Here I am stripped,
kneeling at your tomb
while those treacherous
Saxon monks of yours
are getting ready
to thrash me.
Me, with my delicate skin.
I bet you'd never have
done the same for me.
But, I suppose I have
to do this penance
and make my peace with you.
What a strange
end to our story.
How cold it was
when we last met
on the shores of France.
Funny, it's nearly
always been cold,
except at the beginning
when we were friends.
We did have a few,
fine summer evenings
with the giris.
Did you love
Gwendolen, Archbishop?
Did you hate me the
night I took her from you,
shouting, "I am the King"?
Perhaps that's what you could
never forgive me for.
Look at them lurking there,
gloating.
Oh, Thomas,
I'm ashamed of this
whole silly masquerade.
All right, so I've come
here to make my peace
with their Saxon hero,
because I need them now,
those Saxon peasants of yours.
Now I'll call them my sons,
as you wanted me to,
you taught me that too.
You taught me everything.
Those were the happy times.
Do you remember?
At the peep of dawn
and as usual
we'd been drinking
and wenching in the town.
You were even better
at that than I was.
Shhh, listen.
Upstairs.
She's up with someone.
Well, go on up.
Get up man, get on up there!
Quick, out through the window.
Thank you.
Come on now.
Come on.
Come here.
I'll lay my hands on
her, the dirty slut.
Where is he the swine?
You don't,
don't you dare,
don't you dare.
Here catch.
Go on, get in there.
Here take my good boot.
I can't get my boot back on.
Faster now.
Oh, rub harder pig,
I'm cold.
Ah, no one does it
the way you do, Thomas.
Thank you.
I think you actually
like the cold.
I made you a nobleman,
why do you play
at being my valet?
I'm your servant
in the council chamber,
or here in the bath.
My Norman Barons resent it,
they feel it's your Saxon way
of mocking their nobility.
Nobility lies
in the man, My Prince,
not in the towel.
Have you any idea
how much trouble
I took to make you noble?
I think so,
I recall you pointed
a finger and said,
"Thomas Becket
you are noble".
The Queen and your mother
became very agitated.
They're always agitated.
No, I mean trouble
from the Barons,
they hate you, you know?
Of course, one always
hates what one wrongs.
When you Norman's
invaded England,
you seized our Saxon land,
burned our Saxon homes,
raped our Saxon sisters.
Naturally you hate Saxons.
Don't include me,
it was my great
grandfather William
who was called
"The Conqueror",
I'm an old resident.
I did not mean you.
Didn't you?
You know when I took
you into my service,
everyone predicted you'd
put a knife in my back.
Did you believe them?
No, I showed them that
you were a man of honor,
and a collaborator.
That was accurate of you.
How do you combine the two?
My Lord?
Honor and collaboration?
I don't try.
I love good living,
and good living is Norman.
I love life and the
Saxons only birthright
is to be slaughtered.
One collaborates to live.
And honor?
Honor is a concern
of the living.
One can't very well
be concerned about it
once one's dead.
You're too clever
for me, Thomas,
but I know there's something
not quite right
about your reasoning.
Honor is a
private matter within,
it's an idea
and every man has
his own version of it.
How gracefully
you tell your King
to mind his own business.
Time for the council
meeting, My Lord.
Ugh.
Will My Lord dine
with me tonight?
On gold plates?
Always.
I am your King,
and I eat off silver.
Your expenses are heavy,
I have only my
pleasure to pay for.
Tonight you can
do me the honor
of christening my forks.
Forks?
Yes, from Florence.
A new little invention,
it's for pronging meat
and carrying it to the mouth,
it saves you
dirtying your fingers.
Then you dirty the fork.
Yes, but its washable.
So are you fingers,
I don't see the point.
Well, it hasn't any
practically speaking
but it's refined,
it's subtle,
it's very un-Norman.
You must order me some.
For my Barons.
I have enough
forks to go around,
bring the gentleman
with you tonight.
I shall.
We won't tell them
what they're for.
They'll probably think
they're a new kind of dagger.
All right, gentlemen,
the Council is open.
Gentlemen,
I've called you here
to find out why
a simple request for taxes
causes such
unpriestly caterwauling.
My Lord...
We must come to
an understanding
about who rules this kingdom,
the church...
My Lord, I wish to ask you...
Just a moment, Archbishop.
The church, or me?
There are many troublesome
issues between us,
which call for a reckoning.
Amongst other abuses
is the claim you make
of judging your clergy
accused of civil crimes
in your own
ecclesiastical courts.
I warn you,
there can be only one
justice in this country,
and that is the Kings.
But before we quarrel,
here is some happy news.
I have decided to revive
the office of
Chancellor of England,
keeper of the Lion's Seal,
and entrust it to
our loyal servant
Thomas Becket.
Yes, my little Saxon?
My Lord?
Well, for once I've
taken you by surprise.
My Lord,
this is a stupendous honor,
for which I may
not be worthy.
I'm inexperienced
in these matters
and frivolous by nature.
Rubbish,
you know more than
all of us put together.
He's read books
you know, its amazing.
He's drunk and wenched
his way through London
but he's thinking all the
time, aren't you, Thomas?
He'll checkmate
the lot of you,
even you Archbishop.
I never did anything
without your advice.
No one knew it,
now everyone will, that's all.
There,
that's the
Great Seal of England,
don't lose it,
without the seal
there's no more England
and we'll all have to pack up
and go back to Normandy.
May I crave leave
to greet our young
and learned friend,
for I noticed him
when he was first
made Archdeacon.
Thank you, Archbishop,
but don't rely
too much on Becket
to play your game,
he's my man.
I'd forgotten you were
an Archdeacon, Thomas.
So had I, My Prince.
Now to business.
The law demands
that every landowner
send soldiers
to give me service
or pay a tax in silver,
is that correct?
I have heard so, My Lord.
We are about
to cross the channel
to force Louis of France
to return the Norman towns
he has taken from us.
I have received
neither soldiers
nor silver from you
gentlemen, for this war.
But surely one must
distinguish between
the individual landowner
and God's church?
The law doesn't distinguish.
But this has never
been spoken of before.
I've never been
this poor before.
No, I've made up my mind
and I'm passing
around the plate,
just drop in the money.
Oh, my backside's sore.
Is that all,
count your blessings, Sire.
I don't know
about you, Thomas,
but I'm starving,
have them bring
us something to eat.
The layman who shirks his duty
and fails to supply
his King with arms
should pay the tax,
nobody will question that.
Least of all the clergy.
On the other hand,
a priest's duty
is to assist his
King with his prayers
for Godliness and peace,
he cannot maintain men at arms
without violating
the very essence
of that sacred function
therefore he cannot be
held liable for the tax.
Your priest
fought well enough
in the days of a conquest
when there was
booty to be had.
Sword in fist,
rumps in the saddle,
death to Saxons scum,
it's God's will,
it's God's will.
Those violent days are over.
The priest is back
in his sanctuary
it is peacetime now.
But not for long, pay up,
I don't intend to budge.
Come on Chancellor,
say something,
has your new title
made you tongue-tied?
May I respectfully draw
to My Lord
Archbishop's attention
one small point?
Respectfully but firmly,
you're Chancellor now.
England is a ship,
the King is the
captain of the ship.
That's neat, I like that.
My Lord Chancellor,
in point of fact,
there is also a saying
the captain is sole
master after God.
After God!
Nobody's questioning
God's authority, Archbishop.
Most certainly God
protects the ship
by inspiring the captain
but I've never heard
that he determines
the wages of the crew,
nor instructs the
paymaster in his duties.
God has more
important business.
Our young deacon's ambition
has carried him
away from the church
but he cannot have forgotten
that what is important
is revealed to man
only through his church
in the person of our
Holy Father in Rome,
his bishops and his priests.
Or does the Chancellor
think otherwise?
True, there is a priest
onboard every ship.
He gives God's blessings,
but neither God nor the church
ask him to take the
wheel from the helmsman.
My Reverend Lord,
the Bishop of London
who I understand
is the son of a sailor
surely cannot
have forgotten that.
I will not allow
personal insinuation
to compromise the integrity
and honor of the church.
Please, Bishop, no long words.
All that's at stake
here is its money.
I need money to
fight the French,
will the church give it to me,
yes or no?
My Lord,
your illustrious ancestor
William the Conqueror
granted these tax
exemptions to the church.
May he rest in peace,
where he is now,
he doesn't need money.
I'm still on Earth and I do.
This is not primarily
a question of money,
Your Highness,
this is a
question of principle.
I need troops, Bishop.
I've sent for 3,000 Swiss
to help me fight
the King of France
and no one has ever paid
the Swiss with principles.
My Lord, Chancellor,
it is pointless to
continue this discussion.
The law has given us
the means of coercion,
we will use it.
You,
you owe everything
to Holy Mother Church.
Would you dare plunge
a dagger into her bosom?
My Lord and King who
rules by the grace of God,
has given me his seal
with the three
lions to protect.
My mother is England now.
Traitor,
Saxon.
My Reverend friend,
I strongly suggest that
you respect my Chancellor
or else I'll call my guards.
Ahh, here they are now.
Oh, no,
it's only my snack.
Now, gentlemen,
if you will excuse me,
at this hour in the morning
I need sustenance
or else I tend to feel weak
and a king must never weaken,
I'm sure you will agree.
I'll have it in my chapel.
Then I can pray
directly afterwards.
Come on, Thomas,
keep me company.
He means it's
time for the hunt.
Not until we have
eaten, my dear Bishop.
Race?
Right.
The Kings hunt.
Eh?
Oh, inside quick.
Let's get under cover
before we're drowned.
We've lost the Barons.
Oh, they'll find us,
here, hold this.
Oh, I'm cold, my pretty.
Go on sit on there,
that's a good girl.
Go on, get on there.
I'm freezing,
get the fire going.
There'll be no
wood in this house.
In the middle of the forest?
These people are entitled
to two measures
of deadwood a year,
one branch more and they hang.
My edict?
Your edict.
Come here, old man.
We need firewood.
Don't be afraid.
Thomas!
Thomas, come here!
Look at this.
She stinks a bit
but we could wash her,
what would you think
of it, cleaned up a little?
She's a child.
What would it be
like when it's a woman.
How old would you
say it was, 16, 17?
It can speak, My Lord,
how old are you.
Eh?
Of course it can speak.
How old's your daughter, dog?
Odd the number of
dumb people I meet
when I set foot
out of my palace,
I rule over
a kingdom of mutes.
They're afraid.
Quite right, too.
Don't stand there,
put the wood on the fire.
Hello, pretty.
Look at it.
The odd thing is it's so ugly,
yet it makes such
pretty daughters.
You're a member of the
family, explain that?
Well, at 20 before
he lost his teeth
and took on that ageless
look the common people have,
he may have been handsome.
He may have had
one night of love,
one moment when he was
a king and shed his fear.
Afterwards, his
paupers life went on
eternally the same.
The moment faded
and he forgot it all,
the seed was sown.
Will she grow ugly too?
Surely.
If we made her a whore
and kept her at the palace,
would she stay pretty?
Perhaps.
Then we'd be doing her
a service, wouldn't we?
No doubt.
Look at it,
it understands every word.
Stop staring at me, dog,
get me something to drink.
I have some
drink in my saddle.
What's the matter, Thomas?
Nothing.
I'm getting you a drink.
Thank you, Thomas.
Our escort.
want some?
What's the matter, you hurt?
It's nothing.
Show me.
Now you know you can't
stand the sight of blood.
My horse bit me.
That is too funny.
My Lord here, makes us all
look silly at the jousts
with his fancy horsemanship,
he goes to his saddlebags
and gets bitten like a groom.
You look quite
shaken, little Saxon.
Funny, I can't bear
to think of you in pain.
All this just
to get me a drink
wounded in the
service of the king.
This deserves a gift.
What would you like?
This girl,
I fancy her.
That's very tiresome of you,
I fancy her myself,
and where that
subjects concerned
friendship goes by the boar.
All right, she's yours.
Thank you, My Prince.
But you will return the
favor equally one day.
At your pleasure.
Equally, favor for favor,
you give me your
word as a gentleman?
I do.
Right, she's yours.
Shall we take her with us
or shall we have her sent?
No, no, no, the
soldiers can bring her.
Wash your daughter,
dog, and kill her fleas,
she's coming to the palace
for My Lordship here.
He's a Saxon too,
so I hope you'll be pleased.
Give him money, Thomas,
I'm feeling generous
this morning.
Don't worry
about your daughter,
nobody will come
to take her away,
I'll see to that.
And tell your son
he should stay
hidden in the forest
until he can
handle a knife better.
Here.
Forgive me,
not for fighting,
my dear Baron,
for eating.
Go on, it's lovely.
Noisy brutes.
You seem to spend
a great deal of time
in their company.
No, I can forget it
when I come to you.
I'm happy that
I can relieve you.
Now don't tease me
tonight, Gwendolen.
I'm off to France
again tomorrow, and war.
I am My Lord's captive,
whatever his purpose
and whatever his mood.
I hope so.
It is God's will,
since he gave the Norman's
victory over my people.
And that's the only
reason you're here?
If the Welsh had won the war,
I would have married
a man of my own race
at my father's castle.
God did not will it so.
All right.
I'm sorry I was so
late coming to you
but the King is demanding
and the Barons
have to be kept at bay.
I'm lying,
you are My Lord,
God or no God.
If we had won the war,
you could just as easily
have taken me from
my father's castle.
I would have come with you
for you had taken my heart
before you captured my body.
Have I said
something wrong?
Somehow I can
never support the idea
of being loved.
I told you that.
Oh, please.
Sit.
Play something,
something sad,
it helps the digestion.
Play.
Oh, sweet and melancholy.
Sit, Thomas,
witness one of
my finer moments.
I behave like a brute,
but I'm as soft as
swan's down inside.
You know, Thomas,
sometimes I think
that you and I
are the only civilized
men in England.
I eat with a fork,
and you've made
me into a man
of the most
delicate sensibilities
and now if you
really love me
you should find me a
beautiful well bred girl
to give me a little polish.
Favor for favor,
do you remember?
I am your servant, My Lord.
All that I have is yours.
But you are also
gracious enough to say
I am your friend.
Yes, that's what I mean,
as one friend to another.
You do care for her then?
You do care about something?
Or do you?
Go on, tell me,
tell me if you
care for her or not?
I said, "favor for favor"
and I asked for your word.
And I gave it to you.
Right.
Well, that's settled then.
May I have a moment's grace?
Surely, surely.
After all, I'm not a savage.
Did you promise me to him?
No.
I promised him
anything he asked for.
I never thought
it would be you.
If he sends me away tomorrow,
will you take me back?
No.
I leave you this,
you've almost
learned to play it.
You've not found anything
in the whole worid
to care for, have you?
No.
We both belong
to a conquered race,
but you've forgotten
that people
robbed of everything
can still have one thing
left to call their own.
Yes,
where honor should be,
in me there is only a void.
I loved you,
Thomas Becket.
My Lord.
Enter.
How careless you are, Thomas,
you had forgotten her.
But you told me
that you fancied her
and I remembered.
You see I really
am your friend
and you're wrong
not to love me.
Goodnight, Sire.
Shall I undress, My Lord?
What?
Shall I undress?
Thomas?
She's dead.
She's killed herself.
All this blood.
Help me, Thomas,
I'm frightened.
I'm the King!
Get rid of her.
Guard.
I'm sleeping here tonight.
Give this girl a silver
piece and let her go.
He won't hurt you.
I don't want to
be alone tonight.
I'm here, My Prince.
You'll hate me now.
I'll never be
able to trust you.
You have nothing to fear.
You gave me your seal,
and while I wear it
my duty is to my king.
But I'll never know
what you're thinking.
Sleep now.
We cross the channel tomorrow.
When we face the French
on the field of battle
there will be simple
answers to everything,
so long as Becket must
improvise his honor
from day to day,
he will serve you faithfully.
But what if one day
he should meet
his honor in truth,
face to face?
But where is Becket's honor?
An early good morning
to you, gentlemen,
I've just ridden
from the town.
I've arranged for
its capitulation.
Well, will there be loot?
No, I want these people
to collaborate
with good grace.
The French Bishop will
deliver the keys of the city
to the King at eight
o'clock in the cathedral.
No fighting,
what are we here for?
To secure King Henry's
possessions in France.
You have three more
towns to recapture.
I'd rather sack the town
and slaughter the lot.
Yes, and have a dead city.
No, I want to give
the King living cities
to increase his wealth.
From dawn this morning
I'm the townspeople's
dearest friend.
And what of England's pride?
England's pride, my dear Baron
is to succeed.
What a mentality.
Chancellor of England.
Who knows what he is,
he's a Saxon.
Release him.
Leave us Sergeant.
My Lord?
Leave us.
What are you, a Saxon
monk doing in France,
they'll kill you, you know?
I'm prepared to die.
How old are you?
18.
Hmm, dying is easy at 18.
Your knife stinks of onions
like every proper
little Saxon's knife.
You used to be a Saxon.
Now you belong
to the Normans.
I see.
A Saxon knife
for a Saxon collaborator.
Did you think
that by killing me
you could liberate your race?
No, not my race, myself.
From what?
My shame and yours.
The Normans have
occupied England
for a hundred years
since Hastings,
shame is an old
vintage to the Saxon.
Your father and
your grandfather
drank it to the dregs.
The cup is empty now.
No, never.
What's your name?
What is your name?
John.
Sergeant.
Well, Brother John,
I'm going to save your life.
It has no importance for me
but it's very rare for fate
to bring one face to face
with one's own
ghost when young.
My Lord?
Have this monk
returned to England
to the custody of the
Abbott of his monastery.
I want him treated
without brutality,
but carefully watched.
Yes, My Lord.
My Lord?
Good morning, My Lord.
Oh, French wine.
I had a little
too much last night.
It's their major
contribution to civilization.
Here's another.
I must say I adore
my French possessions,
they're certainly
worth recapturing.
What's your name, my pretty?
Name?
Marie.
Marie, very French.
A French luxury
is very luxurious.
And for the moment free.
We take possession of
the town this morning.
Yes, I heard.
You managed that
very well, Thomas.
Personally, I shall
miss the fighting,
meanwhile we have
some business to discuss.
I've been studying the
dispatches from England.
You love work don't you?
If you love anything.
I love doing what I have
to do, and doing it well.
You'd be as efficient against
me as for me, wouldn't you?
If fate had
arranged it that way.
So what in most
people is morality,
in you it's
just an exercise in,
what's the word?
Aesthetics.
Yes, that's the word.
Always, aesthetics.
Yes.
Well now,
look at that.
Isn't that aesthetic, too?
Some people go into
ecstasies over cathedrals
but that's a work of art.
Look at it,
round as an apple.
Want her?
Business, My Lord.
All right, business.
Sit down.
Listen carefully, Marie,
to the droppings of the
greatest brain of our day.
Now piecing together
all the information
I've received from London
there are some unpleasant
deductions to be made.
The power of the
Bishops is increasing
like the pestilence,
soon it will rival your own.
Talk sense, Thomas,
priests are always intriguing
but I can crush
them anytime I wish.
If you don't crush them now,
in five year's time
there will be two
Kings of England,
the Archbishop of
Canterbury and you,
in ten year's time
there will be only one.
And it won't be me?
I fear not.
Grant to horse,
Thomas, to horse,
war on the clergy,
death to the Archbishop.
My Lord, I can't breathe.
What are you doing down there,
spying for the clergy?
Be off with you.
Put on your
clothes and go home.
My Lord, am I to come
back to the camp tonight?
Yes,
no,
I don't know.
I'm thinking of priests
now, not you, go away.
Wait, I'd rather be sure
I'm getting
another one as good.
Yes, come back tonight.
You're adorable.
You must always
tell them that,
even when you pay.
That's high politics too.
Only one,
it won't be me?
It won't be you.
But what will God say
if I attack his church,
after all they're his bishops?
We must manage the church.
One can always come to a,
sensible little
arrangement with God.
Becket, you're a monster.
You flatter me, My Lord.
But please,
My Lord, dress quickly.
It's, it's inelegant
for conquerors to be late.
You're a monster.
You see, they love us
dearly, these French.
So they should,
we paid them enough.
In that case, we
should have found some
that didn't dress
out of a rag barrel.
The rich are at home sulking.
Supporters of
King Louis of France?
No, it just
would've cost too much.
That sounds real.
Yes, we have soldiers
disguised in the crowd
to encourage enthusiasm.
Why must you destroy
all of my illusions?
Because you should
have none, My Prince.
What do you see?
Reality.
Stop here!
The Bishop is waiting.
As if it mattered what
I do with a Bishop
whose city I've just taken.
It matters.
Am I the strongest,
or am I not?
You are today,
but one must never drive
one's enemy to despair,
it makes him strong
gentleness is better politics,
it saps virility.
A good occupational
force must never crush,
it must corrupt.
Make a note of the house.
Oh, never mind.
My Lord, the Bishop.
Yes, papa.
No, papa.
Put your men at rest, Captain.
Is this William, of Corbeil?
Yes, Sire.
I hardly recognized you
without a tankard
covering your face.
How did they pry
you away from it?
I had urgent messages from
London for you, My Lord.
It seems that God
is on our side
after all, Thomas.
What is that, My Prince?
He's just recalled the
Archbishop of Canterbury
to his bosom.
That frail old man,
he was the first Norman
to take an interest in me.
God rest his soul.
He will, he will
and he'll be much
more use to God
than he ever was to me.
Thomas.
An extraordinary idea
is creeping into my mind.
A masterstroke,
I'm suddenly
very intelligent.
It probably comes
from making love
to that French
girl last night.
I'm subtle,
I'm even profound.
Oh, I'm so profound
it's making my head spin.
Are you listening
to me, Thomas?
I'm listening, My Prince.
We need a new
Archbishop of Canterbury.
I think there is
a man we can rely on.
No matter who it is,
once the Archbishop's
miter is on his head
he will not longer
be on your side.
But if the
Archbishop is my man,
if Canterbury
is for the King,
how could his power
possibly get in my way?
My Lord,
we know your bishops,
once enthroned at Canterbury,
every one of them will
grow dizzy with power.
Not this man.
This is someone who doesn't
know what dizziness means,
someone who
isn't afraid of God.
I'm sorry to deprive
you of the French giris
and the other
spoils of victory but,
are you listening
to me, Thomas?
You're leaving
for England tonight.
On what mission, My Prince?
You are going to
deliver a letter
to all the bishops of England.
Uh-huh.
My royal edict nominating
you, Thomas Becket,
Primate of England,
Archbishop of Canterbury.
Shut up.
Thomas, I'm in deadly earnest.
My Lord,
don't do this.
You have an odd way
of taking good news.
I should think
you'd be triumphant.
But I, I'm not even a priest.
You're a deacon,
you can be ordained priest
and consecrated
Archbishop the next day.
Have you considered
what the Pope would say?
I'll pay his price.
My Lord,
this frightens me.
I thought you had God in the
palm of your hand, Thomas.
I beg of you,
do not do this.
You've never
disappointed me, Thomas,
and you're the
only man I can trust.
You'll leave for
England tonight.
Becket?
Thank you for returning
to us the keys of our city.
The die is cast, Thomas,
make the most of it.
And if I know you,
I'm sure you will.
There you are.
Thank you, My Lord.
You're welcome,
it will keep you warm.
He'll only sell it for drink.
Then that will keep him warm.
Yes, Your Grace.
No, not Your Grace,
I will not be consecrated
Archbishop until tomorrow.
I'm sorry, Father.
That is temporarily correct.
You don't really intend
to give away
your winter cloaks?
Everything, has all
the gold plate been sold?
Yes, the money from the
sales is in those purses.
Excellent, bring me
the rest of the money.
But Your Grace...
I mean, Father...
Everything.
Well, welcome to
Canterbury, My Lord Bishop,
is anything wrong?
May I ask what is
happening here?
Go sell all that thou hast
and give it to the poor
and thou shal't have
treasure in heaven.
I doubt if the Lord, Jesus
meant that to apply
to a Chancellor
about to be
consecrated Archbishop.
Perhaps then it's
a touch of vanity.
A truly saintly man,
I know would never
do all this in one day.
Let us call it
the clumsy gesture
of a spiritual gatecrasher.
Most clever,
an Archbishop who
gives all so dramatically
to the people would be
most popular with them.
Oh no, Folliot,
I'm simply
enjoying all of this.
I'm beginning to
believe he's not a
sad God after all.
Forgive me, I fear my
inexperienced methods
will never meet
with your approval.
I know that you cast
the only vote against me.
In the end I gave way
to the King's wishes.
I don't blame
your reluctance
as Bishop of London
and senior churchman
you should've
been Archbishop.
Now to have to
consecrate me instead
and place the
miter on my head.
I have no choice.
I'm only performing
my function as Bishop.
I see you still wear the seal
of the King's Chancellor.
Yes, I will
continue to wear it,
that and the
Archbishop's ring.
You do not find
this inconsistent?
No, God is best served
when the two rest
side by side in harmony.
These excessive
acts of humility
will not compensate for
subservience to the crown.
Thank you.
We are both aware of the
delicacy of my position.
Let us trust that God
will find a solution for it.
And now,
since humility seems to be
a little hard on the knees,
I trust you will be
comfortable under our roof,
My Lord Bishop.
Dear Lord,
I wish there was something
I really regretted
parting with
so that I might
offer it to you.
But forgive me, Lord,
it's like going on a holiday,
I've never enjoyed myself
so much in my whole life.
Lord,
are you sure you're
not laughing at me?
It all seems far too easy.
It is a Bishop's
duty to pass judgment,
to interpret,
to consecrate,
to ordain,
to offer sacrifice,
to baptize and to confirm.
Let us pray beloved Brother,
let the goodness
of Almighty God
providing for the
well-being of his church,
may bestow upon
this Bishop elect,
the abundance of his grace
through Christ our Lord,
Amen.
May these hands be anointed
with hallowed oil,
with the chrism
that sanctifies.
Even as Samuel
anointed David,
King and Prophet
so may these hands
be anointed and consecrated.
Take this ring,
token of the pledged word.
Yours it is,
donned with
unshakable fidelity
to preserve and guard,
in unblemished honor
God's bride, the Holy Church.
Lord, on the head
of this Bishop
and champion of thine,
I put the helmet of
defense and salvation
that with forehead
thus adorned,
head armed with the horns
of both testaments,
he may appear fearsome
to the enemies of truth.
His Grace, will
receive you here.
It isn't every day
that a Saxon monk
has an audience
with an Archbishop.
Open your eyes.
You'll kiss his ring
and show respect to His Grace,
or you'll get my
foot on your backside.
You're welcome to Canterbury.
Kneel to His Grace.
I see our young Brother
is quite unchanged.
Has he been
troublesome to his Abbott?
Stubborn as a mule, My Lord.
Father Abbott tried kindness,
but in the end
had to have recourse
to bread and water,
even to the whip.
Nothing has any effect.
Except for a good
kick in the rump
if Your Grace will
pardon the expression.
Stand up straight.
Pay attention to your Brother.
As a rule, the sin of
pride stiffens a man's back.
Look me in the face.
Now,
what do you have
to say for yourself?
I see.
Now Brothers, we
relieve you for the day
from your rule of abstinence.
Go to our kitchen
before you depart
and I hope you'll do
justice to our cuisine.
And this one?
We will keep him here with us.
He's vicious, Your Grace?
We are not afraid.
Well, now,
wouldn't you rather
have a Saxon Archbishop
than a Norman one?
I hope I won't
regret sending for you.
Why did you?
I'm not sure.
Perhaps in a young,
intemperate way,
yours is a voice that
is good for me to hear.
Then why...
But please, not too often
and not too loud Brother John.
You betrayed your Saxon race,
now you betray God.
Perhaps you will succeed
in teaching me humility,
it's a virtue I've
never really mastered.
Enter.
Your Grace, Bishop Folliot
has just arrived from London,
he wishes to speak
to you urgently.
Well, My Lord
Bishop, what is it?
But, Your Grace?
You may speak freely,
Brother John is
in our confidence.
What is it?
Your Grace, I have a most
serious matter to report,
which requires your
immediate intervention.
Proceed.
A parish priest in
Lord Gilbert's domain,
who is accused of
debauching a young girl,
has been seized by
His Lordships soldiers
and dragged before
the civil courts.
Is the priest guilty?
That is immaterial.
As a consecrated
minister of God
he can only be tried
by our ecclesiastical courts.
You must demand his release
into church
custody immediately.
The principle is a vital one.
Does the King know of this?
He knows, but he
turns a deaf ear.
Lord Gilbert is his friend.
I'm also a friend
of King Henry's.
As Chancellor
you are his friend.
But I wear the miter now.
You also wear the
great seal of England
and I warned you,
you could never
do so honorably.
It is fortunate that I do.
I will plead our
case to the King.
I did not come here to
ask you to plead a case.
I'm asking you to
defend a principle
and you'd better do so
quickly, Your Grace.
Thank you for your warning.
We appreciate your
efforts to chart the course
you would naturally
have followed
had you become Archbishop.
At least, Your Grace,
I could never
have been accused
of divided loyalties.
Should I go now?
Can I go?
No.
See who's outside.
This is
Brother Philip, Your Grace.
He's come with a message
for the Bishop of London.
I told him he just left
but now he
insists on seeing you.
Your Grace,
I wouldn't have dreamed
of disturbing you but...
It's you who are
disturbed, Brother Philip.
What is it?
I believe My Lord Bishop
of London came to you
to demand the custody
of the accused priest.
Yes.
The priest is dead.
Dead?
Yes.
He tried to escape
but Lord Gilbert's
soldiers caught him
and in the presence of
his Lordship, killed him.
Thank you, Brother Philip,
you may retire.
Leave us now, Brother John.
My Lord Jesus,
I find it difficult
to talk to you.
What can I say?
I, who have
turned away from you
so often with indifference
I have been
a stranger to prayer,
undeserving of your friendship
and your love.
I've been without honor
and feel unworthy.
I am a weak and
shallow creature,
clever in only
in the second rate
and woridly arts seeking
my comfort and pleasure.
I gave my love,
such as it was elsewhere,
putting service
to my earthly king
before my duty to you.
But now,
they have made me
the shepherd of your flock
and guardian of your church.
Please, Lord, teach me now
how to serve you
with all my heart,
to know at last
what it really is to love,
to adore.
So that I may
worthily administer
your kingdom here upon earth
and find my true honor
in observing your divine will.
Please, Lord,
make me worthy.
You are a creature
of extremes,
aren't you, Brother John.
Get up.
Forgive me.
I didn't know,
I never realized.
Nor did I.
Get up.
You were very good at
admonishing an Archbishop.
Do you think you
could talk to a king?
Yes.
Good.
Then you will
memorize what I write.
Henry?
What is it mother?
Why do you keep
gazing out of the window?
Becket won't come you know,
he's much too busy
giving money to the poor
and fitting
sandals on beggars.
I never liked him
as an adventurer,
but now that he puts
on the airs of a saint,
he certainly keeps himself
in splendid isolation
since you made
him Archbishop.
He's in retreat.
It's part of the ritual.
Anyway, I don't need
to be reassured
by his presence.
He's my friend.
More is the pity.
He has a strange way
of showing gratitude.
Your friend,
you mean you went to
the whorehouses together.
It was he who lured you away
from the duties
you owed to me.
Madam,
in matters of debauchery
it was I who lured him
and I didn't need
anyone to lure me
away from the
duties I owe you.
I made you four children
very conscientiously,
thank the Lord
my duty is done.
I pray heaven he
stays away from you.
When you realize
how he has used you,
you may appreciate the
joys of family life again.
The joys of family life
are limited, madam,
to be perfectly
frank, you bore me,
you and your
everlasting backbiting.
Stop this.
And this eternal
tatting of yours.
In God's name how long does
it take to make a tapestry
and it's mediocre
beyond belief.
One performs
according to one's gifts.
Yes.
Shut up, the lot of you!
Which one are you?
Henry the III.
Not yet, sir,
number two is in
the best of health.
A fine way you bring up
your children, madam.
Do you see yourself
as regent already?
No wonder I shun your bed,
it's not amusing to make
love to one's own widow.
Who's that?
A messenger
from Canterbury
if you can spare the time
from bullying your children.
Messenger?
Is your master ill?
No, Your Highness,
I have a message
from His Grace.
A message?
These are Becket's words.
"Whereas men at arms
of the Lord Gilbert
under his orders
and in his presence
have seized and killed
a priest of the church,
I Becket,
Archbishop of Canterbury,
Primate of England,
do now ask that Your Highness
in accordance with
the law of the Realm
apprehend Lord Gilbert
and charge him with
the crime of murder."
Well, my son,
now you have heard
from your friend.
Get out!
Get out, both of you!
Take your royal
vermin with you!
Your Highness,
is there a reply
for the Archbishop?
Your Grace.
Yes?
The King is here.
Are you certain?
He came mounted and alone,
but I'm sure it's he.
My Prince.
Why did you send a messenger?
Canterbury's only
five hours from London.
I've just ridden it in four,
I'm frozen stiff.
Would you like some wine?
No.
Give me a reason.
Why did you send a messenger?
What answer did you give him?
You've arrived
here before he has.
I detect ill,
devious Becket here.
What game are
you playing, Thomas?
No game, My Prince.
Lord Gilbert
murdered a priest.
I want the guilty punished.
The guilty of what?
This priest was
a scandal to his parish.
That was never proved.
Gilbert should've
handed the accused
over to the church
for process of law.
If guilty, we would have
determined his punishment.
I am the law.
Gilbert will recourse to me,
I gave him leave
to arrest this priest.
I can't allow any of my clergy
to be thrown into prison
and tried by the
civil authorities.
Neither can I stand by
and let my
priests be murdered.
You?
You can't allow?
You can't stand by?
Are you taking yourself
seriously as Archbishop?
I am the
Archbishop, My Prince.
By my grace.
Are you demented,
you're Chancellor of England,
you're mine.
I'm also the Archbishop
and you have introduced
me to deeper obligations.
And if I won't charge Gilbert?
I can't force you,
but there is always
a final judgment
beyond the King's justice.
Oh that, Lord Gilbert
will face his fate
on the day of judgment,
as we all will.
I'm sure he'll have a
great deal more to answer for
than killing
a felonious priest.
Lord Gilbert will
come to that judgment
already damned, Sire.
I intend to excommunicate him.
You are demented.
Don't you understand
that when you attack
my nobles, you attack me,
and when you attack me,
you attack England!
There is more to
England than the crown.
You must learn to face
that eventually, My Prince.
Damn you, don't lecture me!
You once told me
you didn't know what honor
was, and I laughed at you.
But now to betray me,
to challenge my power.
I do not seek
power, My Prince.
It is only that
I finally discovered
a real honor to defend.
Whose honor?
Whose honor is
greater than the King's?
The honor of God.
Forgive me.
Hmm,
you give the lions
of England back to me,
like a little boy who
doesn't want to play anymore.
I would have gone to war
with all England's
might behind me
and even against
England's interest
to defend you, Thomas.
I would have
given away my life
laughingly for you,
only I loved you
and you didn't love me
that's the difference.
Stay away.
But thank you for this
last gift as you desert me.
Now I shall learn to be alone.
Bishop.
What do you want, Philip?
Your Majesty,
alone without an escort?
The King nevertheless.
Bishop, I wish to confess.
The King has
his own confessor.
It is an important
court prerogative.
Don't be nervous, Bishop.
I'm not asking for absolution.
I have something far worse
than a sin on my conscience.
A mistake,
a crass mistake.
I ordered you
to vote for Becket
in the election at Canterbury.
I repent of it.
I bowed beneath
the royal hand.
Very reluctantly, I know.
I'm told this compromise
with your conscience
made you seriously
ill afterwards.
God cured me.
Very good of him.
You wear his uniform
and have his ear.
He's let me fall ill
without lifting a finger
and I must cure myself.
I did not know of this...
I have the
Archbishop on my stomach,
a big, hard lump
I shall have to vomit back.
I think you are a man
one can talk to, Bishop.
I believe I misjudged you,
friendship blinded me.
Is the King's friendship
for Thomas Becket
dead, Your Highness?
Yes, Bishop,
it died quite suddenly,
a sort of heart failure.
A curious phenomenon,
Your Highness,
but quite frequent.
I hate Becket now.
I hate him,
as much as you
are jealous of him.
He's like an animal
tearing my guts,
I can't bear it anymore.
I shall have to
turn it loose on him.
But I am the King
and my office
stands in my way.
I need someone to help me.
My only interest
is for the church.
Oh, come, Bishop.
We're alone and
the church is empty.
The church is never empty.
The little red lamp
burns in the chapel
signifying God's presence
in the tabernacle.
Do you take me for one of
your sheep, Holy Pastor?
I like playing games,
but only with
boys of my own age.
The one for whom that
little red lamp burns
has seen into
your innermost heart
and mine a long time ago.
Of my hatred
of Thomas Becket
and your envy of him,
he knows all there is to know.
Strange, I'd always
taken Your Highness,
for a perennial adolescent
who cared only
for his pleasures.
One can be wrong
about people, Bishop,
I made the same mistake.
Now, if it could be proved
that Becket had committed some
gross impropriety
as Chancellor,
say embezzlement,
what would the church do?
If that were established,
I say if,
the Bishops could
legally dissolve
their allegiance to him
pending their
report to the pope.
And beyond that?
You,
you would go beyond that?
The whole way.
In his guilt,
if he were found guilty,
he would then be
charged under canon law.
And the penalty?
That would be for
Your Majesty to decide.
Thomas.
You love him don't you?
You still love him.
That impostor,
that Saxon guttersnipe,
that mitered hog.
Hold your tongue, Priest.
All I confided to you
was my hate, not my love.
For England's sake,
you'll help me get rid of him,
but don't ever
insult him to my face.
He will be accused,
and you will play
your proper part.
According to law.
I would spit,
if I were not
in God's house.
My Brothers,
as you have been told
your presence
here is voluntary.
If any of you have
second thoughts
you may retire now.
Thank you for attending.
Good day, My Lords.
I did not expect to
see you at Canterbury.
Do you still disagree
with my decision?
Your Grace, can nothing
persuade you to delay?
Oh, yes, the King's
arrest of Lord Gilbert
on the charge of
sacrilegious murder.
There will be an arrest
but not Lord Gilbert's.
The sheriff of London
is waiting in the sacristy.
He has orders to summon you
before the King's
grand justicer,
the instant you pronounce
the excommunication.
How curious, on what charge?
Embezzlement.
The King finds that there are
large sums of money
missing from the treasury
during your
administration as Chancellor?
How much?
Forty thousand
pounds in fine gold.
There was never that much
gold in the whole treasury.
I beg of you do not do this.
You will strike a blow
that will split church
and state for a generation.
If I do not strike it now
the church as we know it
will not survive a generation.
God will see that it survives.
No, the Kingdom of
God must be defended
like any other Kingdom.
Gentlemen,
it is a supreme irony
that the woridly Becket,
the profligate and libertine
should find himself
standing here at this moment.
But here he is
in spite of himself.
But the King for good or ill,
chose to pass the burden
of the church onto me
and now I must carry it.
I've rolled up my sleeves,
and taken the
church on my back.
Nothing will ever make
me set it down again.
Now, Lords,
if you will forgive me.
Lord Gilbert,
Baron of England, by
the grace of His Majesty,
King Henry the II,
seized upon the
person of a priest
of the holy church
and unlawfully did
hold him in custody.
Furthermore,
in the presence
of Lord Gilbert
and by his command,
his men seized
upon this priest
when he tried to escape
and put him to death.
This is the sin of
murder and sacrilege.
In that,
Lord Gilbert has rendered
no act of contrition
or repentance
and is at the moment
at liberty in the land,
we do here and
now separate him
from the precious body
and blood of Christ
and from the society
of all Christians.
We exclude him from
our Holy Mother Church
and all her sacraments
in heaven, or on earth.
We declare him excommunicate
and anathema.
We cast him into
the outer darkness,
we judge him
damned with the devil
and his fallen angels
and all the reprobate
to eternal fire
and everlasting pain.
So be it.
As the Lord
Sheriff of London,
I'm commanded to summon you,
Thomas Becket,
to the King's court
on the charges
herein set forth,
stamped with the King's seal.
I Robert de Beaumont,
Duke of Leicester,
Grand Justicer of the Realm,
do now summon Thomas Becket
to this court of law,
for the third and last time.
Thomas Becket, step forward.
He's doomed, isn't he?
Yes.
At last.
I forbid you to gloat.
At seeing your enemy perish.
Why not?
Becket is my enemy
but in the human balance
traitor that he is
and naked as
his mother made him,
he's worth 100 of you madam,
with your crown
and your jewels
and your august uncle the
emperor into the bargain.
I'm forced to fight
him now and crush him
but at least he gave
me with open hands
everything that is
at all good in me,
and you have never
given me anything
but your coping mediocrity
and your everlasting obsession
with your puny little person
and what you
thought was due to it!
That's why
I forbid you to smile
while Becket
is being destroyed!
I gave you my youth,
I gave you your children.
I don't like my children!
And as for your youth,
that withered flower
pressed between the
pages of a hymn book
since you were 12 years old
with its watery blood
and stale insipid scent,
you can bid farewell
to that without a tear.
Your body was an
empty desert, Madame,
which duty forced
me to wander in alone.
But you have never
been a wife to me,
and Becket was my friend,
red blooded,
generous and full of strength.
Oh, my Thomas.
And I?
I have given you
nothing I suppose?
Life, yes.
Thank you.
But after that
I never saw you
except in a passageway
on your way to a ball,
or in your crown
and ermine mantle
10 minutes before
official ceremonies
when you were forced
to tolerate my presence.
No! No one on this earth has
ever loved me except Becket!
Call him back then,
absolve him if he loves you,
give him back his power,
but do something.
I am.
I'm learning to be alone.
By the authority granted me,
I, Robert de Beaumont,
servant of the crown,
do now before this council,
charge Thomas Becket
with the crimes of...
Robert.
I charge you, Thomas Becket...
Robert de Beaumont,
hear me for the
sake of your soul,
which is in
the gravest danger.
All in this assembly
know how faithfully I've
served My Lord the King.
It was he who willed
that I be Archbishop
and it was for love of
him alone that I accepted.
I am innocent
of any wrongdoing
in my administration
of the King's treasury
as Chancellor,
or at any other time.
I therefore refuse to plea
to these trumped up charges.
I will be judged
by the Pope alone,
to whom before you all
I now appeal and place myself
and my church
under his protection.
As head of the
Church of England
and as your spiritual father,
I forbid you to
pass judgment on me.
I command you
and all who would charge
me to hold your peace
on pain of endangering
your immortal souls.
Well played, Thomas.
Do you think you can
carry this off
indefinitely you fool?
We are all God's
fools, My Lord.
Becket,
you are a liar!
You are a traitor!
Sheathe your sword Morville
before you impale
your soul upon it!
It's funny,
it's too funny.
He's made mincemeat of them.
I'm surrounded by fools!
Becket is the only
intelligent man
in my kingdom
and he's against me!
Your Highness,
it was impossible...
Shut up,
get to your feet.
Did you hear him,
he appeals to the Pope.
If he gains the
Pope's ear, Bishop,
we may find the
entire kingdom
under Papal interdict.
I could be
excommunicated myself.
But, Your Highness,
I do not think that...
I want no more thinking!
Becket must not
cross the channel.
King Louis of France
would be the first to
help him get to the Pope.
The Archbishop must not
leave England, see to it.
From now on, Bishop,
it is total war.
Psssst...
My French Knight
takes your English Bishop.
Your Majesty's adroit.
Pardon, Sire.
To snug.
Why do all tailors want
to strangle one's armpits?
Your Majesty, the English
ambassador's extraordinary
insist that I convey
their compliments.
They've already done that.
I'll see them when I'm ready,
that's my job.
They wish respectfully Sire,
to call your
attention to the fact
that they have been
waiting for three days.
Let them wait,
that's their job.
Ambassadors are paid to
pace about in anterooms
especially in these
times of uneasy peace.
But they have an
urgent communication
from Henry of England, Sire.
The King of England
and his ambassadors
can drown themselves
in what they are
impertinent enough to
call their English channel.
But, Your Majesty, the
extradition of a criminal
is a courtesy due
from one crowned
head to another.
My dear man,
crowned heads are free
to play a little
game of courtesy,
but nations owe
one another none.
Oh.
All right, show them
in, show them in.
No, you may stay.
The ambassadors can
share our attention
with our tailor.
It will demonstrate
to the English
that exact social
status of our court.
May I be permitted to
present to, Your Majesty,
the two envoys extraordinary
from His Highness,
Henry of England,
His Grace,
the Bishop of London
and Robert de Beaumont,
Duke of Leicester.
Welcome My Lords.
Fresh from England?
How is our good King Henry?
He was well, Your Majesty,
when we left him
two weeks ago.
Two weeks to cross
the channel, gentlemen?
We have been waiting upon
Your Majesty, for three days.
Why was I not informed?
Girot.
Your Majesty?
See what I have
to contend with.
But perhaps I can
make it up to you.
Would you permit
me to furnish you
with some French garments
made by our craftsmen here,
it will only take two weeks?
We thank, Your Majesty,
but we have urgent
business in Rome.
Too bad.
Well, is there anything
else I can do for you?
I wish to deliver a message
from Henry, King of England
to his friend Louis,
King of the French.
We are all ears.
He wishes you to know...
Oh, just one moment.
Yes, do continue.
He wishes you to know
that Thomas Becket,
Archbishop of Canterbury,
has been found
guilty of treason
and has forthwith
fled his kingdom.
He therefore entreats you
not to allow this criminal
to reside within
your territories,
nor to permit
any of your vassals
to give counsel
or support to him.
He solemnly declares
that your enemies
would receive none from him,
nor from his subjects.
Henry, King of England,
Duke of Normandy.
Gentlemen, we have
listened most attentively
to your sovereign's
gracious request,
and we shall
shortly be drafting
a formal reply to it.
In the meantime, however,
we can only express
our astonishment.
No news has reached us
of the Archbishop
of Canterbury's
presence in our domains.
But Sire, we have word
that he is in your domains.
He's taken refuge in
the Abbey of San Martin
My Lord Bishop,
we flatter ourselves
there is some
order in our kingdom.
If he were there,
we should most certainly
had been informed.
Bring in Thomas Becket.
Rise, Thomas Becket,
and greet us as the
Primate of England.
The bow would've been enough
and if I know my etiquette
you were entitled to
a slight nod of
the head from me.
That's done.
I might also be
required to kiss the ring
if this visit
were an official one
but I am under the
impression that isn't.
No, Sire.
I'm on an exile.
That too is an
important title in France.
I'm told you are
a dangerous one.
I'm afraid so, Sire.
How delightful,
shall we discuss
it in private.
We enjoy danger Becket,
it keeps us alive.
Do you value candor?
I do, Sire.
Then let me tell you that
were you a French official
I might have kept you
into prison myself.
For the moment, however,
we are pleased to grant
you our royal protection.
I humbly thank
you, Your Majesty,
but I'm bound to tell you
that I cannot buy your favor
with any act
hostile to my country.
You do us an injustice,
that was understood.
I believe that in
the past however,
you have been no stranger
to the art of
political maneuver.
That is true, Sire.
Well, speaking frankly,
you suit our purpose
in our chess game.
England is splitting
into the Henry camp
and the Becket camp
and that suits us admittible.
We ask nothing further of you,
but, there is always a but,
as I'm sure you are aware?
I am aware.
I am responsible only for
France's interest, Becket.
Unfortunately, I cannot
afford to shoulder
those of heaven as well.
For the moment it suits me
to shelter any fugitive
from Henry's court.
His recent impertinence
in claiming and capturing
some of our frontier towns
must be well known
to you, Thomas,
since you more than
distinguished yourself
in several of
these engagements?
In a month or so, however,
my dealings with Henry
may require a
different tactic.
I might even be obliged
to ask you to leave France.
I hope to have a solution
to such a dilemma.
Oh?
I intend to go onto Rome
to put my case
before the Holy Father,
if you will give
me safe conduct.
You shall have it, of course,
you're the ideal guest.
But might I be permitted
to give you a word of advice.
I would appreciate it.
The Pope is a most holy man,
but like so many
lofty personages
he is surrounded by men
of a somewhat inferior stamp.
They need money
and King Henry might
be willing to provide it.
Keep your eyes open.
I will.
But permit me to
show you my aviary.
That man Becket smacks
of too much sincerity.
A practice that is
most disconcerting.
Fiddlesticks.
Sincerity is a
form of strategy
just like any other.
In a pinch I have been
known to use it myself.
The trouble is,
if your opponent starts
being sincere at the
same time you do,
then the game becomes
horribly confusing.
Shh.
I assure you, Your Holiness,
it's a simple matter.
No, no, no, Zambelli,
I don't agree,
it is impossible.
If we take the money
from King Henry,
I cannot possibly
receive Becket.
Receive the money from
the King, very Holy Father,
and receive the
Archbishop too.
The one will
neutralize the other.
You know what they say,
Becket is going to ask me?
No, Holy Father.
Zambelli, don't play
the fox with me.
It was you who told me.
I beg your pardon,
Holy Father.
I had forgotten,
or rather as Your Holiness
asked me the question
I thought you had forgotten
and so I took a chance and...
Zambelli,
if you start out maneuvering
yourself to no purpose,
we'll be here all night.
Well, bring him in.
His Holiness
will receive you now.
I'm sorry to be
importunate, Your Holiness,
but time is running out
and my course concerns
the very life of the
church in England.
I know, I know,
and your cause is worthy
but nevertheless, Becket,
the church must seek
to exist peacefully
within the framework
of the state.
I sought that with
desperation, Your Holiness.
Precisely, Becket.
You are new to God's service
and perhaps for that reason
you were somewhat hot headed
and intemperate
in your methods.
You have proved
your moral worth,
but you have also split
the church in England
into two parties
and that is regrettable.
Holy Father, I fear
this may be true
and it has given
me much agony.
If I'm guilty,
if my judgment was wrong,
then I am most
sincerely repentant.
unfortunately that
doesn't solve the problem.
Holy Father,
relieve me of the
title of Archbishop,
let me be an ordinary priest.
All right, done.
Zambelli.
Why do your request this?
Then, Your Holiness, could
make a free and open decision.
The protection of my position
as head of the English church
may prove an embarrassment
I would like to relive you of.
No, that would mean
our total surrender
to the state.
You will maintain
your status as Archbishop
but you will, for the present,
maintain it in
a monastic retreat.
Where do you wish
us to send you?
To the Abbey of
San Martin in France.
I ask only that
my former servant,
Brother John
be allowed to accompany me.
Of course,
God grant you
peace, Thomas Becket.
That man is obviously
an abyss of ambition.
How long a retreat?
A very long retreat.
I wouldn't count on it.
Wait till he tastes
the food at the monastery.
You look concerned,
Your Grace?
Is something wrong?
No, Brother John.
You are unhappy here?
No, perhaps I'm too happy.
Can I help?
No, only God can help.
Lord,
what do you
really want me to do?
To remain here, a poor monk
in simplicity of spirit,
is it a path to bring
me nearer to you?
Or is to easy a way,
perhaps even a luxury?
The path to holiness
in this monastery
is too effortless.
I think it would be too
easy to buy you like this.
Bargain price.
It has pleased you
to make me Archbishop
and to set me
like a solitary pawn
face to face with the
King on the chessboard.
I think you mean me
to defend your honor,
peacefully if I can
with argument
and with compromise
and if I cannot
then with the full
challenge of my office
and the soaring force
of what I know to be right.
So,
I shall take up
the miter again
and the golden cope
and the great silver cross
and I shall go back
and fight with the weapons
it has pleased you to give me.
All the rest,
thy will be done.
Look, Thomas,
your King awaits you.
I'm glad you weren't born
on this side
of the channel, Thomas,
you'd have been
a thorn in my side too.
How did you bewitch me
into doing this for you?
I convinced you that if
the King and I reconciled
he will be placed
in your debt.
True.
Why does he hate you so?
He's never forgiven me
for preferring God to him.
Go, Thomas.
You know, it's
a strange thing
but Becket's safety has
become quite dear to me.
You look older, Thomas.
So do you, My Prince.
Are you cold?
I'm frozen stiff,
chilblains are killing me.
You love it of course,
you're in your
element, aren't you,
just that Monk's habit.
I always told you
one must fight the cold
with the cold's weapons.
Strip yourself naked
every morning and...
splash yourself with cold water.
I used to,
when you were
there to make me.
I never wash now, I stink.
How's your son?
he must have come of age.
He's an idiot
and sly like his mother.
Thomas, don't you ever marry.
You took that
matter out of my hands
when you had me ordained.
If we start on that
we're sure to quarrel.
Talk about something else.
Very well.
Has Your Majesty
done much hunting lately?
Yes, every day.
It doesn't amuse me anymore.
Becket, I'm bored.
My Prince,
I wish I could help you.
What are you waiting for?
For the honor of God
and the honor of the
King to become one.
That may take long.
Yes, that may take long.
I'm the King, Thomas,
and so long as
we are on this earth,
you owe me the first move.
I'm prepared to
forget a lot of things
but not the fact
that I am King.
You yourself taught me that.
Never forget it, My Prince,
you have
a different task to do,
you have to steer the ship.
And you, what do
you have to do?
To resist you
with all my might
when you steer
against the Lord God.
What do you expect of me then?
Are you hoping I'll weaken?
No.
I'm afraid we must only do
absurdly, what it has
been given to us to do
right to the end.
Look suppose we
come down to earth
and use words that make sense
to a bore like myself
otherwise we'll
never get anywhere.
And there'll be
two frozen statutes
trying to make their peace
in a frozen eternity.
My Lord, I was doing my best
to make you understand.
I'm an idiot then,
talk to me like an idiot.
Will you lift
the excommunication
you pronounced
on Lord Gilbert?
No, because it's the
only weapon I have left
to defend what was
given into my care.
Will you agree to
the ten proposals
which the Bishop's
accepted in your absence,
particularly, to the
surrender of priests
who seek the
protection of the church
to escape
my courts of justice?
No.
My role is to defend my sheep
and they are my sheep.
But I shall agree to
the nine other articles
in the spirit of peace
and because I know
you must remain King
in all and of all,
save the honor of God.
All right,
I will give way
on this one point
in memory of
our past friendship.
You may return to England.
Thank you, My Prince.
I meant to go back in any case
and give myself
up to your power.
For in all things
that concern this earth,
I owe you obedience.
We're finished now,
and I'm cold.
I feel cold too,
now.
You never loved
me did you, Thomas?
In so far as
I was capable of love,
yes, I did.
Did you start to love God?
You mule!
Answer a simple question!
Yes.
I started to love
the honor of God.
I should never have seen you.
It hurts too much.
My Prince.
No, no pity,
it's dirty.
This is the last time
I shall come begging to you.
Go back to England.
Farewell, My Prince.
I sail tomorrow.
I know that I shall
never see you again.
How dare you say that to me
when I've given
you my royal word.
Do you take me for a traitor?
Thomas!
Sit.
Come here you.
Sit here.
You look to me, sir,
not your mother.
Sit, you witless baboon.
What is the meaning of this?
Henry, what are you doing?
I know very well
what I'm doing madam.
Out.
Before you fill your bellies,
we have something to announce.
Reviving an ancient custom,
we have decided
to have our successor
crowned in our lifetime.
We do this to
protect the kingdom
from future
pretenders to the throne.
Henry, this...
Shut up.
Stop dribbling while
I raise you to glory.
To my successor,
Henry the III.
When will the
coronation take place?
As soon as we
arrive in England.
Where, may I ask?
You may well ask.
At York.
Not at Canterbury?
My good mother, gentlemen,
is hinting with her
customary delicacy
that there is a double
purpose to this mummery.
There is.
We are going to show
our freshly
reinstated Archbishop
that we can still
do without him.
A coronation of
the English King
is the most jealously guarded
privilege of Canterbury.
I'd give anything
to see Becket's face
when he learns he's lost it,
and that York has got it.
That will fix him.
Get out of there,
you young cretin,
you're not crowned yet.
What a look.
Filial devotion
is a beautiful thing.
You'd like to
be the real king,
wouldn't you, you little pig.
With that number
three after your name
and papa good and
stiff in his tomb.
Well, you'll have
to wait a bit.
Papa is well,
papa is very well indeed.
My son, you know
I've always been against
any reconciliation
with that wretch Becket.
You know I understand
your hatred for him,
but do not let it lead
you into an action,
which you may
bitterly regret.
This boy is not clever
ambitious men will
use him against you
long before you
cease to reign.
I'm still very
much alive, madam,
and in control.
Henry, for all our
sakes, think of England
and not of your disappointed
love for this man.
Love?
A moment ago it was hate.
And what gives
you the right madam
to meddle in my
loves and hates?
You have an
obsession about him,
which is unhealthy
and unnatural,
and now that he no
longer gives you comfort...
Oh, God.
If Thomas Becket
were a faithless woman,
you'd behave no differently.
Sweet Jesus, you tear
him out of your heart.
Oh, if I were a man.
Thank God, madam,
he gave you breasts.
An asset from which I derived
not the slightest benefit.
I was let out to be
suckled by a peasant girl.
That no doubt
is why it is so difficult
to see the king
beneath your crown.
So you have something
to add my lady.
Well go on, add it,
add it, get it out of you,
once and for all
in one great whine.
Let's hear the poison
you've accumulated.
I pity you.
I tolerated your
mistresses, sir,
but do you expect me
to tolerate everything?
Becket!
Always Becket!
I am a woman,
I am your wife,
I am a Queen!
I'll complain to my father!
I'll complain to
my uncle the Emperor!
all the Kings of Europe!
I'll complain to God!
If I were you, madam,
I'd start with God!
Go to your chapel
and see if he's at home!
Get out the pack of you.
I wretch with boredom
at the sight of you!
To the devil,
with my whole family
if he'll have you!
And as for you,
young Henry the III,
here's my royal foot
up your royal buttocks!
Ah,
that's better.
Let us drink, gentlemen.
Let us drink,
till we roll under the table
in vomit and oblivion.
My faithful hounds.
It's warm beside you,
like beasts in a stable.
Good sweat.
Comfortable nothingness.
Not the least glimmer inside
to spoil the fun.
And to think before
I met Becket I was like you,
a well oiled machine,
for belching,
whoring and punching heads.
What did you put
in mine, Thomas,
That stopped the machine?
Tell me, do you ever think?
Never, Sire,
a gentleman has
better things to do.
Here, drink up.
What's the news from England?
Has Becket landed?
He has landed, Sire.
Was no one there
to receive him,
Lord Gilbert for example?
Oh, he was there,
damned and
excommunicated as he still is.
But there were
seven bishops there
charging his soldiers
not to cause bloodshed
and give the light
of the safe conduct
you gave Becket.
Yes,
I gave him safe conduct.
The peasants escorted him
from village to village.
They cheered him
all the way to Canterbury.
Not a single gentleman,
not a single Norman
showed his face.
Only Saxons?
Yes.
Swarms of them.
Becket left
England a fugitive,
an exile.
He's returned there
to find an affection
that people have always saved
for their king.
A man who ate my bread.
A man I raised from nothing.
A man I loved.
Yes,
I loved him.
I loved him,
and I still do.
Enough, oh God, enough.
Stop.
I can do nothing,
I'm as useless as a woman.
So long as he's alive,
I tremble,
I shake.
I'm the king,
and yet I shake.
Will no one rid me
of this meddlesome priest?
A priest who mocks me.
Are all around me cowards,
like myself?
Are there no men
left in England.
It's my heart.
It's too fast,
too fast,
it's too...
Thomas.
Make haste.
It's difficult with
all these little laces,
it warrants a woman's hands.
A man's hands
are better today.
What's worth doing,
is worth doing well.
Yes.
If it's worth doing,
it's worth doing well.
Do up all the laces,
every one of them.
I must look my best today.
God will give us time.
There, that's done.
But I just as soon had cleaned
out our pigsty at home,
it's not half
so much hard work.
Are you fond of your pig?
Yes, I was.
At my father's house
we had some pigs too
when I was a child.
Did you now?
Will it...
be today?
It's possible, my son.
Are you afraid?
Oh, no,
not if I have time to fight.
All I want is the chance
to strike a few blows first,
so I shan't have done nothing
but receive them all my life.
If I can kill one
Norman first, just one,
that'll seem fair
and right enough to me.
Are you so set
in killing one?
Yes, I am.
I don't mind if I am
just a grain of
sand in a machine
because I know
by putting more and more
grains of sand in a machine,
one day it'll come
grinding to a stop.
And on that day,
what then?
Well, we'll have a fine,
new, well oiled machine
in place of the old one,
and this time we'll put
the Normans into it instead.
That's what justice
means, doesn't it?
Now give me my silver cross,
I must hold it.
My Lord, it's heavy.
A good swipe with this
and they'd feel it.
Lucky little Saxon,
for you that would
settle all accounts
in this black worid,
wouldn't it?
There Lord,
I am ready,
adorned for your festivities.
Come,
let us go to the altar.
Your Grace.
There are armed
men at the doors.
I bolted the doors but...
It's time for vespers.
Does one bolt the
doors during vespers,
I've never heard of it?
But Your Grace?
Open them.
Everything must
be as it should be
for divine service.
It is here now,
the supreme folly,
this is its hour.
One does not carry
arms into God's house.
What do you want?
Your death.
We will continue
with the service.
Saxon!
Dog!
Traitor!
Oh Lord,
how heavy thy
honor is to bear.
Poor, Henry.
Thank you.
Yes, yes, it was all agreed.
I forgive you, pigs.
Saxon pigs.
They certainly wanted
their money's worth.
Is there a
large crowd outside?
Yes, Sire.
There's nothing more
certain to win them over
than the sight of
a king doing penance
and humbling himself
under the lash.
The honor of God, gentlemen,
is a very good thing
and all things considered
one gains by having
it on one's side.
Thomas Becket our friend,
always used to say so.
Tonight in council,
we will determine
what punishment
his murderers should receive.
Sire, they are unknown.
Our justice will
seek them out,
you may be sure.
It is a time my dear Barons,
for all of us to do penance.
Hear me!
People of Canterbury
and citizens of England.
As I have submitted
myself to the lash,
so have I petitioned the Pope.
And this day,
I have received his answer.
Thomas Becket,
former Archbishop
of Canterbury
and martyr to the cause
of God and his church
shall henceforth be honored
and prayed to in this kingdom
as a saint.
Is the honor of God
washed clean enough?
Are you satisfied now, Thomas?