Come on, come on.
Where the hell have you been?
Late.
That I figured.
Honey, this is
a big deal for me.
Well, Hendricks had the keys to the
jeep and I couldn't find the spares.
Terrific. Listen,
do me a favor
act as if you've been
here the whole time.
How do I do that?
Just look bored.
Thank you, Amity High School Band
for that eloquent selection.
We're happy once again...
Mama, Michael won't talk to me.
What are you doing here, tiger?
Mrs. Silvera couldn't come.
It's okay. It's okay.
And now, this year's Miss Amity,
Tina Wilcox...
...will cut the ribbon,
officially opening
this luxurious new hotel.
This money tree,
you may have noticed,
is donated by Len Peterson,
the builder of Amity
Shores Condominiums,
as a gesture of goodwill
towards the community.
Let's hear it for Len.
Thank you, Len.
$1,500 as a special gift to
the Amity Scholarship Fund.
Go ahead, Tina. Cut it.
Atta girl.
And now the Amity High Schoo!
Band once again.
Refreshments on
the patio, everyone.
Oh, boy.
Let's go get it.
Brody, how are you?
Hey, Len, how are you?
Hello, Martin.
I think it went well.
Oh, hell of a speech, Larry.
Terrific. Larry, it was
right on the money.
Thank you very much, Len.
Oh, Len, have you
met my son, Larry?
No, no.
Larry Junior.
Uh, Larry, would you
get over here, please?
Don't go away.
Here we go, Larry.
Say hello to Len.
How you doing?
Hi, Lar.
- Hi.
Nice lookin' boy.
Thank you.
Ellen.
Honey, would you be a love,
make sure that the bar is open
and everyone is taken
care of and happy? Hmm?
Happy. Sure.
Yes, sir, fantastic lady.
Don't know what
I would do without her.
Really? Neither do I.
How old is your cousin?
She's 17.
She's a senior.
I'm not crazy about blind dates.
Oh, they're okay if they got
little white canes and tin cups.
That's awful.
Oh, what the hell.
Did your mom
put all this together?
Yeah, it's her job.
Did she make the punch?
No.
Good. It's terrible.
Do you dance?
Nope.
Me neither.
Who you gonna ask next?
Tina Wilcox.
Ed's girlfriend.
You're crazy.
It doesn't hurt to ask.
Sometimes the most beautiful
girls are the loneliest.
That's a crock of shit!
I know.
Was it the fourth or fifth
night at the Jersey shore?
It was the fourth.
I thought you
wouldn't respect me.
I did. I did.
Why don't we get outta here?
Want to fool around?
Why not?
You're on.
This pipe has
more barnacles than you do.
What are you doing?
I told you...
Brush it off to your left.
Your other left.
Hey, I thought you're
supposed to be off duty.
Well, good morning.
Till noon.
This is on my own time.
Hey, Chief?
Yeah?
You got a gold-plater
in the main channel.
A big cruiser.
Whereabouts?
Off the Point.
No running lights.
Just a diver's flag.
Want me to run out there?
Yeah, would you? I can't run
this damn thing anyway.
Happy to do it.
Okay, I'll see you
back at the office.
And take the old man
of the sea with you.
All right, cast off the bowline.
And then cast off
the stern line.
the spring line. Let's go!
Look, we're only gonna be
here for a few minutes
and then we're gem' out.
Can't I come with you?
No.
Please? He can come
with me if he wants.
Yay!
No!
No yav?
No yay-
Boo, off the boat, brat.
Oh, he can help me
at least then. Come on.
Boo. Big brothers.
Hey, Sean, you ever
been an anchor before?
Come on! Whoa!
Hey, Mike, m.
Hi.
Going out right away?
No.
Good. I want you
to meet my cousin.
Look, don't worry, I'll meet her.
I'll meet her.
Okay, Tom, see you later.
Same time Thursday-
Hey, Andy!
Over here!
See you guys later!
What do we got?
What's the problem?
Uh, what isn't?
Brooke?
Brooke!
Jackie, hi!
Quick, quick, quick, who's that?
I think I'm in love.
Yeah, I hope that's the cousin.
Lucky, lucky, lucky, lucky!
Hey, Tim, did you see the
way she was looking at you?
Oh, she wants you, man.
No, she wasn't looking at me.
What are you saying? She was
staring at you and drooling.
No! I'm thin,
I wear glasses.
I live in Amity
Island year 'round.
I'm not good enough for her.
I guess you're right.
Probably wasn't lookin' at you.
Oh, Larry, look!
Larry, look!
What?
Look at her!
So glad to see you.
Oh, hi. Thanks.
She's got tits like a sparrow.
Do you have to talk like that?
What are you, my mother?
Will you undo the jib?
We're all going sailing.
Sailing?
Yeah, come on. I want
you to meet this guy.
Okay.
He's so cute.
Hey, look, I'm walking.
Leave him alone! He's tannin'
the soles of his feet-
Mike, over here!
Douglas!
I can't watch the news anymore,
I can't watch a ballgame anymore,
I can't even watch a movie!
All I hear is that damn
kid and his damn radio
gem', “Breaker,
breaker, breaker.“
Well, listen,
I'll do what I can,
but remember it's under
federal jurisdiction.
Well, call the FBI, will you?
Chief Brody, can I talk
to you for a minute?
Okay, one at a time,
one at a time.
Now, you two talk to Miss
Polly and you come with me.
Every time it's an out of
state car in my driveway...
Now, uh, what's this
about Grace Kinney?
Her bedroom window faces
my oldest boy's bedroom.
And she's teasing him.
She's dancing, dancing
around in her towel!
Dancing, huh?
Oh, Hendricks. Good, right this way.
Excuse us, please.
Now I want you to come in
here and check out this 908.
What the hell's a 908?
I never heard of a 908.
908 means get me outta
there-What's that?
A diver's camera. Tom
Andrews brought it up
from under the
abandoned cruiser.
Oh, the abandoned cruiser?
A couple of rich guys. Home
is Newport, Rhode Island.
You know, if I had
a $100,000 boat,
I wouldn't leave
it in the Channel.
If you had a $100,000 boat,
there'd be an investigation.
Very funny.
Grace Kinney is driving
my boy to distraction.
Dancing. You wanna check
out this dance for me?
Dance?
Wanna go back up?
Now back up, Mike!
Mike, it's twisted!
Underneath you, Mike.
Drop it down now.
Are you okay?
You okay?
Get down, Mike!
The weather
continues to be warm and clear.
And now back to the
music 24 hours a day
from Plymouth,
the rock of New England.
Wait. Take a break
for a minute, okay?
Hey, Tina?
Where you goin'?
Hey!
Eddie, come on, let's go skiing.
What's up?
What?
Come on, we can
use my uncle's boat.
Let's do it next week,
all right?
God, with you
everything is next week!
Terry?
WOW!
God!
I can't find anyone out here.
They must've gone to the bottom
or drifted with the tide.
Well, I've got witnesses that say
there was one person in the boat
and one person water skiing.
I told you, nothing here.
Well then, I want
you to try dragging.
For how long? Current's
moving everything around
and it's gonna be
dark pretty soon.
I don't care. I want you to
stay on it as long as it takes.
Ten-four.
We heard this noise like a boom,
and when we looked
there was this cloud of smoke.
That was the explosion.
One minute they were having a
wonderful time and the next...
And you've no idea what
could have caused this?
I don't know what
could have done that.
Were they
off-islanders?
I don't know.
Can we go now?
Chief?
Chief Brody, can we go, please?
Yes, thank you, Tina.
We've been over
this a dozen times.
I know, I know!
How much longer?
Until we find something.
I'm cold, bored!
You're bored?
Holy shit!
Jesus, this is heavy.
Aw, shit, drop it!
Well, what is it?
Drop it!
It's a power line.
Aw, terrific!
Let me untangle it.
We don't want a power
blackout on the island.
Let's get outta here
before we do find something.
That's your third smoke already.
With coffee.
Try a doughnut.
I want Fruit Loops.
Eat Cheerios.
You eat Cheerios.
I want Fruit Loops.
What are you guys up to today?
I don't know about him,
but I'm goin' sailing.
Again?
Well, what else is there to do?
How about that job you
were supposed to get?
Do I have to?
He doesn't really have to.
I mean, this is his vacation.
I wonder where I
left my date book.
Good morning.
Everybody up early today?
Something going on
I shouldn't know about?
Lots.
Look, this kid is 17.
We've talked about him
getting a job before.
I know, you're right.
I wish you could spend some time with him.
Take a half day off?
How can I? I'm in the
middle of a boat accident.
I've only got three regular
cops and a secretary.
And a deputy who's fallen in
love with the police launch.
And here's another one.
I mean, what is it
about this place?
Everybody's a boat freak.
It's an island.
I'm going.
Hold It, wait a minute.
I don't want you to go out
too far if it gets rough.
We've had a lot of
trouble out there.
Okay, I'll see you later.
I mean, be careful.
I'll be careful,
I'll be careful.
Tina, come back here.
Nope!
Come on.
Give me my hat!
Double nope!
Come on, Tina!
Come back here!
I wonder why they
decided to move?
Too hot in the lighthouse.
Too hot for those two?
I can't believe it.
Yuck!
I called you as soon
as I heard about this
because I hear the bites are big.
Really big.
Well, after we've
looked, we'll talk.
- All right.
- Here it is.
Uh, could you move back, please?
Could we have a little air?
That's right, move back.
Please just move
back? Thanks.
Jesus.
What do you think?
First things first.
Tip of the snout, please.
Length? Seven
and a half meters.
Seven and a half meters.
Correct.
You better check
the bite radius.
The what?
The shape of the mouth.
The whale's mouth?
Shark's mouth.
What shark?
The shark that did this.
But we don't know that, do we?
That's what we're
here to find out.
And we will.
Now, I can't hear you if you're
going to whisper.
111 centimeters.
Sixty-eight.
I have had some
experience with sharks.
Oh, have you?
Yeah, and I think...
I think a great white
might've done this.
Carcharodon carcharias?
Right.
What makes you think there
might be one in these waters?
Well, it's obvious that...
That a big fish took
a bite outta this big fish.
This is a mammal, not a fish.
Don't quibble with me. Is it
a shark bite or isn't it?
Possibly.
Then again,
this is a killer whale.
It would have to be a shark
of considerable size.
Look, we know that sharks
are attracted by blood
and thrashing about.
And sound.
Sound?
Sound. Like
sonar or radar.
They hone in on unusualsounds,
irregular sounds,
almost any rhythmic
low-frequency vibration-.
That means that there
could be one around.
Not necessarily.
These wounds could have been inflicted
15 miles out to sea or more.
None of them were
immediately fatal.
Currents could have carried
the body 10 miles further.
We got a hell
of a tide this month.
Will you just take care
of the crowd, please?
Dad?
Mr. Hendricks, will you
take this down, please?
No more sailing today, okay?
And I'd like you to
come back with me.
We came out in my boat.
Yeah, but Andy“ take K bash!
I got a date.
She'll understand.
No, she won't.
Mike, for Christ's sakes, give
me a break here, will you?
Seventy-two centimeters,
allowing for salt water erosion
and subsequent small
predator tissue attacks.
It's either a great white
or another killer whale.
Well, I'd like to know which.
Well, it's impossible for me to
tell when the body's like this.
This animal has been
ashore for 10 or 12 hours
and drifting for a day at least.
Every little nibbler in
the sea's taken a bite.
I know that
dolphins communicate.
I mean, they send signals.
You don't think that
if a shark was destroyed,
that another shark could...
Could come and...
Sharks don't take things
personally, Mr. Brody.
Dad, can I please take my... No!
Hey, look, don't worry about it.
I'll take it back and
tie it up at the dock.
Bye, Mike, see you later.
I'm sorry.
It'll be okay, Mike. I'll see
you tomorrow. All right?
I appreciate it. Thanks.
Larry? Larry,
wait a minute.
I'm showing summer rentals.
I think we have a hell of a
good season going for us.
That's swell, Larry, but I
have to talk to you alone.
We're alone.
I think we may have
another shark problem.
Are you serious?
You bet I'm serious.
I've got a half-eaten
whale out on the beach.
I've got two persons missing.
This whale has got a bite
out of it about this big.
Martin, no one has seen
a shark. Be realistic.
I think the selectmen
should know about it.
I know it's just a feeling,
but you've got to understand.
Larry, for Christ sakes,
I not only have this attack,
but I've got... I've got two
water skiers who have...
A tragedy.
But a boating accident.
No fin, no sharks,
nothing but a boating accident.
But their boat's still missing.
We have a lot of deaths in these
waters that never turn up.
Are they all shark victims?
Maybe they are.
Oh, bullshit!
Bullshit?
Is it bullshit I got a whale on the
beach with a bite in it this big?
What am I, an ass?
When you called me, I called
Elkins and her bosses.
Nothing she saw is
proof of anything.
So that means we're not
gonna do anything, huh?
Martin, don't press
it this time.
Well, I've got to
get back to work.
Okay.
Okay, Larry, but you just
remember this conversation.
You just remember it!
Chief?
Yeah?
Chief? Hi.
Missed you at the funeral home.
Santos said you'd be here.
Yeah. Christ,
what a mess.
You didn't miss much.
Positive ID?
Well, we're pretty sure
it was the woman
aboard the boat, all right.
Yeah?
Thank you, operator,
just keep trying.
Anything new on
those two divers?
Nothing.
I think we ought to keep
sight-seers away from there.
Did you take a look
at that stuff in that box?
No.
How about that camera?
Might be something in it.
Yeah, right.
Why don't you take it over to
Fogarty's and get it developed?
I'll do it first
thing in the morning.
Why not now?
It's too late.
Christ, I'm late for dinner.
Listen, I'm expecting
a long distance call.
When it comes through, have them send
it over to the house, all right?
Okay, Chief.
Yes. Yes,
I can hear you.
Yes, I will. I'll give
him the message.
Thank you. MIKE: All right, now.
Look out.
That for me?
Oh, got it.
Hi, Dad.
Hi, gang.
Well, sort of.
Matt Hooper.
He's on the research
vessel Aurora,
presently in
the Antarctic Ocean,
and he won't be in radio
range till next spring.
Yeah, I gave him a call.
- Got you.
- Your point.
Martin?
Yeah?
You're a mess.
Where were you?
I had to go over to Santos', I dragged
a body outta the ocean today.
Ugh.
Do you have any
idea what happened?
No, we don't know.
Santos seems to
think it might be one of
the victims from
that boat accident.
Do you wanna talk about it?
No.
Just routine.
Okay.
Hey, Mike, come here a minute.
Yeah? What is it?
I've got something
for you to do tomorrow.
Well, I kind of had plans.
What, sailing?
Oh, no, forget it. You're grounded.
Beached. That's it.
Hey, come on, Dad. BRODY: I
talked to John down at the beach.
He's got a job that's gonna last
right till you
go back to school.
Hey, that's all of summer.
I know it's all summer, but he
wanted a job and now he's got one.
I want that boat out of the
water by tomorrow night.
Dad, please,
can I just take it out...
By tomorrow night.
And I mean it!
Now, everybody here?
Just about.
Okay. Terrific.
Now, folks,
this is the town beach.
Now, the development naturally
has its own private access,
but what I wanted you to really
see was the concession area,
and take a look at this sand.
- It's like sugar.
- It's beautiful.
- Hmm?
- It really is.
You know, in the summer
time when the sun sets,
it goes right down there and the
whole beach looks incredible.
It really is. It can
be absolutely breathtaking.
I think you'll find this little
bandstand very interesting.
And, uh, we take quite
a bit of pride in this.
It was built in about...
Hello. Selling some
more of the good life?
Oh, yeah, piece of
this, piece of that.
It all adds up.
Your husband's been here all morning.
What's he doing?
His job.
Dad's got you working, huh?
- Yeah.
- I'm helping.
Good.
Do you happen to
know where your dad is?
Yeah, he's up there.
Oh, for Christ sake!
Well, if you have any questions,
any questions at alt about
recreational possibilities,
our lovely Ellen Brody here will
be only too happy to answer them.
Yeah, Len, Len.
Can I speak to you for a minute?
Sure. Excuse me
a moment, please.
Okay, anybody
have any questions?
Larry, I think we've got
a couple of live ones.
Brady's riding his tower.
Oh, shit!
Whoo! Let's go.
Let's go faster.
You got it, sweetheart!
Come on! Whoa!
Yeah.
This fast enough for you?
No, faster!
Faster?
Faster!
Hey, look, there's my dad.
Wave. Wave to my son.
Good.
How the hell do we
get him down from there?
Well, maybe nobody noticed.
Let's get 'em all
back in the van, huh?
Yeah, come on.
Renee wants to know, what's
that man doing way up there?
Man? What man?
Oh, he's, uh, watching.
You know, a lookout.
For what?
It's a shark tower.
I saw one in Florida.
He's looking for sharks.
Excuse me, dear, it's an
observation platform.
That's our chief of police,
he's just checking it.
That's right.
You see, normally it's used
for bird watching, you know?
Uh, weather,
uh, measurements and,
uh, nature observation,
that sort of thing.
Ellen, excuse me, uh...
Ellen, we're running
a little late, Ellen.
Well, if we can all
get back in the bus,
maybe we could show you the country
club and the flower shows.
Right. You see, uh,
the country club has...
Outta the water!
Outta the water now!
Everybody out!
Get out! Get outta there!
Get out!
Out of the water!
What the hell is
that idiot doing?
Everybody out!
Get outta there! Get out!
Everyone out!
Out of the water!
Get out! Get out!
Get outta the water!
Get out!
Get out! Get out!
It's just blue fish.
Blue fish! Geez!
It's a school of blue fish.
It's just blue fish!
Martin!
Ellen, Ellen, Ellen.
It's all right.
Leave him alone.
Let's not make
it worse. Come on.
Okay, folks, it's
all over. Come on.
Let's get back to the truck, all right?
Let's break it up.
It's... It's okay.
It's just...
It's a false alarm!
It's all right, go back!
Oh, my God.
Come on, let's go. It's over.
Break it up. Come on.
Polly, no calls now, huh?
Fogarty?
Okay, put him on.
Yeah, Phil.
What pictures?
You're kidding.
I'll be right over.
Yeah.
This is the Orca.
Good lens, too.
Fast. One-four, I think.
You notice that
diffusion over there?
Look, Phil, don't jerk me around.
What else have you got?
Over here. I exposed
another bunch this morning
but I haven't had a chance
to develop 'em yet.
That's it.
That's the one.
Well, speak of the devil.
Martin, this is kind of
an official meeting.
Oh, good, I'm glad
you're all here.
I've got something to
show you. Look at this.
Fogarty just developed it.
It came out of that camera
from the missing divers.
Seaweed?
I don't know.
What is it?
It's underwater, isn't it'?
That's why it's so dark.
It's nothing I can see.
What are you talking about?
Look at this.
That's a shark!
Look at the outline.
Look at the mouth! The eyes!
Is that what it is?
Sorry, I just don't see it.
Neither do I, it's nothing.
Martin, it could be anything.
Oh, no, no, no. Waita minute.
Are you people telling me
I don't know what
a shark looks like?
Brody, this is nothing. Seaweed,
mud, something in the lens?
(Lens my ass).!
You're dammed
right it's your ass!
Now, uh, be
reasonable. Please.
Reasonable with what?
With him?
God damn it, will you
listen to the man?
Will you just listen to him?
Be reasonable?
Look, Brody,
you started a panic
on a public beach.
You shot up the damn place!
God knows who you
could've injured.
Now, what if somebody
decides to sue us?
Did you ever stop
to think about that?
It could ruin us!
You don't have to worry about
being sued, or being ruined.
If this turns out to
be what I think it is,
because there
won't be anybody here.
Yeah. Now, Martin,
let's not, uh...
Let's not what?
Larry, what?
Oh, Jesus. Larry, huh, come on?
Let's just forget it!
He won't listen!
Now, it's obvious the man
has made up his mind.
You bet your life
I've made up my mind.
But I'm telling you, and
I'm telling everybody
at this table that
that's a shark!
And I know what
a shark looks like,
because I've seen one up close.
And you'd better do
something about this one,
because I don't intend
to go through that hell again!
Martin.
Could you wait
here for a minute?
For what?
Please, just have a seat
while we look at the picture
and make up our own minds.
All right.
I'll have a seat.
For what it's worth.
Thank you.
Gentlemen, please.
Yeah!
Hey, Mike, saw your dad
over at the Town Hall.
I know.
Hey, did he really freak
out on the town beach?
I don't know.
Hey, don't worry about them,
it's all bullshit, anyway.
Hey, Ellen,
you know this is
the only dump in town
where the garbage man delivers?
Hey, does anybody wanna
go to the lighthouse?
Now? At night?
Tomorrow. Maybe
spend the day?
My dad left a couple of cases
of beer in the garage.
Is it Still there?
Well, it's kind of
vacationing on my boat.
All right!
Hey, Mike, you gonna go?
Yeah, why not?
Because you might be painting
toilets at the beach.
Very funny.
Hey, are we gonna have a picnic?
Yeah. You
bring the food.
Mike?
Hi.
I'd like to go to
the lighthouse with you.
Well, I'm not sure I can go.
I'm beached. I'm grounded-My dad
won't let me take my boat out.
Do you always do what
your parents tell you to?
No.
Good. Then I'll be
at the dock at 8:00.
8:00, everybody.
I don't know what I'd do.
Hey, what is this?
A wake for a funeral?
You surprised us.
Chief, I walked over as
soon as I heard about it.
They only fired me,
they didn't bury me.
Hello, baby, I'm home.
I know.
I know you know.
Listen, I got something for you.
This is gonna look
better on you, than on me,
because you're
a snappier dresser.
Oh, hey, you're
drinking the good stuff.
How about a toast?
A toast to the new chief.
Yeah.
Come on, Ellen, the new chief is
gonna need all the luck he can get.
No? Okay.
We'll do it together.
A toast to the new chief!
Hail to the chief.
Well, go on,
drink, for Christ sakes,
it's a milestone in your career.
Ease up, Martin.
Look, Chief,
not only don't I want your job,
but I came over to tell you that
I think you're the greatest.
And I...
Oh, Jeff, it's okay.
Come on, it's not
your fault, I know that.
Well, I gotta go anyway.
Thank you for coming by, Jeff.
You've really been a big help.
Thank you.
Good night, Jeff.
Good night.
Poor Hendricks.
They'll fire his ass, too.
You'll see.
Showed 'em
a picture of that shark.
They didn't see it.
They see only
what they wanna see.
But it's out there all right.
It's a big mother, too.
Is that why they fired you?
It wasn't just that.
Well, what was it?
The scene at the beach?
I was there,
I saw what happened.
Oh, I blew it. I blew it!
I shot off my mouth, I shot off my gun.
Four years down the drain.
Shot to hell.
What a dummy.
What else?
I never been fired before.
You know that?
I mean, once... Once when I was
17, when I was a kid, yeah,
but never from a real job.
Nobody...
Nobody ever told me
I couldn't hack it.
They're not saying that.
Yes, they are.
They are.
Maybe they're right.
I'm tired.
Tired.
Too damn tired.
Too damn drunk,
that's what you are.
Too dammed drunk.
Are you going out?
Yeah.
Are you going sailing?
Maybe.
Take me.
No.
I wanna go with you.
Quiet!
Michael!
All right, come on.
But be quiet.
Today's a better day.
Hello, Denise, love of my life.
If you're grounded, what are
we doing this for? Practice?
Yeah, practice.
Why are we here? Why don't
we go to the beach?
We can putz around, we can make
some money, pick up some girls.
Hey, look, if you're gonna get in
the way, you can just go home.
I'm not in the way.
Andy, am I in the way?
You're always in the way.
Is this guy causing you trouble?
Put me down!
Come on, you can
go out in my boat.
SEAN; Yeah!
You want him?
You can have him.
I think you just made
somebody very happy.
- Hi, guys.
- Hi.
Mike, you going out?
Yeah. I thought you
were grounded-
I can go out if I want to.
You can?
Is there enough room
for all of us on the boat?
Oh, I don't know, we're a
little over-crowded ...
Oh, yeah, we got plenty of room.
Here, come on aboard-
I guess so.
Brooke, I've got room.
Great.
You'll go with me?
Sure.
Thanks, guys, but I'm going with Timmy.
Come on.
Fantastic.
That's a big mistake.
Don't worry about it, all right?
Come on, you guys, I'm ready.
Hey, I thought you said
she was comin' with us?
Obviously she's not.
You wanna talk about it?
You wanna swim home?
Hey, Tom.
Hey, Nicholas, you're
supposed to be in class!
You dive for me.
I've got company.
I'm going for lobster!
Great! Bring me one!
I want mine drawn with butter.
You got that, Tom?
So long, turkeys.
Okay, Sparky's gonna
take you down today.
If everybody's ready,
let's buddy up and drop.
Get us in, for Christ sake!
Get us in!
Let's get him in
and keep him warm.
I think he'll be okay.
Okay.
Prepare the bowline.
Let's go!
Thank you.
So?
So I'll go down to the office, clean
out the desk, turn in the truck,
and maybe I'll get shitfaced and
rap your boss right in the mouth.
I think I better give notice.
Take it easy.
We may need the income.
Mike's gone.
He's breaking out
early these days.
He must be a morning man.
Like his father.
Good morning.
Hi.
Anything special today?
No. Sean must be out
playing somewhere.
Why don't you let him
have whatever he wants?
Okay.
Okay. Just keep him
away from the candy.
Am I still gonna get my ride?
Mmm.
Better call your
brother the plumber too.
That sink upstairs
is still screwed up.
Frankie? He's my cousin.
Ask him if he can
use an apprentice.
Have a nice day.
Do you wanna just leave
it pointed up like this?
Hold on a minute.
There we go.
Yeah, this is fine.
And what about sailing?
What about it?
Look, don't you worry.
We're gonna make It.
Yeah, we're gonna make it all the way
to Budapest if you're not careful.
Hey, what about the others?
What about them?
Look, I know the others'll
be there when we get there.
They'll have their bonfire and
blankets, clams, liquor...
Yeah?
Yeah, I suppose.
And what are we gonna
do in the meantime?
Well, in the meantime, we're gonna
have to think of something.
Wait a minute.
What?
Get out the blanket.
I got black and blue
marks all over my butt
and my mom's starting
to get uptight about it.
Okay. Out with
the blanket.
You really need a blanket, huh?
I don't need a blanket.
Hey, I can't come up with...
Or we could do something else.
Well.
Here's your blanket.
Eddie!
Help!
Tina!
Help me!
Tina.
Help!
Jesus!
Eddie, swim! Swim fast,
there's a shark, Eddie!
Swim!
Oh, God, Eddie, swim!
Faster! Hurry!
Come on, swim!
Hurry, Eddie, it's a shark!
Eddie, hurry, faster!
Come on, swim!
Hurry!
Hurry, Eddie!
Eddie!
Oh, Mama.
Please, make it go away.
Make it go away.
Make it go away!
Honey, it's not
your job anymore.
I know, I just
wanna take a look.
Come on, get outta there!
Come on, come on!
What happened?
Embolism. Air bubbles
in the blood.
He came up too fast, Chief.
He held his damn breath.
Something must have
scared him down there.
He just panicked.
Don't worry, we're taking good care of him.
Come on, Davidson.
Easy!
How did this happen?
Bite reflex.
Like a spasm.
Happened about an hour ago
right after the kids went out.
What kids?
Oh, Junior Vaughan, Brooke
Peters, Jackie, Mike, Andy.
Our Mike?
Yeah, they said they were
heading for the lighthouse.
Hey, where you goin'?
Look, Chief, you're
not chief anymore.
I can't let you take her out.
Mrs. Brody, look, if he
can't go then you can't go.
Neither one of you can go.
Ellen, get that line.
Chief, please.
Mike is out there.
But I've signed for the
boat. Mrs. Brody, please.
Aw, shit!
Chief, go on up to the bow.
You're doing all that wrong.
Go ahead, untie the bowline.
What the hell, they can't
fire both of us, right?
Somebody's gotta be in charge.
All right, which
direction you wanna go?
You said something
about a lighthouse.
- Let's go!
- All right.
Amity Launch
to Harbor Patrol, over.
This is Harbor Patrol.
Yeah, listen, Ed,
do you think you could
raise me a chopper?
Is that you, Brody?
Not right away.
They're out checking
a buoy in the channel.
I want you to get the chopper
out to the lighthouse.
There's some kids
day-sailing out there.
I want them
brought back to port.
Affirmative. Turn the kids
day-sailing back to port.
I heard you.
Patrol out.
Brody out.
Hurry up, suckers,
you're dragging.
Yeah, come on.
We're gonna lose you.
Hey, let's go
past the lighthouse.
I know a better spot.
Come about!
You got it!
I got it, Chief.
It's all right.
Come on. It's okay.
No!
Take it easy. Just take it easy.
You're all right.
You're all right. Ellen!
No!
It's all right.
Oh, Tina. Tina.
It's still there!
Tina, Tina, it's okay.
What's the matter? What's still there?
What's still there?
Shark!
Shark! Over there.
That boat's gonna take you in.
Where the hell are they?
About 10 degrees
off your starboard bow.
Take a heading
leeward of Sand Island...
Don't give me that shit, point!
There.
All right, I got it.
Mr. Christian. Mr. Christian.
Pump up this boat!
Shave off that
dreadful moustache.
England expects
every man to do his duty.
You may fire
when ready, Quigley.
Damn the torpedoes!
Full speed ahead.
This will be our finest hour.
Oh, shit!
Hey, Bligh, someone
pop your balloon?
It's no problem.
No problem.
Balance the boat!
All right, all right, all right.
Watch out! Marge!
Marge!
Kevin, do something!
Sean!
Timmy, Brooke!
Where is it?
Oh, I don't know.
Larry, get me outta here.
I'm gonna get you outta here.
Don't worry, I'm on my way!
Larry!
Turn!
God damn!
Let's get 'em outta the water.
Will you hurry up?
Mike's out there.
Hurry up.
Out of the water!
Somebody look out for Mike!
I can't feel my arms!
Hang on to something.
Mike!
Get outta there!
Come on, Mike!
Oh, my God!
Mike! Mike!
Brody!
Come on!
Let's hit it.
Okay, get his arms.
Oh, let's go.
Come on.
Get hold of his jacket.
Hurry up, please!
Get in!
Now, come on!
Come on!
Get him up!
Dave, help me!
He's bleeding pretty bad.
We gotta get Mike to a doctor!
Can you sail?
Yeah.
We'll take him in.
Then go for it and get
some help out here fast!
Let's go!
Okay, let's wrap this mess up!
Throw it to Brooke.
Brooke! Brooke, get this
and throw it to Marge!
Marge, here, take it.
Tie it forward around your mast.
Easy.
Let me help with that line.
Come on, Larry,
pull it, come on.
I don't know if it's gonna hold!
All right!
Somebody put a fender up.
I mean, we could use
another hand on this.
Take it easy, just pull.
Tie it off. All right.
Amity Launch to Air Patrol One.
Amity Launch to Air Patrol
One, do you read me?
This is Air Patrol.
Is that you, Brody?
Yeah. Listen, do you have
a fix on those kids yet?
Negative. I'm still down.
Well, you better get the hell up
because I'm out here all alone!
Brody, I gotta
switch frequencies.
Call my boss, I'll meet you
over by Francis Shoal.
Harbor Air out.
Francis Shoal? Where the
hell is Francis Shoal?
Shit!
I'm all alone out here!
Anybody wanna play charades?
No.
Listen, all we have to do is
land at Cable Junction and wait-
Yeah, and how are we gonna do
that floating on this garbage?
What's after Cable Junction?
The Atlantic.
Then Ireland.
God, I'm hungry.
Air Patrol to Base.
I have a positive location
on that sailing party.
Disabled and adrift,
about three quarters of a mile
west of Cable Junction.
Wind and tide carrying
them about due East.
Is everybody all right?
Is anybody hurt?
Now listen, I'm gonna give you
a tow to Cable Junction.
Then I'm gonna call the Coast
Guard to send a cutter.
Throw me a line!
Take it easy.
Here we go!
Oh, what a day!
Here you go!
Okay!
Now hold onto something.
Okay.
Better hang on.
No!
Bob!
Marge!
Sean!
Sean! Sean!
All right,
get him up in the boat!
Sean!
Bob! Come on!
Get him, Marge!
Get him!
Hurry! Come on,
get him up in the boat!
Come on!
Come on. Come on.
Will you pull me up?
I can't get up!
No!
No! No!
Take her to the hospital and
meet me back at the office.
On the double.
Ellen, try to
understand my position.
Tina's gonna be all right.
Are you okay?
Ellen, I'm sorry.
Believe me, I'm sorry.
I was only thinking
of everyone's interest in...
I don't give a damn
what you're thinking.
All I know is a boy is dead and my
son and husband are still out there!
Amity Launch to Harbor Patrol.
Amity Launch to Harbor...
Damn! Damn it!
Sean, catch the rope!
Come on, God damn it!
Come on, Sean.
Sean, try and catch the rope!
Sean, the rope!
Come on, Sean!
Come on, kid!
Sean!
Sean, catch the rope!
The rope, Sean.
Come on!
Come on, Sean!
Come on, he's gotta help
or it's not gonna work.
Well, will you stop?
Please.
Come on, Sean, wake up!
Look at us!
Sean!
Sean, God damn it!
God damn it,
Sean, you look at me
or I'll break your ass,
do you hear?
Okay, come on. Come on.
Okay. Okay.
Okay, Sean, now listen.
Listen now, we're gonna
throw you this rope
and you damn well
better catch it. You hear?
Okay, Sean, you ready?
Okay.
Here it comes, kid.
Get it, Sean!
Come on! Let's go!
Sean, get it!
Come on, get it.
Get it! Get it!
Good, good. Okay, now, tie
it around the center board.
Tie it tight!
Okay, you ready?
Hold on!
Hold onto that.
All right. All right.
Hang on, okay?
Here we go!
Hold on tight.
Okay, kid, okay.
Now take it easy.
Come on, come on.
Okay, let's do it!
Jesus Christ!
Get him out!
Come on! Come on,
get him outta the water!
Thank God!
You okay, kid?
I thought we lost you.
Cable Junction's ahead.
Can we make it?
I don't know!
Hey, I was just asking!
I don't know.
How's she doing?
Just gotta keep her warm.
Somebody give me a hand.
We might be able
to steer this thing.
What the hell are you guys
playing with the tiller for?
I mean, at 7:46
when this tide goes...
Hey, shut up!
I'm sorry, Larry, I can't
stop thinking about this!
Well, you better try!
Hey, come on!
God, please help us!
Jesus.
Holy Mary, Mother of Christ,
please help us.
Please, help us.
We're begging-
Please save us.
Jesus.
Oh, thank Christ!
Here, take that back
through to the cleat.
What happened?
I'm okay.
You sure?
A shark hit us.
Sean's out there.
What?
He wanted to come.
It's okay, wasn't it?
Where are they?
They're in the current drifting
towards Cable Junction.
All right.
You three get to the lighthouse
and stay there, you hear me?
Stay there.
I'm sorry, Dad.
I didn't know-That's all right.
Forget it now.
Just get to the lighthouse.
We're almost there!
I don't think it's gonna work.
Come on, Patrick, more to port.
Keep it goin'! Keep it goin'! We're
gonna make it. Just keep it turning.
We gotta land on it.
Come on, more to
port, God damn it!
It's all the way over.
Shit!
Larry! Larry, are we gonna
make it to the island?
We're steering for it, kid.
Yeah, but the
wind drift is lateral.
Oh, yeah, what does that mean?
It means that
we're going sideways.
For every yard we go that
way, we go that way a yard.
But we had It. We were
heading right for it.
We don't have it anymore.
Shit! Shit,
shit, shit, shit!
No, no, wait,
wait, stop paddling.
What about the island?
The shark!
What's happening?
I don't know.
I think we're stuck.
I think it's just the bottom.
Yeah.
No, it's that thing.
No, no, it's just the bottom.
No, it's not the bottom,
it's that thing.
I know it's gonna kill us!
It's gonna kill us!
Now, I know it!
Jackie, shut up!
No, it's gonna kill us!
That shark is gonna kill
all of us, Larry! Shut up!
Oh, leave her alone!
Leave her alone!
Then you take care of her,
you take care of her!
Look, Larry, she's hysterical!
Beating her head in is not gonna...
Sit down!
Knock it off, Larry.
She's crazy!
Be quiet!
Shut up!
Listen!
I know that she
shouldn't freak out!
Listen!
Do you hear it?
Over there!
It's coming towards us!
It's Dad. It's Dad!
Yay!
Come on! Come on!
Pull yourselves over. Gonna
get the hell out of here.
We can't.
We're stuck on the bottom here!
I'll get you closer.
Then you'll come aboard.
Just move alongside.
Please hurry!
All right, hold it steady.
Watt! Wait! Walt!
Dad!
I'm all right, hold on!
All right, take this!
And I'll try and get you over.
Right, tie it on!
Okay.
All right.
Pull these hooks
over with the rope.
And then secure
them to the raft!
And then I'll pull you back
with the winch. You got it?
Okay!
All right!
Now, pull it over!
It's stuck!
Wait a minute, I'll put...
I'll put it in reverse.
Lucy!
Lucy! Look out!
Oh, my God, no!
No!
Lucy! Lucy!
It's all right!
No!
Oh, my God!
Dad!
Hold on!
No!
Get away!
Jackie! Jackie!
Sean!
Dad!
Where is he?
No.
There he is!
There he is over there!
Chief!
What are you doing?
What is he doing?
Get outta there!
Chief, he's
heading right for you!
Watch out!
Come on, you big bastard!
Come on!
I got something for you now!
Chief!
That's it!
Atta boy! Come on!
Right over here!
Dad!
That's it! Come on!
Oh, no, get outta the way!
He's coming!
He's gonna take
hold of the wood!
Dad, watch out!
Come on!
Look out!
Come on, open wide!
Open wide!
Say "Ah!"
Oh, no!
He got him!
He did it! He did it!
Did you see it? He did it!
Did you get it?
It's dead?
It's dead!
Oh, thank you.
Thank you.
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
And you!
They made me go with 'em!
Sure they did.