♪♪ [ Drums, Piano: Fox Fanfare, Rock]
♪♪ [ Intro, Slow Tempo]
♪ Michael Rennie was ill ♪
♪ The day the Earth stood still ♪
♪ But he told us where we stand ♪
♪ And Flash Gordon was there ♪
♪ In silver underwear;
♪ Claude Rains was the Invisible Man ♪
♪ Then somethin' went wrong ♪
♪ For Fay Wray and King Kong ♪
♪ They got caught in a celluloid jam ♪
♪ Then at a deadly pace ♪
♪ It came from outer space ♪
♪ And this is how the message ran ♪
♪ Science fiction ♪
[ Chorus]
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Double feature ♪
jD/ZX/
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Will build a creature ♪
♪ See androids fighting ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Brad and Janety
♪ Anne Francis stars in ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
j Forbidden Planet}
♪ Whoa-oh, oh-oh, oh-oh ♪
♪ At the late-night ♪
♪ Double feature ♪
♪ Picture show;
♪ I knew Leo G. Carroll ♪
♪ Was over a barrel ♪
♪ When Tarantula took to the hills ♪
♪ And I really got hot;
♪ When I saw Janette Scott;
♪ Fight a triffid
that spits poison and kills ♪
♪ Dana Andrews said prunes ♪
♪ Gave him the runes ♪
♪ And passing them used lots of skills ♪
♪ But when worlds collide ♪
♪ Said George Pal to his bride ♪
♪ I'm gonna give you ♪
♪ Some terrible thrills ♪
♪ Like a;
♪ Science fiction ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Double feature ♪
jD/ZX/
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Will build a creature ♪
♪ See androids fighting ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Brad and Janety
♪ Anne Francis stars in ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
j Forbidden Planet}
♪ Whoa-oh, oh-oh, oh-oh ♪
♪ At the late-night ♪
♪ Double feature ♪
♪ Picture show;
♪ I wanna g0 ♪
♪ Whoa-oh, oh-oh ♪
♪ To the late-nighty
♪ Double feature ♪
♪ Picture show;
♪ By RKO;
♪ Whoa-oh, oh-oh, oh-oh ♪
♪ To the late-nighty
♪ Double feature ♪
♪ Picture show;
♪ In the back row;
♪ Oh-oh, oh-oh ♪
♪ To the late-nighty
♪ Double feature ♪
♪ Picture ♪
♪ Show f,”
♪♪ [ Organ: “Wedding March”]
[ Bells Ringing]
[ Photographer]
Here they come.
[ Guests Shouting, Cheering ]
[All Laughing, Chattering ]
[ Movie Camera Whirring ]
[ Photographer] I 'd like the
parents and the grandparents.
Yes, all the close family.
Smile! Hold that. Beautiful!
And... click!
[ Cheering, Laughing]
[Applause Continues]
Hey, Ralph. Congratulations.
[ Guests Chattering ]
[ Photographer]
Congratulations.
Bye-bye. See you.
Well, I guess
we really did it, huh?
I don't think there's any
doubt about that.
You and Betty have been almost inseparable
since you met in Dr. Scotfs refresher courses.
To tell you the truth, Brad, that was the
only reason I showed up in the first place.
[ Chuckles ] [Laughs] I mean-
Okay, you guys, this is it!
You ready?
[Women Clamoring ] Looks like
Betty's gonna throw her bouquet.
Ready?
Okay, here it comes!
Isqueann
I Qot it! g 1
I got it!
Hey, big fella.
[ Car Horn Hanks ] Looks like it
could be your turn next, hey?
Who knows?
So long. See you, Brad.
[ Ralph]
We'd better get going now, Betty.
Come on, hop in.
Good-bye, Betty!
Bye! Bye!
[ Guests Shouting, Chattering ]
See you, Brad.
[ Guests Shouting Good-byes ]
[ Shouting, Cheering ]
[ Woman ]
Bye, Betty!
Oh, Brad, wasn't it wonderful?
Didn't Betty look radiantly beautiful?
Oh, I can't believe it. An hour ago,
she was plain old Betty Munroe.
And now-
Now she's Mrs. Ralph Hapschatt.
[Sighs]
Yes, Janet. Ralph's a lucky guy.
Yes.
[Woman ]
Oh, I always cry at weddings.
Uh, everyone knows that Betty's
a wonderful little cook. Yes.
[ Crows Cawing]
Why, Ralph himself- he'll be in line
for a promotion in a year or two.
Yes.
Hey, Janet.
Yes, Brad?
I've got something to say.
Uh-huh?
♪ I really loved the-J
[ Thunder Rumbles ]
♪ Skillful way;
♪ You beat the other girls ♪
♪ To the bride's bouquet;
Oh. Oh, Brad.
[ Thunder Continues]
- ♪ The river was deep, but I swam it ♪
- [American Gothic Couple ] J~Janet ♪
♪ The future is ours so
let's plan it; j Janet,»
♪ So please don't tell
me to can it ♪ ♪ Janet ♪
♪ I've one thing to say
and that's dammit, Janet ♪
♪ I love you ♪
J The road was long but
I ran itJ J Janet J
- ♪ There's a fire in my heart
and you fan it ♪ - ♪ Janeij
♪ If there's one fool for
you then I am it; ♪ Janet ♪
♪ I've one thing to say
and that's dammit, Janet ♪
♪ I love you ♪
[Sighs]
Whoo!
♪ Here's the ring to prove
that I'm no joker)
[Ga
on: SD31
♪ There's three ways that love
can grow ♪
♪ That's good, bad ♪
[ Giggles ]
♪ Or mediocre ♪
Oh.
♪ on, J-A-N-E-T ♪
Oh!
J Oh, it's nicer than Betty Munroe
had J [Others ] J Oh, Brad J
♪ Now we're engaged and I'm
so glad ♪ ♪ Oh, Brad ♪
- ♪ That you met Morn and you
know Dad ♪ - ♪ Oh, Brad,»
♪ I've one thing to say
and that's, Brad, I'm mad ♪
♪ For you too ♪
♪ Oh, Brad J"
♪ Oh, dammit ♪
♪ I'm mad A'
♪ Oh, Janet ♪
♪ For you ♪
♪ I love you too ♪
♪ There's one thing left to do
Ah-ooh ♪
♪ And that's go see the man who
began it; [ Others 1; Janet ♪
J When we met in his science
exam, it J J Janet J
♪ Made me give you the eye
and then panic; ♪ Janet;
♪ Now I've one thing to say
and that's dammit, Janet;
♪ I love you ♪
♪ Dammit, Janet ♪
♪ Oh, Brad, I'm mad ♪
[together]
♪ I love you ♪
I would like, if I may,
to take you on a strange journey.
It seemed a fairly ordinary night...
when Brad Majors
and his fiancée, Janet Weiss-
two young, ordinary, healthy kids-
left Denton
that late November evening...
to visit a Dr. Everett Scott,
ex-tutor and now friend
to both of them.
It's true there were
dark storm clouds-
heavy, black and pendulous-
toward which they were driving.
It's true, also, that the spare tire
they were carrying...
was badly in need of some air.
But they, being normal kids
and on a night out,
well, they were not going to let a storm
spoil the events of their evening.
On a night out.
It was a night out
they were going to remember...
for a very long time.
[ Thunderclap]
[ Richard Nixon On Radio ] I ha ve ne
ver been a quifler. ♪♪ [ Humming ]
To leave office before my term
is completed...
is abhorrent
to every instinct in my body.
But as president,
I must put the interests
of America first.
America needs
a full-time president...
and a full-time Congress,
- particu/ar/J/ at this ti/ne with
the prob/ems- - [ Motor Revving ]
Gosh, that's the third motorcyclist
that's passed us.
They sure do take their lives in their hands,
what with the weather and all.
Yes, Janet.
Life's pretty cheap to that type.
...would almost totally absorb
the time and attention...
of both the president
and the Congress-
What's the matter, Brad, darling?
Hmm. We must have taken
the wrong fork a few miles back.
[Janet] Oh. But then where did
that motorcyclist come from?
Hmm. Well, I guess
we'll just have to turn back.
...to continue to fight through the
months ahead for my- [ Tire B/o I/VS ]
What was that bang?
We must have a blowout.
Dammit! I knew I should've
gotten that spare tire fixed.
You just' sla y here and keep
Warm, and I'll g0 for help.
Where will you go?
We're in the middle of nowhere.
...the great issues of peace abroad
and prosperity Without inflation at home.
Didn't we pass a castle
back down the road a few miles?
[ Nixon]
...I shall resign-
Maybe the y have e telephone I
could use- I'm going with you.
Oh, no, darling, there's no sense
in both of us getting wet.
I'm coming with you.
[ Seat Belt Alarm Beeps ]
[Sighs]
Besides, darling, the owner of that phone
might be a beautiful woman,
and you might never
come back again.
[ Chuckles ]
[Hollow Thud]
[ Thunder Rumbling]
[ Thunderclap]
♪ In the velvet darkness ♪
♪ Of the blackest night ♪
♪ Burning bright ♪
♪ There's a guiding star;
♪ No matter what ♪
[ Thunderclap ]
JON“
♪ Who you are ♪
[ Together]
♪ There's a light;
[ Chorus]
♪ Over at the Frankenstein place ♪
♪ There's a light;
[ Chorus]
♪ Burning in the fireplace ♪
♪ There's a light;
♪ Light in the darkness ♪
♪ Of everybody's life ♪
♪ The darkness must go ♪
♪ Down the fiver ♪
♪ Of nights dreaming ♪
♪ Flow morphia slow;
♪ Let the sun ♪
♪ And light come streaming ♪
♪ Into my life ♪
♪ There's a light;
[ Chorus]
♪ Over at the Frankenstein place ♪
♪ There's a light;
[ Chorus]
♪ Burning in the fireplace ♪
♪ There's a light;
♪ A light)
♪ In the darkness ♪
♪ Of everybody's life ♪♪
And so,
it seemed that fortune
had smiled on Brad and Janet...
and that they had found the assistance
that their plight required.
Or had they?
[ Thunderclap]
Brad, let's go back.
I'm cold and I'm frightened.
Just a moment, Janet.
They may have a phone.
[ Doorbell Clangs]
[ Lock Turns]
[ People Laughing, Shouting, Muffled ]
[ Door Creaking ]
Hello.
Hi! My name's Brad Majors.
This is my fiancée,
Janet Weiss.
I wonder if you might help us. You see, our
car broke down a few miles up the road.
Do you have a phone
we might use?
You're wet.
Yes, it's raining.
Yes.
[ Thunderclap]
I think, perhaps,
you better both come inside.
You're too kind.
♪♪ [ Rock And Roll]
[ People Laughing, Shouting]
♪♪ [ Continues]
Brad, I'm frightened.
What kind of a place is this?
Oh, it's probably some kind of
hunting lodge for rich weirdos.
Oh.
[ Door Slams]
This way.
[ Laughing, Shouting Continue]
Are you having a party?
You've arrived
on a rather special night.
It's one of the mastefls affairs.
Oh.
Lucky him.
You're lucky.
He's lucky. I'm lucky.
We're all lucky!
[ Laughing Loudly]
[ Clock Chiming]
♪♪ [ Downbeat]
♪ it's astounding ♪
♪ Time is fleeting ♪
♪ Madness takes its toll ♪
[Laughs]
♪ But listen closely;
♪ Not for very much longer)
♪ I've got to keep control ♪
♪ I remember;
♪ Doing the time warp ♪
♪ Drinking those moments when ♪
♪ The blackness would hit me ♪
[ Together]
♪ And the void would be calling ♪
♪ Let's do the time warp again ♪
[ Speaking Lyrics ]
♪ it's just a jump to the left ♪
♪ And a step to the fight ♪
♪ With your hands on your hips ♪
♪ You bring your knees in tight;
♪ But it's the pelvic thrust ♪
♪ That really drives you insane ♪
♪ Let's do the time warp again ♪
[Sighs]
♪ it's so dreamy;
♪ Oh, fantasy free me ♪
♪ So you can't see me ♪
♪ No, not at all ♪
♪ In another dimension ♪
♪ With voyeuristic intention ♪
♪ Well secluded ♪
♪ I see all;
♪ With a bit of a mind flip)
♪ You're into the time slip ♪ Ah!
♪ And nothing
can ever be the same ♪
♪ You're spaced out on sensation ♪
♪ Like you're under sedation ♪
♪ Let's do the time warp again ♪
♪ Well, I was walking down the street
just having a think;
♪ When a snake of a guy
gave me an evil wink;
♪ He shook-a me up
He took me by surprise ♪
♪ He had a pickup truck
and the devil's eyes ♪
♪ He stared at me
and I felt a change ♪
♪ Time meant nothing
Never would again ♪
♪ Let's do the time warp again ♪
♪ it's just a jump to the left;
♪ And then a step to the fight ♪
♪ With your hands on your hips ♪
♪ You bring your knees in tight;
♪ But it's the pelvic thrust ♪
♪ That really drives you insane ♪
♪ Let's do the time warp again ♪
[Columbia Squeals]
♪♪ [ Rhyth -
Ah!
Oh! Whoa!
Yeow!
[Means]
[All ]
♪ Let's do the time warp again ♪
♪ it's just a jump to the left;
♪ And then a step t0 the right,»
♪ With your hands on your hips ♪
♪ Bring your knees in tight;
♪ But it's the pelvic thrust ♪
♪ That really drives you insane ♪
♪ Let's do the time warp again ♪
♪ Let's do the time warp again ♪♪
♪♪ [ Slows Down]
♪♪ [ Drum Beats, Piano Tinkles]
JV [Ends]
[Whispering ]
Say something.
Say!
Do any of you guys know how to Madison?
[ Groans]
Huh? [AH Murmuring]
Huh?
Brad, please,
let's get out of here.
For God's sake,
keep a grip on yourself, Janet.
- Bu! it' seems so unhea/fh y here.
- It's just a party, Janet.
Well, I want to go. Well, we can't
go anywhere till I get to a phone.
- Then ask the butler or someone.
- Just' a moment', Janet.
We don't want to interfere
with their celebrations.
This isn't the Junior
Chamber of Commerce, Brad.
They're probably foreigners
with ways different than our own.
They may do some more...
folk dancing.
[ Chortling, Snickering ]
Look, I'm cold, I'm wet
and I'm just plain scared!
I'm here.
There's nothing to worry about.
[ Guest' ] Oh, my. [ Screams ]
♪ How do you do, I;
♪ See you've met my ♪
♪ Faithful handyman ♪
♪ He's just a little brought down
because ♪
♪ When you knocked ♪
♪ He thought you were
the candy man ♪
♪ Don't get strung out;
♪ By the way I look;
♪ Don't judge a book by its cover;
♪ I'm not much of a man;
♪ By the light of day;
♪ But by night
I'm one hell of a lover;
♪ I'm just a sweet transvestite ♪
♪ From Transsexual ♪
♪ Transylvania ♪
Ah, ha, ha!
♪ Let me show you around ♪
♪ Maybe play you a sound ♪
♪ You look like you're both
pretty groovy ♪
♪ Or if you want something visual ♪
♪ That's not too abysmal ♪
♪ We could take in an old
Steve Reeves movie ♪
♪ I'm glad we
caught you at home ♪
♪ Could we use your phone ♪
♪ We're both in a bit of a hurry;
Right.
♪ We'll just say where we are ♪
♪ Then go back to the car;
A pleasure to meet you, Dr. Furter.
♪ We don't want to be any worry ♪
[Speaking Foreign Language]
♪ Well, you got caught with a flat;
♪ Well, how about thaw
♪ Well, babies, don't you panic;
♪ By the light of the night)
♪ it'll all seem all right;
♪ I'll get you a satanic mechanic;
♪ I'm just a sweet transvestite ♪
♪ From Transsexual ♪
♪ Transylvania ♪
Ah, ha!
♪ Why don't you stay for the night;
♪ Night;
♪ Or maybe a bite ♪
♪ Bite ♪
♪ I could show you
my favorite obsession ♪
♪ I've been making a man ♪
♪ With blond hair and a tan ♪
♪ And he's good for relieving my ♪
♪ Tension ♪
♪ I'm just a sweet transvestite ♪
♪ From Transsexual ♪
♪ Transylvania ♪
Ah, ha!
Hit it! Hit it!
♪ I'm just a sweet transvestite ♪
♪ Sweet transvestite ♪
♪ From Transsexual ♪
[All ]
♪ Transylvania ♪
Ah, ha!
♪ So come up to the lab ♪
♪ And see what's on the slab ♪
♪ I see you shiver with antici- ♪
♪ --.Patton ♪
♪ But maybe the ram ♪
♪ ls really to blame ♪
♪ So I'll remove the cause ♪
[Chuckling]
♪ But not the symptom ♪♪
[ Guests Exclaiming, Chattering ]
[ Man ]
Wonderful!
[ Guests Chattering ]
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
[Sighs]
on! on!
Oh! Brad!
It's all right, Janet. We'll play along for now
and pull out the aces when the time's right.
Oh. Oh!
Oh. Slowly, slowly.
It's too nice a job to rush.
- Hi. My name's Brad Majors, and this is
my fiancée, Janet Weiss. - [ Murmurs ]
Uh, you are-
You're very lucky to be invited
up to Frank's laboratory.
Some people would give
their right arm for the privilege.
People like you maybe?
Hah!
I've seen it.
Oh!
[ Magenta ] Uh-huh.
[ Clock Chi/hing ]
[ Magenta ] Come along. The master
doesn't like to be kept waiting.
Shift it!
[ Bottle Shatters]
[Janet] Is he, um- Frank, I mean.
Is he your husband?
[ Magenta Laughs]
The master is not yet married.
Nor do I think he ever will be.
We are simply his servants.
Oh.
[ Frank]
Magenta.
Columbia.
Go and assist Riff Raff.
I will entertain, um-
[ Chuckles ]
Brad Majors.
This is my fiancée, Janet Vice.
Weiss. Weiss. [ Clears Throat ]
Mmm! Enchanfé.
[ Giggles ]
Well, how nice.
And what charming underclothes you
both have. [ Guests Cho/T/e ]
But here, put these on.
They'll make you feel
less, uh, vulnerable.
[Chuckling]
It's not often
we receive visitors here,
let alone offer them hospitality.
Hospitality? All we wanted to do
was to use your telephone. Goddamn it!
A reasonable request
which you've chosen to ignore!
Brad, don't be ungrateful.
Ungrateful?
How forceful you are, Brad.
Such a perfect specimen
of manhood- so dominant.
[ Guests Exclaim, Giggle]
You must be awfully
proud of him, Janet.
Well, yes, I am.
[ Both Chuckling ]
Do you have any tattoos, Brad?
Certainly not.
Oh, well.
How about you?
[ Giggling ]
Everything is in readiness, master.
We merely await your word.
- Tonight, my unconventional
conventionists- - [All Chuckling]
You are I0 Witness a ne W
breakthrough in biochemical research.
And paradise is to be mine!
[All Exclaiming]
[ On P.A. ]
It was strange the way it happened.
Suddenly, you get a break.
All the pieces seem to fit into place.
What a sucker you've been.
What a fool.
The answer was there all the time.
It took a small accident
to make it happen.
An accident! [ Magenta,
Columbia ] Accident!
And that's how I discovered
the secret.
That elusive ingredient.
That spark...
that is the breath of life.
Yes.
I have that knowledge.
I hold the secret...
to life itself!
[ Guests Applauding, Cheering]
[ Exclaims ]
[ Cheering, Applauding]
[ Noisemakers Tooting, Rattling ]
You see, you are fortunate.
For tonight is the night...
that my beautiful creature
is destined to be born!
[ Cheering ]
[ Noisemakers Tooting, Rattling ]
♪♪ [ Drumroll]
hoopla!
[ Guests Gasping]
Throw open the switches
on the sonic oscillator.
And step up the reactor power input...
three more points!
[ Electricity Crackling]
[ Strains, Grunts]
[ Gasps ]
Oh, Brad!
It's all right, Janet.
[ Laughing]
[ Exclaims, Laughing]
Oh!
[ Guests Gasping]
[ Gushes ]
[ Panting ]
[ Electronic Squealing]
[Laughing Maniacally]
[ Machines Squealing, Buzzing]
[ High-pitched Whine]
[ Whine Intensifies]
[ Loud Whooshing]
[ Guests Applauding, Cheering]
[ Gasps ]
9h, Rocky!
' [ Growls]
- [ Cackling]
♪ The sword of Damocles
is hangin' over my head ♪
♪ And I've got the feeling someone's
gonna be cuttin' the thread ♪
You idiot!
♪ Oh, woe is me ♪
♪ My life is a misery;
♪ Oh-oh, can't you see ♪
♪ That I'm at the start
of a pretty big downer ♪
♪ I woke up this mornin' with a start
when I fell out of bed ♪
♪ That ain't no crime ♪
♪ And left from my dreaming
was a feeling of unnameable dread ♪
♪ That ain't no crime ♪
♪ My high is low ♪
♪ I'm dressed up with no place to go ♪
♪ And all I know;
♪ ls I'm at the start
of a pretty big downer;
[ Frank]
Oh, ROCky!
♪ Oh, no;
♪ Sha-la, la-la That ain't no
crime ♪ ♪ Oh, no, no, no ♪
♪ Sha-la, la-la That ain't
no crime ♪ ♪ Oh, no, no, no;
♪ Sha-la, la-la
That ain't no crime ♪
♪ That ain't no crime ♪
- ♪ The sword of Damocles is hangin'
over my head ♪ - Oh, really!
♪ That ain't no crime ♪
♪ And I've got the feeling someone's
gonna be cuttin' the thread ♪
♪ That ain't no crime ♪
♪ Oh, woe is me;
♪ My life is a mystery;
♪ And can't you see ♪
♪ That I'm at the start
of a pretty big downer;
[ Sobbing ]
- ♪ Sha-la, la-la That ain't no
crime ♪ - ♪ Oh, no, n0, n0 ♪
♪ Sha-Ia, Ia-Ia
That ain't no crime, 0h, no ♪
That ain't no crime ♪
♪ Ain't no crime ♪
[Gushing, Sobbing]
- ♪ Sha-la, la-la That ain't
no crime ♪ C♪ Oh, no, no, no;
- ♪ Sha-Ia, Ia-Ia That ain't no
crime ♪ C♪ Oh, no, no, Do,!'
♪ Ain't no crime
Sha-la-la ♪♪
- [All ] Mmm!
- [Frank] Well, really!
That's no way to behave
on your first day out.
[Whimpers ]
But, um, since you're such
an exceptional beauty,
I'm prepared to forgive you.
Ooh!
[ Guests Exclaiming, Applauding]
Oh, I just love success!
He's a credit to your
genius, master. Yes.
A triumph of your will.
Yes.
He's okay.
“Okay”?
I think we can do
better than that.
Come on.
Now, Brad and Janet,
what do you think of him?
Oh. Well,
I don't like men
with too many muscles.
[Guests Chuckling ]
I didn't make him for you!
[Gasps]
He carries the Charles Atlas
seal of approval.
[Murmuring, Laughing]
♪♪ [ Piano Fanfare]
♪ A weakling
weighing 98 pounds ♪
♪ Will get sand in his face ♪
♪ When kicked to the ground ♪
[Chuckling]
♪ And soon in the gym ♪
♪ With a determined chin ♪
♪ The sweat from his pores ♪
♪ As he works for his cause ♪
♪ Will make him glisten ♪
♪ And gleam  ♪
♪ And with massage ♪
♪ And just a little bit of steam ♪
[Gushing]
♪ He'll be pink;
♪ And quite clean ♪
♪ He'll be a strong man ♪
♪ Oh, honey, but the wrong man ♪
[ Chorus] ♪ But the wrong man ♪
♪ He'll eat nutritious high protein ♪
♪ And swallow raw eggs ♪
♪ Try to build up his shoulders ♪
♪ His chest, arms and legs ♪
♪ Such an effort
If he only knew of my plan ♪
♪ In just seven days ♪
♪ I can make you a man ♪
♪ He'll do press-ups and chin-ups ♪
♪ Do the snatch, clean and jerk;
♪ He thinks dynamic tension ♪
♪ Must be hard work;
♪ Such strenuous living ♪
♪ I just don't understand ♪
♪ When 'm 'gust seven days
oh, baby ♪
♪ I can make you a man ♪
[Gushing]
[ Beeping ]
- Ahh! Who? Wha-
- Eddie!
[ Screaming ]
[ Guests Screaming]
[ Engine Stops]
♪♪ [ Rock And Roll]
Whoo!
♪ Whatever happened
to Saturday night ♪
♪ When you dressed up sharp
and you felt all right;
♪ It don't seem the same
since cosmic light ♪
♪ Came into my life ♪
♪ I thought I was divine ♪
♪ I used to go for a ride
with a chick who'd go ♪
♪ And listen to the music
on the radio ♪
♪ A saxophone was blowin'
on a rock-and-roll show;
♪ We climbed in the back seat
Really had a good time ♪
♪ Hot patootie, bless my soul ♪
♪ I really love that rock and roll ♪
[All ]
♪ Hot patootie, bless my soul ♪
♪ I really love that rock and roll ♪
Lovely party-
♪ My head it used to swim
from the perfume I smelled ♪
♪ My hands kind of fumbled
with her white plastic belt ♪
♪ I'd taste her baby pink lipstick
and that's when I'd melt;
♪ She'd whisper in my ear
tonight she really was mine ♪
♪ Get back in front
and put some hair oil on ♪
♪ Buddy Holly was singin'
his very last song ♪
♪ With your arms around your girl
you tried to sing along ♪
♪ It felt pretty good ♪ Whoo!
♪ Really had a good time ♪
[ Squealing ]
[All ]
♪ Hot patootie, bless my soul ♪
♪ I really love that rock and roll ♪
Huh? Where are you going?
♪ Hot patootie, bless my soul ♪
♪ I really love that rock and roll ♪
♪ I really love that rock and roll ♪♪
- [Screaming]
- [ Shouting ]
[ People Screaming]
- [ Shrieking]
- [Screaming] No!
[ Hacking ]
[ Columbia Screaming, Sobbing]
One from the vaults.
[ Guests Chuck/mg ]
[ Bars Rattling]
on, baby!
Don't be upset.
It was a mercy killing.
He had a certain naive charm...
but no muscle.
[Squeals]
♪ But a deltoid ♪
♪ And a bicep ♪
♪ A hot groin and a tricep ♪
♪ Makes me ♪
[ Gushes ]
♪ Shake ♪
♪ Makes me want to take
Charles Atlas ♪
♪ By the hand ♪
♪ In just seven days
oh, baby ♪
♪ I can make you a man ♪
♪ I don't want no dissension ♪
♪ Just dynamic tension ♪
♪ I'm a muscle fan ♪
[ Frank]
♪ In just seven days ♪
♪ I can make you a man ♪
♪ Dig it if you ♪
♪ Can;
♪ In just seven days ♪
♪ I can make you a man ♪♪
[ Electronic: “Wedding March”]
[ Guests Chanting ]
Rocky, Rocky, rah, rah, rah!
There are those who say
that life is an illusion...
and that reality is simply
a figment of the imagination.
If this is so, then
Brad and Janet are quite safe.
However, the sudden departure
of their host...
and his creation...
into the seclusion
of his somber bridal suite...
had left them feeling
both apprehensive and uneasy.
A feeling which grew
as the other guests departed...
and they were shown
to their separate rooms.
[ Clatters, Water Sloshes ]
[Both Chortling]
[Chuckling]
[ Wolf Howls]
[Knocking]
[ Gasps ]
Who is it? Who's there?
Oh. [ Brad ] it's
only me, Janet.
Brad, darling, come in.
Mmm!
Oh, Brad!
[ Both Moaning ]
Yes, my darling!
Oh, but what if-
it's all right, Janet.
Everything's going to be all right.
Oh, I hope so, my darling.
[W0/fH0W/s]
[Yelping, Screaming]
Oh! it's you! [ Frank]
I'm afraid so, Janet.
But isn't it nice?
Oh!
Oh, you beast! You monster!
What have you done with Brad?
Well, nothing.
Why, do you think I should?
You tricked me! I wouldn't have.
I've never, never-
[ Crying ]
Yes. Yes, I know.
But it isn't all bad, is it?
I think you really will
find it quite pleasurable.
[ Both Moaning ]
So soft, so sensual.
Stop. I mean, help!
Oh, Brad. Oh, Brad!
Shh.
Brad's probably asleep by now.
Do you want him to see you
like this?
Oh! Like this? Like how?
It's your fault! You're to blame!
[ Sighs ]
I was saving myself.
[ Chuckling ] Well, I'm
sure you're not spent yet.
[ Wolf Howling]
Promise you won't tell Brad?
Cross my heart
and hope to die.
[Moaning, Laughing]
[ Both Laughing]
[ Sizzles ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Hissing]
[Whimpering]
[ Chortling ]
[ Laughing]
[Straining, Grunting]
[ Hissing]
[Grunts]
[ Laughing]
[Sucking ]
[ Gasps ]
[Janet] Oh, Brad, darling,
it's no good here!
It'll destroy us.
Don't worry, Janet.
We'll be away from here in the morning.
Oh, Brad, you're so strong
and protective.
[ Both Chuckling, Moaning]
Wha-
YOu!
[ Frank] I'm afraid so, Brad.
But isn't it nice?
Why, you-
What have you done with Janet?
Nothing.
Why, do you think I should?
You tricked me. I wouldn't have.
I've never, never. Never!
Yes, I know.
But it isn't all bad, is it?
Not even half bad.
I think you'll really quite enjoy it.
[ Brad Moaning]
So soft. So sensual.
No, stop, stop. No.
Oh, Janet.
[ Moaning ]
Janefl
Shh!
Janet's probably asleep by now.
Do you want her to see you like this?
Like this? Like how?
It's your fault! You're to blame.
I thought it was the real thing!
Oh, come on, Brad, admit it.
You liked it, didn't you?
There's no crime in giving yourself
over to pleasure.
Oh, Brad, you've wasted
so much time already.
Janet needn't know.
I won't tell her.
You promise you won't tell?
[ Moaning ]
On my mother's grave.
[ Device Beeping]
Master, Rocky has broken his chains
and vanished.
The new playmate is loose
and somewhere in the castle grounds.
Magenta has just released the dogs.
[Dogs Barking]
Hmm?Oh
Coming! [Chuckling ] Oh!
What is happening here?
Where's Brad?
Where's anybody?
[ Dogs Barking]
[ Rocky Whimpering ]
Oh, Brad!
Brad, my darling. Oh!
How could I have done this to you?
Oh! If only we hadn't
made this journey.
If only the car hadn't broken down.
Oh! If only we were
amongst friends...
OF sane DEFSOHS.
Oh, Brad.
What have they done with him?
Brad.
Oh, Brad! How could you?
[ Crying 1
Oh!
[ Rocky Whimpering]
[ Whimpering]
[ Janet Gasps ]
Oh. But you're hurt.
Did they do this to you?
Here. I'll dress your wounds.
Poor baby, there. Oh.
[ Criminologist] “Emotion:
Agitation or disturbance of mind;
vehement or excited mental state.”
It is also a powerful
and irrational master.
And from what Magenta and Columbia
eagerly viewed on their television monitor,
there seemed little doubt
that Janet was indeed its slave.
[Together]
Tell us about it, Janet.
[ Both Laughing ]
♪ I was feelin' done in ♪
♪ Couldn't win ♪
♪ I'd only ever kissed before ♪
You mean she-
Uh-huh.
♪ I thought there's no use getting ♪
♪ Into heavy petting ♪
♪ It only leads to trouble ♪
♪ And seat wetting ♪
♪ Now all I Want' f0 know,»
[Laughs]
♪ Is how to 90$
♪ I've tasted blood
and I want more ♪
[ Together]
More, more, more.
♪ I'll put up no resistance ♪
♪ I want to stay the distance ♪
♪ We got an “ch to scratch ♪
♪ I need assistance ♪
♪ Touch-a, touch-a, touch-a
touch me ♪
♪ I wanna be dirty;
♪ Thrill me, chill me, fulfill me;
♪ Creature of the night;
♪ Then if anything grows ♪
[ Giggles ]
♪ While you p088 ♪
♪ I'll oil you up
and rub you down ♪
Down, down, down.
♪ And that's just
one small fraction ♪
♪ Of the main attraction ♪
♪ You need a friendly hand ♪
♪ And I need action ♪
♪ Touch-a, touch-a, touch-a
touch me ♪
♪ I wanna be dirty;
♪ Thrill me, chill me, fulfill me;
♪ Creature of the night;
♪ Touch-a, touch-a, touch-a
touch me ♪ [Laughing]
♪ I wanna be dirty;
♪ Thrill me, chill me, fulfill me;
♪ Creature of the night;
Oh! ♪ Touch-a, touch-a, touch-a
touch me ♪
♪ I wanna be dirty;
- ♪ Thrill me, chill me, fulfill me ♪
- [ Laughing ]
♪ Creature of the night;
Creature of the night.
Creature of the night?
♪ Creature of the night;
Creature of the night.
♪ Creature of the night ♪♪
[ Moans ]
[ Riff Raff Whimpering ]
[Grunting]
Mercy!
[Yelps ]
How did it happen?
I understood
you were to be watching.
I was only away for a minute,
master.
Well, see if you can find him
on the monitor.
[ Mutters ]
[ Riff Raff]
Master.
Master, We have a visitor.
[ Brad ]
Hey! Scotty!
[Laughs]
Dr. Everett Scott.
You know this earthling-
this... person?
I most certainly do. He happens
to be an old friend of mine.
I see.
So this wasn't simply
a chance meeting.
You came here
with a purpose.
I told you, my car broke down.
I was telling the truth.
I know what you told me, Brad.
But this Dr. Everett Scott,
his name is not unknown to me.
He was a science teacher
at Denton High School.
And now he works for your
government, doesn't he, Brad?
What? He's attached to the
Bureau of Investigation...
of that which you call U.F.O.'s!
Isn't that right, Brad?
He might be. I don't know.
The intruder is entering
the building, master.
He'll probably be in-
in the Zen Room.
A ch]
Shall we inquire of him in person?
[Grunts]
[Power Humming]
A ch]
Great Scott!
[ Engine Zooming]
[ Wheels Screech/ng ]
[ Crash ]
Frank-N-Furter.
We meet at last.
Dr. Scott!
Brad. What are you doing here?
Don't play games, Dr. Scott.
You know perfectly well
what Brad Majors is doing here.
It was part of your plan, was it not,
that he and his female
should check the layout for you?
Well, unfortunately for you all,
the plans are to be changed.
I hope you're adaptable, Dr. Scott.
I know Brad is.
I can assure you that Brad's presence
here comes as a complete surprise to me.
I came here to find Eddie.
Eddie? I've seen him. He's-
Eddie?
What do you know of Eddie,
Dr. Scott?
I happen to know a great deal
about a lot of things.
You see, Eddie
happens to be my nephew.
[ Gasps ]
[ Rocky Groans]
[ Janet Gasps ]
Dr. Scott.
- Janet!
- Dr. Scott!
- Brad!
Rocky!
- Janet!
- Dr. Scott!
- Brad!
Rocky!
- Janet!
- Dr. Scott!
- Brad!
Rocky!
Listen! I made you,
and I can break you just as easily.
[ Loud Clang ]
Master! Dinner is prepared!
Excellent.
Under the circumstances,
formal dress is to be optional.
Food has always played a vital role
in life's rituals.
The breaking of bread, the last meal
of the condemned man...
and now this meal.
[ Criminologist]
However informal it might appear,
you can be sure there was to be
very little bonhomie.
[ Lid Clatters]
[ Silverware, Glasses Rattle ]
[ Electric Knife Whirring ]
[Whirs]
[ Whirring]
A toast.
- 7'0 absent' friends.
- To absent friends.
And Rocky.
[ Scraping, Clattering]
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday, dear Rocky;
[ Janet] _ ♪ Happy birthday
to you ♪♪ Sha“ we'?
[ Cart Clatters]
We came here to discuss Eddie.
- Eddie!
- [ Whirring]
That's a rather tender subject.
Another slice, anyone?
Excuse me.
[ Columbia Screaming]
[ Sobbing ]
I knew he was in with a bad crowd,
but it was worse than I imagined.
Aliens.
Huh'?
[ Together]
Dr. Scott!
Go on, Dr. Scott.
Or should / say Dr. van $0012'?
Just what exactly are you implying?
It's all right!
But; Dr. Scott'.
That's all right, Brad.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Slow Tempo ]
♪ From the day he was born ♪
♪ He was trouble ♪
♪ He was the thorn ♪
♪ In his “mutter's” side ♪
♪ She tried in vain ♪
♪ But he never caused her
nothing but shame ♪
♪ He left home ♪
♪ The day she died ♪
[ Up-beat Tempo ]
♪ From the day she was gone ♪
♪ All he wanted ♪
♪ Was rock-and-roll porn ♪
♪ Und a motorbike ♪
♪ Shooting up junk ♪
♪ He was a low-down
cheap little punk ♪
♪ Taking everyone for a ride ♪
♪ When Eddie said
he didn't like his teddy ♪
♪ You knew he was a no-good kid ♪
♪ But when he threatened your life
with a switchblade knife ♪
- ♪ What a guy ♪
- ♪ Makes you cry ♪
♪ Undmxd;
♪ Everybody shoved him ♪
♪ I very nearly loved him ♪
♪ I said, hey, listen to me;
♪ Stay sane inside insanity ♪
♪ But he baked the door
and threw away the key ♪
♪ But he must've been drawn ♪
♪ Into something ♪
♪ Making him warn me ♪
- ♪ In a note which reads ♪
- ♪ What's it say, What's it say ♪
[ Eddie's Voice]
♪ I'm out of my head,r
♪ Oh, hurry, or! may be dead ♪
♪ They mustn't carry out
their evil deeds ♪
[ Screaming ]
♪ When Eddie said
he didn't like his teddy ♪
♪ You knew he was a no-good kid ♪
But when he threatened your life
with a switchblade knife ♪
- ♪ What a guy ♪
- ♪ Makes you cry ♪
♪ Undmxd;
♪ When Eddie said
he didn't like his teddy ♪
♪ You knew he was a no-good kid ♪
♪ But when he threatened your life
with a switchblade knife ♪
♪ What a QUY ♪
♪ Whoa, oh, oh ♪
♪ M k
[ Crisis you Cry ♪
♪ Hey, hey, hey ♪
♪ undmxd;
♪ Edtfie N'
[Chuckles]
Oh.
[Janet Screaming ]
Oh. Rocky!
How could you?
[Janet Screaming ]
[ Screaming Continues]
Quick! This way! This way!
[ Both Laughing ]
Shut up!
♪ I'll tell you once
I won't tell you twice ♪
;“YoukibefiervWseLn>
JanetVW§ss;\ [vvhknpefing]
♪ Your apple pie
don't taste too nice ♪
♪ You'd better wise up
Janet Weiss ♪
[ Groans ]
[ Screaming ] ♪ I've laid the
seed It should be all you need ♪
♪ You're as sensual as a pencil ♪
♪ Wound up like an E
or first string ♪
♪ When we made it
did ya hear a bell ring ♪
♪ You got a block
Well, take my advice ♪
♪ You'd better wise up
Janet Weiss ♪
♪ The transducer
will seduce ya ♪
[ Power Crackles ]
My feet! I can't move my feet!
My wheels!
My God, I can't move my wheels.
It's as if we're glued to the spot.
You are.
So quake with fear,
you tiny fools.
[ Crying 1
Oh, we're trapped.
♪ It's something you'll get used to ♪
♪ A mental mind-fuck can be nice ♪
[Shrieks] No!
[ Dr. Scott] You w0n't find Earth
people quite the easy mark you imagine.
This sonic transducer,
His,I suppose, some kind of audio-vibratory,
physiomolecular transport device?
You mean-
Yes, Brad.
It's something we ourselves have been
working on for quite some time.
But it seems our friend here
has found a means of perfecting it.
A device which is capable
of breaking down solid matter...
and then projecting it
through space...
and, who knows,
perhaps even time itself.
You mean he's gonna
send us to another planet?
♪ Planet schmanet, Janet;
♪ You'd better wise up
Janet Weiss ♪
Build your thighs up ♪
♪ You'd better wise up ♪
And then she cried out-
Stop!
[ Metallic Clanking]
♪ Don't get hot and flustered ♪
♪ Use a b“ oi mustard ♪
♪ You're a hot dog ♪
♪ But you'd better not
try to hurt her ♪
♪ Frank Furter ♪
[ Dr. Scott]
♪ You're a hot dog ♪
♪ But you'd better not
try to hurt her;
♪ Frank Furter ♪
♪ You' re a hot dog- ♪♪
[ Machine Squeals]
My God! I can't stand
any more of this.
First, you spurn me for Eddie,
and then you throw him off
like an old overcoat for Rocky.
You chew people up,
and then you spit them out again.
I loved you.
Do you hear me? I loved you.
And what did it get me?
Yeah, I'll tell you- a big nothing.
You're like a sponge.
You take, take, take...
and drain others
of their love and emotion.
Well, I've had enough!
You've gotta choose
between me and Rocky-
so named because of
the rocks in his head.
- Mmm!
- [ Machine Squeals]
It's not easy having a good time.
[ Machine Squeals]
Even smiling
makes my face ache.
And my children turn on me.
Rocky's behaving
just the way that Eddie did.
Do you think I made a mistake splitting
his brain between the two of them?
[ Magenta ]
I grow weary of this world!
When shall we return
to Transylvania? Huh?
Magenta,
I am indeed grateful to both you
and your brother, Riff Raff.
You have both served me well.
Loyalty such as yours
shall not go unrewarded.
You will discover that, when the mood
takes me, I can be quite generous.
I ask for nothing, master.
And you shall receive it
in abundance!
Come. We are ready
for the floor show.
[ Elevator Motor Whirring]
[ Criminologist] And so, by
some extraordinary coincidence,
fate, it seemed, had decided
that Brad and Janet...
should keep that appointment
with their friend, Dr. Everett Scott.
But it was to be in a situation...
which none of them
could have possibly foreseen.
And just a few hours
after announcing their engagement,
Brad and Janet had both tasted...
forbidden fruit.
This in itself was proof that
their host was a man of little morals...
and some persuasion.
What further indignities
were they to be subjected to?
And what of the floor show
that had been spoken of?
In an empty house...
in the middle of the night?
What diabolical plan...
had seized
Frank's crazed imagination?
What indeed?
From what had gone before,
it was clear that this
was to be no picnic.
♪♪ [ Rock And Roll]
[Squeals]
♪ It was great
when it all began ♪
♪ I was a regular Frankie fan ♪
♪ But it was over
when he had the plan ♪
♪ To start a-workin' on a muscleman ♪
♪ Now the only thing
that gives me hope ♪
♪ Is my love of a certain dope ♪
♪ Rose tints my world ♪
♪ Keeps me safe
from my trouble and pain ♪
♪ I'm just seven hours old ♪
♪ Truly beautiful to behold ♪
♪ And somebody should be told ♪
♪ My libido hasn't been controlled ♪
♪ Now the only thing
I've come to trust ♪
♪ ls an orgasmic rush of lust;
♪ Rose tints my world ♪
♪ And keeps me safe
from my trouble and pain ♪
♪ it's beyond me ♪
♪ Help me, MOmmY ♪
♪ I'll be good, you'll see ♪
♪ Take this dream away ♪
♪ What's this ♪
♪ Let's see ♪
♪ I feel sexy ♪
♪ What's come over me ♪
Whoo! ♪ Here it comes again ♪
[Means]
♪ I feel released ♪
♪ Bad times deceased ♪
[ Chuckles ]
♪ My confidence has increased ♪
♪ Reality is here ♪
♪ The game has been disbanded ♪
♪ My mind has been expanded ♪
♪ it's a gas that Frankie's landed ♪
♪ His lust is so sincere ♪
[ Kisses ]
♪♪ [ Drumroll]
♪♪ [ Trumpet Fanfare]
[ Morse Code Beeping]
♪ Whatever happened ♪
♪ To Fay WFHY ♪
♪ That delicate ♪
♪ Sam-draped flame ♪
♪ As it clung to her thigh ♪
♪ How I started to cry ♪
♪ 'Cause I wanted to be dressed ♪
♪ Just the same ♪
♪ Give yourself over;
♪ To absolute pleasure ♪
♪ Swim the warm waters ♪
♪ Of sins of the flesh ♪
♪ Erotic nightmares ♪
♪ Beyond any measure ♪
♪ And sensual daydreams ♪
♪ To treasure forever ♪
♪ Can't you just see it;
♪ Whoa-oh, oh ♪
[Means]
[ Water Splashes ]
[ Harp Glissando ]
♪ Don't dream it ♪
;Beu:
♪ D0n't dream it,r
[All]
♪ Don't dream it;
;Beu:
♪ Don't dream it ♪
£5617,»
Ach/
JV [Singing Continues]
We've got to get...
out of this trap...
before this decadence...
saps our wills.
I've got to be strong...
und try to hang on.
Or else my mind...
may well snap.
Und my life will be lived...
♪ For the thrill ♪
♪ It's beyond me ♪
♪ Help me, MOmmY ♪
♪ God Mess ♪
♪ Lili St. Cyr;
♪ My, my. my ♪
♪ M-my, my, my, mY ♪
♪ My, my, my, myr
♪ My-ay ♪
♪ I'm a wild and an untamed thing ♪
♪ I'm a bee with a deadly sting ♪
♪ You get a hit
and your mind goes “ping” ♪
♪ Your heart'll thump
and your blood will sing ♪
♪ So let the party
and the sounds rock on ♪
♪ We're gonna shake it
till the life has gone ♪
♪ Rose tint my world
Keep me safe from my trouble and pain ♪
[All ] ♪ We're a wild
and an untamed thing ♪
♪ We're a bee with a deadly sting ♪
♪ You get a hit
and your mind goes “ping” ♪
♪ Your heart'll thump
and your blood will sing ♪
♪ So let the party
and the sounds rock on ♪
♪ We're gonna shake it
till the life has gone ♪
♪ Rose tint my world
Keep me safe from my trouble and pain ♪
♪♪ [ Saxophone ]
♪ We're a wild and an untamed thing ♪
♪ We're a bee with a deadly sting ♪
♪ You get a hit
and your mind goes “ping” ♪
♪ Your heart'll thump
and your blood will sing ♪
♪ So let the party
and the sounds rock on ♪
♪ We're gonna shake it
till the life has gone, gone, gone ♪
♪ Rose tint my world
Keep me safe from my trouble and pain ♪♪
Hey!
♪ Frank-N-Furter ♪
♪ It's all over ♪
♪ Your mission is a failure ♪
♪ Your lifestyle's too extreme ♪
♪ I'm your new commander;
♪ You now are my prisoner;
♪ We return to Transylvania ♪
♪ Prepare the transit beam ♪♪
[ Frank]
Wait!
I can explain.
[ No Audible Dialogue]
♪♪ [ Piano, Slow Tempo]
♪ On the day I went away;
♪ Good-bye A'
♪ Was all I had to say;
[All]
♪ I want to come again and stay;
♪ on, my, my:
♪ Smile and that will mean I may;
♪ May-W A'
♪ 'Cause I've seen ♪
JON?
♪ Blue skies through the tears ♪
_;~ In my eyes;
- [Yawns]
♪ And I realize ♪
♪ I'm going home ♪
[Chorus]
of QU/I/Tg hQ/'nej
[ Frank]
♪ Everywhere, it's been the same ♪
[ Chorus ]
♪ Feeling ♪
♪ Like I'm outside in the rain ♪
♪ Wheeling ♪
♪ Free to try and find a game ♪
♪ Dealing ♪
♪ Cards for sorrow ♪
♪ Cards for pain ♪
♪ 'Cause I've seen ♪
JON?
♪ Blue skies ♪
♪ Through the tears ♪
♪ In my eyes ♪
♪ And I realize ♪
♪ I'm going home ♪
[With Chorus]
♪ I'm going home ♪♪
[ Audience Applauding]
[ Cheering ]
Bravo! Bravo!
[ Applause, Cheering Continue]
[ Cheering, Applause Fade]
How sentimental.
[ Riff Raff] And also
presumptuous of you.
You see,
when I said “we”
were to return to Transylvania,
I referred only
to Magenta and myself.
I'm sorry, however, if you
found my words misleading.
But, you see,
you are to remain here-
in spirit anyway.
- [ Dr. $002'! ] Go00' hea vens, Ihafs a
laser. - [ Riff Raff] Yes, Dr. $0027'.
A laser capable of emitting
a beam of pure anti-matter.
[ Brad ]
You mean you're going to kill him?
What's his crime? You saw
what became of Eddie.
Society must be protected.
Exactly, Dr. Scott.
And now, Frank-N-F utter,
your “me has some.
Say good-bye to all of this...
and hello to oblivion.
[ Columbia Screaming]
[Whimpers ]
No.
No. No!
[ Shrieks, Whimpering]
[ Screaming ]
[ Screams ]
[ Curtain Clattering]
[ Rocky Groaning]
[Whimpering]
♪♪ [ Chorus Vocalizing]
[ Sobbing ]
[Grunting]
[ Rocky Screaming ]
[ Brad ]
Good God!
You killed them.
But I thought you liked them.
They liked you.
They didn't like me!
They never liked me!
You did right.
A decision had to be made.
You're okay by me.
Dr. Scott,
I'm sorry about your...
nephew.
Eddie?
Yes, well, perhaps
it was for the best.
[Laughs]
You should leave now, Dr. Scott,
while it is still possible.
We are about to beam the entire house
back to the planet of Transsexual...
in the galaxy of Transylvania.
Go.
Now.
[ Magenta Laughing]
Our noble mission
is almost completed,
my most... beautiful sister.
And soon we shall return...
to the moon-drenched shores
of our beloved planet.
Ah.
Sweet Transsexual.
Land of night.
To sing and dance once more
to your dark refrain.
To take that...
step to the right.
Hah!
But it's the pelvic thrust-
♪ That really drives you insane ♪
[ Magenta ]
And our world...
will do the time warp again!
[ Both Cackling ]
[ Engines Roaring]
[ Magenta, Riff Raff Laughing]
JV [Ends]
[ Speaking Lyrics]
♪ And crawling ♪
♪ On the planet's face ♪
♪ Some insects ♪
♪ Called the human race ♪
♪ Lost 'm “me ♪
♪ And lost in space ♪
♪ And meaning ♪
[ Chorus]
♪ Meaning ♪♪
♪♪ [ Piano Tinkling]
[ Lips ]
♪ Science fiction ♪
♪ Double feature ♪
♪ Frank has built and ♪
♪ Lost his creature ♪
♪ Darkness has conquered ♪
♪ Brad and Janety
♪ The servants gone to ♪
♪ A distant planet ♪
♪ Whoa-oh, oh-oh, oh-oh ♪
♪ At the late-night ♪
♪ Double feature ♪
♪ Picture show;
♪ I wanna g0 ♪
♪ Oh-oh, oh-oh ♪
♪ To the late-nighty
♪ Double feature ♪
♪ Picture show ♪♪
♪♪ [ “The Time Warp”]
♪♪ [ Slows Down]
♪♪ [ Drum Beats, Piano Tinkles]
JV [Ends]
English - US - PSDH