- Peter, I'm so happy to see you.
- Hi. How are you?
- I'm wonderful. How are you?
- Good, good.
Is this a night
for a party or what?
- I mean, this huge mix-up--
- Okay, everyone.
- I found his commercial. Come on in.
- Oh, I can't wait to see it.
Oh, he-- he can't weasel out
of this one. We're gonna show it.
It's show time, folks.
Let's go.
- Shh! Shh! Shh!
- Hey, quiet!
I came from fairly humble beginnings
from upstate New York.
- And to be honest, I'd never
even been on an aeroplane before.
- Nice make-up.
Not until the Air Force
taught me to fly in 1969.
I ended up doing 28
combat missions for them.
In, uh, 1971--
Oh, a tough year--
I threw everything I owned
into a charter service.
- You look better than those frogs
in that beer commercial.
- When we kicked off...
we had a six-seater and one DC-3,
and we would fly anywhere.
We were like
the yellow cabs of the sky.
In 1979, we started Endeavor, and
we only flew to four different cities.
But, uh, I think the passengers
picked up on my, my joy in flying.
And we've grown
to 37 countries worldwide.
We're still pretty small
in the scheme of things.
But then, I never wanted
to be the biggest, just the best.
The most important thing
to me these days: family.
Mine. Yours.
That's the good thing
about an airline.
It actually brings families
closer together, among other things.
And that makes me
feel good. 1971. Man.
I had the devil in me back then.
But today-- people change.
Sort of.
- He really didn't want to do it.
- I thought he was great.
- He was good.
- Author!
- Where did he go?
Okay, get it over with,
you pack of freeloaders.
- Put it there. I got big shoulders.
- When's it air?
I was afraid to ask, actually. No,
you're too kind. No, you're too kind.
Actually, I'm contemplating
suicide before it airs.
Oh, yes, of course.
Because he's so shy.
And next month, he's doing the underwear
billboard in Times Square. Ow!
You should have seen-- You should
have seen the look on his face.
He couldn't figure out
where I got that information.
- And where did you?
- I took safe-cracking at MIT.
- No, the guy couldn't believe it.
- Hey, Sean, you eat something?
- You okay?
- Yeah.
- Good.
You know, the guy's a wacko.
I mean, seriously, he's, like, whoo!
- Unbelievable, unbelievable.
- What I can't figure out is how
someone expects you to bite...
without expecting you to know
everything about his business.
- I agree.
- Yeah. Anyway, uh,
David's on the carpet.
- All right, time to fold
the tent, fella. Come on.
- Tom?
- Yeah?
- Where did you get the tile
in the kitchen? It's great.
Oh, God, Louisa,
that's a Kate question.
See, I only answer Tom questions
like, uh, you know, what's wrong
with my chain saw?
- What's the best time of day
to kill a grizzly bear?
- I have a perfect Tom question.
How do you feel about Jackie Brown
filing a civil suit against you...
from his prison cell?
Sean, why don't you, uh, brush,
get ready. I'll be down in a minute.
David, would you get Bob, please?
- And you are?
- I'm just givin' you heads-up
because this Brown guy now says...
that he has proof that you paid him
to head off the machinists' strike.
Well, that's not novel. I mean,
he's been saying that for months.
I know, I know. But now he says he has
proof that you even initiated the bribe.
I'm Sammy Adler from
the Daily News. I just thought
if we could spend a couple seconds--
- Oh, oh, Bob Stone,
Sammy Adams from the Daily News. Uh--
- Adler.
- Why don't you make sure
he gets home safe?
- Can we get-- Can we do
something for two seconds?
- I hope you had
a good time here. Drive safely.
- All right, all right.
- We're very civil here.
- Guys, I'm a reporter. All right?
- We know who you are.
- I'm not a stalker, guys.
Listen, your boss is gonna
have to deal with this.
Jackie Brown says he was set up.
I think you gotta find
someone else to talk to.
- He's in the clear,
you understand, Sammy?
- Listen, if I was--
- I came from humble--
- Cut.
- Sean?
- Okay, try it again.
- About four cities, but l--
- Sean?
- But people picked on my--
- Oh, I guess he's not here.
So I'll lie down and take a nap
while I wait for him to turn up.
God, this mattress is lumpy.
And damned noisy too.
And it's got hair and-- what?
This mattress needs to be tickled!
No laughing.
No laughing allowed.
And why are you watching
my goof-ups again?
- What is this bug in the-- Sorry.
- Cut.
- That's funny.
- Yeah? Well, must make you
feel good inside...
to know your old man
can't even talk.
Grobe?
A shrinking grobe?
Was that guy mad
at you upstairs?
No. He's, uh, not mad.
He's, uh, he's curious. Yeah.
- It's his job, you know. He's gotta--
- It seems like someone's
always mad at you.
- That the way that seems?
- Mm-hmm.
Well, I guess that--
You're not mad at me, are you?
- No.
- Well, I can-- I can fix that.
- A knuckle sandwich before bedtime.
- Stop it! Stop it!
I said get your ass movin'!
- Get on the car! Shut the fuck up!
- I ain't do nothin'!
- Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
- Shut up, Romeo.
- Calm down. Joey! Joey!
Take it easy. Take--
- Get him outta here.
- A fuckin' track star, huh?
- You little faggot.
- Faggot? What?
- You're lucky I don't put one
in your back, you fuck!
- Hey, hey, hey! Hey, hey.
Hey, hey, hey. Take it easy.
- All right? You all right?
- I'm all right.
- All right.
Honey, you better work the door.
I think the Mayor wants to leave.
Oh, thank God. You okay?
- Yeah.
- Good.
Okay, did you brush your teeth?
-I brushed them this morning.
-No, no, no. We're gonna brush them now.
45-Adam to Central-K.
207 West 30th Street.
- Two unidentified suspects--
- Hey, hey. What are they, mink?
Yeah, why? You wanna buy one?
Take a walk.
Oh, God. I'm beat.
So where was that guy from?
Daily News?
- Does it make a difference?
- Ohh! I'd like to kill those bastards.
When they come after you,
they come after us.
It's freezing.
- Oh, God.
- I'd like to come after the contractor.
- Yeah, well, you gotta find him first.
- Yeah, really.
It's freezing in here.
Oh, that feels good.
Don't let those guys
get to you, okay?
- Yeah.
- That's what they want.
I just wanna say
Singin' makes me feel so fine
Drivin' in my truck, man
I'm always on the go
Makin' my deliveries
from here to Tupelo
- Tupelo
- But singin' bass--
Okay, now I'd like to introduce
to you the person responsible
for this wonderful event.
Uh, a fantastic lady. In fact,
chairlady of the Junior Science Fair...
Mrs Katherine Mullen.
- All right! Yea!
- Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you, Mayor.
And welcome to the tenth annual
New York City Junior Science Fair.
We have 54 young inventors
competing today...
- representing 22 schools--
- Dad?
- Yeah?
- Why can't I enter?
Well, it wouldn't be fair, Sean.
Your mother's a judge here.
- And, uh, how would that
look if you won?
- Why don't I enter
under a different name?
- What, you mean, like John Smith?
- No. Like Professor X.
Well, I don't think you'd get
away with that, Professor X.
I mean, you're too young to have
a degree. You got to be bald,
have an eye patch. You know.
No, better.
Professor von X.
And the third judge, I regret to say,
is myself, Katherine Mullen...
Events Chair for
the 125th Anniversary of Central Park...
and former teacher of biology
at Evander Childs High School.
So let the games begin.
Our judges will now
begin circulating.
- So all of our inventors
should be with their booths.
- Wow. Destination: Yonkers.
That's gotta be the best project out
here. Don't you think it's gonna win?
- Whoa!
- Oh, look, there's me!
Yeah, the wind is taking it.
Down left rudder.
Remember, we're going to want
all of today's winners on stage
at 1:00 to receive their award.
- Good luck, everybody.
- It's not fair, Dad.
I worked really hard.
I know. I know you worked really hard,
and you did an amazing job.
- But we talked about this before,
didn't we, Sean?
- Yes.
Okay? Come on.
Lighten up a little. Enjoy the day.
- Okay.
- Anyone else that has not registered...
- Tom!
- Hey!
- Hey, how are you?
- must have their registration
cards in right now.
This is your last chance.
- P.S. 41.
- Okay, P.S. 41. Yeah.
Solar system here?
And this big guy here is what?
- The sun.
- Okay.
- And how many planets
do we have around it?
- Nine.
- I see Mars.
Okay, folks, we'd like to thank
the Friends of Central Park...
and Mayor Barresi
for allowing this event...
to take place here
at the beautiful Bethesda Fountain.
- And a special thanks to our--
- Hey, Katie, look at the blimp.
- Me too.
- Looking forward to it.
...for ten years strong. Lisa?
Well, folks, there's still
a few of those souvenir
science fair T-shirts left.
- She's incredible. I mean,
the work she's put into this.
- Yeah.
Well, I don't know
where she gets the energy.
- And who is this orange guy over here?
- That's Venus.
That's Venus.
Where's Earth?
- Earth is this one.
- There's Earth.
Mr Vincent Barnes, we have not
received your class's registration cards
for Curtis High School--
For the workshop.
- See Mrs Moran at the exhibit.
- Excuse me for a minute.
Sean?
Brooklyn, Queens to my left, Bronx,
Manhattan and Staten lsland to my right.
- You're it.
- We ask you to stay with your boroughs.
- Teachers, please keep a head count.
- Sean.
What do you think, Kate?
Kate?
- Kate. The score.
- I-l-l scored it.
Sean?
- Cassandra, have you seen Sean?
- No. Kate, are you all right?
Okay.
Sean.
Sean. Sean Mullen,
please come to the judge's stand.
Sean?
Oh, please, God.
He's probably just
bustin' chops, you know, 'cause
we wouldn't let him enter the contest.
Who didn't we call?
- Sean?
- You have E-mail.
- I have your son.
- Oh, Jesus!
- I want $2 million
in fifties and hundreds.
- Oh, God!
No consecutive
serial numbers.
No new bills.
No marked bills.
The money will fit into two Samsonite
hard-shell suitcases, model #260.
Do not involve the police or the FBl.
If you do, I will kill him.
Do not inform the media,
or I will kill him.
No tracking devices in the money
or the cases, or I will kill him.
You have 48 hours to get the money.
I will contact you.
Open your mouth. Open your mou--
Would you open your mouth now?
Open it. Swallow it.
You little prick.
- What are you doing?
- Why don't you just clean your shirt?
Look, we talked about this.
Oh, yeah. Forgot.
Bitch.
Kate. Kate! Who are you calling?
He said no police.
- Why did you do that?
Why did you do that?
- He said he'd kill him
if you called the police.
- I can have the money inside 3 hours.
- Why did you leave him?
- I didn't.
I saw you.
You walked away.
All right.
- All right, I'm calling the police.
- Call the FBl.
- For Christ's sake,
just let me pay this bastard.
- Tom, please, call the FBl.
Kate, the FBI just spent
three months trying to bury us.
- Do you think they give
a good goddam about you or me or--
- Tom, they know us.
They know us. Please.
All right.
- Lennon Paints.
- Wait. What? What?
- We're the painters.
Yeah, we're goin' to
the Mullen apartment. Uh, we're
just finishin' work on the library.
Oh, yes. Yeah. I get this call.
Go ahead. Okay.
- Behind you.
- Mr and Mrs Mullen are waiting for you.
- Thank you.
Uh, Mr Mullen, how are you?
Lonnie. Hawkins.
-Uh, we got Kimba Welch, Jack Sickler...
-How do you do?
-How are you, sir?
- David Levin, Ron Lambert.
- How do you do?
- Find the phone panel.
- Fatima, could you show these gentlemen
everything they want to know?
- Paul.
- Who's sweepin'?
- And this is Paul Rhodes.
- How do you do?
- Hi. How you doing?
- This here is as close as
we could get to a look-alike.
- Oh, I see.
- Now, look, Mr Mullen, I'm not
allowed to advise you on this...
- but if you decide to pay the money--
- It's here. It's right over here.
- This the money?
- Yeah, $2 million.
- Well, Paul here can make
the drop for you.
- Sure, sure.
- Tom?
- Yeah, David?
- Bob's got some stuff
for you right here.
- Tom, this is all I could get...
- from the National Center
for Missing Children.
- Good, good.
- Uh, Agent Hawkins,
this is David Torres.
- Pleased to meet you.
- What about the electric files?
- Where's your phone panel, Mrs Mullen?
- I-l have no idea.
- That's okay. We'll find it.
You know, what I don't
understand is these people--
this he, she, it, whoever--
has got enough brains to snatch
my son right from under my nose...
but they only ask me
for $2 million.
- Don't they know what I'm worth?
- No, no. He's being smart, okay?
Keepin' it nice
and simple for you.
Now, he knows you got it. Knows you
won't have a problem coughin' it up.
Maybe, uh, that's all he needs.
Uh, uh, can l-- can I just, uh--
Look, the-the reason
you're here and not the police...
is that we, my wife and l, we believe
that this might be somehow connected...
- with the, uh, machinists'
union indictments.
- Okay.
So, uh, Jackie Brown.
The man was caught on tape
takin' a pay-off...
during contract negotiations
with another airline, uh, lnfinite Air.
It was a sting, okay?
So there he is, dead in the water.
He says to your people,
"Can we do something here?"
And, uh, so he offers me up.
Yeah, he said Tom gave him
a quarter of a million dollars...
for a sweetheart deal
with the union.
Now, I have been investigated
exhaustively; me, my company,
my-my family. My family.
We've been dragged through
the tabloid mud, courtesy of FBI leaks,
and nothing. All right? Nothing.
Now Jackie Brown's in jail
where he belongs, and he's pissed,
and I think he's got some pretty
unsavoury associates out there.
- Uh, Mr Mullen, obviously we're
very aware of the Jackie Brown
situation, Mr Mull--
- An-And?
- We're still working on it.
- Jesus Christ, I think you
should pay a little more attention.
- We're paying-- No.
Can I make a suggestion, Mr Mullen?
- What? What?
Now, we are going to get
into all of this in time,
but for now, just hang loose.
- Just sit tight so we can get a plan--
- Hang loose? Hang loose?
Sit tight? Which one?
Tom, just let him finish.
- No, it's okay. It's okay.
No, look, look.
- I'm sorry.
If this were my child,
I'd be the same way. Believe me.
It's not a problem at all.
All right, kid, I know
this is hard on you, all right?
But you gotta hang in there.
- How many kidnappings
have you worked before?
- All together, 33.
Uh, now you take away the custodial,
gang, drug-related, I've worked ten.
Now, that's ten traditional,
ransom-oriented abductions
in the last five years.
Now, that's a lot. Believe it or not,
this kind of thing is kind of rare.
Well, um, out of the ten,
how many did you get back?
Got back seven.
Well, the others.
What, um, went wrong?
Oh, life.
What we call the "X" factor.
What's the "X" factor?
What is that?
- Are we set?
- No!
Shit, Jack!
Any demands that come up,
now, you just agree.
Let him know he's in charge. Your only
priority is getting your boy back.
Get your boy back.
You follow me?
Now, you've got to give us
some time, Mr Mullen.
You ask to speak to your son.
Ask for some sign that he's alive.
Any information you can get.
Then tell him he has an allergy,
he has, uh, some medical condition.
You want to know what kind of weather
is he in. Is he indoors? ls he outdoors?
- Are we set?
- Go!
- Get your boy back.
- Okay.
Hello?
Cancel it.
We got it. Brenda Chance,
4108 Utopia Parkway.
That's his secretary.
Yeah, we know.
Is our son dead?
Don't ever think that.
Open your mouth.
It's all right. It's food.
So, why can't you starve
in the desert?
'Cause of all
the sandwiches there.
What are you doin'?
What the--
- Voters on Manhattan's East Side...
- What are you thinkin'?
- will be headed to the polls tomorrow--
- What the hell is going on?
I was tellin' the kid a joke.
What's the big deal?
You like this kid? You wanna get to know
him? Get a little relationship goin'?
You think that's gonna make
things easier or harder?
- Make what easier, Maris?
- Is he for real?
- Yeah, I'm for real, bitch.
Are you for real?
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Whoa! Whoa. Why don't you
just back off, all right?
You step up,
and I'll back off.
Come here.
Listen to me. Look.
With the candy bars and shit--
It's just that you might be makin' beds
in a burnin' house.
You understand what I'm sayin'?
Yeah, but, Clark, man,
the kid's in a cocoon.
And he can't ID anybody.
What the hell
he's supposed to tell 'em?
Wait a goddam second, man.
Clark, you never said nothin'
to me about killin' no kids!
Do you understand
what is goin' on now?
You do not joke with this kid. You don't
play with him. You don't talk to him.
- Don't talk to my brother, all right?
- He is not your pet.
- This is real.
- You don't gotta talk
to my brother, all right?
You got nothin' to say to him.
Who do you think you are? What do you--
- You think you're runnin' shit here?
- No, I'm not runnin' shit.
My man is runnin' shit.
- Oh. Your man. Right.
- But if I have a problem,
I'm going to address it.
- Yeah, I understand. All right.
- I gotta tell you, boys.
She's scarin'
the bejeepers outta me.
- And you're fuckin' drinkin' again.
- Well, that's okay, though...
see, 'cause I haven't
been drinkin' with the kid.
I have to tell you something
that I think you should know.
Okay.
I paid him off.
You understand I'm not a priest. I'm not
a psychiatrist. I'm not a lawyer.
Tom, this is not
a protected conversation.
I understand.
See, most guys at the top,
they've acquired their airline.
But not me, no, I built Endeavor
from the ground up.
And it's mine, and no bastard's
takin' it away from me.
No union, no government,
no gangster like Jackie Brown.
I initiated the bribe.
I had a business to run.
I had 2,000 employees,
God knows how many customers...
and I didn't have time
for a goddam machinists' strike.
So, after what I did--
what I proposed and, and carried out--
he's in jail and I'm not.
So my question to you is:
Did Jackie Brown take my son?
Do you wanna go ask him?
I been thinking about you.
- Where's my son?
- What?
Do you think that ending up
in this place is the worst thing
that can happen to you?
- What are you talkin' about?
- Where is my son?
Oh.
Somebody nabbed your kid...
and you think that it's me.
How?
I don't got no connections.
I don't got no friends.
I got no job.
I got no money.
And you, motherfucker,
are accusing me?
Hey! Hey, get off of him!
I got six of my own kids,
and I would die for every one of them.
- Get him outta here!
- And I haven't seen them since I got
locked up in here because of you!
- Get him outta here. Come on!
- Why aren't you in here? Huh?
You fuckin' belong in jail!
Who did you bribe?
- I ain't done with you,
you fuck! I'll kill you!
- Get him out! Get him outta there!
- Who'd you pay to set me up, you fuck?
- Get him outta here!
Come on. You tell me that again.
Say it again. Come on.
- I said that I wasn't
runnin' out this door--
- You weren't runnin'?
Damn, man. I said
I wasn't runnin' with him.
I was runnin' away from him
'cause he was, like, chasin' me.
Yeah, look me in the eye
and tell me that now.
- I was, I was runnin',
but I was runnin--
- Yeah, where were you goin'?
- Got the gat, Jimmy.
Huh? Whoa, whoa. Hey.
Look at that.
- You ever seen that before?
- Uh-uh.
- No? I'm not gonna find
your prints on there?
- No.
No? Bag that up.
Jimmy, uh, we got a problem here.
This guy doesn't want to close
his store right now.
Fuck it. Forget about it.
Now, tell me about your buddy.
Oh, man. Uh, I don't know.
I never saw him before.
- It was the first time I saw him.
- Here. Feel that.
- Christ, this thing's pumpin' Kool-Aid.
- Yeah, you got a heart problem, there?
- I was runnin'. I wasn't--
- Hey! Hey! Hey!
Wait. I smell a little bullshit here.
I think he's runnin' a game on me.
- I think he's an LAD.
- You a lyin'-ass dog?
- You got any, uh, Frankenberry
cereal with the marshmallows?
- The guy was chasin' me and l--
- Yo, you get me a lawyer, all right?
- You get your own fuckin' lawyer.
Yo, man, these cuffs
are too tight, man.
That's cause they're new.
They'll stretch. You gotta
give them a little time.
- Get in the car. You want a pizza?
You want a hot dog? What do you want?
- Here you go, Jimmy.
- Thanks.
- Let's go back to the house.
Are you a known scumbag in
this precinct or not? Shake your head.
Go on.
Now, a high-profile kid
got snatched yesterday.
You have no idea who knows
about it, huh? NYPD, FBl. Do you?
Shake your head.
No. So what do you do?
You, a known scumbag, walks into
a grocery store filled with cops...
and you ask for a box
of kiddie cereal.
I don't know about you, but I think
that makes you a four-star asshole.
What do you think?
What the hell were you
gonna do with the videos? Huh?
The kid's got tape on his eyes,
for Christ's sake.
I thought he could
listen to 'em.
Don't be stupid again.
- Jimmy.
- Hey.
I was just dreamin' about you.
- Was it good?
- Mm-mmm.
No. My father was back,
and then he was beating me up again.
And then you were there,
but you-- you didn't do anything.
You were just standing
there and watching.
Yeah, well, you know
that's just a dream.
- I locked his ass up, remember?
- Yeah. I know.
Where you been, man?
I'm goin' out of my mind here, you know.
Hey, it's all right.
These guys--
These guys are wacko.
They don't listen to me.
They don't respect me.
- I don't trust them.
- Don't worry about them.
They're afraid of me.
- Why do we need them? Why?
- We can't do this alone.
And the kid.
I'm scared shit of this kid.
I think we should just do this now.
Get rid of him.
- Get it over with,
'cause he's like a time bomb.
- Hey, hey, hey, listen to me.
You think you're scared
of the kid, but you--
you know what you're really scared of?
Your own humanity.
Your own decency.
'Cause you're good, and that's okay.
That's all right.
That's what I need from you.
When the time comes, the kid's
my problem, not yours. All right?
Well, you still trust me, don't you?
Yeah? 'Cause you know
I can do this, right?
- Yeah.
- Right?
Good.
'Cause it's time to get paid.
- Is there anything in the reports?
- Yeah.
A lot of stuff we already know.
A lot of stuff we don't know.
Stuff you don't want to know.
You know, you tell yourself--
No, you lie to yourself...
that, uh, you're doing all this...
for your family.
Security, money, the future.
All this-this-this king
of the mountain bullshit.
It's bullshit.
I keep seeing him tied up like that
with those handcuffs, and, uh...
I can't help him.
I can't help him. I can't--
- It's upstairs.
- Kate, where's Tom? Come on, now.
Let's do this.
Come on. Come on.
- Comin' in.
- All right, here they come.
Here they come.
Remember the drill. Jack!
Hello?
- Mr Mullen?
- Yes.
- Are you good to go?
- Am l-- Am l-- Am I what?
Get in the car and drive.
96th Street West. Come alone.
Take the Westside Highway North.
I'm-- I-l-l don't have the money yet.
Not yet. But I need more time.
- I'll get it. I-l just--
- Don't fuck with me.
I want, I want to talk to my son.
- Come alone.
- Wait. Hold on, uh. S--
Uh, Sean has asthma.
Uh, it's very serious.
So, what's the weather like?
Is it rainy? Damp?
Is he in a cellar?
On a mountaintop?
Please, don't.
My son gets vertigo.
- How's the linguist
doing with my accent?
- The w-what? The ling--
N-- Hey, there's no one here.
Just me.
- Are you sure?
- Hey, you think I'm a fuckin' idiot?
- I want to get this over with.
- Very good.
- Let's keep it that way.
- So how do I get my son back?
- Are you going to pay me?
- Of course I am.
Then it shouldn't be a problem.
- He'll call you.
- He'll-- When? Who? No, you'll call?
He'll call me?
- When?
- 96th Street. Come alone.
- Goddam it!
- Yes. Sweet and pretty.
They jammed us.
Everything's frozen.
Um, did you get it? Where--
Where did you trace it to?
They crashed the computer.
- Did I pick the right guy or what?
- Yeah.
- Huh? What'd I tell you?
- Yeah. Yeah.
We're gonna get it.
- Let's get Paul wired up.
- Whoa, whoa. I'll do it.
I'll do it. Let me.
- He gonna be all right?
- He's gonna be great.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
He better be.
I got a situation here. Legally,
I can't stop you from doing this.
Understand that this guy--
I don't know where he's coming from...
and I think he's a professional.
Now, if he starts throwing us
curve balls out there...
we are gonna have to improvise,
and we might not be able
to protect you, Mr Mullen.
I think it would be wiser if you just
let one of our guys make the drop.
- Ma-Maybe you shouldn't do it.
- Look, I'm okay. I'm okay, really.
I-- I just want to give him
what he expects.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
Look. It's almost over, kid.
I'm gonna get you back
with your parents. Promise.
- When?
- Soon.
When?
-There are tracking devices in the bags.
-Monty wants the packages--
- Do you have any other questions?
- All right, the car's completely wired.
- Any problems, we'll be right there.
- He said I was to come alone.
- All we're doin' is
following the money, Tom.
- Okay.
- We'll always be a safe distance away.
Listen. Let me give you a tip.
This here's a business
transaction. All right?
You're a businessman.
He's a businessman.
You think of this as business,
you'll be fine.
All right?
Get him back.
CP to S.O. units. All units
converge on 269 West 125 Street.
500 Unit to CP.
We have a visual on the package.
Yeah?
Okay, listen up.
I'm only gonna say this once.
Get off at 125th Street,
go right three blocks...
to the Kasarda Rec Center.
- Take the suitcases inside with you.
- Son of a bitch is scrolling us.
In the swimming pool, there's
a locker key down by the drain...
in the deep end.
There'll be somebody watching you.
You won't see them,
but they'll see you.
I want you to get that key.
I want you fully clothed
when you do.
You so much as remove
your wristwatch, your son dies.
When you have the key,
go find the locker.
- You got seven minutes.
- All right, I'll do everything you say.
I just need you to repeat it
so I could be very clear.
- Seven minutes.
- To do what? To get there?
To jump in the pool?
Goddam it. Ah, Jesus.
- We got it.
- He what?
- Blocked out the trace.
Should we pull it?
- No.
Run the trace again.
All right, let's start
dumping hackers and phreakers
in the profile. Anybody high tech.
Uh, we'll cross match that with military
background, police background...
uh, security training,
uh, hostage negotiations.
- Where's the pool?
- It's over there.
Hands in front of you.
Hands straight out.
Hands to the side. Push.
Hands in front.
Hands up.
Hands in front of you.
Shit! We lost him.
Damn it.
Track all unsubs
that exit the building.
You're going too slow.
Get your ass moving.
Now, put on the hat
and the overalls.
Take the canvas bags downstairs
to the boiler room.
Use the stairs by the shower.
Put the money into the new bags.
Then leave the building
and find a Monte Carlo.
There's a key taped
to the phone.
Leave the phone with the suitcases
and drive to the Holland Tunnel.
We'll be watching you, Tom.
We're getting a reading on
those suitcases. They haven't moved.
Tell the S.O. Ieader
I want that building cleared.
500 to S.O. units.
We got an eyeball. We got the car.
The car has not moved.
S.O. 15 to CP.
Located the packages. They're empty.
Sir, we've got four vehicles ID'd in the
perimeter, one with a broken taillight.
Put out a description
of those vehicles.
Have all units grid out
and locate them.
Pick me up, asshole.
Now what?
So how you holding up?
Did you have a nice swim?
Not bad. How're you doing?
Hey, I'm good. I'm good.
You know, thanks for asking.
- How's Sean?
- Havin' the time of his life.
Hey, I saw your TV commercial.
It's not bad. It's pretty good.
But let me ask you something.
You got a frequent flyer programme?
'Cause if you do,
maybe when this is over...
I might just take an Endeavor flight
the hell outta here.
Why? Why me?
Why you?
'Cause you buy your way
out of trouble.
Don't you? I read about you
and that union guy.
You should've gone to jail
for that, but I guess you're
a pretty goddam good liar, huh?
I saw you on TV, Tom...
telling everybody
how innocent you were.
I looked at your eyes.
You know what?
You're a lyin'-ass dog, pal.
I know you paid that guy off.
You're a payer.
You did it once.
Now you're gonna do it again.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
- Listen, Cub. You want me to do this?
- Jimmy said me.
- Fuck what Jimmy said.
- Look, I know the job, man.
Clark, man.
I ain't giving Jimmy
the money until he cuts the kid loose.
I-- I just ain't
gonna do it, man.
What are you-- Cub.
You a movie fan, Tom?
- Ever see that movie The Time Machine?
- No.
It's the, uh,
land of the future, right?
There's only two kinds
of people in the world now:
the Morlocks and the Eloi.
- Okay.
- And the Elois, they live above ground.
They wear togas.
They're all blond.
They eat grapes
and shit like that.
But it's like
the Garden of Eden there.
I mean, basically, everybody
just lays around, listens to harp music.
- How do I get my boy back?
- Now, the Morlocks...
they live underground, right?
Big, hairy, ugly suckers
like you wouldn't wish on an ape, right?
They're down there with all this
machinery. They're doing all the labour.
They're making sure that the Elois
have enough food and-- and togas.
- Are you gonna answer me?
- Well, this is a great deal
if you're an Eloi, right?
There's only one thing.
Every once in a while,
a Morlock comes up to the surface...
and snatches an Eloi,
takes him down there.
All right, I'm done driving 'til
you tell me what I want to know.
The Morlocks,
they don't eat grapes.
They're cannibals.
They eat Elois.
So when I think about,
uh, The Time Machine...
it kind of reminds me
of New York City, you know?
See, you're an Eloi.
You and all your friends,
walking around like zombies...
with no fuckin' idea of the shit
goin' on down below.
So does this make me a Morlock?
I don't like to think
of myself like--
I guess it does.
And every once in a while,
one of you gets snatched.
I guess that's--
See ya.
What a city.
See you at the Whitney.
See you at the Four Seasons.
See you at the Met. See ya.
See you.
- You on the move again, Tom?
- Yeah.
Okay, here we go.
About a mile up ahead, the road splits.
Take the exit onto Saddle River Road,
go to the stone quarry.
Drive ten miles an hour.
I'm jumpin' through all your goddam
hoops. How am I gonna get my boy back?
We'll swap. You give me the bags,
I'll give you an address.
Good luck to you, laddie.
Get back in the fucking car!
Now, throw out the keys.
Give me the money, man.
- Give me the address.
- Give me the fuckin' money, man!
- You said you were gonna
give me the address.
- What?
Do you want to see your kid again, man?
Then give me the money!
Goddam it! Give me
that address, goddam you!
- Don't be fuckin' stupid, man!
- This is the FBl.
Drop the gun and step away
from the vehicle.
- Put your hands in the air.
Step away from the vehicle.
- Son of a bitch!
- Mullen, stay back. Get down.
- CP, need some help here.
He's surrounded.
We've gone overt.
We have one subject
on the ground operating an ATV.
A white male armed
with a handgun, and he's got--
- We have an eye on him.
- Good.
- Who is that?
Come on, Cubby. Come on, Cubby.
- Stop, or we'll shoot.
- Get off the vehicle and lie down.
You have no way out.
You are surrounded.
Give yourself up.
- This is the FBl.
- You've got nowhere to go.
We have agents on the ground.
This is your last warning.
Surrender yourself now!
This is the FBl.
There is nowhere to go.
Drop the gun. Stop at once.
Move! Move!
SWAT Team Leader to CP.
We have deployed. We're movin' in.
Got a green light!
Take him out!
Oh, shit.
SWAT Team Leader to CP. We have
an agent down. We have a subject down.
Who got shot?
Who the hell was shot?
Where is he?
What have you done with him?
What?
Say it. Come on.
- Stand back. Come on. Step back.
- No, no, he--
- He's trying to tell me something.
- Look, back off. Let us stabilize him.
- Medic!
- He's trying to tell me
where my son is. I'm sure of it.
What are you people do--
I did not authorize this!
- We're here under orders.
- That fucking liar!
- Oh, we're losin' him.
- Don't let him die.
Jesus Christ, don't let him die.
God, don't let him die.
- Come on, man.
Don't give up. Don't give up.
- Get the choppers.
Stay with him. Come on.
- Shit!
- What?
Ten-seven, sir.
He's dead.
How-- How am I
gonna find Sean now?
You killed my son.
SWAT Team Leader to CP.
We're movin' out.
S.O. Leader, you've got it.
Give me as much as you can.
This guy's got to be on parole,
probation, something.
- Get the name of--
- I told you no cops.
- Ah, jeez!
- You were supposed to follow the money!
- They were following the money, Tom.
The guy had a gun in your face.
They didn't have a choice.
They thought you were
in direct danger.
What does that mean? What does-- What
does "wrong" mean? I mean, is he dead?
Because if he's dead,
just say he's dead.
Don't tell me something went wrong.
- Just say my son is dead!
- Kate, we are operating
under the assumption that he's alive.
You mean you don't know! You don't know
where he is! You don't know if he is!
You're the goddam FBl,
and you don't know shit!
- We have every agent-- every agent--
- You killed the son of a bitch
and now-- What?
- Katie. Katie.
- Get-- God!
Go. Go away. Go. Go.
We know that the kidnapper
at the quarry was not alone.
We know that.
We also have a real good idea
about who he was teamed up with.
Now, let me show you something.
The guy at the quarry, Cubby Barnes,
has been in jail twice for burglary.
This is no high-tech mastermind.
This guy right here--
Kate, Tom, you recognize him?
- Do you?
- No.
- Okay.
Now, this is Clark Barnes,
brother to the subject.
Now, we went back and we found him
in your son's video of the park.
This guy is the brains
in the family...
and we also know he's a lot higher up
the criminal food chain.
According to the NYPD,
this guy Clark, his brother Cubby,
they're supposed to be inseparable.
Now, I guarantee you,
we are gonna do our homework on this...
and we will come up
with another player.
In the meantime,
what we gotta do--
Aw, Christ. Not this shit.
- We got a cameraman.
- Jack.
Can we get some agents out there?
- This just in. A breaking story
from our New York bureau.
- Lonnie. It's out.
State police sources tell us
a man has been shot and killed
in an apparent botched ransom drop.
There's also word
that multimillionaire airline mogul
Tom Mullen has been placed at the scene.
With more on that story,
let's go to Donna Hanover live...
-in front of Tom Mullen's New York home.
-Goddam.
-Donna.
We have no official report yet
on the identity of the victim...
or his role in
the Sean Mullen kidnapping.
Hopefully, we'll have more information
for you later in this hour...
but details have been slow to come
from the police and FBI sources.
We'll bring you full
developments tomorrow morning...
beginning with
Good Day, New York, and, of course...
- as things happen here at
the Mullen apartment building,
- Hey, wh-what are you doing?
- we'll bring you the information.
- Calling my mother.
- No, man, you can't do that.
- Not from this phone.
- Get the fuck outta here.
- Hey, hey, put the phone down.
What's the matter, Jimmy?
You don't want my mother to know that
her son's dead 'cause you fucked up?
-Turn that shit off.
-I mean, that's what happened, isn't it?
I mean, it's not exactly like
this guy just rolled over, is it, Jim?
Just take it easy.
Put the goddam phone down.
He's a fuckin' kid.
Oh, shit!
Hey, hey, calm down.
Take it easy.
You want me to calm down, huh?
You want me to fucking calm down?
You realize they're looking for me
right now, Jimmy? I'm fingered!
- I can't go back to my life!
What do you want me to do? You tell me!
- Shut up.
- You tell me, huh?
- You know, you're not gonna
be able to go to your brother's
funeral either, man.
Shut the fuck up!
The kid goes in the ground, Jim.
That's it. That's it.
Fuck the money.
- We do the kid, and I'm outta here.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa. Wait a minute.
He's right. I mean,
you said you were gonna do it anyhow.
Shut up!
- Where are you goin'?
- Get out of my fuckin'--
Take a breath.
Come on, come on. Take a breath.
I brought you in on this
'cause you had brains and balls.
Think.
Hmm? The kid's gonna die...
when we don't need him any more.
Now, use your fuckin' head.
Go check on the kid.
It's all right. Go on.
Go on.
They kill your brother,
and you wanna walk away?
What the hell does that make you?
This thing is not over.
I swear to you right now...
now, more than ever...
this guy will pay.
Can I have a chocolate bar?
- I know you.
- No, you don't.
Don't look at me!
Don't look at me.
Chocolate bar. What,
do you think this isn't happening?
What, you think your dad's gonna come in
and save you? ls that what you think?
Well, he ain't.
Nobody's comin', all right?
You understand that? Nobody's comin',
'cause this is it for you.
...surfacing surrounding
the high-profile kidnapping case
of Tom Mullen's son, Sean.
- New York One has
exclusive information about--
- You know what the brothers call this?
This is "more drama," right?
Like, "Shit, man, more drama?
Best stay indoors today."
You ever hear that?
"More drama."
More drama. More Dramamine.
Drambuie.
- You all right?
- No, yeah. Yeah, good.
Yeah.
- Kimba, listen to this.
- It shouldn't be a problem.
- That.
After "lt shouldn't be
a problem," what do you hear?
Wait. Play it back again.
- It shouldn't be a problem.
- It sounds like some kind of horn.
Yeah, I know it's a horn,
but what-- It's like--
- It's like there's a horn,
a sort of foghorn.
- It's too fast for a ferry.
It shouldn't be a problem.
In the meantime,
now you give her a big hug from me.
Nah, I don't care.
You wake her up.
Nah, don't wake her up.
I'm just--
Ah, girl, I am so glad
we are not rich.
You just gotta thank God
for what you have.
I love you too. I gotta go.
I'm gonna call you back.
Okay. Bye-bye. Hey.
Why--
Why would this guy, these people--
Why would they--
Why would they ever let
my son go no matter what I do?
I mean, no matter what I do.
I mean, pay, don't pay, comply,
tell him to go fuck himself.
Why would they give him back?
I mean, he's a witness
any way you cut it.
It's all bullshit. It's all just--
just seven out of ten.
What are you saying?
All right.
Morlock Man gets his money,
I don't think we'll ever see Sean again.
That's if he's still alive
to begin with.
- Well, now...
- Tom?
are you talkin' about not paying?
- No. No, we pay him.
- Now, wait a minute. Listen to me.
Morlock Man says the pick-up guy
will give me an address for Sean.
I get there, the guy
sticks a gun in my face.
I said, "You want the money? Now give me
the address. Where's the address?"
You should have seen his face.
He had no, absolutely no idea
what I was talking about. None.
- Okay.
- This is not business to him.
This is very personal.
I tell you that everybody pays,
and we get back seven out of ten.
- If we give him what he wants,
he will kill Sean.
- Tom, you gotta play the odds, man.
I've been doing this
for 18 years.
And if I were a betting man,
I would bet on the people who pay
every time out of the gate.
Did you bet on the ones
where you got back a corpse?
Kate.
If you want to see your child again...
you gotta help me with him.
- Stations!
- Mark it.
-Mullen.
-You think you can run a game on me
and fuck me out of my money?
No, l--
It was out of my control.
I did exactly what you said.
You did?
This is how you want to play it, huh?
You're gonna bullshit me, Tom?
Who do you think
you're dealin' with?
They told you they were
just gonna follow the cash, right? Huh?
Who's the asshole
you're listening to over there?
Is he a fed? I said no cops.
No FBl. You pay me.
It shouldn't be a problem.
Now we got a fuckin' circus out there.
All right. Just say
what you want to say.
- The money.
- I want to talk to my son.
Take the FDR Drive down
to the Williamsburg Bridge exit.
- No. I know he's dead.
- You don't know shit.
- Take FDR Drive down
to the Williamsburg Bridge--
- My son is dead. Go to hell!
What did you do?
Tom, what did you do?
Oh, God. Please, God. Please, God.
Please, God. Please. Please, God.
Mullen.
- Dad?
- Sean?
Williamsburg Bridge.
And you assholes listening in, if
I smell you clowns within ten miles...
of that money,
I'll gut this kid like a fish.
Is there anything else
we can use?
Uh, give me Mr Wallace.
I'm going alone.
Is that understood?
No helicopters, no wires.
Just me.
- You got the phone?
- Yeah, I got the phone.
You gonna be all right?
- Yeah, I'm gonna be all right.
- Okay.
Hey, hey, here he comes.
Come on. Let's go. Let's go, let's go.
Mr Mullen! Mr Mullen!
- Mullen!
- Mr Mullen!
Mr Mullen-- It's not Mullen.
Let's go. That's him.
- Hey, John, keep shooting.
- Man, this is fucking great.
Hey!
Come on!
Endeavor Airline CEO
Tom Mullen and his family...
are no strangers
to the public eye.
As head of the country's
fourth largest airline...
Tom Mullen, whose personal stake in the
company was reported earlier this year--
But nothing in his triumphant,
high-profile life...
could prepare Mullen for the drama
presently unfolding around him--
the taking of his nine-year-old son
by unidentified kidnappers.
- Where are you at now?
- I don't know.
Head up to Houston and Broadway.
- But for now, the city and
the country anxiously await word--
- You hear me?
Mullen?
- Change of plan.
- What?
Turn on your TV.
Channel 5. Keep watching.
It shouldn't be more
than an hour or two.
You understand
what I'm telling you?
Mullen, what the fuck--
It's mine. Hello?
David, I need you
to contact Don Campbell at WNYW.
- All right.
- Good.
- Bob, can I talk to you, please?
- Sure.
David.
- All right, here we go.
- Okay, they're ready.
Pull out of it.
All right, everyone. Look alive.
Mr Mullen, we're gonna
get you set up right over here.
We'll get you wired up with a mike.
I will signal to you
from next to the camera.
Ready to go? On five, four...
three, two--
Good afternoon.
We are interrupting this programme
to bring you an exclusive report.
As you know, we've been
following the Mullen kidnapping
for about a day or so.
We will get back to
our regular programme, but right now
we're going to show you something...
that you will only see
right here--
Tom Mullen,
Sean Mullen's father.
Mr Mullen?
Tom, you're on.
The whole world now knows...
my son, Sean Mullen, was kidnapped...
for ransom three days ago.
This is a recent
photograph of him.
Sean, if you're watching,
we love you.
And this--
Well, this is what waits
for the man that took him.
This is your ransom.
Wait. Shh, shh.
I want to see this.
Two million dollars
in unmarked bills, just like you wanted.
- Oh-ho!
- But this is as close
as you'll ever get to it.
You'll never see one dollar
of this money...
because no ransom will ever
be paid for my son.
Not one dime. Not one penny.
Instead, I'm offering this money
as a reward on your head.
Dead or alive.
It doesn't matter.
So congratulations. You've just
become a $2 million lottery ticket.
Except the odds
are much, much better.
Do you know anyone that wouldn't
turn you in for $2 million?
I don't think you do.
I doubt it.
So wherever you go and whatever you do,
this money will be tracking you
down for all time.
And to ensure that it does,
to keep interest alive...
I'm running a full-page ad
in every major newspaper every Sunday...
for as long as it takes.
But-- and this is
your last chance--
if you return my son
alive, uninjured...
I'll withdraw the bounty.
With any luck,
you can simply disappear.
Understand-- you will never see
this money. Not one dollar.
So you still have a chance
to do the right thing.
If you don't, well, then God
be with you because nobody else
on this Earth will be.
Well, he's got nerve.
That's it.
Well, there you have it, Rosanna.
A shocking turn of events.
The ransom has turned
into a $2-million bounty.
Tony, it's obviously
a very dangerous situation.
Anything could happen. Of course,
we wish him the best of luck.
Did you notice he,
uh, described the kidnapper
as a $2 million lottery ticket?
- The stakes are high on this one.
- Yeah, as you mentioned also--
- Could you turn it off?
Could you turn it off?
- Mr Mullen also appealed to his son.
He said, "Sean, if you're
out there listening, I love you."
- It was very heartbreaking.
- Also, our producer is telling me, uh--
- Yeah.
- Mullen, you're a fool!
Stupid ass!
I'm proud of you!
A pair of armed bandits
held 'em up last night.
Police say a pair of gun-toting crooks
went into the Korean church
at Murray Street...
in Flushing last night
and announced a robbery.
- They took wallets, handbags--
- Hey, where'd they take the kid?
You know. The place we said.
I had to do this.
You had to do this?
Kate, please.
I'm so scared, but I know if
I give him the money, he'll kill Sean.
- I would if I was him.
- What did you just say?
Just look at it
from his point of view.
You think you're smart.
You've got everybody off balance.
- You think you've
got it all figured out.
- You tryin' to screw me?
And then suddenly,
out of left field, the one thing
you thought would never happen does.
- We gotta end this.
- What are you doin'?
No ransom, no money, no profit.
Nothing. Nothing but downside.
Because you've got this boy's father--
he's coming on like a stark,
raving mad lunatic.
- You turned her around, didn't you?
- I mean, the guy can piss $2 million...
- but he's willing to risk everything
just to fuck you up.
- Don't!
How can you negotiate with
a lunatic like that, huh? You can't.
- Now you're off balance.
- Get down. Lay down!
You wanna stay down there forever,
maggot? Did I get my money?
Pretty soon you realize if you don't
return this kid in mint condition
as soon as possible...
you're gonna be the most hunted man
on the face of the Earth.
And this maniac will never,
ever quit until he's got you.
Nobody pulls out on me.
You know me.
This is my show.
I say when it's over.
- Take it back.
- No.
- Tell him that you were wrong.
- Kate, no, I can't. No, Kate,
there is no other way. None.
- Take it back.
- He's my son too,
and I want you to pay him.
- Kate. They will kill him.
Please, all we have
is each other.
Do you think any of them--
Do you think they give-- It's just us.
Do you think I don't
want him back? ls that it?
You think I wouldn't do absolutely
everything in my power to get him back?
I'd cut my arm off.
I'd-- I want him back so bad.
Katie, please. I don't think
I can take this if you're not with me.
Don't quit on me.
Tom. Now--
I think what you did was wrong.
You put your son at greater risk.
Now, I need you
to withdraw that reward.
Just pay this bastard.
Now, I believe that
you will get your son back.
And when we do,
we will nail this son of a bitch.
Now, God forbid you don't...
your son--
I swear to you
I will work on nothing else.
If I have to, I will take
a leave of absence from the FBl...
and you can hire me as
your personal security consultant.
And I will work on this
as long as I am physically able.
- Lonnie, please. I--
- Tom.
I never told anybody,
any of my people...
about you and Jackie Brown, the real
truth of it, and maybe I never will.
You think I'm worried
about going to jail?
Mayor Barresi today voiced his
disapproval of Tom Mullen's decision.
- Donna Hanover joins us
later in the broadcast.
- You, uh, care for an update?
Oh, yeah.
Well, in the last two hours
since your husband's TV thing,
we've had 4,000 calls.
- And you know how
many real, good, solid leads?
- How many?
Zero. And every time
one of these...
greedy little whack jobs calls...
that is one less agent
looking for your child.
Now, I gotta tell you, Kate.
I have never been confronted with such
an unbelievable act of sabotage...
by a parent toward
the recovery of their child...
as what your husband
pulled off here today.
It is all on you now to talk to your
husband, get him to withdraw this money.
- Otherwise we are in deep trouble.
- Withdraw the mo-- What if he's right?
What if they have no intention
of returning Sean at all?
- I trust him.
- You trust him?
Yeah. I believe in him.
I stick with Tom...
and we always manage
to land on high ground.
High ground? Huh.
Like with the Jackie Brown situation?
Yeah.
What exactly did
your husband tell you...
about Jackie Brown?
- David?
- Yeah.
- Can I talk to you for a minute?
- Yeah, sure.
Look, Hawkins said that if I can come up
with the $2 million, that he'd work it
so that I can make the drop.
- Come on, Kate--
- Now, all I can raise is
about a half a million.
I know you have access
to a discretionary fund.
Kate. Jesus, please. Listen,
you should talk to Tom about this.
- This isn't about Tom.
- Really.
- This is Sean.
I'm doin' okay.
I'm holdin' up all right.
Uh, Kate, l-l can't do it.
All right?
I--
He told you not to give me
any money, didn't he?
Kate, he's my boss. Okay?
Okay, eat this.
Thank you.
Again, I say if it
were my kid, I would pay.
I like the idea, "Yeah, you want
the money, come and get it."
And when he comes and gets it, I hope
somebody cuts their heads off, you know?
I'd get my boys from the Bronx,
and we'd just totally--
- Take care of him.
- We'd mess him up big time.
I think he's risking
his son's life.
I think he's a fool.
His child's life is in danger.
Pay the money.
Get on with your life.
I'd beg, borrow and steal,
if I had to. He should pay.
What?
- A man calls me at my home today.
- Mm-hmm.
He ask me to look in my mailbox.
He told me to give you this,
and nobody else.
He said if the police
know anything about this...
if Mr Mullen knows about this...
they'll kill Sean.
Okay.
Who is it?
Oh, God!
It's very simple.
I'm growing very, very tired
of this bullshit.
- Then could you--
- Now it's up to you.
Get him to take back the reward
and pay me my money...
or you're gonna find pieces
of your little boy all over New York.
I'm not gonna waste a bullet.
I'm just gonna sharpen my knife.
Oh, God! Please!
And he never raised
his voice at all, Kate?
No, he-- No, he was whispering.
I-- He was whispering.
Okay. Come on.
We'll take it to the lab.
You paid off
to save your airline.
Why won't you pay off
to save your son?
I'm not a marriage counsellor.
I'm here to get your boy back.
I'm sorry.
I hope...
that you can
forgive me for that.
And for what I have to do now.
Get the shirt to Forensics.
- Make sure they check for
more than one blood type.
- Sure, Lonnie.
Where are you goin', Tom?
Where are you goin'? What you--
I'm not-- All right.
Just think before you act.
- There he is.
- Mr Mullen!
- I'd like to make a statement.
- Quiet.
And that is that I'm undeterred
in my course of action.
And I'm raising the reward.
Uh, I'm raising it
by $2 million.
- Mr Mullen, why are you doing this?
- I want my son back.
Thank you. Thank you.
The FBl's efforts
in this area--
This just in: Tom Mullen
has reportedly raised the reward money
for his son's life...
by $2 million.
Hey.
Where are you goin'?
You've ruined my life.
Who the hell you think
I'm doing this for?
A stunning development tonight as
Tom Mullen doubles the reward money...
to $4 million
for the capture of--
- What?
- Wanna talk to your son?
- Yes, of course I do.
- Mmm, Daddy? Dad?
Sean.
- Sean. Sean. Son.
- Sean? I wanna listen.
- That's enough.
- No, put him back on.
I wanna-- I wanna talk to him.
You just did.
Now, you listen...
real, real good.
You got one more chance to pay up
or you're never gonna talk to him again.
No more fuckin' around.
This is it right now.
What's it gonna be?
No. Bullshit. You're not gonna
touch him. You can't be that stupid.
Do you have any idea
the rain of shit I can put on you?
Look at your wife.
Look at her face, motherfucker.
Do you know what I can do to your boy?
Is it dark where you're calling from?
You got the shades drawn?
Kind of like a cellar, right? Like a
cave? Well, you better get used to that.
You better get used to crawling
in the dark for the rest of your days...
because I am going to get the best group
of manhunters in this country...
and I am gonna dedicate my life
to tracking you down!
- You understand?
- Hey, hey, get your head
out of your ass!
You think you can threaten me, huh?
Who do you think you're dealing with?
Give me the money!
Fuck you and your $2 million!
Don't you understand English, you
useless piece of shit? No money! None!
Let me tell you something. You think
you're suffering right now? Huh?
You got no idea what suffering is.
If I don't get the cash in one hour,
this kid is dead!
I don't get my son back, and I mean
real soon, you better kill yourself...
because when I catch up with you
I'm gonna take my goddam time!
By the time we're finished,
you're gonna wish you weren't born!
I'll have your head on a fuckin' pike!
You understand me?
Fuck you! I'll fuckin'
kill him right now!
- I wanna talk!
- You kill him, you kill yourself,
you motherfucker!
- Give me back my son!
- Hello!
- You want him?
- Yes!
Daddy!
Oh! Jesus! Jesus!
Oh, Jesus! Oh! Oh!
Oh! Oh, God!
I'll fuckin' kill you, Mullen!
You son of a bitch! You killed him,
you son of a bitch! Goddam it!
- Whoa, whoa.
- Oh, God. Oh, God.
- Come on. Easy. Come on.
- Kate!
- Both of you listen to me!
- You killed him! Not them! You!
No, Kate! Kate.
Okay, it's all right.
- Take her in the other room.
- Oh, God! Oh, God!
- Oh, God. I wanted to talk to him.
- I know.
- I wanted to talk to him.
- You'll talk to him, honey.
You will. You will.
- What do we do about this kid?
- Ain't my problem any more.
Can't ID anybody, right? Fuck 'im.
Oh, God. Oh, God.
Oh, please, help me. Please.
Okay, Katie, all right.
It's okay. It's okay.
Oh, God. Oh, no.
- Ohh! Ohh!
- Oh, Tom.
South 44 to Base.
- Oh, God. Oh, God.
- South 44, go.
2627 18th Street.
10-13. Officer needs assistance.
I have several armed men in a house.
Possible kidnap situation.
Repeat, possible kidnap situation.
10-13. Officer
in civilian clothes.
- Police!
- Shit.
- Get the fuck out of the van!
- Go, man. Come on.
Drop the gun!
Move! Move! Go!
Clear!
- Police! Freeze!
- Whoa! Whoa, whoa, whoa! I'm a cop!
- Clear!
- Hold your fire. I'm a cop.
He's all right.
I'm a cop.
Kate. Tom.
FBl. Comin' through.
Comin' through.
Stay with me. Stay with me.
Comin' through, fellas. Comin' through.
Wh-- Where is-- Where is--
Oh, Jesus Christ.
Wh-Where is--
L-Lonnie? Where's Sean?
In the house. In the house.
Right over here.
Don't stop here, guys.
Keep movin' all the way through.
-Clear the doorway here, okay?
-The boy's in there.
-All right, here comes the boy's father.
Sean? Sean?
I'm-- I'm the father.
Sean?
- Who is it?
- Sean. It's me. It's Daddy.
Daddy?
Is he-- Is he all right?
C-Can I pick him up?
- Can I hold him?
- Oh, he's gonna be all right.
- Oh, Sean.
He's just got a nasty cut on his hand,
and he's, uh, a little dehydrated.
- Sean, it's Mommy.
- You're okay, buddy.
You're okay. We got ya.
- We got ya now.
- Hi, Mom.
- Hi, sweetheart.
- You're okay.
- Take me home, okay?
- Oh, sure. Sure.
- Take me home.
- Okay, honey.
- I love you, Sean.
- Me too.
Mama's here, Sean.
You're okay.
-Is-ls-ls-ls he seriously injured?
-Here's your man. He's right over there.
He's gonna be okay.
Step to the side, please.
- All the way to the right.
- Lieutenant, we--
- All the way back. Get back.
- Back off.
- Mr Shaker?
- Step back, please.
Step back. Step back.
Did you get a chance
to talk to him?
- I said step back.
- Thank you.
- Call it justice.
It's a department courtesy.
- All right, now, if you please.
- Move. Move.
- Guys, help us out, will ya?
- Thank you.
Ho, ho, ho, ho!
Tom. Tom? Just come this way.
What-- What-- Mr Mullen!
You know her?
Yeah.
I do.
Jesus Christ. I mean,
she w-worked for me.
Catering.
Please, sir! Here!
- Mr Mullen! Tom! Tom!
- Mr Mullen, this way!
Wait! This way! Right here!
Right here! Look over here, please!
- You okay?
- Not now. Come on, back off.
Not now. Leave 'em alone.
- Give us a break now!
- Sean, here!
-Sean! Mr Mullen!
-Mr Mullen, this way! Mr Mullen, please!
Aaah! Turn the lights on!
Turn the lights on!
- Hey.
- It's all right.
- I'm afraid of the dark.
I don't like the dark.
- You're all right.
- Leave the light on.
- Yeah, we'll leave 'em on.
We'll leave 'em on all the time.
Okay?
Next thing I know,
one guy starts blastin' away at me.
The-- The other guy,
he goes to run me over.
So, you know,
I just did what I had to do.
What about the woman?
Jimmy?
Uh, you know, I just, uh,
got spun around by the bullet.
I didn't know
it was a woman 'til after.
He's a, an honest cop.
He does a hell of a job.
- He's kind of a to-himself
type of a guy.
- No, just one.
- But I tell you what,
when the chips are down...
- Cancel the other one.
this is the one
I'd want with me.
- How do I feel?
- No.
- I'll tell ya, this is
the second time...
- Jimmy Shaker's been shot.
- Just one-way.
He got clipped once before in 1992,
and this guy keeps coming back.
Yeah. Uh, Mr Kinney.
Yeah. Thanks.
Continuing our coverage
of the Mullen kidnapping case...
questions still surround
Maris Conner.
With no prior criminal record,
authorities are interrogating
family and friends...
seeking any associations that would
connect her to the other slain suspects.
Sources reveal today that
the investigation continues...
and the search for
other suspects is by no means over.
Many investigators believe that,
indeed, the mastermind
of the Mullen kidnapping...
may still be at large.
- Whoa!
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
- We can make it.
- Oh, sh--
- Ohh!
- You cold, honey?
- Yeah. My hands.
- Do you wanna go home?
- I didn't bring my gloves.
- No. No. No.
You sure? Hey, you're squinting a
little. Is the sun still bothering you?
- Put these on.
- Yeah.
- I'll go get your gloves.
- Okay.
You'd better practise.
I'll be back.
Look at me.
You look good in those, honey.
- Look at my glasses. Can you see?
- Mm-hmm.
Look like your daddy
in those.
Well, David, it's a little hard
to focus right now. Can it wait?
No? Well, the hell with it, then.
Let him have it. Let it go.
Yeah. Listen, I got Sean waitin' for me
in the park, so maybe we--
- Hey.
Uh, I'll call you back, David.
Call you back.
- Mr Mullen.
- Uh--
- The doorman just called up.
- Mr Shaker wants to see you.
- Yeah, yeah, I'm sorry
to show up like this.
Oh, hell, no. Come in.
I-l wanna talk to you.
- Thanks.
- Come in. Come in. How's the shoulder?
Ahh, you know. I'll live.
Yeah. Well, I'm surprised
to see you up and about so quick.
- Uh, uh, Fatima,
this is, uh, Jimmy Shaker.
- Hi.
I'm very proud to meet you.
- Very proud.
- Thanks.
How's the, uh, kid doin'?
Oh, he's fine, you know,
all things considered.
- It'll take a while.
- Yeah.
Um, uh, forgive me.
I, uh, I thought
we were gonna meet on Monday.
M-Maybe I screwed up. I don't-- I--
Uh, yeah, uh, you're right.
Monday. We-- That's what we said, uh--
See the special officer
holding 4-5-9--
Look, I don't want you to get
the wrong impression of me here...
but I was hopin'
we could do this today.
- You know, the reward and all?
- Oh. Of course. Oh, Jesus.
- 'Cause I gotta tell ya...
it's, uh, kinda crazy
around me, you know,
with the, the press and everything.
Oh, I understand. Yeah.
Look, they're maniacs.
- Yeah.
- Nothin' easier. Follow me.
I'm not used to this, you know.
I-- I just gotta get outta here.
Kind of a private person,
you know.
To tell you the truth,
I never killed anybody before.
Havin' a hard time with it.
Yeah, well, I'm sorry.
Uh, I'm glad you did
what you did.
But I'm sorry.
- Sit down, please.
- Thanks.
Uh, so, is it, uh--
is it Jimmy? James?
James.
James'll do.
- Can I ask you a personal question?
- Sure.
Why didn't you pay the ransom?
Well, because I was dealing
with human garbage.
No contract would have been honoured,
not by them.
You know, the funny thing is,
I would have paid ten times as much...
if I had any sense that
they'd stick to the deal, but no.
- Really.
- Oh, yeah. Really.
The thing that really kills me
about that is the woman.
She'd been in this house five,
six times over the last year.
Nice. Pleasant. You know.
You just can't, uh--
I-l don't know how people
can walk around with that--
That cold-blooded, two-faced--
That bitch.
Well, uh, you know,
in fairness to the dead...
we're all a little two-faced
in this day and age.
It's a survival mechanism. You kn--
You know what I'm saying?
I mean, you know, as a cop...
you should hear some of the stuff that's
been thrown my way over the years.
Tom, just forget about the gloves,
honey. He wanted to come home.
- Kate, uh--
- Hi, Tom.
- Mr Shaker's here.
Mr Shaker.
Ohh, um--
God bless you.
Uh, thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Listen, you-- you gotta meet Sean.
I'll go get him.
No, uh, he's, you know, had enough.
Let's give him a breather. Yeah?
Yeah, yeah.
He's-He's had enough.
Okay. Uh, can I get you anything?
No, I'm fine.
Oh, well, again, l--
I can't even begin to--
I understand.
Don't mention it.
Okay.
Fatima, would you please help me
with some things downstairs?
I'll be right there.
Well, this is, uh,
one hell of a deposit you've got here.
Shouldn't be a problem.
Well, you'll probably
wanna be on your way.
Uh, unless there's anything else
I can do for you.
Good. Right.
Well, I know how these vultures
out there can drive ya nuts, so--
You know, there's a back door
out if you, you know,
wanna be a little more s--
This check is bullshit, Tom.
What'd you think,
I'm just gonna waltz outta here,
you lying motherfucker? Huh?
Let you make a phone call,
have half the cops in New York
waitin' for me while I cash this thing?
- You can't lie to me.
- Look--
Shut your mouth.
Fuck!
You know who I am.
Now you sit down.
Everybody was gonna make out fine.
But you had to go
and put it together...
and now we got
a little problem here, don't we?
Tell me that part again about
why you didn't pay the ransom.
- I think we can do something here--
- Say it!
You were dealing with what?
- You had my son.
- You have no idea what
human garbage is, motherfucker.
Do you know what the fuck you're
talking about? No, I don't think you do.
'Cause look where you fuckin' live, man.
Look at the airline man here.
This fucker won't pay one cent
to save his only kid.
- It wasn't gonna get him back, was it?
- Hey, did you read the papers? Huh?
Did you see the TV?
I took a bullet.
I risked my life to save your kid.
I took a bullet, and now you're gonna
try to fuck me out of my money. Huh?
- What's over here?
- Where are you going?
- Where's Mommy and Junior?
- Now I'll pay. Now.
- Oh, yeah.
You're gonna pay, all right.
Right now.
Do you have an account I can wire
the money to? I mean, you got to have
been all set up for this, right?
I mean, you're not dumb. You and me,
we go right now to my bank...
and we wire the money
from my account to yours.
Just the push of a button.
Just like that.
We'll just go down to the bank
and get it done.
Pick up the phone.
Wire it from here.
Uh, no, we'll go to the bank
and do it.
And you'll get the money and all I want
in return is you out of this house now.
Hey. You do not call the shots.
Well, then, you just go ahead
and kill me right here and now,
you son of a bitch.
You fuck! Fuck you!
I'm not pickin' up that phone.
You got that?
I'm not pickin' it up.
Look, uh, you can kill me.
Go ahead. Kill me. Just kill us.
Let us live. Doesn't matter.
Any way you cut it, you're on the run.
Now, you can come with me to the bank
and be on the run with $4 million...
or you can just start shootin'
and be on the run with whatever
you got in your wallet.
It's up to you.
Come on, Jimmy. Let's go to the bank.
Oh, Jesus Christ.
I got what I want.
Bottom line: I got my son back.
And you d-- you delivered him.
I got my own plane. I can fly you out
of here myself anywhere you wanna go.
You can still win this thing.
Think. You can still win.
We do what you say.
We go to the bank.
If anything goes wrong, you're gonna
turn around and I'll be gone.
Okay? And if that happens...
from this day on...
any time your kid leaves
this house to go to school...
go play, see a friend...
to buy a fuckin' comic book,
you're gonna have to ask yourself:
Is today...
Jimmy Shaker day?
I got to him once.
I'll get him again.
And when I do...
I'm not gonna want money any more.
Do we understand each other?
Sure.
That's from Maris.
Call the airport.
Where are we goin'?
Mexico. Guadalajara.
David, this is Tom. Uh, fuel up the jet.
I'm going to Guadalajara.
Yeah, well, something came up.
I'm on my way to the bank now.
- Is the kidnapper with you?
- Absolutely.
I'll explain everything later.
Give Katie a call. Bye.
Antone, get me the Mullen house.
Sean, what's the matter, honey?
Come here.
Taxi! Taxi!
Stay on my right.
What are you guys doin'?
You can't park there.
Oh, we're just goin'
to the bank. Five minutes.
- Shaker?
- Yeah.
- How you doin', Jimmy?
- How are ya?
- Nice to meet you.
- Yeah? You too.
- How you doin', Mr Mullen?
Good to meet you.
- Hey.
Just wanna shake your hand, boss.
You made us proud.
- Well, you know, just doin' the job.
- Yeah.
What do you think
of this guy, Mr Mullen?
- Well, what can I say? He's the man.
- Yeah!
- Okay, guys, uh, take it easy.
- Later, Jimbo.
- Okay.
- You guys take it easy now.
- All right.
- You guys not gonna be long, right?
- No, just five minutes.
- No, no, no.
- No problem.
Mr Mullen,
what a pleasant surprise.
Welcome.
- Uh, have I still got any money
in this bank? I have to do
some business with Mr Shaker here.
- Yes.
- This is Michael.
- Mr Shaker, of course. Right this way.
Terrific. Okay, that's enough.
Let's get this man his money.
- Thanks very much.
- No, not a problem.
All units in the 22,
looking for Detective James Shaker...
white male, 41 years,
wearing black jacket, white shirt.
Shaker is thought to be in the vicinity
of Madison and 90th Street.
Subject is an armed
New York City detective.
Just push enter and it's yours.
Four million.
Congratulations.
Yeah, thanks. Okay.
Hey, Shaker.
What's goin' on?
I just got a call over the radio.
Oh, hey, hey, it's my birthday.
You know, the guys are tryin'
to pull something.
- I-l got it covered.
- Can we talk to you for a second, man?
No, we have to detain you.
Shaker! Freeze!
Hey, he's over here!
- Put it down! Put it down!
Put the gun down!
- Put the gun down!
- Hold your fire! Tom, it's me, Lonnie.
- F.B.I.!
- Hold your fire!
- It's over, Shaker. Over!
- Drop it!
- Put the gun down, Tom.
Put the gun down.
- No!
- Step away! Tom!
- Drop it now! Drop it now!
- Put the gun down, Tom, and walk away.
Mullen, put
the goddam gun down!
Put the gun down.
- Down, Mullen! Now!
- Come on. Come on.
Put the gun down.
- Drop the gun!
- Come on. Walk toward me.
- Tom, don't do nothin' stupid.
- Put down the gun now!
- Put the gun down, Tom!
- Drop it!
On the ground, Shaker!
On the ground!
- Tom, put the gun down now!
- Down!
Stay right there!
Now, don't move!
Put the gun down.
That's right. Now, back off, Tom.
Just walk away.
- Go ahead, Officer.
- Two-one, Sergeant. Code eight.
A want at 1268 Madison, forthwith.
We have shots fired,
and a member of the service is down.
10-4. The bus is ordered.
Get up against the wall!
Move! Spread 'em!
Tom Mullen is with us!
Back away!
No! No!