Please keep all limbs and branches inside.
I believe this is yours.
Thanks.
Welcome to Element City.
Please have your documents
ready for inspection.
Next.
Your names?
Great. And how do we spell that?
How about we just go with Bernie and Cinder?
Welcome to Element City.
Hot logs.
Hot logs for sale.
Cantankerous guy...
Hey, watch it, Sparky!
Water.
Dry leaves.
I'm okay.
Welcome, my Ember, to your new life.
Our Blue Flame hold all our traditions...
and give us strength to burn bright.
Do I burn as bright?
One, two, one, two, one, two.
This shop is dream of our family.
Someday it'll all be yours.
-Welcome.
Everything here authentic.
Then I've got to try the kol-nuts.
Kol-nuts, coming up.
Kol-nut, coming up.
Good daughter.
Someday this shop will all be mine.
When you are ready.
Delivery!
Two sugar pops, please.
I got it, Àshfá.
Hey!
Water. Keep an eye on them.
Oops.
You splash it, you buy it.
You showed them, huh?
Nobody waters down Fire.
Yeah!
Can the shop be mine now?
When you are ready.
-The truth is...
-She's not in love with him.
...I'm not in love with you.
Knew it.
Àshfá, customer.
How about you take it today?
For real?
How can I help you?
All of this and the...
The sparklers are buy one, get one free?
-That's right.
-Great!
I'll just take the free one.
No, see...
you need to buy one to get one free.
But I just want the free one.
Sorry, that's not how this works.
But the customer is always right.
Not in this case.
Nope.
Nope. Nope. Nope.
Just give me one for free!
That's not how this works!
Happy birthday.
What just happened?
Why you lose temper?
I don't know.
He was pushing, and pushing, and it just...
Calm, calm.
Sometimes customer can be tough.
Just take breath...
and make connection.
When you can do that and not lose temper...
then you will be ready to take over shop.
This is too expensive,
and that is not made in Fire Land.
-They weren't crunchy...
-Take breath.
-...and there wasn't enough sauce.
-Make connection.
Take breath.
Make connection.
Make connection!
Sorry. Sorry about that.
Sorry, sorry.
She almost went full purple.
I've never seen anyone go full purple.
Sorry, everyone.
Please forgive my daughter.
She burn bright, but sometimes too bright.
Nice hat, by the way.
Let me make you a new batch.
On the house.
Okay.
Sorry, Àshfá.
I don't know why that one
got away from me.
You are tense
because of big Red Dot Sale tomorrow.
It has us all in a broil.
I guess.
It's just that some of these customers,
they get me all...
I know. I know. Just do what we practice.
You are so good at everything else.
You're right.
I'll get it.
I just want you to rest.
Done.
You okay?
Just tired.
Let me help.
Bernie, that cough is terrible!
Almost as terrible as your cooking!
When you gonna put Ember
out of her misery and retire, huh?
Finally put her name on the sign out there?
She take over when she's ready.
And speaking of ready...
we are more than ready
for you to actually buy something...
if you'd ever get up off your lazy ash.
Burn!
But she is so close.
I mean, she'll probably never do deliveries
as quick as me...
You don't think that I can beat your record?
Because I have been taking it easy on you...
so I don't hurt your feelings,
Mr. Smokestack.
But game on.
Before I see if you are a match...
I splash this on your heart...
to bring love to the surface.
And I will read the smoke.
Ember, I'm doing a reading.
Sorry, got to grab some stuff.
Going for Dad's record.
So, are we a match?
It's true love.
Which is more than I ever smelled
on this one.
Goody, this old chestnut.
Yep. Nothing.
Just a loveless, sad future of sadness.
Ember, work with me.
Your finding match
was my mother's dying wish.
Promise me one thing...
marry Fire.
Nice try, Mom. Got to go.
-Save it for the wedding.
-Hey.
Yo, yo, yo, Ember.
Yo, Clod. Can't talk, in a hurry.
And don't let my dad
catch you out here again.
What? Come on,
he doesn't like my landscaping?
Anyway, June Bloom is coming...
and you just got to be my date
'cause check it out.
I'm all grown up.
And I smell good.
My queen.
Sorry, buddy, elements don't mix.
Flame.
Gotta go.
Come on, go to the festival with me.
You never leave this part of town.
That's because everything I need
is right here.
Plus, the city isn't made
with Fire people in mind.
Sorry, but it'd take an act of God
to get me across that bridge.
An act of God?
Or an act of Clod?
Gotta run.
As ordered.
Going for Dad's record.
Move it!
Winner winner, charcoal dinner...
Head to bed, I'll close things up.
Still have much to prepare for Red Dot Sale.
Dad, I'll take care of it.
You need to rest.
How?
I learned from the best.
I am old. I can't do this forever.
Now that you've beaten my time,
there's only one thing you haven't done.
Tomorrow I sleep in...
and I want you to run shop for Red Dot Sale.
Seriously? By myself?
If you can do that
without losing your temper...
it will show me you are able to take over.
You got it, Àshfá.
I won't let you down, I swear.
You'll see.
Good daughter.
Yes!
Blue Flame, please, let this go my way.
-Good morning!
-Morning!
Take a breath.
Calm as a candle.
Morning, welcome to The Fireplace.
Whoa, whoa. They're all the same.
Just take one from the top.
Thanks for shopping.
So many stickers for sale.
-Are these fragile?
-No, wait.
You have to pay before you eat.
What's your return policy?
Does this come in a large?
Take breath.
My dad broke this.
Make connection.
Mind if I test this kettle?
Be back in five minutes.
No, no, no.
Stupid temper. Not today.
What is wrong with me?
What the...?
What a happy family.
Is that you and your dad?
I love dads.
And it's your birthday.
Who are you?
What are you doing here?
I don't know.
I was searching for a leak on the other side
of the river and got sucked in.
This is bad, I can't lose another job.
I just can't seem to find my flow.
Dang!
That pipe squished me all out of shape.
That's better.
Dude, just get out of here.
I gotta clean this mess
before my dad sees what I did.
Actually...
I'm afraid I'm gonna
have to write you a ticket.
-A ticket?
-Yeah.
I'm a city inspector,
and this pipe is definitely not up to code.
I sucked a city inspector into our pipes?
I know. Ironic, right?
Stop messing with that.
-Well, I need to make sure it's solid.
-Everything's solid.
I should know.
My dad rebuilt this place himself.
Wait, your dad did?
Yes, with his bare hands,
every brick and board.
It was a ruin when he found it.
Wow. He did all of this himself?
Without permits?
I'm gonna have to write that up too.
First, I'm sucked into a pipe...
and now I have to write citations
that could get this place shut down.
Oh, gosh. It's just too much.
Shut us down?
I know, it's awful.
No, you can't shut us down, please.
This is a big day for me.
It's our Red Dot Sale.
Hey, take it easy.
This is as hard on me as it is on you.
-Get back here.
-Sorry.
I got to get these to City Hall
before the end of my shift.
Flame.
Get back here.
Next stop, Element City.
-Hey!
-Sorry.
Hey!
What the...?
This stop, City Hall.
Hands off!
Sorry.
Stop!
Hey!
Stop.
My new jacket.
Whoa!
Hey!
My chili oil!
Come on, guy.
You can't get through this.
So, it is time to hand them over.
Oh, boy, I'm sorry.
This is gonna be
really disappointing for you.
No, no, no.
Sorry.
Please...
No.
You don't understand.
This shop is my dad's dream.
If I'm the reason it gets shut down...
it will kill him.
He will never trust me to take over.
Why didn't you say that before?
Wait, does that mean
you'll tear up the tickets?
I mean, I would, but I just sent them over...
to the processing department.
But I can take you there
so you can plead your case.
Hey, Fern.
How you doing?
Living the dream.
You know those citations
I just gave you from Firetown?
I was about to send them to Mrs. Cumulus.
Then get sprayed for fungus rot.
Wait.
Tell him what you told me
about your dad and letting him down.
No. That's personal.
It really got to me.
He might feel it too.
-Her dad will be...
-Nope. Nope.
...super disappointed in her.
Stop it.
He might even be ashamed.
What are you doing?
But the main thing is...
if her father can't retire,
it will be all Ember's...
Stop talking!
Looks like I'm going home early today.
No, don't.
Expect to get shut down within a week.
Have a good one.
Sorry.
What?
Already?
Hello?
Oh, no.
Dad, what happened?
We lucky nobody hurt.
It ruined Red Dot Sale.
-Did he do this?
-Who?
The Water guy I see you chase.
Yeah, he did.
He just broke through a pipe.
I don't know why.
Luckily, I was able to close it off.
I couldn't catch him though.
Water, always trying to water us down.
He was a Water person, Dad, not just water.
Same thing.
And why is water in pipes?
City shut down years ago.
There should be no water.
Dad!
Bernie.
We will get through this.
Just like before.
Before?
There is a reason we left Fire Land.
Ember, we loved it there so much.
Most everyone had a Blue Flame.
And it connected us all together.
To our traditions. Our family.
It was hard living.
But your father began to build a life for us.
We put everything into it.
But then a great storm came.
All was lost for us.
Your father understood
we had to leave everything.
Our home. It was the only way
to create a better life.
It was the last time
your father ever saw his family.
That is why we came here.
To build all this.
Àshfá, nothing will happen to this shop
or the flame again, I promise.
Good daughter.
Fire! Fire!
-Fire!
-Hey, hey!
Sorry.
You're so hot.
Excuse me?
No, I mean, like, you're smoking.
No, I didn't mean it like that.
-Are you done yet?
-Yes, please.
I'm waiting to talk to your boss.
So, make like a stream
and flow somewhere else.
Actually, Gale won't be in today.
She's a huge airball fan...
and the Windbreakers
are finally in the playoffs.
Toot toot.
Okay. Well, I just came by...
because I left my passes
for the game here last night.
Passes? Like, plural?
Where is she?
Up there, in that skybox.
Come on!
Okay. Time to cancel some tickets.
Toot Toot juice.
Get your Toot Toot juice.
Toot Toot juice,
get your Toot Toot juice.
You'll be great. This way.
-Excuse me.
-Jimmy, what's up?
-Sorry. Pardon.
-Wendy.
Sorry. Fire girl coming through.
Break some wind!
Hi, Gale, how you doing?
Look at the score, what do you think?
Blow the ball, not the game!
Yeah, so, Gale.
My name is Ember Lumen.
My family runs a Fire shop.
Wade wrote us a bunch of tickets yesterday...
What kind of call was that?
Lumen? Yeah, a Fire shop
with 30 citations.
Thirty?
Anyway, friend, I was hoping
we could work something out.
Come on, ref!
Are your eyes in the back of your head?
-Oh, no.
-Yeah, bummer.
Yeah. Okay, so, the 30 citations.
Do you mind? There's a game going on.
Fireball.
Fireball?
Actually, I do mind.
This is my life we're talking about.
Not just some game.
Some game?
This is the playoffs.
So, forgive me
if I don't want to hear a sob story...
about the problems of some little shop.
Well, that little shop matters way more...
than a bunch of overpaid cloud puffs
blowing some ball around.
I dare you...
say "cloud puffs" one more time.
Cloud puffs.
Oh, no!
Lutz!
Lutz, man. He's been in such a funk
'cause his mom has been sick.
That is so not cool, he's doing his best.
We love you, Lutz!
Lutz!
Come on!
We love you, Lutz! Everybody!
We love you, Lutz!
-Yay!
-Yeah! Way to go, Lutz!
Yeah, Lutz!
That was amazing, Lutz!
Yeah! Yeah! Yes!
What a comeback.
Check out who found the gift shop.
I gotta admit, that was pretty cool.
You can see why I can get all churned up...
but as a cloud puff who used to
come here with her dad...
all these wins mean a little bit more.
And as a fireball who's supposed
to take over her dad's shop...
I sure don't want to let him down,
and I could use a win, too.
Now, I just got to stop water
from coming in.
-Water? In Firetown?
-Yeah.
Water was shut off to there years ago.
Forget the tickets...
I'm gonna have to take apart your dad's shop
to figure out what's going on.
You can't!
My dad put his whole life into that place.
I bet this is connected
to that fluffing leak.
Yeah, we've been trying
to track down a leak in the city.
It's why I was in the canal and...
Wait, I know where
I got sucked into Ember's shop.
Ember and I could track the water
from her shop to find the source of the leak.
Keep talking.
I could call in a city crew
to fix whatever we find.
Yes. And there'd be no need
to touch my dad's shop.
You're lucky you're a cute couple.
We're not a...
You got until Friday.
If you can find the leak
and get a crew to fix it by then...
those tickets are forgiven.
If not, your dad's shop gets shut down.
Break wind! Break wind!
Thank you.
-Please take all that off.
-But I got you a hat.
Okay.
Just keep out of sight, okay?
It'd be a whole thing.
Now water upstairs?
It's in the walls.
I don't understand.
I fix one pipe and another one leaks.
Water!
How could it be worse?
Now that the water's back, the pressure
is forcing it up to all your pipes.
We gotta find the source.
How did you even end up here?
Well, I was in the canals
checking the doors for leaks...
when I found some water
that shouldn't have been there.
Rusty with a hint of motor oil?
There was this whoosh of water.
And I got sucked into a filtering system.
Help!
But then I heard this explosion.
That's how I ended up at your place.
Oh, flame! My temper caused this.
So, we're searching for water
somewhere in a canal?
Those canals go everywhere.
It's why tracking down that leak
has been so dang hard.
The roof.
You might want to step back.
Holy dew drop!
Get in.
Okay, that's where I got sucked in.
More water.
Go that way.
Yeah, right there.
Nothing weird going on here.
Just a little pruning.
So, what do you do at the shop?
If you don't mind me asking.
My dad's retiring and I'll be taking over.
Someday.
When I'm ready.
It must be nice knowing what you're gonna do.
After my dad passed,
I got all, "What's the point?"
Now I just go from one job to the next.
There's a word in Firish.
Tìshók.
It means embrace the light while it burns
because it won't always last forever.
Tee-shook.
Or something like that.
-You okay?
-Yeah.
You sure?
It's just, that building over there...
that's Garden Central Station.
When I was a kid, my dad took me there
because they had a Vivisteria tree.
I'd always wanted to see one.
It's the only flower that can thrive
in any environment.
Fire included.
I was so excited.
But they said our fire was too dangerous...
and they wouldn't let us in.
Go back to Fire Land.
My dad was so angry...
-Burn somewhere else!
-Get outta here!
...and embarrassed.
The building flooded a few years later.
So, I missed my one chance
to see a Vivisteria.
You must have been so scared.
I was.
How do you do that?
-Do what?
-Draw people in?
You got a whole stadium to connect with you.
I can't even connect with one customer.
My stupid temper always kicks in.
I guess I just say what I feel.
And I don't think a temper is so bad.
Sometimes when I lose my temper...
I think it's just me trying
to tell me something I'm not ready to hear.
That's ridiculous.
Maybe.
Hey, there.
Put us down there.
That's not right.
Motor oil.
Yup, this is the source.
Why is there no water?
Because the doors are broken.
This is supposed to catch spill over
from those main canals and...
Run for your life!
Help!
Grab this!
Firetown.
Catch!
Ember, throw me more!
So, will this hold?
Yup. It should for sure.
At least long enough for me
to get a city crew to fix it before Friday.
What?
You've got a little sand.
Here? Here?
It's right there.
Thanks.
Well, let me know when it's done, I guess.
I'll make sure there's a city crew
here by Friday.
Okay. See ya.
Wait.
Any chance you're free tomorrow?
To hang out with a Water guy?
With a Water guy?
My dad would boil you alive.
He doesn't have to know.
We can meet in the city.
I promise, nothing weird.
Maybe a little pruning?
Sorry, that's not going to happen.
You smiled. I saw it.
Tomorrow, I'll be at the Alkali Theater.
3:00!
Yeah because then you know with the light...
Your ceiling is dripping again.
More leaks?
Don't worry.
This whole problem is going away.
I can feel it.
And since we're all good,
I am also going away to do deliveries.
Do I smell something on Ember?
Yo, Ember.
Clod.
I grew another one.
My queen.
Oops, sorry, but gotta go.
Started out on a one-way train
Always knew where I was gonna go next
Didn't know until I saw your face
I was missin' out on every moment
You'll be one and, baby, I'll be two
Would you mind it if I said I'm into you?
I'm into you
So if it's real,
then, darlin', let me know
I wouldn't mind
if you steal the show
You and I,
we go together
You're the sky
I'll be the weather
A pretty thing, the sunny rain
who knew?
Oh, yeah
Summer night,
perfect occasion
Where am I?
You know I'll be waitin' for you
Oh, for you
So if it's real,
then, darlin', let me know
I wouldn't mind
if you steal the show
Who is this guy?
Shine
You shine, like forever
Lasts forever
You shine, you shine,
and steal the show
So if it's real
then, darlin', let me know
I wouldn't mind
if you steal the show
Started out on a one-way train
Always knew where I was gonna go next
So if it's real
then, darlin', let me know
Whoa.
How'd you do that?
It's the minerals.
Check this out.
Awesome.
Wow.
Watch this.
Another?
No, no, no!
The water is back.
Ember Lumen.
Delivery for Ember Lumen.
Flowers for Ember?
Excuse me. These are so beautiful.
I'm gonna go put these away.
What are you doing here?
I got bad news.
The sandbags didn't hold.
Obviously.
Yeah. And I also got worse news.
I'd forgotten a tiny detail
about the last time I saw that city crew.
You knocked over three tons of cement dust.
Half the guys still haven't recovered.
I guess you could say
they still have hard feelings...
because they won't help us.
Wade, Gale's deadline is tomorrow.
We need more sandbags.
But that didn't work before.
Well, I can't just do nothing.
Ember, did you fix leak?
-It's you again.
-Who? Me?
You're the guy who started all this.
No, Dad. Different guy.
Not all Water looks alike.
You are city inspector?
No.
Right?
Right! I am not an inspector.
You are inspector.
Why you poking around?
Is this because of water leak?
No. Not because of water in any way.
He's a different kind of inspector.
Right?
Yeah. Yeah.
I'm a food inspector.
I've come to inspect your food.
I think he's lying through his feet.
-Teeth.
-Whatever.
Food upstairs. Come.
Food inspector?
I panicked.
You really food inspector?
As far as you know, yeah.
Then inspect this.
Dad.
Yep, all looks good to me.
No, no, no.
Inspect with your mouth.
You see? He likes it.
You must try these.
Straight from Fire Land.
Dad, those are too hot.
I'm okay.
I love hot food.
Hey! Watch your water.
So, did we pass?
A plus.
Actually, after the heat dies down,
that's really good.
If you don't mind.
See? It's really tasty
if you water it down a little.
Water us down?
Where's camera?
We will never be watered down by you.
Get out!
All right, sir, you gotta go.
Dad, don't worry.
I've got this.
Look, meet me at the beach
and we'll make more sandbags.
We have to figure out
how to fix those doors.
Water want to water us down?
Then Water no longer allowed in shop.
He is panned.
Banned.
Banned!
Àshfá, it's okay.
It's all going to be okay.
I don't think this is going to work.
Well, it won't
unless you hold the bag straight.
Maybe your dad will understand.
I'm serious.
Look, I know it can be tough.
I mean, with my dad,
we were like oil and water.
I never got a chance to fix that.
But you guys are different.
It might be time to tell him.
Yeah, right. And tell him what?
That I got us shut down
and destroyed his dream?
I think I'm failing.
My Àshfá should have retired years ago,
but he doesn't think I'm ready.
You have no idea how hard they've worked.
Or what they've had to endure.
Family they left behind.
How do you repay a sacrifice that big?
It all feels like a burden.
How can I say that?
I'm a bad daughter.
Hey, no. You're doing your best.
I'm a mess.
Nah. I think you're even more beautiful.
Maybe you're right when you said
my temper is me trying to tell me something.
Look what your fire did to the sand.
It's glass.
It looks like a Vivisteria flower.
I know how to seal those doors.
Yes.
Are you crying?
I've just never been punched in the face
with beauty before.
It worked!
I'll have Gale come by right after work.
I'll let you know the second I hear anything.
You think this will be good enough for her?
Honestly, it's hard to know.
She could go either way.
Here. I saved this for you.
It's special.
Àshfá, you okay?
Yes, yes. Just too much to fix.
I'll take care of it.
You need to rest, and that's an order.
Yes, ma'am.
Ember, I see a change in you.
Happier, calmer with customers...
and with that food inspector.
Always putting shop first.
You prove I can trust you.
I'm so lucky I have you.
Love?
Ember, you found it.
Everything okay?
Please tell me that
you have some good news from Gale.
I'm getting really worried about my dad.
This has to break my way.
Yeah, I haven't heard from her yet,
but she swore she'd call tonight.
Actually, my family stopped by for dinner.
You want to come up
and wait for the call together?
Your family?
Okay. I'll come up for a bit.
I'm sorry, you live here?
It's my mom's place.
Oh, my gosh!
I'm afraid I can't let you in.
Residents and guests only.
Okay. I understand.
You're surprisingly good at your job.
You're surprisingly fast for your age.
You have no idea.
Ember! I'm so excited to finally meet you.
Do we hug, or wave, or...?
Don't want to put you out.
A hello is fine.
Hardly. Wade hasn't stopped talking about you
since the day you met.
-The boy is smitten.
-Mom.
Oh, come on. I'm your mother.
I know when something's lighting you up.
I just didn't know she'd be so smoky.
Come this way, meet the rest of the family.
Oh, honey, you won't believe
what your baby niece did today.
She smiled.
No, she didn't.
Yeah.
Hey, everyone, this is Ember.
Hey!
That's my brother Alan and his wife Eddy.
Hi.
And we got two kids that are
swimmin' around here somewhere.
Marco! Polo!
What?
Hi, Uncle Wade!
-Do you die if you fall in water?
-Whoa!
-Marco!
-Kids, right?
Don't hate us.
Anyway, that's my little sib, Lake...
-and her girlfriend, Ghibli.
-'Sup!
They're students at
Element City School for the Arts.
Yeah. Following in Mom's wake.
Nonsense. I'm just an architect.
The real artist is my brother, Harold.
I just dabble in watercolors.
Or as we like to call them, "colors."
Don't listen to him.
He's a wonderful painter.
One of his paintings just got in the
Element City Museum's permanent collection.
Wow, that is so cool.
My only talent is "Clean up on aisle four."
Talk about being modest.
Ember's got an incredible creative flame.
I've never seen anything like it.
I just have to say that
you speak so well and clear.
Yeah, it's amazing...
what talking in the same language
your entire life can do.
Hey, Ember...
did Wadey here ever tell you that
he's deathly afraid of sponges?
No.
I was traumatized.
I still can't use a sponge around him.
I was stuck in there for hours.
Alan! That was new.
My bad. I'm all whirlpools tonight.
I can fix it.
Sorry.
That was incredible!
It's just melted glass.
"Just melted glass"?
Every building in the new city
is built from just "melted glass".
Oh, no, you have to do something
with that talent.
See, I told you, you're special.
Thought bubble.
Maybe after dinner we play The Crying Game?
Yes, yes, yes.
Let me guess, you try to cry?
We try not to cry.
You have one minute. Go!
1979. November. You were...
Never got a chance to say goodbye to Nana.
Damn, you're good.
Okay, Ember, Wade, you're up.
Yeah, this is almost unfair
because I have literally never cried.
You got no chance.
Sounds like a challenge.
Ready, go!
Butterfly, windshield wipers...
half a butterfly.
Okay.
An old man on his deathbed
remembers the summer he fell in love.
She was out of his league
and he was young and scared.
He let her go, thinking surely
summer would come again.
It never did.
Almost out of time.
Ember...
when I met you I thought I was drowning.
But that light...
that light inside you
has made me feel so alive.
And all I want now is to be near it.
Near you.
Together.
Hello? Gale, hi.
Glass? You repaired it with glass?
Hold the storm.
Tempered glass. Solid as a rock, I like it.
Consider the tickets cancelled.
-We did it?
-Yup!
Awesome!
Thank you, Mrs. Ripple.
This was...
This was really great.
Yeah, it was.
And I mean what I said about your talent.
I have a friend who runs
the best glassmaking firm in the world.
During dinner,
I slipped out and I made a call...
and I told her about you.
They're looking for an intern.
It could be an amazing opportunity.
For real?
It's a long way from the city,
but it would be an incredible start.
You have a bright future.
Look at me, I have an original Ember.
Hold up, I'll walk you out.
I'm afraid you're still
going to have to...
wait out here, ma'am.
And I'm afraid...
I will throw up.
Ember.
Ember, hold up, what's going on?
I can't believe
she basically offered me a job.
I know! Could be cool.
Yeah, super cool, Wade.
I could move out and make glass
in a faraway city. Do whatever I want.
-I don't understand.
-I'm going home.
Fine, then I'm going with you.
A Water guy?
Look, my mom was just trying to be helpful.
She doesn't know
how excited you are to run the shop.
-What is the matter?
-Nothing!
Yeah? 'Cause we're going, like, a thousand...
Bus!
You don't know me, Wade. Okay?
So stop pretending like you do.
What is this about?
Nothing.
Everything. I don't know. It's...
I don't think I actually
do want to run the shop. Okay?
That's what my temper
has been trying to tell me.
I'm trapped.
You know what's crazy?
Even when I was a kid,
I would pray to the Blue Flame...
to be good enough
to fill my father's shoes someday...
because this place is his dream.
But I never once asked...
what I wanted to do.
I think that's because deep down,
I knew it didn't matter.
Because the only way
to repay a sacrifice so big...
is by sacrificing your life too.
Ember!
Don't move.
Oh, blaze! My mother.
Mom, it's okay.
He's just a friend.
Silence!
I could smell you from over there.
You stink.
What are you talking about?
You know what I'm talking about.
You're smelling love on me?
If your father find out...
Fire and Water cannot be together.
I prove it. Come with me.
I splash this on your heart
to bring love to the surface.
And then you must light these with your fire,
and I read the smoke.
See, Ember? It cannot be.
Actually...
What are you doing?
Cinder?
Who down there?
It's my dad.
You have to go.
Wait, are we a match?
What's going on?
I wake up and nobody upstairs.
It was just me.
I was double-checking the locks.
And Mom came down and...
Yes, and we began looking at this door.
We don't talk about this door enough.
Pull it together.
Well, since you're awake...
I was gonna tell you tomorrow,
but I'm too excited to sleep.
In two days, I retire.
Oh, Bernie.
Two days?
Yes. We're going to throw big party.
A grand reopening.
That way I can tell whole world
my daughter take over.
And I have gift for you.
I've had this for a while,
but after our talk...
I know now is the time.
Before I give it to you...
I need you to understand what it means to me.
When I left Fire Land...
I gave my father the Bà Ksô...
the big bow.
It is the highest form of respect.
But my father...
did not return the bow.
Did not give me his blessing.
He say, if we leave Fire Land...
we will lose who we are.
They never got to see all of this.
They didn't get to see
that I never forgot we are Fire.
This is burden I still carry.
Ember, it is important that you know...
you have my blessing
every day you come in here.
So I have this made for you.
Wow, Àshfá.
It's gonna be big, bright.
Everyone's gonna see this.
"Ember's Fireplace."
We unveil it at grand reopening.
Come, Bernie.
You need your rest.
Ember, so, what'd your mom say
about our reading?
Nothing.
Look, I have a gift for you.
And you came all the way here
to give it to me?
Wait, why are you giving me gifts?
Oh, no.
No, no, no.
Hold on, I think I have
something to show you.
Just give me two seconds.
And you're gonna need a pair of boots.
Wade, what are we doing here?
Just wait.
Why do they even have these?
Who knows?
Hey, it's my favorite fireball.
Hey, Gale. What's going on?
I know you think you have to end this...
but that flooded tunnel,
it goes to the main terminal.
Okay.
Do you still want to see a Vivisteria?
Gale?
Wait, I'm supposed to get in there?
The air should last...
At least 20 minutes.
They said you couldn't go in there.
Why does anyone get to tell you
what you can do in your life?
Whoa.
A Vivisteria.
-Ouch.
-Hey, you're running out of air.
Almost there.
Try to breathe slow and steady.
I'm so sorry. I should never...
Are you kidding?
That was amazing!
I finally saw a Vivisteria!
It was inspiring.
You were inspiring.
No. Wade, we can't touch.
Maybe we can.
No.
But can't we just prove it?
Prove what?
Let's see what happens...
and if it's a disaster,
then we'll know this would never work.
But it actually could be a disaster.
I could vaporize you.
You could extinguish me, and then...
Let's start small.
I'm so lucky.
I'm so lucky I have you.
I have to go.
Wait, what?
Where are you going?
Back to my life at the shop where I belong.
I take over tomorrow.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, hold up.
You don't want that, you said so yourself.
It doesn't matter what I want.
Of course it does.
Listen. Listen.
You've got an opportunity
to do something you want with your life.
"Want"?
Yeah, that may work in your rich kid,
"follow your heart" family...
but getting to do what you want
is a luxury...
and not for people like me.
Why not?
Just tell your father how you feel.
This is too important.
Maybe he'll agree.
Yeah.
Funny.
And this whole time
I thought you were so strong...
but turns out you're just afraid.
Don't you dare judge me.
You don't know what it's like...
to have parents who gave up
everything for you.
I'm Fire, Wade.
I can't be anything more than that.
It's what I am and what my family is.
It's our way of life.
I cannot throw all of that away just for you.
I don't understand.
And that alone is a reason
this could never work.
It's over, Wade.
Everyone, welcome.
It is good to see your faces.
I am honored to have served you...
but it's time to move on.
Come.
My daughter...
you are the Ember of our family fire.
That is why I am so proud
to have you take over my life's work.
Pretty good trick, huh?
This is lantern I bring from old country.
Today, I pass it on to you.
I thought of other reasons.
Wade?
Oh, boy.
What are you doing here?
You said me not understanding
is the reason we can never work.
But I thought of other reasons.
A bunch of 'em.
Like, number one, you're Fire, I'm Water.
I mean, come on, that's crazy.
Right?
-Who is this?
-No idea.
Number two, I'm crashing your party.
Like, what kind of a jerk am I?
-A pretty big one.
-Right?
Number three,
I can't eat your delicious foods.
Very unpleasant.
Wait, I know him.
He is food inspector.
Oh, right. Number four,
I'm banned from your father's shop.
There are a million reasons
why this can't work.
A million nos.
But there's also one yes...
we touched.
And when we did, something happened to us...
something impossible.
We changed each other's chemistry.
Enough!
What kind of food inspection is this?
A food inspection of the heart, sir.
Who are you?
Just a guy who burst into your
daughter's life in a flooded old basement.
So you are the one who burst the pipes?
What? Not me. It was...
You?
You burst the pipe?
-I...
-Ember.
-Silence!
-No!
Take the chance.
Let your father know who you really are.
Look, I had regrets when my dad died.
But because of you, I learned
to embrace the light while it burns.
Tìshók.
You don't have forever
to say what you need to say.
I love you, Ember Lumen.
And I'm pretty sure you love me too.
No, Wade, I don't.
That's not true.
I did their reading.
Bernie, it's love.
It's true love.
No, Mom, you're wrong.
Wade, go.
But, Ember...
I don't love you.
Go!
You have been seeing Water?
Àshfá, I...
You caused leak in shop?
I trusted you.
You will not take over the shop.
I no longer retire.
Why can't I just be a good daughter?
Firetown.
Well, one-way ticket to anywhere but here.
Go. Travel the world.
Heal that broken heart.
My little drip, drip baby boy.
Drip, drip, drip, goes the baby boy
I made you a painting.
It's of a lonely man...
awash in sadness.
Ember.
Mom, Dad!
Water's coming!
Watch out!
Behind you!
Climb! Climb!
Flash flood! Hurry!
Mom, water!
Get to higher ground!
Bernie!
The flame!
Let me go!
Ember, no!
-Wade?
-Keyhole.
I was hoping to make a more heroic entrance.
You came back, after everything I said.
Are you kidding? And miss all this?
Hold the door.
No! No.
No, no, no.
Ember, we have to go!
We have to go now!
I can't leave.
I'm sorry to say this, but the shop is done.
The flame is done.
No! This is my father's whole life.
I'm not going anywhere.
Throw me that lantern.
No.
No, no, no.
Oh, Wade.
Thank you, thank you.
It's too hot in here.
Climb!
Back up! Back up!
-I have to open that up.
-No!
The water will come in
and you'll be snuffed out.
But you're evaporating.
I don't know what to do.
It's okay.
No, it's not okay!
Ember...
I have no regrets.
You gave me something
people search for their whole lives.
But I can't exist in a world without you.
I'm sorry I didn't say it before.
I love you, Wade.
I really do love it
when your light does that.
They're in the hearth!
Wade is gone.
Oh, my daughter.
He saved me.
Dad...
this is all my fault.
The shop...
Wade.
I need to tell you the truth.
I don't want to run the shop.
I know that was your dream,
but it's not mine.
I'm sorry.
I'm a bad daughter.
Ember...
the shop was never the dream.
You were the dream.
You were always the dream.
I loved him, Dad.
Butterfly.
Butterfly. Windshield wipers.
Half a butterfly.
An old man on his deathbed
remembers the summer he fell in love.
She was out of his league...
and he was young and scared.
He let her go, thinking surely
summer would come again.
It never did.
You are perfect match. Ten out of ten.
I don't understand.
What's going on?
Just say something
to make Water guy cry, okay?
You are no longer panned.
Banned.
I want to explore the world with you,
Wade Ripple.
I want to have you with me in my life.
Forever.
Your chimney needs cleaning.
I knew it. My nose always knows.
If you were a vegetable,
you'd be a cute-cumber.
My queen.
I can't believe I was gonna
shut this place down.
Sorry.
Fern, you're a Windbreakers fan?
Toot toot.
Oy, you know what I like best
about running this shop?
Not having to eat Bernie's kol-nuts?
Sorry, I couldn't hear you
through my retirement.
Hey!
-Hi, Wade.
-Hey, Wade! Yo, yo, yo!
Ember, it's time.
You know, I'm not really
one for tearful goodbyes.
Wade.
You big liar.
Drip, drip, drip
Goes the baby boy
Are you sure about this one?
I'm sure.
Dad...
I'm sorry the internship is so far away.
I mean, it's the best glass design company
in the world...
but who knows if it'll become a real job.
I'll be back in a few months anyway...
and it might not end up being anything...
Go, start new life.
Your mother and I will be here.
Now, with more time for hanky-panky.
Started out on a one-way train
Always knew where I was gonna go next
Didn't know until I saw your face
I was missin' out on every moment
You'll be one and, baby, I'll be two
Would you mind it if I said I'm into you?
I'm into you
So if it's real,
then, darlin', let me know
I wouldn't mind
if you steal the show
You and I, we go together
You're the sky, I'll be the weather
A pretty thing, the sun and rain
Who knew?
Oh, yeah
Summer night, perfect occasion
Where am I? You know I'll be waitin' for you
Oh, for you
So if it's real, then, darlin'
let me know
I wouldn't mind
if you steal the show
So if it's real,
then, darlin', let me know
I wouldn't mind
if you steal the show
You shine
You shine, like forever
Lasts forever
You shine, you shine,
and steal the show
So if it's real,
then, darlin', let me know
I wouldn't mind
if you steal the show
Started out on a one-way train
-Always knew where I was gonna go next.
-So if it's real
Didn't know until I saw your face
Then, darlin', let me know
You'll be one and, baby, I'll be two
Would you mind it if I said I'm into you?
I wouldn't mind
if you steal the show