I'm gonna play it again.
You play that thing one more time and
I'm gonna melt it down into hair spray.
Let me play that side then.
No, Rayette, it's not
a question of sides.
It's a question of musical integrity.
Then let me sing one for you.
-When there's a fire...
-Hold it.
Bobby!
You quit that now!
You said you're gonna
help me pick a song.
I'm gonna cut off
your damn water, Bobby. I swear.
Selfish.
You play on the piano...
...and your whole family can play
on some type of musical instrument.
All I'm asking is for you
to help me improve my musical talent.
You would think you would.
Why don't you take
that sign off your tit...
...and let's you and me go out
and have some real good time?
Where are we going?
I don't know. I'll holler up
to Elton and Stoney.
Bobby, now listen a minute.
You know, I'll go out with you...
...or I'll stay in with you...
...or I'll do anything
that you'd like for me to do...
...if you would tell me
that you love me.
You can sing the song.
You are never satisfied.
That's right.
-Honey, I'm sorry.
-lt's okay.
All right. Here it is.
They were all set up right for you.
Get it right in there, Dipesto.
All you gotta do, just relax, honey.
Keep that left foot forward.
Set her down!
Not too much of a match, is it, EI?
Don't lead out with your right foot.
-ln the gutter. Isn't that wonderf ul?
-lt's just heavy for me.
The pins, you know. I can't see them.
Just squint. I squint.
There they are right down there.
All these little boards.
You notice them leading down?
Just spot...
But there's so many.
What's that for?
That's for luck.
-Get on out there.
-Great, he slobbered on me.
Yeah, ain't the first time.
Watch this.
There she is. She's doing a little
variation on "The Apache Shift"!
I taught her that.
-Are you mad at me?
-No, I'm not mad at you.
-lt'll be all right.
-Tell me you're not mad at me.
I'm not mad at you.
Go on, beat it.
-I'll show you how it's done.
-Don't talk about it. Do it!
Isn't he pretty?
Good one!
Show me a little something now.
Give me spirit!
It's just the thing
just goes off cocky-wobbly.
Just do what I tell you.
I did, didn't l, EI?
You got another ball coming.
-Come on, Rayette!
-Just relax.
That's a boy, Ray!
That was real good, wasn't it?
I finally did it.
Great! You throw
the big Z's for 19 f rames...
...and then you throw a strike
on the last ball of the losing game.
Wonderf ul, just wonderf ul.
Wasn't that wonderf ul, ladies?
Are you talking to us?
Wonderf ul.
I guess I'll go wait in the car.
Why don't you go
wait in the car, Rayette?
I will. I'll wait there right now.
One minute, honey,
and I'll go with you.
Me and Stoney got to get on home.
Relieve the sitter.
Why don't you and Ray
just come on by the place?
All right, why don't you go on?
Here. I'll take care of the beers.
And would you walk Rayette
along with you?
-Sure.
-Thanks, EI.
What do we owe you?
Four dollars, sir.
Ex cuse me.
Here's a five. Thanks very much.
We've been wanting to ask you...
...you're on the TV, aren't you?
Am I?
She says you're the guy
that sells all the cars...
...on TV.
I might've sold a few cars.
I told you!
My name's Shirley, but they
call me Betty. And her name's Twinky.
-Twinky?
-Yeah, because she's so "twinky"!
Boy, oh, boy!
Well, Betty and Twinky,
it sure is nice talking to you girls.
I wish I had some more time.
That's a wig you wear, isn't it?
I told her that you're wearing a wig...
...because on the TV
you're mostly all...
...bald up there.
Hey, your little f riend's real sharp.
I don't...
I don't wear the wig on TV.
If you're gonna be out there...
...in f ront of 2 million people,
you got to be sincere.
I like to wear it in bowling alleys
and slipping around.
It gives me a little class.
What do you think?
Yeah, but I can see
a little bitty of a net up there.
That's what gave it away.
A little net?
Well, I...
I wish I had more time
to talk to you girls, but...
I have to... I'll...
Come on, Ray.
We're gonna go over to Elton's.
I'm not.
You're just gonna sit here?
Yes.
Okay, I hope no one hits on you.
I hope they do.
See you later.
No one would want to hit on you.
You look too pathetic.
Come on, Dipesto,
we can still have a good time.
You're the pathetic one. Not me.
I'm going over to Elton's.
I am not a piece of crap.
I'm sorry.
You treat me like I was.
Go slip around,
right before my face...
...and in f ront of Elton
and Stoney that way.
What do you imagine they think
of somebody you treat like that?
Now, now, Ray.
Now, sweetheart, Elton and Stoney
know that I love you.
They're just gonna think that
I'm not too nice a guy, which I'm not...
...and that you're a hell of a good person
for putting up with me, that's all.
You'll just find me dead one time.
You'll just kill me.
Come on, be a good girl.
If you ever really
get up and leave me...
...you'll read about it
in the newsprint.
I'm not gonna get up and leave you.
Now come on.
Let's go over to Elton's
and have a good time.
You love me, Bobby?
What do you think?
You got banana on your face.
I do?
I still ain't figured out how
you got me working back out here.
I got you to come out here?
I ain't figured out how you let me
get you to work on these rigs.
I never worked on these things before.
You worked on them before.
I can't figure out how
you let me get us out here.
Somebody had to look out for you.
You're a mess.
You're crazy.
-I'm gonna bet $2 right off.
-I'm in.
You're bullshitting me now.
-I have to see it.
-I got a pair of nine.
Can you beat two pair?
-There's three aces, right there.
-Piss on you.
I got me a hand there!
It's time for me to go home.
See you in the morning, boys.
See you, Glen.
I don't know if I'm going
out there tomorrow at all, man.
I got a lot of money tied up,
and everything I got telling me to...
I don't want no chains
going around, and all this.
I prefer card playing. Where is it?
What the hell is going on in this game?
People talking...
We got money here, or what?
Ride a cockhorse to Banbury Cross
To Banbury Cross we go
When I was 4, just 4 years old...
...I went to my mother and I said,
"What's this hole?"
I saw this dimple in my chin.
I didn't know what it was.
And my mother says:
"When you're born, you go
on an assembly line past God.
If He likes you, He says, 'You cute
little thing, ' and you get dimples.
And if He doesn't like you,
He goes, 'Go away."'
So about six months later
my mother found me saying my prayers.
And I was going,
" Now I lay me down to sleep."
She says, "What're you
covering up your chin for?"
And I said,
" Because if I cover up the hole...
...maybe He'll listen to me."
Ride a cockhorse to Banbury Cross
To Banbury Cross we go
Do you wanna buy a ticket
To a raffle of a dog
That comes a runnin' licking
When you whistle, holler, "Claude"
A big brown dog just as sound as a ring
He'll be 8 years old
If he lives to the spring
Unfit! Do I look unfit to you, Elton?
I'm fit! I'm fit!
If you haven't got your ticket yet
Well, you better order it
He'll wet your carpet
And he'll fertilize your grass
And he's got three white feet
And a hole in his ass
Don't you know no songs
about women or nothing?
Yeah, but I'm just too loaded
to think of them now.
Watch out for all this traffic.
-God!
-I ain't in no hurry.
Can you believe starting off your day
like this, going to work?
Unbelievable.
Let me have a drink, will you?
Thanks, Elton.
Boy! That's tough in the morning.
What the hell are
these people doing here?
Isn't this some goddamn thing, Elton?
Jesus Christ!
What does he want? What I can't stand
is sitting on this goddamn f reeway.
Why don't you flash your lights so as we
can see what else you got for Christmas?
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
Where are you going?
Why don't we all line up
like a goddamn bunch of ants...
...in the most beautif ul
part of the day and gas ourselves?
Hey, get off my car!
Hey, Bobby!
Shit! What's he doing?
Play it!
Bob, quit fooling around! Come on!
Bobby!
He's turning!
I was with Elton last night, Ray.
It's the truth.
Rayette?
Son of a bitch!
Now reach for it.
Come on, reach for it!
Come on!
Good boy!
Come on, let's go see Bob.
I can't see!
Isn't he sweet?
Can't see the set well.
You take him for a while now.
Go ahead now.
How you doing?
You ought to get yourself
one of them, Bob.
That's it. Just crush that one too,
then I won't get any.
Well, bless my soul,
it's a new harmonica!
That's for your birthday.
Well, how do you know
when my birthday is?
Bye, Stoney.
Kitchen's on fire, Stoney.
Your mother just died, Stoney.
Bye-bye.
See you out in the field, Bob.
Okay, thanks a lot.
Honey, you just love
that little baby, don't you?
Well? What if she was, Bob?
I can't see nothing so bad in that.
What if I let you in
on a little secret, that she is?
That's right.
She told me.
She's all torn up about it too,
which I hate to see.
Isn't it something
you just have to face up to?
Somewhere along the line,
you even get to liking the whole idea.
When Stoney first gave me the news,
I could've shit!
Well, isn't that nice?
It's ridiculous! I'm here,
listening to some cracker asshole...
...lives in a trailer park,
compare his life to mine!
Keep on telling me about the good life,
because it makes me puke.
If you think you're something better
than what I am, that's something else.
I can't say much of someone who could
leave a woman in a situation like this.
That's all I have to say.
I'm glad that's all, because I'm
as tired of your mouth as I am...
...working on this goddamn job!
Shit-ass!
Hey! Longcipher!
I'm quitting!
Do you hear me? I said I'm quitting.
I don't give a damn what you do.
I'm glad to get rid
of the both of you dumb guys.
Hey!
What's going on?
Don't do that, Bob!
Don't mix in!
They got the right, Bob! It's the law!
It's the law!
Don't you think you could
just leave him?
If he'd have known who you were,
he wouldn't have done that. Bob?
What the hell's going on?
All right, let him go.
What's going on, Elton?
I got accused of robbing
the filling station. Didn't I tell you?
I just got wild and jumped my bail.
And here they come running at me a whole
year later. Isn't that something?
Hey, tell Stoney for me, you hear?
Hi.
Miss Dupea?
Upstairs.
It's upstairs and to the right.
There she goes again.
My 1 -year-old can
carry a tune better than that.
Miss Dupea?
I'd like to remind you again that this
is not an opera or a musical comedy.
I'm sorry. Was I singing again?
If you wanna call it that.
You have simply to tell me.
That's all.
That's exactly what I am doing again.
You let me get 2l3 of the way through
the movement... This is tiring me.
I have another suggestion.
Why don't we take a break?
For pity's sake!
Is she gonna cry again?
I don't want to take a break.
Some coffee?
What would you like
in your coffee, Miss Dupea?
-Tea.
-One tea.
Tell her Bobby's here.
Bobby's here.
Oh, my goodness!
Robert Eroica.
I can't look at you.
Well, don't, then.
You always do this to me.
I don't mean to. Here's your tea, Tita.
Thank you.
-Don't put it there.
-Why? What's wrong?
This is a very special CB-275.
No kidding?
It has absolutely
no objectionable idiosyncrasies.
Robert, I have to talk seriously to you.
Everybody still living up on the island?
At the moment, there's really
just Daddy, Carl and myself...
...and Van Oost.
-Who's Van Oost?
-Catherine.
She's a pianist.
She's working with Carl.
Carl's a fiddler.
What's he doing coaching piano?
Well, 11 months ago...
...he was on his bicycle on his way
to the post office in the village.
And he ran straight into a Jeep
and sprained his neck.
Strained his neck?
That's not f unny.
He permanently sprained his neck.
And since then it's been extremely
painf ul for him to tuck the violin.
Crashes into a Jeep
and totals his neck!
Robert?
I have...
I have to tell you.
Daddy's very ill.
What's...
-What?
-He's had two strokes.
He's not...
They feel he...
He might not recover f rom it.
Don't tell me about this.
But don't you think it's right
that you should see him at least once?
-Miss Dupea?
-Just a minute, please!
Don't you think it's right
you should see him?
Yeah, I guess so.
I'm going back tonight.
Will you come with me?
No.
I'd rather drive up.
Maybe I'll go into Canada after.
I'm not gonna stay long, Tita.
One week at the most.
I know.
Well...
Come on, I'll walk you out.
I'll be back in two minutes.
We've had our break, Miss Dupea.
They hate me, I feel.
Maybe you better stay.
I want to talk to you
about so many things.
I'll be seeing you in a couple of days.
I'm so glad.
Me too.
Bye.
Hello?
You got the day off?
Are you sick?
I guess you heard about Elton.
I got your point.
I hope you didn't strain yourself
getting in here before I hit the door.
I have to go home.
My father's sick.
I'll be gone for two or three weeks.
You'll be gone, period.
I'll try and call you f rom up there.
Come on, Dipesto.
I never told you that
it would work out to anything.
Did I?
I'll send you some money.
That's all I can do.
I'll try and call you f rom up there.
Bye, Ray.
You wanna go with me?
There's been hot spells and cold spells
Ever since we met
I've seen your big fires, small fires
But I won't give up yet
Oh, someday you'll yearn
Because your heart's gonna burn
For that old familiar glow
You'll be burnt...
-Like it?
-I love it.
You'll be burnt out or smoked out
And come back to me
I know
-What the hell are they doing?
-ls that...
Is that an accident?
Who was driving?
Who was driving? You were driving!
Hey, what the hell's going on?
Rotate, mac!
Look at my car! Look at my car!
I just bought it brand-new
f rom the used-car lot!
You're lucky nobody was hurt.
Give us a lift?
Terry, we got a ride!
You gonna give those people a lift?
-I can't just leave them here.
-I'd like to punch that son of a bitch!
Jesus! What a rude person!
What's your name?
Palm Apodaca.
Terry Grouse.
What?
How far are you going to?
Washington.
We'll get off in Washington.
We'll hook a ride.
Where are you going?
Alaska.
Alaska?
What are you? On vacation?
She wants to live there
because it's cleaner.
Cleaner?
Cleaner than what?
Don't tell everybody. Soon they'll all
go there, and it won't be so clean.
What makes you think it's cleaner?
I saw a picture of it.
Alaska's very clean.
It appeared to look very white to me.
Don't you think?
Yep. That was before the big thaw.
Before the what?
I had to leave because
I got depressed seeing all the crap.
And they're making more crap,
you know?
They got so many stores
f ull of crap...
...I can't believe it.
Who?
Man, that's who.
Pretty soon,
there won't be any room for man.
They're selling more crap that people
go and buy than you can imagine. Crap!
Everybody should have a big hole
where they burn the stuff.
They'd never find
a hole big enough. Never.
Now, take me. Look at me.
When I was just one person,
before I was with Bobby...
...I was collecting onto me
more garbage every day...
...till I was thinking
that I should get a disposal.
Disposal?
What's that but more crap!
I've never seen such crap!
Mass production does it.
To be honest,
you're not clean either.
I'm not that neat maybe,
but I am clean.
Well, you're not that bad.
But some people.
People's homes. Just filth!
I've been in homes...
I think that more people
are neat than are clean.
In my personal thing, I don't see that.
I'm seeing more filth. A lot of filth.
What they need to do every day
is a cockroach thing...
...where they spray the homes...
Can you imagine if their doors were
a pretty colour, with a pot outside?
-Could be adorable.
-And they picked up!
It wouldn't be filthy
without Coke bottles and whiskey...
...and those signs everywhere.
They should be erased!
All those signs
selling you crap and more crap!
I don't know. I don't know.
I don't even want to talk about it.
It's just filthy! People are filthy!
That's the biggest thing
that's wrong with people!
I think if they were clean
they wouldn't have anybody to pick on.
Dirt!
Not dirt. See, dirt isn't bad.
It's filth! Filth is bad.
That's what starts maggots and riots.
Follow that truck.
They know the best places to stop.
That's an old maid's tale.
Bullshit!
Truck drivers know the best places.
Salesmen and cops know. If you'd
ever waitressed, honey, you'd know.
Don't call me " honey, " mac.
Don't call me "mac, " honey!
I wouldn't be a waitress.
They're f ull of crap.
You just hold on to your tongue!
Hold on to this.
If you think you can...
Shut up!
All of you!
I'd like a plain omelette,
no potatoes, tomatoes instead...
...a cup of coffee and wheat toast.
No substitutions.
You don't have any tomatoes?
Only what's on the menu.
You can have a plain omelette.
Comes with cottage f ries and rolls.
I know what it comes with,
but it's not what I want.
I'll come back
when you make up your mind.
I have made up my mind.
I'd like a plain omelette,
no potatoes on the plate.
A cup of coffee
and a side order of wheat toast.
We don't have any side orders of toast.
I'll give you a muffin
or a coffee roll.
You don't make side orders of toast?
You make sandwiches, don't you?
Wanna talk to the manager?
Hey, mac!
Shut up!
You've got bread
and a toaster of some kind?
I don't make the rules.
Okay, I'll make it
as easy for you as I can.
I'd like an omelette, plain, and
a chicken-salad sandwich on wheat toast.
No mayonnaise, no butter,
no lettuce and a cup of coffee.
A number two, chicken-salad sand.
Hold the butter, the lettuce
and the mayonnaise, and a cup of coffee.
Anything else?
Yeah, now hold the chicken,
bring me the toast...
...give me a check for the sandwich,
and you haven't broken any rules.
You want me to hold the chicken, huh?
I want you to hold it
between your knees.
You see that sign, sir?
You all have to leave. I'm not taking
any more of your smartness and sarcasm!
You see this sign?
Fantastic that you could
figure that all out...
...so that you could come up
with a way to get your toast!
I didn't get it, did I?
No, but it was very clever.
I would've just punched her out.
People! Shit!
Animals are not like that.
They're always cleaning themselves.
Do you ever see pigeons?
He's always picking
on himself and his f riends.
Always picking bugs out of their hair.
Monkeys too. Ex cept they do something
out in the open that I don't go for.
You know, I read where they
invented this car that runs on...
...that runs on...
When you boil water?
Steam.
A car that you could ride in
and not cause a stink.
But do you know they
will not even let us have it?
Can you believe it?
Why?
Man!
He likes to create a stink!
I mean, I've seen filth
that you wouldn't believe.
What a stink!
I don't even wanna talk about it.
You depressed about your daddy, hon?
No.
I imagine it's me then, isn't it?
Is what you?
Are you depressed I come along?
Who says I'm depressed?
Is that a happy face I see?
Because if it is,
I'll just catch a Greyhound back.
Oh, you're not gonna kill yourself
this time. I wish I'd known.
Well...
I don't know if I'm gonna be able
to get to sleep.
Hint, hint.
Guess I'll have to count the sheep.
One...
...two...
...three...
...four...
...five...
...six...
...seven...
Look at this old cold shoulder.
What am I going to do about it?
You know, if you wouldn't open your
mouth, everything would be just fine.
Take a look.
Why can't I come out with you
to your family's house?
I have to see what's going on first.
My father's sick. They wouldn't be
prepared for my bringing anyone.
How long do I have to sit in that place?
If you can't do what I'm asking you...
...why don't you take the money
and go on back south with it?
Don't talk like that.
Try to understand
this is not something that I wanna do.
Jesus Christ, you ought to
know me well enough for that!
All right, honey.
It'll be all right.
I mean, there's stuff for me to do.
They got magazines in there
and TV, right?
I'll try and call you
in a couple of days.
All right.
Bye.
He doesn't even know who the hell I am.
-Remember, mother used to say, " Bobby..."
-Ex cuse me.
-Go ahead.
I was going to ask Robert how long
it had been since he'd been away.
Three years.
No, it's more like two years, isn't it?
It's been more than that.
Tita, you have no sense of timing
away f rom the piano, dear.
I don't think that's true.
It's true.
What have you been doing?
Odd jobs. I work here and there.
Nothing too interesting.
You no longer play at all?
Before my misfortune...
I'm not sure
you're aware of my accident.
Tita was telling me about it.
It's difficult...
...for me to turn my neck.
This way especially.
If I look at Catherine...
...I shift the whole base
of my body around this way.
I was real sorry to hear about it, Carl.
I said, I was real sorry
to hear about it.
Anyways...
Catherine, what was I saying?
Yes, just after I'd come off tour
with the Betenthaller Quartet.
Father, Herbert and I
had a summit conference.
A summit conference?
Where was I?
Polishing silver behind the coal bin?
Well, I don't know where you were,
penis envy.
I hope I didn't hear that.
They wanted a detective to ferret
you out, and I talked them out of it.
Whatever you were doing,
you had a right to do...
...no matter how nonsensical your
ventures may be. It was that simple.
I really appreciate it, Carl.
I don't think you ought to imply
that Daddy was wrong in f ront of Daddy.
Don't force him that way.
How long have you been here?
Only two months.
Well, satiety is my father and mother!
Carl?
If you're finished,
I think I'd like to go do some work.
Certainly, dear.
Ex cuse me. See you later.
I hope you feel right at home.
I feel fine.
He has ways of communicating, Robert.
I can tell when he's expressing approval
or disapproval. Just f rom his eyes.
Yeah.
Some range.
I can't take much more of seeing him
sitting there like a stone.
It's not that bad.
Yes, it is.
Will you stay a while?
I don't know.
Breathe!
All right!
Now once more, once more...
Hello.
Hi. I've been
looking all over for you.
You have? I went riding.
Riding?
That's dangerous, you know.
Play the piano all day and then
jump on a horse, you can get cramps.
Well, I like to ride.
Rain or shine, I do it any chance
I can get. It's very invigorating.
-ls it?
-Yes.
Well, I don't like to get
too invigorated, myself.
You don't?
What else do you do?
Well, there's fishing, boating.
There's concerts on the mainland.
I feel silly telling you this.
This is your home.
You know what there is to do.
Nothing.
Nothing?
It must be very boring for you here.
That's right.
I find that hard to comprehend.
I don't think I've ever been bored.
Ex cuse me.
What're you doing right now?
Right now, I plan to take a hot tub
and soak myself.
Then after that?
After that...
...I plan to read some music
and rest for a while.
Tomorrow, then?
Tomorrow?
Tomorrow's a f ull practice day.
But the day after tomorrow
I will be f ree.
Carl has hydrotherapy on Tuesdays.
The day after tomorrow?
Will you be f ree?
Yeah, I'll probably be f ree.
One thing I find...
...very difficult to imagine...
...is that one could have this
incredible background in music...
...and walk away f rom it
without a second thought.
I gave it a second thought.
I mean, how could you no longer play
at all? I think that's very strange.
I played a little bit here and there.
As a matter of fact,
once I was a rehearsal pianist.
For ballet? An opera?
Las Vegas musical revue.
-You don't call that music!
-Oh, yes, I do.
It's music, you know.
Bring on the girls
I'm singing you a song
Are you feeling better?
I feel great.
More gingerbread?
No, thank you.
Applesauce?
You know what I suggest, Ray?
Well, that's what I suggest...
...because I don't know
how long it's gonna be.
I have to go now.
I have to get off now, Ray.
Yeah, well...
I'll try and call you
in a couple of days.
If you're gone, you're gone.
Bye.
Robert, my playing put father to sleep.
Would you help me with this, please?
That's it.
You sure you should be playing, Carl?
What do you mean?
I'm in superb shape, ex cept for my neck.
There's something f unny
about the way you move.
Well, I'm not aware of...
What do you mean?
Two-eighteen.
I'd hate to see you walk
across a concert stage like that.
Two-nineteen.
I'd get somebody to coach you
on how to walk, if I was you.
I think it's a substantial problem.
Damn it!
Look at that.
Why are you being so mean?
Mean? I'm not being mean.
He does walk f unny. Don't you see that?
I don't think I'd notice.
I'm so used to Carl.
Yeah, well...
Bobby?
Do you think Spicer is attractive?
I think he's got a terrific personality.
Spicer was formerly a sailor.
Look. Don't you see that?
Look at that. The guy is...
Sailors are sadistic, I feel.
You see, there's nothing wrong
with my walk. Now, where were we?
At game, Carl.
Well, that's three games to Z, Carl.
What do you say about a rematch?
I thought you're going to the mainland.
You'll miss the ferry.
Just when I was hitting my stride. Say
goodbye to Catherine for me, will you?
Can I play now?
Tell her I'll be back sometime
tomorrow probably, will you?
Where is she, anyway?
Who?
Shopping in the village.
My turn!
Why don't you and Spicer play?
Spicer?
What's the matter?
Nothing.
Robert...
...would you do something for me?
Would you play for me?
Catherine, your game!
Catherine?
Will you?
That was beautif ul. I'm surprised.
Thank you.
I was really very moved, but...
What's wrong?
Nothing. It's just I picked the easiest
piece that I could think of...
...and I first played it when I was 8
years old, and I played it better then.
Can't you understand it was the feeling
I was affected by?
I didn't have any.
You had no inner feeling?
None.
Well, then, I must
have been supplying it.
Maybe if you supply a little more,
it might rub off on me. Who knows?
I doubt it.
I could get interested.
Well, I couldn't.
What does it have to be with you?
Grim and serious?
Look, you played.
I honestly responded.
And you made me feel embarrassed
for having responded to you.
It wasn't necessary.
Yeah, it was. I faked a little Chopin,
you faked a big response.
I don't think that's accurate.
All I've been getting f rom you is
meaningf ul looks at the dinner table...
...and vague suggestions about the day...
I am not conscious
of having given you any looks.
As for the day after tomorrow,
this is the day after tomorrow!
And I am, unfortunately, seeing you.
If you'll ex cuse me,
I'd like to take a bath.
-What do you want anyway?
-Some bath oil.
Some bath oil?
How about some avocado? Or this?
Or some of this jasmine?
How about this?
What are you doing?
What are you doing screwing around
with all this crap?
I do not find your language
very charming.
It isn't. It's direct.
I'd like you to leave...
...so that I can take a bath.
Is that direct?
Serious?
Is that what's important to you?
Yes.
Let's be serious. Sit down!
-Don't do that!
-Shut up!
No inner feeling?
I told him the truth, finally.
He was my husband
and I loved him very much.
But, it wasn't working any better
the second time than it did the first.
He was a cellist.
And there was I...
...no longer 17, looking up at him.
And I said to him:
"Joseph, you're f ull of beans!"
And I left him.
Is that what you said to him?
Something like that.
As a matter of fact, Joseph introduced
me to Carl right around then.
How are you?
Incredible.
Carl restored me. He really did.
He's much more substantial
than you give him credit for being.
Do you think you could discreetly
move across the hall now?
Yes, I think I could discreetly
move across the hall now.
Robert?
I have some f ree time tomorrow morning
before Carl gets back, if you'd like.
Of course I'd like it.
Bananas! Bananas!
You certainly do have a beautif ul piece
of real estate out here, Mr. Dupea.
Can he hear me?
He's not hard of hearing.
That's a blessing at least.
This certainly is an improvement
on the motel and the coffee shop.
How could you ever leave
such a beautif ul place?
I don't know.
You've been staying
in a motel all this time?
For two weeks there wasn't hardly
nobody there to talk to, but me.
But why did you stay at the motel?
There's plenty of room here.
Well, I was going to...
...but Bobby had to come up here
and feel it up here first.
But then it took so long.
I run flat out of money.
You didn't leave me
any number or anything, honey.
And I had to, you know,
get in a taxi and come on out here...
...in the hopes that I would not
be intruding myself.
No, not at all.
You're perfectly welcome to stay here.
Well, thank you.
That's a very nice thing for you to say.
Not at all.
You have a beautif ul head of hair.
Thank you.
Is it natural?
-Rayette?
-What?
Just finish eating.
Am I holding up dessert?
No, not at all.
Take all the time you want.
I do eat slow as a bird...
...whereas Bobby can pack it away
like a speed swing.
Is there any ketchup around?
For God's sake!
Please, let's not be rude.
That's okay.
He didn't mean anything by that.
I don't, huh?
Bobby's just about the moodiest man
I've ever been with.
Are you all right?
Where are you going?
To pick up some f riends
of Carl's and mine.
I wanna talk to you.
I'll be back later.
I wanna talk right now.
I wanna explain...
-No, it isn't necessary!
-Yes, it is!
Come on! Move it!
Will you shut up?
Come on!
This is impossible. I have to go!
Will you just wait one minute?
I haven't been being fair to Carl.
I have to tell you that.
What? I can't hear you!
I'm sorry everything's
been so conf using.
I'll see you later this evening.
You see, man is born into the world with
his existent adversary f rom the first.
It is his historic, mythic inheritance.
Is this startling?
Aggression is prehistoric.
An organism behaves
according to its nature...
...which derives f rom the circumstances
of its inheritance.
Fact remains that primitive man took
delight in tearing his adversary apart.
That is where, I think,
the core of the problem resides.
Doesn't that seem apocalyptic?
I do not make poetry.
Is there a TV in the house?
I remarked to John...
...that rationality is not
a device to alter facts.
I think of it
as an extraneous tool, a gadget...
...somewhat like the television.
To look at it any other way
is ridiculous.
There's some good things on it.
I beg your pardon?
The TV. There's some
good things on it sometimes.
I have strong doubts.
Nevertheless, I am not discussing media.
But there is always hope.
-For the few.
-What about love?
What about it?
Wouldn't you say that more ill has been
done f rom love than f rom abomination?
No. No, I wouldn't.
Well, you are a romantic, Catherine.
And once more about to be married.
So you can be ex cused...
...f rom objective discussions.
But ask Carl.
Ask him if even the institution
of marriage is completely f ree f rom it.
Ask him.
I think these cold,
objective discussions are aggressive.
Ex cuse me.
That's reactive!
If I may say, without dampening
the spirit of your adventure...
You haven't dampened my spirit.
-Ex cuse me.
-I should hope not.
But it's still open to some dispute that
there seems to be less aggression...
...or violence, if you like...
I'm sorry, I don't speak French.
...and loftier natures...
What kind of doggy is this?
This is a Border collie.
I had a pussycat once.
It was a little fluffy thing.
Bobby gave it to me. Remember, Bobby?
The little pussycat you gave me?
Yeah.
Had two little white f ront paws.
And I was crazy after her.
We left it at some f riends' house...
...and she got squashed flat
as a tortilla outside their mobile home.
There! Do you see what I mean?
The choice of words juxtaposed
with the image of a fluffy kitten!
The enchantment of words,
"squashed, " "flat, " etcetera...
Well, she was.
Perhaps. But it was just
what I was trying to point out.
Don't sit there pointing at her.
I beg your pardon?
I said, don't point at her, you creep!
But I was just...
Where do you get the ass to tell anybody
about class or what she typifies?
You shouldn't even be
in the same room with her!
This is really too much.
-Just calm down!
-You're f ull of shit!
You're all f ull of shit!
Catherine!
Catherine?
I can't talk to you.
Leave me alone.
What the hell's going on?
-What're you doing?
-What's...
Hey, where...
Where's Catherine?
I don't know where Catherine is!
I'm talking to you, Tita!
I told you just to take
your hands off my sister, nurse!
Move out!
Stop it!
Stop it! Stop it!
Hold it, will you?
Hold it! Take it easy!
Take it easy, will you?
Stop it! Let him go!
You give up?
Do you give up? Do you?
Stop it! Stop it! Stop it!
-Give up?
-Stop!
Give up! Give up! Give up!
Bobby!
I just wanted to talk to you.
It's useless.
Look, give me a chance.
I'm trying to be delicate with you...
...but you just won't understand.
I couldn't go with you. Not because
of Carl, but because of you.
You're a strange person, Robert.
I mean, what would it come to?
A person who has no love for himself,
no respect for himself...
...no love of his f riends,
family, work, something.
How can he ask for love in return?
Why should he ask for it?
Living here in this rest-home asylum,
that's what you want?
Yes.
That'll make you happy?
I hope it will. Yes.
I'm sorry.
Okay.
Are you cold?
I don't know if you'd be...
...particularly interested
in hearing anything about me.
My life, I mean.
Most of it doesn't add up to much...
...that I could relate as a way
of life that you'd approve of.
I move around a lot.
Not because I'm looking
for anything, really...
...but because I'm getting away
f rom things that get bad...
...if I stay.
Auspicious beginnings,
you know what I mean?
I'm trying to imagine you're...
...you're half of this conversation.
My feeling is, I don't know...
...that if you could talk,
we wouldn't be talking.
It's pretty much the way
that it got to be before I left.
Are you all right?
I don't know what to say.
Tita suggested that we try to...
I don't know.
I think that she feels...
I think that she feels that we've got...
...some understanding to reach.
She totally denies the fact...
...that we were never that comfortable
with one another to begin with.
The best that I can do is apologize.
We both know that I was never
really that good at it anyway.
I'm sorry it didn't work out.
Bobby!
You're leaving?
Yeah. I said a week.
I think I overstayed myself.
You were going without
saying goodbye to me.
I didn't want to say goodbye to anyone.
But what about me?
I'll say goodbye to you, Tita.
Oh, Robert!
Watch the birdie!
Bye.
Come on, Ray.
I want to take a picture
of us in f ront of the place.
Not now, Ray.
Listen, I never got to
thank you all for your hospitality.
Tell Carl if any of you wanna come to
our place, you'll be more than welcome.
Bye, now.
Your kiss is like a drink
When I am thirsty
Oh, and I'm thirsty for you
With all my heart
But don't love me then pretend
As though we've never kissed
Don't touch me
Cut it out!
Son of a bitch, Bobby!
You quit pushing me away like that!
I've had enough of that
to last me an entire lifetime!
Why don't you just
be good to me for a change?
There isn't anybody gonna look
after you and love you as good as I do.
Did you hear me?
Baby?
I'm going to that caf for some coffee.
You want anything?
No.
You got any change?
You don't have any change?
Sure you don't want anything?
Fill it up, will you?
Hey, wait!
Don't you got a jacket
or anything with you?
No.
Jesus!
Got burned up.
Everything in the car
got the shit burned out of it.
Everything.
All I got is what I got on.
I got one behind the seat
if you want it.
No, it's okay.
Suit yourself.
Tell you one thing.
Where we're going
it's gonna get colder than hell.
That's okay.
I'm fine.