Give it over, Michael.
Thanks.
Rose!
- Yours?
- Aye.
My dad got it when they
sold up Lady Pawson's.
Lady Pawson, is it?
Fine fish, Michael.
Give him a smile and you'll maybe
get one of the claws for your supper.
Michael!
I've told you, Michael,
they're created creatures!
Get off!
It'll make me sick!
Poor Mike's no answer to
a young maid's dreams...
but do you not think he
just possibly knows that?
I can't abide him, Father Hugh.
You used to ride to
school on his back.
- I can walk for myself now.
- Aye.
Where are you walking this
afternoon dressed up like that?
- Nowhere precisely.
- Just so.
What do you do, Rose, mooning
about all day by yourself?
Read.
- Well, I wasn't really reading it.
- You're doing nothing, then?
- I suppose so.
- Have you nothing to do?
Precisely that!
Well, Miss Precisely, that's a pity.
Doing nothing is a
dangerous occupation!
Morning.
- Blowy day?
- That's right, Corporal.
It's the wind.
Only want to be friendly, kids.
Then go back to London
and write us a letter.
- Don't come from London, love.
- Go anyway.
- Morning, Mr. O'Connor.
- Good morning to you, Corporal.
Will you listen to that now?
Aren't the police a dirty lot,
hobnobbing with the British soldiers?
I heard that, Maureen Cassidy.
You were meant to, Constable O'Connor.
Hey, Michael!
Michael, darling, show us your fish.
How much does he weigh then, Mike?
How long is it, Michael?
I've never seen a
lobster the equal of that.
- Michael, can I touch it?
- Come here and show it to us, Michael.
Michael.
Now what? Now what?
What am I to do with you? What?
- Actually it's only a bit of fun, Father.
- Fun?
Are you brainless,
Maureen Cassidy, or what?
Fun.
Devil take me if the lot of
you is not possessed and damned.
I don't know what's the matter
with the youngsters in this place.
I don't at all.
Their talk is filthy, their doings
are secret, and cruelty for fun.
Unemployment is the matter
with them, Father Hugh.
It's the deliberate policy
of the British government...
that Irish youngsters
shall corrupt in idleness.
Well, it's working fine.
I just seen your Rosy
loafing about the beach again.
How much you give for
that black lace umbrella?
Three and six.
You'll ruin that girl.
It's time she had a fellow of her own,
Tom. A house of her own. Floors to scrub.
My princess isn't interested
in fellows, Father.
Your princess has
fellows enough in here.
And fellows running loose in
there will do a girl more damage...
than a barrack full of drunk dragoons.
Well...
if there's one of that lot as is fit for
her, maybe you'll point him out, Father.
Rose.
Mr. Shaughnessy.
Well...
this is nice, Rose.
Well, you're back, then?
Yes, I'm back, and I...
- Thanks.
I came to meet you.
Well, that was kind.
A party of us went to a couple
of concerts while we were there.
I saved you the programs.
- "The Royal Philharmonic."
- Berlioz and Tchaikovsky.
- No Beethoven?
- No Beethoven.
Do you know that the British
government has got a law now...
- forbidding the playing of German music?
- No.
- Can you imagine such foolishness?
- British.
Well, all governments
is foolish, more or less.
An Irish government would be the same.
Well, maybe.
Thank you.
- You enjoyed yourself in Dublin, then?
- Well, I did and I didn't.
A conference of village school
teachers, you know, is not exactly a...
- Bacchanalia?
- Bacchanalia. Precisely.
We did have some interesting
discussions, though.
There was a lady teacher among us
from Belfast, a stimulating woman.
Oh.
- Did she come to the concert?
- She had the score.
In what way, precisely,
was she stimulating?
She had a fine and fresh mind,
Rose. Very modern in her thoughts.
She'd been at the
teaching for over 50 years.
Old folk with fresh minds
are very stimulating.
Then there was a ministry
inspector, he gave us an address...
But the best we had was this
professor from the Sorbonne.
Now, there was a man
with a mind, if you like.
- Why? What did he say?
- I couldn't tell you, Rose.
Whatever it was, it was wasted on us.
Teachers are a poor lot, surely.
If teachers were the poor lot,
like you're always making out...
how would the pupils
be learning such riches?
What?
Some young fellow's
going to be a lucky man.
- Rose?
- I've something in my eye.
Rose.
The nuisance.
- Will I get it out, then?
- Oh, no, it's nothing.
It's only the wind.
- Are you away to the schoolhouse, then?
- No, Rose, I think...
I'll scramble up the dunes
and pay my respects to my wife.
Oh, yes.
Good day, Rose.
Good day, Mr. Shaughnessy.
Hello, Michael.
- Shaughnessy.
- There you are, Mr. Shaughnessy.
So, you're back again, Charles.
Home is the voyager,
safe from the sea.
- The usual?
- Thanks.
And...
what did you see in Dublin?
- You mean, the trouble?
- What else?
Well, nothing, really.
- Did you not go and see Sackville Street?
- I passed it, yes.
- Passed it?
- Well, I'll be damned.
What did you see as
you passed it, Charles?
- It did look terrible smashed about, Father.
- It's true, then.
- The Government used guns.
- I've not said that, Father.
All right, you've not said
anything. What did you hear?
I heard they used heavy guns...
like them they're using on the
Western Front against the Germans.
And our poor lads pursued
from house to house...
with not one rifle between three.
Now, if the Germans
had an ounce of sense...
they'd send us guns to
use against the British.
That's treason you're talking.
And friends that are
listening surely to God.
It's foolish, all the same. You'll
blather yourself into jug some day.
Charles, what do they say they'll do
with the lads they've got in prison?
They say they'll hang them, Father.
Good luck to all Irishmen.
Bad luck to the British.
Success to the Germans.
And...
And a very good morning
to you, Corporal.
Two black stouts, please, Mr. Ryan.
And one for yourself?
Well, seeing you're a man
of wealth, Corporal, yes.
- Father?
- No.
- Mr. Shaughnessy? -
Well, I don't mind if I-
No, I'd best be on my way. Term
is starting tomorrow, you know...
It seems the Jerries...
are giving your brave lads out
there a terrible scrimmage, then.
Aye.
You see, Tom, Jerry's
a tougher proposition...
than unarmed Irish children.
So far as I know, Mr. McCardle,
no children were killed.
All right, then. There were.
They get you in this uniform.
You point your gun where
you're told to point it...
and you pull the trigger.
And so does Jerry.
And so would you.
You've seen that place,
Passchendaele, maybe?
No, not Passchendaele.
- You're well out of it, Corporal.
- That's right.
Well, duty calls.
Good day, Charles.
Well, good day.
Welcome home.
Will you imagine that fellow?
A fortnight in Dublin.
Does nothing, sees nothing.
It's working with children,
makes a man childish.
No, it was that wife of his,
knocked all the spirit out of him.
She was a good, pure woman.
- Pure, she was.
- Is that nothing?
Oh, no. No.
Well, did you come to
lend me a hand, then?
Well, now, let's see. For a
start, you could put the kettle on.
I didn't come for that at all.
I've come to say something.
I feel like a child in this place.
And I'm not a child.
Do you know that?
I know that.
Rose, I've...
maybe an idea of what you came to say.
You have no idea at all.
Well, I'm just saying, in case
it helps a bit, I maybe have.
I love you.
- Will you come inside?
- No.
Will you sit down, then?
- Why?
- I'd like to talk to you, Rose.
Well, I know what that means.
Rose, this sort of thing
can come about, you know...
a girl taking a fancy to a teacher.
- Thanks.
- Fancy's all it is, Rose.
Rose, you've mistaken a
penny mirror for the sun.
Do you not see that?
I see you always digging
a low pit for yourself...
when you should be
standing on a heap of pride.
Well, Rose...
your coming here today and
saying what you've said...
is the only cause I've
ever had for pride.
Don't you see, Rose? I
only taught you about...
Byron and Beethoven and Captain Blood.
I'm not one of them fellows myself.
- I'm not daft, you know.
- But you're terribly young.
- Aye, and that's a hanging matter, isn't it?
- No, it's not.
Well, then?
It's not a hanging
matter to be young...
but it maybe should be a hanging
matter for a man of middle age...
to try and steal the
youth from a young girl.
Especially a man like
me and a girl like you.
You were meant for the wide world,
Rose, not this place, not this.
Me, I was born for it.
It wouldn't do, Rose.
I just know it wouldn't.
So you don't want me, then?
Don't want you?
- Yes.
- Oh.
Would you like a fat pheasant,
Constable? It'll cost you nothing.
Whoa.
He recognized you.
- Well, you'll have
to be quick... Shut up!
Bring the cart!
Jesus.
- Fine pair of gunrunners we are.
- Come on.
We'll never walk to
the coast, Commandant.
- It's 200 miles.
- We'll walk to Limerick.
- Limerick?
- The lads are waiting for us.
- Oh.
- And cheer up, Pat.
They're waiting with a lorry.
About 30 fellows.
Now...
marriage is a sacrament ordained
by God. That means, Rosy...
once it's done, it's not up to me,
nor you, nor Charles. It's done...
- till one or other of you is dead.
- I understand that.
God ordained it for three reasons.
First, that Charles and you should
be a comfort to each other...
in the long, dull days
and the weary evenings.
- Do you understand that?
- Yes.
Secondly, for the procreation of children,
and to bring them up as good Catholics.
- Well, you understand that.
- Yes.
And, thirdly...
- for the satisfaction of the flesh.
- Yes.
Are you scared of that?
Yes.
It's nothing to be scared of,
Rosy. A function of the body.
I suppose all girls
is a bit scared before.
And fellows, too.
- Yes?
- Oh, yes.
It will make me a
different person, won't it?
- Marriage?
- No, the satisfaction of the flesh.
That's a gate I have not
been through myself...
but, no, it won't make
you a different person.
I want it to.
Child, what are you expecting?
Wings, is it?
All right, try it.
Seven boats. All currachs.
One thing at a time. Keep a look out.
Top of the morning, Father.
Morning!
- Morning, Father.
- Morning, tinker.
You'll find nothing much here. It all
gets carried round the head to Killins.
Ah.
- Good luck with it, anyway.
- Thanks, Father.
And if them two's tinkers,
I'm the Bishop of Cork.
Now, we'll have one
light on the beacon...
and one on the cliff.
- What now, then? Back to Dublin?
- Tomorrow.
I want to see what Ryan's like.
Are you not done, Mrs. McCardle?
Easy, Mr. Ryan, dear.
They'll not start without her.
Women.
Tim, did you review the volunteers
in Phoenix Park before the war?
- Yes, why?
- Will you come here?
Aye, you're looking
at me picture, lads.
Here.
You recognize someone?
- That's yourself, landlord.
- It is.
And he that has me by the hand...
- is Commandant Tim O'Leary.
- Never.
Red Tim himself. That
1,000 secret policemen...
have been hunting for
these last five years.
And himself, no doubt at this very moment
walking the broad streets of Dublin.
- He's a brave man, surely.
- Nerves of steel.
You know him well, then?
- I get my orders from time to time.
- Landlord, you're a desperate man.
I'll tell you something.
- Come on then, Mr. Ryan.
- Right, ma'am.
Good luck to the young lady.
Talk.
This whole cursed country
will capsize with talk.
The locals are no good.
I'll have to bring you some
hard lads from Dublin...
when the time comes.
- When will that be, Commandant?
- I don't know.
Depends on our clever lads in Germany.
And they're great talkers, too.
With this ring, I thee wed.
In the name of the Father...
the Son...
and the Holy Ghost. Amen.
This gold and silver, I give thee...
token of all my worldly goods.
Good night, Father Hugh.
Good night, Rosy.
Well, is no one going
to kiss the bride?
Steady, lads. Steady!
Get off out of it!
Enough. Now, cut it out.
Now, then. That's
enough. Come on, boys.
That's enough.
Now, lads, that's enough.
- Lucky man, and how are you feeling?
- Lucky.
Are you all right, princess?
It was only their bit of fun.
Good night, Father.
Good night, Rosy.
Now, go on, away in with you.
Well, you'll be away early
in the morning, I suppose?
We will, yes, Mr. Ryan.
You're a wonderful girl, Rose.
No.
No, I'm not.
Charles, how you getting on?
Them fellows has an
elegant sense of humor.
It doesn't matter.
Charles, get a handful of this.
Now, come away.
- Rose?
- Yes?
Are you all right?
Yes.
- Good night, Rose.
- Good night, Charles.
Rose?
I got you these.
They're all growing, see?
- When did you do it?
- Last thing yesterday. Just before church.
Charles, you're a rare man.
Well done.
- Here, no.
- They're not heavy.
I can't believe you're here.
Well, I am.
Well, now.
Beethoven.
I...
I don't think you care
much for my flowers, do you?
I like them better growing, surely.
Well, sure, things are better growing.
I'm afraid you're too
late for snapdragons.
Well, I'll put in some
lilies, then. I like them.
- What's the matter?
- My shirt, Rose. I'd like to get my shirt.
Charles, you're fine as you are.
Well, all right, Rose.
I don't know, Rose,
suppose somebody came in.
Charles.
- You're always on about if someone came.
- Well, it's not decent.
- Decent.
- Well, it's not, you know.
All right, then.
I'm sorry, Charles.
Put it on.
No. What does it matter?
No, you're right. Please, put it on.
No, well, I'll be
out again in a minute.
Six ones are six.
Six twos are twelve.
Six threes are eighteen.
Six fours are twenty-four.
Six fives are thirty.
Six sixes are thirty-six.
Six sevens are forty-two.
Six eights are forty-eight.
- Six nines are...
- Fifty-four.
Fifty-four.
Six tens are sixty.
Six elevens are sixty-six.
Six twelves are...
Seventy-two.
Now, your work is on the board.
You've all got your pencils.
There's no need for talking,
Kathleen. Now get on with it.
Get on.
Rose?
Rose.
- Where are you going, Rosy?
- Nowhere.
You're in the devil of a hurry there.
Now, stop.
Now, what exactly is the
trouble between you and Charles?
No. No trouble.
Are you asking me to
believe you're happy?
- I'm not asking you anything.
- Are you happy?
No.
Why not?
I don't know.
- Come on, Rosy, now give me a try.
- I don't.
All right.
Because I am stupid and conceited...
and self-centered and ungrateful
like you've always told me.
For I have everything
I wanted, have I not?
You have!
- What more are you wanting now?
- I don't know that, either.
- That's a lie.
- It's not.
How can I know?
I don't even know what more there is.
- You've got a good man now, haven't you?
- The best.
Well?
And you've got enough
money. Not much, but enough.
Aye.
And you've got your health.
- You're not sick?
- No.
There is nothing more,
you graceless girl.
- But, there is.
- There is not.
I know there is.
- There must be, Father Hugh.
- Why?
Glory be to God, why must there
be? Because Rosy Ryan wants it?
Aye.
Have you got any warm old clothes,
Rosy? Poor Patsy Wheelan's in a bad way.
I'll find some, Father.
Thanks.
Rosy, don't nurse your wishes.
You can't help having them,
but don't nurse them...
or sure to God, you'll get
what you're wishing for.
Major Doryan, sir.
Sorry, sir, I had to change a wheel.
Sir.
Get in.
In!
Come on, kids, out of it.
You were in Second Battle of
the Marne, weren't you, sir?
- Yes.
- So was I, sir.
- Yes?
- It was too much for me, sir.
I reckon that's why they sent me here.
Camp coming up, sir.
Slope...
arms.
Capt. Smith, sir.
Hey.
That's all we're short of,
that is. A crippled bloody hero.
Well, now, sir.
This is our communication
with the outside world.
Field telephone to the police
station down the village.
Now, then. Records.
Hello? Constable O'Connor here.
- Were you calling?
- No, no, Constable, just testing.
Well, now, sir, where was I?
Oh, aye. Records. Records. Transport.
They're sending a...
Well, I guess you'd
better see your room.
Well, now, duty.
Our duties are light.
Oh, good lad, Jimmy.
Jimmy will look after you
right nicely, Major Doryan.
Tired?
Yes.
- That leg gives you gyp, don't it?
- Yes.
Sent you here for a rest, did they?
Yes, I think they did.
Well, you'll get that, if naught else.
There's nothing to do here but walk.
Oh, I'm sorry. I expect walking's out.
No, I'm supposed to
walk. Five miles a day.
Oh. Well, then. They've
sent you to the right place.
There's some nice walks here.
Our duties are light
enough, God knows.
Our duties. It's more
like police work, isn't it?
The publican's a
source of information.
- An informer?
- Aye. Publican, name of Ryan.
Well, he's nothing to inform, has he?
But the police slip him a
fiver now and then, you know.
Oh, he's all right.
Big mouth, open hand,
empty pocket, you know?
Typical publican. But
he's all right, really.
- Jimmy.
- Sir?
- Are my bags on the lorry?
- Yes, sir.
I'll be straight off, if
it's all the same, sir.
- I've given myself leave.
- Yes?
Embarkation leave.
France.
Second battalion,
Southeast Lancashires.
They're in the front line.
Will you tell me
something, man to man?
What's it like, really?
Front line?
Aye. Well...
I'll find out soon enough.
I'm a coward, you see.
No, I always have been.
From being a lad.
I can't master it.
Well, perhaps I've
never tried, really.
But, I'd give my left arm to
have a bit of what you've got.
I hate it.
Just the bloody thought
of it gives me the shakes.
That's my nightmare, as a
matter of fact, the shakes.
I don't mind dying.
Not if it's quick. Life's
not that much, is it?
I wouldn't mind a gammy
leg like you've got.
Though I don't suppose it's funny.
But the shakes?
Shellshock.
Just shaking and shambling
like a epileptic baby.
Nay, I'd rather be dead.
I can see what's coming.
I'm going to disgrace myself.
You don't know what you'll do.
No one does. You don't
know what you're doing.
Really?
I read what you did in the newspapers.
That were no flash in the pan.
You'd do the same again, I dare say.
You'd be wrong.
Well, you've done your bit.
It's someone else's turn now, eh?
Oh, dear. You look
about finished, sir.
Here.
Good stuff, this. Cheap, too.
That's the generator.
The bloody thing stays on all
night, but you'll get used to that.
This your house?
- Yes.
- Well, I never.
- Wife?
- Yes.
- May I?
- Please.
Oh.
Bonny woman.
Thank you.
- She'll be coming out, then?
- No, I don't think so.
There's no local crumpet.
It's married or virgin here, you know.
And that priest down there has
got eyes in the back of his head.
It gets bloody lonely here.
Why not have her out?
Sorry.
Fools rush in, eh?
You're probably better
on your own a bit.
Excuse me.
I'll pop back to say goodbye.
It's him.
Peg leg.
Sir?
Excuse me, I didn't
realize you were serving.
Well, I'm just minding.
What did you want?
Whiskey.
Water?
Did you want water?
Please.
Thank you.
I must open the door.
Sit, please.
- Is this where you live?
- What?
Is this where you live?
- I live at the schoolhouse.
- Schoolhouse?
- I'm married to the teacher.
- Oh.
They're back.
- I don't know your name.
- Shaughnessy, Rose Shaughnessy.
Come away in, then.
One round on the house!
That's my dad.
Your father is the publican?
Yes, why not?
Now, I can't just say
you're very welcome, sir.
Not in your official function.
But in yourself, you're welcome.
A brave man is a brave
man in any uniform.
English khaki, Irish
green, aye, or German gray.
Aye, you've a large mind, sir.
Put it there.
You've met my daughter, then?
Yes.
All right, everyone, the
Major isn't a peep show.
Princess.
Guess what your old dad's got
for you this time from the fair?
Guess.
- I don't know, Father.
- Come and look.
- Now, then.
- Father, you can't afford it.
Oh, it's nothing.
Just a little blood mare I
picked up at the fair, is all.
- She's a Connemara.
- All right.
You look as if you'd be a judge, sir.
Maybe you'll favor us with your opinion.
Now.
It's a fine horse, Mr. Ryan.
- Are you away, then?
- Yes.
Good day, Mr. Ryan, Mrs. Shaughnessy.
Snob!
Of course he's a snob. Isn't that
what the English is famous for?
Aye.
On the house.
Hello.
Did you see our lord and master, then?
- I did. Fine looking young man.
- Blather.
- Will you meet me tomorrow?
- How?
Where?
- The tower.
- What tower?
Ask.
When?
- 3:00?
- Yes.
Whatever is this, darling?
It must be the lilies.
You're restless, Rosy.
Yes, I am a bit.
I think maybe I'll take
Princess out tomorrow.
Aye, yes, do that.
It'll please your father.
How long will you be here?
Till I ask to be sent back.
To the front?
To my unit.
They're at the front.
You'll not do that?
No. Not now.
Not now.
Oh, darling.
Darling.
- Tomorrow?
- If I can.
Good night, darling.
Good night.
Rosy.
- Hello, Charles.
- Hello, Rose.
Where've you been, Rose?
What's happened, Rosy?
- Princess took a fall.
- Rose, no.
I'm fine. I'll just change.
It was my own fault, really.
I put her at a ditch
she wasn't up to, and...
she lay on my leg and wouldn't get up.
- Your leg, darling? Let me have a look.
- It's nothing at all.
- If you're sure.
- I'm certain sure. It's nothing.
Subtitles downloaded from www.OpenSubtitles.org.
But she wouldn't get up for anything.
Do you know who came
to get me out of it?
That new English officer.
- Major Doryan?
- Aye, him.
He came and got her up.
Well, that was lucky.
- What have you been doing?
- Waiting for you.
You mustn't worry about
me, darling. I can ride.
You can ride Champion, surely. But
the mare's not properly broke, Rose.
Rose, she's not properly broke.
Well, Major what's-his-name
did say he'd help me.
- With the horse?
- Aye.
But, I don't suppose he meant it.
- He looks a man of his word to me.
- Does he, Charles?
Seems like a fine
young fellow all around.
You always think the
best of people, don't you?
Why not?
Well, we'll see.
- Could you eat some supper?
- I could have a go at it, yes.
Rose?
Yes?
You'd never be unfaithful
to me, would you?
Charles.
I'm sorry, I shouldn't
have asked that.
No, that's a rotten question
for a man to ask his wife.
Sir, what's that there?
What's that?
Well, that's not the cuttlefish
that I told you to look for.
That's for a start.
That is an insulator.
Aye, an insulator, that is.
Probably off a German battleship.
I'm sure there's no German
battleships coming here, sir.
- You don't know, there might be.
- No, Timmy's right.
Now, tell me this.
Why is there so much
stuff around Killins Bay?
It's a tide... Tidal
eddy around the head.
Tidal eddy. Very good, Tim. Good.
All right, come on,
now. Go on looking.
The tide's going
down. Go on, hurry up.
Go on, Kathleen. Off with the others.
You never know, you might
find a diamond tiara.
Sir, sir.
Aye, that's a cuttlefish.
- Good lad.
- I'll try and find a bigger one.
You do that, Tim.
Come on.
What is it, sir?
No, it's nothing. Nothing.
'Tis all right, Kathy.
Come on.
Time we had lunch.
We're eating at Barrow.
It's a long way to Barrow, sir.
Step off, then. That's
where we're eating.
Tide's coming in, sir.
So it is.
Hey, would you look at Michael?
Michael.
It's the Major.
Hey, Tom, will you
have a look at this?
He's getting worse, you know.
Michael, let's have
a look at your V.C.
- How many Germans did you kill, Michael?
- All right.
All right, very entertaining.
Michael, you're a perfect fool.
You ask for trouble. Come on,
now, take the foolish things off.
Michael, take them off, now. Come on.
Michael!
What's eating him?
- What've you been doing?
- Don't know, Father.
We've not done anything.
Come on now, Michael.
What're you up to?
Let go!
Michael, let go, or I'll hit you.
Michael, darling, let go.
Major, darling, let me touch your V.C.
You see, my husband hasn't got one.
Well?
Well.
What was the meaning
of that pantomime?
I don't know.
- Where have you been?
- Riding...
- with Major Doryan.
- You're bold as brass.
You think that's a suitable
connection for a decent Irish wife?
I think that is for my
husband to say, Father Hugh.
- You've told him, have you?
- Yes.
Yes, you would.
Your husband would say anything
you wanted, pretty well...
because he loves you
sorely, doesn't he?
- Yes, he does.
- Have you nothing to say to me?
- What should I have to say to you?
- You could say:
"Father Hugh, there's nothing
between me and Major Doryan."
- There isn't.
- Say it, then.
There is nothing between
me and Major Doryan.
Look at me, Rosy.
Oh, child, what a face.
- Rose, tell me now.
- What?
You'll have to tell it in
confessional, you little fool.
I don't have to come...
- to the confessional.
- Child!
Child?
- Father.
- Hello, then.
Rosy...
was there something?
No, I just...
- Will you take the prayers, then?
- Aye.
"Our Father..."
"who art in Heaven,
hallowed be thy name."
"Thy kingdom come, Thy will be done..."
"on Earth as it is in heaven."
"Give us this day our daily bread.
And forgive us our trespasses..."
"as we forgive those
who trespass against us."
"And lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil."
In the name of the Father and
of the Son and of the Holy Ghost.
All right, children, off with you.
Thank you, Father. Good day.
Glad to help, Charles.
Is there anything else
I can help you with?
No, I don't think so.
Well, I'll be off home, too, then.
- You're late.
- I took them for a nature walk.
Up Brandon?
Along the shore.
- For cuttlefish?
- Aye.
For cuttlefish.
If you'd come up Brandon,
we might have seen you.
Why?
- Did you go to Brandon?
- Aye.
I got some heather.
So you did.
You haven't been to the beach, then?
No.
Oh, well.
- It's nice up Brandon.
- Aye, it's grand.
Is something the matter?
I don't know, Rose. Is there?
There's nothing the matter with me.
Nothing's the matter, then.
And the jam, and the...
The jam...
and the soap.
Maggie.
That'll be 18 pence.
Could it wait to the
end of the week, missus?
Aye, to the end of the week.
Not to the crack of doom.
Thank you.
- What was it, then?
- I want a dishcloth, please.
- I've none.
- Oh.
Then I'll just take some
potatoes. Five pound.
I've no potatoes, either.
What's them, then?
Aye, them.
They're gone. I've no potatoes.
Oh, I... I see.
The way I see it, Mrs. Kenyon, there's
loose women and there's whores...
and then there's
British soldiers' whores.
- Coming up fast, Father.
- Aye.
Will you look at those things?
You'd think they was
announcing the coming of Christ.
- Off you go!
- Right.
Put her down!
Slowly does it.
All right, now! That's it. Come
on, Joe, there's a good lad.
Come on, it's late.
All right. Come on, Sean.
Come on, Tom. You've
got to go to sleep.
Go on. Good night!
Hello, Tom.
- You? What are you doing here?
- Come on, now, Tom.
Phoenix Park, 1913.
Tim O'Leary.
Come on.
Right, lads.
Now, what do you usually
do at this time, Tom?
- I go to bed.
- Right.
This is Bernard. Go on up, lads.
- Paddy.
Sean.
Joseph, Peter...
Mr. O'Keefe.
- And you know Pat.
- Which room?
At the back.
But, Commandant,
sir, what's happening?
Guns, is it?
- That's right, Tom. German guns.
- German?
Dynamite, grenades. All the
stuff the movement needs.
We tried to launch the boat...
- You must get to them somehow, then.
- We can't.
But Sean here says there's a good chance
some of it will break away and come to us.
- Float in?
- You're on to it.
But, if it does, we won't know where.
You can't see the nose on
your face out there now.
So we'll wait till daylight.
- Absolute madness.
- Will you shut up?
Tom...
if it's to be done in
daylight, it's to be done quick.
So we must have some
fellows, say a dozen...
good, strong fellows, and
that's where you come in.
- What if it don't break away?
- Exactly.
Then we'll wait one
hour and go without it.
One hour, Tom...
and 12 strong men.
That's all I'm asking.
Can you do it?
I could rout out a dozen, yes.
- Do you want them now?
- Not at all.
The later they know
we're here, the better.
You let them lie till nearer morning.
Can you find us something to
eat? It's gonna be a long night.
Paddy, Tom.
Take the Constable his breakfast.
Jesus and Mary, what a night.
Now, do not make one sound, Constable.
Right. You.
Fat guts, get the handcuffs.
- Where are they?
- In the cupboard.
Turn around.
- I'm acting under duress.
- Shut up.
Put them on him.
Open your mouth, Constable.
Is that a telephone line?
Cut it.
Oh, God.
Why have you done this to me?
Hello?
This is Ryan.
- Did you cut the wire?
- I did.
You're doing well, Tom.
- Where's the Constable?
- In the cellar.
We can put a bullet
in him if you like.
Constable... No!
- Then get your men.
- Aye, Commandant.
Right.
They've gone!
Busted loose!
It's no good, Commandant!
Why don't you get up
out of it while you can?
Tim!
- Hey, are you Tim O'Leary?
- Yes, son, yes.
Father, what the hell
have you done this for?
I didn't, they did!
Well, do you know what you're doing?
- Do you know what we've come for?
- Aye.
- Have you got it?
- Well, look.
- T'will be on the slabs.
- Where?
The slabs!
Tim!
Come on.
Yes, Kathy?
- Aren't you coming to the beach, sir?
- The beach?
Everyone's at the beach.
- And why is everyone at the beach?
- I don't know, sir. I think it's a wreck.
A wreck?
Now, that's enough, Tom. You're
not as young as you used to be.
Aye, come on!
Oh, God.
Pull!
Right, up you get. You, too,
Father. Up. Keep it going.
That's right, darling.
That's right.
Hey!
Dynamite.
What are you doing here?
- Why shouldn't I be?
- Why?
Thank you, ma'am.
You know, we made speeches
about these people...
but, by God...
Thanks. You're a man!
Come on, then!
One!
Two!
Three!
Sean?
- I must take a chance.
- Aye.
Good luck.
Thank you. Get down, please.
- Sergeant?
- Sir.
You, here. You.
No. No trouble now,
for your own sakes.
O'Leary.
That thing could kill
a lot of people, Major.
Sir?
No.
Go on. Run, Tim!
Run, Tim.
Make it, Tim. Come on!
- Run.
- O'Leary!
Sir.
- No!
- Murderer!
- Don't shoot.
What's wrong with the bastard?
Boo!
Shoot that slut, Shaughnessy.
Careful, man.
My God, they're a well-matched pair.
All right, sir?
- Got a cigarette?
- Yes, sir.
Is there anything you want?
Cigarette.
- Anything else?
- Yes.
Get out of my country.
God bless you, Tim O'Leary!
What are they going to
do with them boys, Father?
They'll hang them, dear.
They'll hang them.
Bastard!
Get out!
You're very kind to me today.
Am I?
Yes. Why?
Am I not usually kind to you?
Yes, you are. Always.
Charles, do you know or not?
I know.
- Since when?
- The beginning.
Don't lower your head, Rose.
Why didn't you speak?
I should have, shouldn't I?
I don't know.
It was easier not to, I suppose.
I didn't want to know, you know.
And then I thought, if I let you
burn it out, the pair of you...
you'd perhaps come back to me.
Charles?
Mr. Shaughnessy has been called
away, so I'm taking class.
What's the first lesson today, Danny?
- Danny?
- My father says not to speak to you, miss.
- It's right then, he's not here?
- No.
I don't know where he is.
- You mean he's gone off?
- Yes.
When?
Last night.
You had a row?
I wasn't here.
Where were you?
Oh, I see.
There's nothing I can do tonight,
I'll find him in the morning.
- If he turns up, you'll tell me.
- Father?
You'd better take his clothes.
His clothes?
He was in bed?
Yes.
You left his bed and went to...
Rose.
Oh, Rose.
Come on, this isn't a picnic.
All right, Corp, but
there's nothing here.
He's got something there, sir.
Padre.
Good morning, padre.
I'm sorry, but what is
it you have there, please?
A man's clothes.
I see.
- And where are you taking them, Father?
- To the man.
Come on, padre. I don't
suppose you mean any harm...
but after the other day, we've
got to be careful. What man?
A man whose wife went off two
nights back with her fancy fellow.
And a man I've been looking
for since dawn today.
- A man...
Excuse me, sir.
A man who must be half out of his mind
to have gone off as he did, barefoot.
That's right. Charles Shaughnessy.
I think we're finished here, sir.
Very well.
- Hello, Charles.
- Hello, Father.
I've brought your clothes.
Thanks, Father. I was
wondering how I should get home.
- And something to drink.
- Thanks.
- Yourself?
- Aye, I will.
- You seem all right, man.
- Aye, more or less.
Well, I'll get dressed now.
Michael.
He'll be after catching
a few flounders.
So, what have you been
doing down here, Charles?
Oh, thinking.
About Rosy?
About myself, mostly.
Thanks for the clothes. You're
a man in a million, Father Hugh.
The children haven't come today, then?
No.
Rose, I have something
to say to you. Come in.
Sit down, will you?
Rose, I thought I could stand by and
let you two burn it out, like I said.
But I find I can't.
I'm not sure I ought to have
tried, but anyway, I can't.
So I'm going to leave you.
- Very well.
- Sit still a minute, Rose.
What about you? You and him?
- Nothing.
- What do you mean, nothing?
It's over.
Was that because I
went and stayed away?
No.
It's over.
- Have you told him?
- No.
He doesn't know, then?
Yes, he knows.
How?
He must.
You're as close as that, are you?
We were, yes.
Rose, you must tell me the truth.
Do you think you're
ever gonna forget him?
Of course not.
He'd be like a ghost about the place.
Rose, am I right?
Yes, you're right.
It's busted, Charles.
I busted it.
Now, have you thought what to do?
- No.
- Well, I have.
I don't think either of us can
stay in this village any longer.
No.
It's time I moved on anyway. And
you were never worse suited here.
I've reckoned up, I've
got about 200 pounds.
Take all this, without the
gramophone, fetch another 50.
We'll split it down the middle.
I can't do it.
We're not enemies, Rose.
Stop that! There's to be none of that.
But why must it be Rosy?
Because she was
fornicating with the fellow.
So, you're back, are you?
What is this? What do you want?
- Not you.
- Well, then get out.
- Go on, get out.
- Shut up, Shaughnessy.
We're waiting for her.
You.
You've been tried and found
guilty. You're the informer.
- What?
- Busting at the seams with innocence.
Joe, for God's sake, don't
hurt her, Joe. Don't hurt her.
If she was a man, Mr.
Ryan, she'd be shot.
- What is this?
- Listen, numbskull.
Someone that morning
went up to the camp...
and betrayed Tim O'Leary.
Now, who lives near
enough? Who had time enough?
Who would? Who did?
That bitch you call your wife.
String her up!
But anyone could have, if anyone
did. The whole village was abroad.
No. The village was down on the beach.
- Except you.
- You came late.
- We came together. We spoke to no one.
- You'd say that, of course.
Young Kathy was with us.
Young Kathy would say black
was white if you told her.
Then anyone, anyone at all could've
gone into the police station...
- and used the telephone.
- That's where you're wrong.
They couldn't. Could they, Tom?
- No.
- Why not?
Because Tom went in there
himself and cut the wire.
Didn't you, Tom?
Well, you went in there
yourself, didn't you?
- Yes.
- And you cut the wire, didn't you?
Yes.
Well, what do you say now?
Nothing.
Take her out.
No, you're taking her nowhere.
Stop it!
- Informer.
- There she is!
Hold him.
Take him by the hands.
Quiet! Get back!
Get back!
Do it.
Princess...
What is it?
There she is.
Look here, Father Hugh, the
stripping of her was an accident.
Steady, Joe.
You're taking advantage
of your cloth, Father Hugh.
- That's what it's for.
- Come on, Joe.
It's not right. A
priest is only a man.
Go on.
Go on, Michael, get off.
Get off out of it!
Hello.
Keep it.
What?
They really thought...
I was the one who betrayed that man.
Rose...
I don't for one moment suppose
that anyone betrayed him.
Why should they? They just...
They just wanted it so, that's all.
And they wanted it to be you, too.
For other reasons.
Truth was told, they envy
you. They always have.
They've always had a rare,
old contempt for me, too.
I tell you, I'm not for letting any
of that lot know we've busted up.
We'll just keep up a front
until I'm well and out of it.
What?
I don't know.
It just seemed funny, that's all.
Michael, give that to me.
All right, keep it.
I thought we were friends.
That one, too. Give it to me.
No! Look.
For Christ's sake, man,
I'm not going to hurt you.
- It'll be the soldiers.
- Soldiers?
Aye.
The beach was fairly littered with
stuff. They'll be destroying it.
Oh, yes.
Come on, lads, pick them up.
What about my blisters, Corporal?
- Well, they're not mourning long.
- No.
Does she think he killed
himself deliberate?
She says...
I think he was a man who
suffered, Father Hugh.
You love her sorely,
don't you, Charles?
Yes.
- Ready, then?
- Yes.
It's not all your doing, Rosy.
I should not have married you.
No.
You can tell Father Hugh that
we're parting if you like.
No.
- Rosy.
- Father.
It'll be a fair day for
the journey, yet, I think.
I hope so, yes.
Well, now, how shall we manage?
Margaret.
Come here, Margaret. Come here.
Kathy, come in.
Kathy, will I take the belt to you?
Take my arm.
A rousing sendoff.
We'll be out of it in five minutes.
Dad.
Goodbye, Dad.
Bye, princess.
I'm all right.
- Are you, darling?
- Aye.
I'm looking forward
to Dublin and that.
Really.
That's your mother speaking.
- Do you remember your mother, Rose?
- A bit.
Do you, like...
- remember the rows?
- Aye.
- I never raised a fist to her, Rose.
- I know that, Dad.
You wouldn't hurt a fly
if you could help it.
- I'll write to you.
- And I'll write to you.
- Well, maybe.
- No. I swear to God, Rose.
- I will write every...
Every... All right, Dad.
We'll both write regular.
Bye-bye.
Well, wait a minute, I must
say goodbye to your husband.
You know, Rose...
when you married him, I thought
you could have done a lot better.
Now I'm not so sure
they come much better.
Would you tell him that?
It's not a thing one fellow
can easily say to another.
Shaughnessy.
Mike.
Goodbye, Shaughnessy.
Goodbye, Mr. Ryan.
Are you all right for money,
you two? I have a bit by me.
We're fine for money,
Dad. Thanks. Goodbye.
Good luck.
- Get out and don't come back!
- Get out!
Informer.
Bus will be here in a minute.
It's brightened for you, like I said.
Aye.
Grand day for a journey.
Sign of good luck.
Thanks.
Bus is coming.
You won't have an address
in Dublin yet, I suppose.
No, Father, we...
I've wrote down here the name
and address of a decent woman...
who'll ask six shillings a week
for a dry room and a clean bed.
Six shillings, the pair of you.
You'll not do better
than that, not in Dublin.
No, I don't suppose so.
Thanks, Father.
Bye, Michael.
I have a parting gift
for you here, Rose.
It's supposed to be a fragment
of St. Patrick's staff.
I don't suppose it is, though.
God bless you, child.
Come on, now. Come on, get on up.
I'll help you load up.
Thanks, Father. Thanks
for a great many things.
Charles?
I think you have it in your mind
that you and Rosy ought to part.
Yes, I thought as much.
Well, maybe you're right,
maybe you ought, but I doubt it.
And that's my parting
gift to you. That doubt.
God bless.
I don't know.
I don't know at all. Come on, Michael.