Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull
In the last years
of the Shang Dynasty,
Emperor Zhou
became a fatuous tyrant.
Seeing an opportunity,
The Fox Devil, Nine Tailed,
transformed herself into Daji,
the Royal Consort
and took control
of the government.
The Fox clan brought chaos
to the world.
Heaven took pity on the people.
When at last
they rebelled,
the Master of Jingxu Hall
sent divine reinforcement.
Thus the Three Realms
were engulfed in war.
Jingxu Hall's
foremost disciple, Jiang Ziya,
set forth to vanquish Nine
Tailed once and for all.
My love, what have you done?
Where are you?
Enough! Stop this at once!
Jiang Ziya.
Aah...
Your illusions
do not frighten me, Fox Devil!
We have the same goal,
do we not?
Must we quarrel
over a single, pitiful dynasty?
It is mankind's destiny
to serve the Fox Clan forever!
I invoke the Suppressing Seal!
Malignant spirits.
Be vanquished!
The war came to an end.
For its victory
over Emperor Zhou,
Jingxu Hall was lauded.
The Revered Master bequeathed
unto the people gods
tasked with the protection
of all living things.
With the rise of a new Dynasty,
there was much
to be done.
Those loyal to the old order
were banished
to the icy ruins of Beihai,
never to return.
For his role in
the triumph,
Jiang Ziya
was celebrated far and wide.
It was thought
he would lead the new gods.
And yet...
What'd I say?
Why is that rock shaped
so weird?
When's the last time you've
ever seen a rock around here?
I'm gonna take a look.
Freeze!
Things aren't... Whoa!
Uh...
Ugh...
That's no rock.
It's one of the Immortals.
- Immortals?
Behold. Following the Great War,
Jingxu Hall let down
a stairway to heaven
and invited mankind to ascend.
The first person to climb it
was none other than
Jiang Ziya himself.
That's how he became a god.
I have completed the mission
given to me.
Jiang Ziya.
The Fox Devil you have subdued
cannot be permitted to live.
As the Three Realms look on.
Nine Tailed must be executed.
By you.
With this act
shall you secure your place
as leader of the gods.
As you are
a servant of the people,
so shall the disciples
of Jingxu Hall be yours
to command
in upholding Heaven's will.
Then so it is done.
Kill her!
- Kill her!
Kill!
Nine Tailed.
These illusions are fruitless.
Your fate is sealed.
This is how you end.
So loyal.
What right does your Master have
to presume the will of Heaven?
He has saved mankind
from your evildoing.
Has he indeed?
Uh...
Very well.
Why does he not move
to save her?
Who is that?
You know nothing of the truth.
This girl, she's...
Jiang Ziya!
Do not let her sow the seeds
of doubt in your mind!
Kill her!
Prepare to meet your end!
Kill!
Look out!
Her sorcery!
Resist the illusion! Stay pure!
See me! Take off the mask!
Huh?
Mark my words,
you will be executed!
If I die,
she dies.
Save me.
Master, there is an innocent
in her clutches!
Huh! No, wait!
Let her go!
Uh...
Come on! Get it together!
It's been long enough!
I want to go home!
You have undone
the seal. You must be punished.
But I saw an innocent spirit
within Nine Tailed.
Silence!
What you saw
was a conjuring trick!
But is seemed so...
Were Nine Tailed
loose in the mortal realm...
The devastations
of the great war
would have been for naught.
Fortunately,
the Fox Devil has been executed.
But you are hereby
banished from Jingxu Hall!
I know what I saw.
Jiang Ziya.
Master.
I have no choice
but to seal your divine power
and exile you to Beihai
until such time as you
are no longer in thrall
to this wicked illusion.
Only then may you return.
This job stinks.
Emperor Zhou gets to be
the God of Marriage, but me?
I'm stuck looking after you.
I'm a baby sitter!
Ah! Four-Alike?
No! That's for the three of us
to share!
Oh, I see how it is!
You wanna bite me! Fine!
Huh!
With a straight hook?
This fish is as dumb as you are.
What... Oh!
You've got to be kidding me.
Unbelievable.
Look at you.
They get to go home, meanwhile
we're rooted to the spot!
I'll do it!
Uh... Wha...
I'll break this thing
into splinters!
Don't test me! Humph!
Stop!
Do you want to go back
to Jingxu Hall or not?
Come on!
It was all in your head!
Um... Nine Tailed
played a trick on you.
It's like that saying
about flies only going
for cracked eggs.
Not that I'm, you know, calling
you an egg or anything...
- Go home.
- Huh?
You deserve better.
It's been ten years.
This is my punishment.
Ugh...
You're a damn fool.
If it weren't
for the Master's orders,
I'd be long gone.
Four-Alike.
Huh?
I've got one eye.
Two big mouths.
Three whole arms.
And four legs!
You lose!
Look at these beauties!
- What?
- Drink!
Bunch of morons.
What? You filthy urchin!
- Mommy! He's bullying me!
- Get back here!
Which one of you lowlifes
is picking on my child?
I'll rip you apart!
Excuse me?
Oh, oh... Oh.
Hot! Hot! Hot! Hot! Hot!
It burns!
Stinking devils
always causing trouble.
Confiscate their weapons!
Cowards! Nine Tailed would'a
killed ya if you hadn't fled!
She'd have taken you lot first!
She can smell fear!
Says the one who reeks of it!
Jiang Ziya?
Why is he here?
Killjoy.
Hmm... Huh...
Oh-oh!
If it isn't
the big shot immortal
who got us all
imprisoned here! Huh?
Excuse me.
Humph. Well, hey!
At least
we're all in this together.
Gotta be worse for you, though!
Scum of the Three Realms
ousted from Jingxu Hall!
Oh, that's a good one!
The scum of the Three Realms!
- Scum!
- You hear that?
So what if you won the war?
You're still
stuck here with all of us!
Barkeep. How much for rice?
My, my.
What a rare treat this is.
Beihai is on a barter system.
The Whip of the Gods
would suffice!
- What about this?
- Hmm...
Kunlun moire.
Your, associate Shen Gongbao
was here earlier,
weeping himself silly.
Ah. Poor fellow.
Forced to trade his earring.
Did you two have a spat?
Oh now, don't take it to heart.
Ha!
Life squeezes us
one way or another.
Get over it and move on,
or lay down arms
and accept defeat.
Sometimes,
the only thing standing
between us and what we want
is admitting we're wrong.
What you saw
was a conjuring trick!
Well. Someone
likes making an entrance.
Step aside.
You're a new face.
Tell me, girl, are you looking
for someone in particular
or just trouble?
Just trouble.
Is that a fact?
Okay, okay! You win!
She's good.
Strong little one, eh?
Huh?
I'm looking for a place.
It's her.
Yeah? And what "place"
might that be, missy?
Somewhere very unique.
Where the black flowers bloom.
Black flowers?
Yeah, sorry. Not ringin' a bell.
You seen anything
like that before?
Interesting. There is only one
such place in the Three Realms.
Mount Youdu,
the traveler's despair!
You know what I'm talking about?
Where is it? Tell me!
- Hmm.
- Don't smirk. I know the score.
Youdu was once
a sacred mountain
not so long ago.
It's where Emperor Zhou
was given the title
"God of Marriage".
Oh, how times have changed.
Strange things are afoot.
Black flowers thrive unchecked
along the mountainside,
hiding the path.
All who search for it
miss the mark.
Ah, but lucky for you
I just so happen to have a map.
And of course,
much more besides.
I trade in rare beasts,
souvenirs, travel essentials...
Everything!
Yes.
There sits Mount Youdu,
in all its glory!
- Let me see!
- Not so fast!
Just the other day, a group
of downtrodden fox hunters
tried to haggle for this item.
If one credits their word,
the mountain is haunted,
by Fox Devils!
But.. weren't they driven
to extinction?
If the Fox Devils have returned,
the Three Realms
will be thrown into chaos!
Such a young thing you are.
What business can you have
with so frightful a place?
That's none of your concern.
Is the map for sale or isn't it?
I appreciate your fire.
But the first rule
of negotiation dictates
that all goods
are subject to inspection!
You stay out of this!
What sort of
despicable operation are you...
You tried to trick me!
Meddler.
What are you doing?
Grab the wretch!
What the?
My inventory!
My Jingxu divination stone!
No! Wait!
That's immortal wine!
I've been saving it for years!
You don't say? Well, then...
It's worth sharing!
Huh?
- Hey!
- Wait I don't...
Someone stop her!
Hands off!
I'll offer a reward!
The map!
- Someone catch it!
- Get the wine!
That's a good boy.
Just hand me the map.
No, no, no!
- Spit it out!
- What are you...
- waiting for? Take her down!
- Spit it out right now!
Kill her if you have to!
Leave her be!
Ugh! Very well!
I'll do it myself!
Fox!
Devil!
If we hand her over
to Jingxu Hall,
we're as good as freed!
None of you get in my way!
Be careful!
They'll want the head intact!
Down there!
I see her!
Don't let her get away!
Hurry!
Huh?
Where do you think you're going?
- Stop!
- Huh?
What is...
Who are you?
Jiang Ziya! Slow down!
You're about to cross
the boundary!
Good thing I can keep up.
If you'd left Beihai,
you'd be in defiance
of the Master.
And that would be bad.
Really, really bad.
Look, all that stuff
I said earlier.
I'm just trying to help!
Hey, whoa! Whoa! Don't do it!
I can only return
to Jingxu Hall...
by first uncovering the truth.
Huh? Please! Be reasonable!
Ah! He's starved.
He's not thinking clearly.
Uh... Okay.
If I have to cross,
then so be...
Jiang Ziya's out of his mind.
It's freezing. Get him inside.
Ha! He's in league
with the Fox Devil!
Huh?
Huh!
Who are you?
Give that back!
Speak. What is your connection
to Nine Tailed?
How far the mighty Jiang Ziya
has fallen.
Treating an innocent little girl
like a common hoodlum.
- Oh, save it!
- Murderer!
So much for being an immortal.
Are all of you
this unreasonable?
If anyone's connected
to the Fox Devil, it's you.
So that bracelet?
- Is none of your business!
- It belonged to Nine Tailed.
Why are you wearing it?
What are you talking about?
It belongs to me!
Stop!
Nine Tailed!
No!
Spirit-taming fires, rise!
What were those?
What do they want with you?
Excellent question.
How the hell should I know?
They've been after me
from the moment I woke up.
There's more every time.
I'm guessing
it has to do with my past.
I don't really know.
The only clue is this bracelet,
and the memory of black flowers.
Mount Youdu.
Sometimes I can see my father.
Waiting for me.
He can prove I'm not a devil!
Do not let her sow
the seeds of doubt.
You're coming with me
to Jingxu Hall!
Are you listening?
I have to find my father!
He has saved
mankind from your evildoing.
You know nothing of the truth.
I have no choice but to seal
your divine power
and exile you to Beihai
until such time as you
are no longer in thrall
to this wicked illusion.
What is this?
Who are you?
Very well.
Let's go.
Where?
To Mount Youdu.
Wait, are you serious?
Yes. Are you afraid?
A-Afraid?
What kind of question is that?
And don't act all high
and mighty, it's my map!
Hey, wait up!
That hasn't healed yet?
I have something
that might help.
My secret recipe!
It's yours. If you give me
a peek at the map.
I thought we were friends!
I wasn't aware
we'd graduated to that.
Whatever,
it's only a matter of time.
We just have
to get to know each other.
Good idea.
- Let's start with you.
- Huh?
You're not an immortal.
So how did you cross
into Beihai?
Uh...
That's kind of personal.
- Are you normally this blunt?
- Uh...
Why I should even trust you?
You're dressed like a vagrant.
A desperate vagrant.
For all I know
you see me as a bounty.
Huh?
Ah!
And you see me as a mark.
Uh, wait!
Okay, okay, okay.
You're so arrogant! That tone.
Four-Alike, that's enough.
Four-Alike?
So this is
the legendary creature
said to move with such grace?
Fearsome? Big as the night sky?
Makes men tremble?
How adorable.
Don't antagonize.
It left Jingxu Hall
on my account.
Oh sure.
Sounds like a reasonable story.
Or maybe it just
couldn't cut it in Heaven.
Give that back! I was kidding!
Four-Alike!
Hey, tough guy! How 'bout
you control your pet?
Ugh! I'll slap a muzzle
on that face!
Get back here!
All right, fun's over!
Don't you even!
Those are mine!
Four-Alike!
Ugh! When I get my hands on you!
Is that all immortals
really are?
A bunch of glorified thieves?
First the map, now my biscuits.
Huh?
Stop.
Ugh! It's just
a stupid wind chime.
They're all over the place.
Spirits are supposed
to be comforted
by the sound of bones rattling.
Something like that, anyway.
Like a consolation prize
for being dead.
Huh?
These are messages
from their loved ones.
A connection to life.
They're a comfort
to the living and the dead.
The war is over.
The Fox Clan has been defeated.
The world is healing.
Rest in peace, all of you.
Sentimental crap if you ask me.
Ugh. That sedative
knocked me out cold.
Okay. Where's
the stubborn bastard gone to?
He's hurt? Of course, he is!
Damn it!
"The Field
of the Undying is known
far and wide
for its trees that don't die,
flowers that don't wilt,
and springs that don't run dry."
Charming place.
Blame it on the Great War.
Everything changed.
You know,
if the heat's getting to you,
I'm more than happy to navigate.
Thank you, no.
Get away!
I don't have any food left!
Uh, huh?
Cut
her ears off!
Uh...
Water. I need water.
You can't do anything for him.
There's barely enough for you.
I'm not letting him die.
That's all there is to it.
Let go! Stop it!
He doesn't deserve saving!
Fox!
The man's a fox hunter.
He only sees me as game.
Who came to my rescue
when they tried
to cut off my ears?
Whatever he is,
he hasn't harmed you!
Just give him the chance!
- Don't!
- Fine!
Have it your way!
Follow her.
Calm yourself.
I only mean to help.
Hear me, Five Emperors.
Ye benevolent powers
that govern the body,
heed my command and heal this...
The fox is mine,
do you understand me?
You can find your own
on Mount Youdu.
Fox Devil.
Damn your trickery.
Mount Youdu it is.
Once upon a time,
there was an immortal
from Heaven.
Sadly, without his map,
there wasn't
a whole lot he could do. Huh?
Ravens.
You guys always assume
you're in charge.
Till I snap your necks!
Help!
I want to go home!
What the...
Well, okay then...
What is this thing?
Move!
Get out of here!
- Uh...
- Take Four-Alike! Go!
Ha! Whoa! Come back!
Idiots.
I told her
to get you out of here!
Stupid mutt!
What are you doing?
Quickly, give me the whip!
- I'm trying!
- Look out!
Oh no!
The wind chime.
Give it the wind chime.
Those things, were they human?
At one time.
Huh?
They're lost souls.
Those who left home.
Died on the battlefield.
No graves. No friends or family.
No hope of finding
their way back.
No way home? That's awful.
Blame the Great War.
Will they be
trapped here forever?
Quite possibly.
There's some hope
for them, though.
The Swallow.
A great beast said
to traverse the sky
when moved by human grief.
When
moved by human grief.
Jiu.
You okay?
I have a home and a family.
My father's waiting.
- I'll find him.
- Huh?
This will be able
to calm your wound.
The map.
What'll we do without it?
Silly creature.
Yeah, you're pretty cute.
Ha!
Uh...
Father...
Get inside.
Devil.
He's only a child!
Fox Devil! Get her!
Don't let her get away!
Give him the knife.
Let him do it.
Cut her ears off!
A nightmare?
"May you sleep
the sleep of the just..."
That's the most practical chant
I've ever heard.
Is it like a traditional one?
It's not exactly a chant.
It's from the Great War.
Soldiers used to say it
before bed.
The Great War.
Was Four-Alike part of it?
The last time we were here,
all this was ocean.
Four-Alike crossed it
with a single step
and shattered enemy ranks.
Vanquish Nine Tailed,
and the world would be restored.
At least that's what
we all told ourselves.
But it didn't work out that way.
The world just fell
into greater ruin.
You think this place had it bad.
You should see where I'm from.
Uh, of course, I'm kidding.
Actually, I bet
you'll think it's beautiful.
So, you know, worth the journey.
What are the odds
your father is still there?
Uh...
Really wish I could tell you.
I haven't been able
to remember anything.
Not since waking up
in the desert.
I dream, though.
About this doll he made.
A little thing.
All strung with stones.
Just clinking away
in the breeze.
It was like a windchime.
Calling me home.
Whenever I'd sneak away,
he'd hang it above
the front door.
The wind would pick up.
And I'd follow the sound back.
Jiu.
In the dream
that's what he calls me.
And the place
where the black flowers bloom?
That's where he's waiting.
It's not just a dream.
It's real.
My whole purpose in life.
You better believe
I'll find him.
Huh...
It's the Swallow.
The restless souls
have been called home.
The Swallow has given them hope.
Shall we go?
According to the map
the tail of the Milky Way
points to Mount Youdu.
Now we're friends.
Eat up, you'll need it.
Impressive memory.
Stop sniffing at me.
I don't have any more biscuits.
Except that one!
That one's mine!
Give it back! Ugh!
"When you
see the Stone Forest,
follow Heishui upstream."
The entrance to Mount Youdu
must be up ahead.
Are you sure?
All I see is a bunch of rocks.
And dirt.
I'm sure.
There's more here
than meets the eye.
Black flowers?
We've gotta be close!
Watch out!
Jiang Ziya!
Where the hell
do you think you're going?
You can't just leave Beihai!
Rules are rules!
Rules you've now broken too.
I had no choice! The Fox Devil
was making an idiot of you!
- Let's go back before...
- I can't go back yet.
Wha...
I, uh, think you're buddy's
about to explode.
Jiang Ziya!
Your face.
That wound should've healed!
C'mon, your powers
are dwindling.
Damn it.
Do you wanna die out here?
I will return to Beihai...
when I have uncovered the truth.
Truth about what?
She's the girl I found
in Nine Tailed clutches.
I have to know who she is.
Huh?
Uh... This is her?
- Why are you so an...
- Speak!
- Put her down!
- What are you?
You've been possessed.
Let go! I don't have
to tell you anything!
Stubborn, aren't we?
- Show me your true form!
- Shen Gongbao!
Four-Alike!
Huh?
- Get back here?
- Stop!
Four-Alike. Where are you?
Four-Alike!
Huh...
Uh...
- Uh?
- Over here.
This way.
Father?
Is that you?
Father!
Use your head.
How many lives
did the Fox Devil destroy?
If the truth is so important
to you, open your eyes!
- Things aren't what they seem!
- Bullshit!
We've been down
this road before!
You are hopeless!
That which is inescapable
we call fate.
That which is unbreakable
we call love.
Father, is that you?
"Father?"
Foolish child,
I am not your father.
- Humph. Who are you?
- Ooh, what a question!
I bind the fates
of mortals together.
I am the God of Marriage!
You're deranged! Untie me!
As you wish.
Your face
is so exquisitely familiar.
Uh, ah...
The Lock of Destiny?
You recognize my bracelet?
How could I not?
It isn't a bracelet.
See. It's a very powerful lock.
What?
It binds two spirits together
inexorably.
If one should perish,
then so shall the other!
My beloved consort
wore the companion
to this very lock on her person,
which can only mean
the two of you
are bound together eternally!
When the chain materializes,
I'll be able to find her again!
Materialize, my love!
Jiu!
Don't you run away from me!
Where are you? Come to me!
Son of a... Why do you keep
making the same mistakes?
You're the Fox Devil
that cost my beloved her life!
Jiu!
Look out!
- Sorcery.
- You see it now?
It's her. She's...
Why?
Why murder the woman
I cherished?
Why destroy my kingdom?
She did this.
It's all her doing.
What you see is evil incarnate.
Kill her.
No one is waiting
for you anywhere.
I have to find my father.
Jiu!
Stop!
Kill her!
No. If she dies so will my love!
Aah...
Jiang Ziya.
How long has it been?
Nine Tailed.
It's you. Didn't the holy device
behead you?
Jiang Ziya saved me.
Let her go!
Release her!
Ha!
My mortal body
was indeed beheaded.
But as long as my spirit endures
taking physical form is simple!
Enough! Foul sorceress!
No one cares!
Where did this precious kitty
come from?
Watch out!
Ten short years.
That's all it's taken for you
to sink this low, Jiang Ziya.
How utterly heartbreaking.
Don't you find that sad?
Jiu?
Oh, forgive me.
I should call you Su Daji.
My beloved.
Behold.
The Zu family's eldest daughter.
Betrothed to Emperor Zhou.
Such a simple human girl.
- Wha...
- Hmm...
What have you done
with my father?
Think carefully, child.
The memory will come to you.
Is that you?
Uh... Father, what?
Go.
I crept into
your ceremonial carriage
and took your shape for my own.
And I becamethe Emperor's
cherished consort.
And yet...
This lock was meant
to tether you.
Binding you to me forever.
Your spirit is strong.
It escaped, taking with it
your former body and
a small measure of my power.
And now? You must return!
Stop!
Cursed feline!
Hiya!
Master?
Alas,
a lock forged
by the Revered Master
is not for the likes
of you to break.
My Power.
My Power!
Shit! Her power's coming back!
Master.
The truth...
- I have to know.
- Don't listen!
She wants to confuse you!
Don't give credence to her lies!
You dare call me a liar?
Heaven is meant
to protect all living things.
Have you any notion
of the atrocities committed
by your Revered Master?
Shen Gongbao!
That said.
If not for Jiang Ziya's kindness
toward one in peril,
never would I have had
the opportunity to break free.
It's a pity you're so mired
that truth eludes you.
- Let them go.
- Don't despair, child.
I won't kill you.
Jiu!
Four-Alike!
Conceal.
- The lock!
- Run!
You're not going anywhere!
Faster!
The lock remains!
You cannot hope to save her!
There is no escape!
The Fox Clan will rise again!
- You were right.
- Huh?
No one's...
waiting for me.
Four-Alike, what's wrong!
Watch out!
Jiu!
Four-Alike!
Huh... No.
Eight Effulgences
of the Three Regions,
heed my command.
Eight Effulgences
of the Three Regions,
heed my command.
Eight Effulgences
of the Three Regions,
heed my command.
Eight Effulgences...
Just hold on.
What's happening?
Four-Alike.
Fore-Alike.
Where are you?
There you are.
My love.
What is the world coming to,
when even
you can become a deity?
Return her to me.
Your consort is as dead
as your legacy.
Farewell.
All these years...
people thought
you were bewitched.
In the end,
we were the fools.
Jingxu Hall
will eliminate Nine Tailed.
But if the Lock of Destiny
isn't broken.
If Nine Tailed dies,
she'll die, too, Won't she?
I don't get it.
If the Master forged it
with his own hands,
what are we supposed to do?
What do we even believe?
Why don't we go to the source?
I'll speak with him myself
and have the lock undone.
Appear!
They won't lower the stairway
for you anymore.
Wait.
It's too costly!
You're not alone in this.
Go to them.
Find the answer!
I seek the Revered Master.
Presumption.
You were ordered
to contemplate your errors.
And instead, you chose to leave.
You should be punished.
Which I accept willingly.
But Nine Tailed lives.
Her spirit tied to an innocent.
The master knows the truth!
Silence!
You may not pass!
If he has nothing to hide
then why
will he not speak to me?
How dare you!
Did you fasten
the Lock of Destiny?
Does Nine Tailed
share your blood?
Is this the way of Heaven?
Would you sacrifice a child?
Master.
Jiang Ziya.
Everything Jingxu Hall does,
it does with the sole aim
of protecting life.
Tell me, please.
Why would you have me believe
what I saw was a mere illusion?
Because the scope
of your understanding is small.
Your heart is kind.
But your compassion, scattered.
Your sense
of the greater good is skewed.
I ordered you
to execute Nine Tailed.
Not to crush evil, but kindness.
Crush kindness?
But,
what is wrong with kindness?
In itself, nothing.
But, alas, for gods...
Kindness shown
to one person only is a sin.
One day there will come a time
when a god
must sacrifice one to save all.
Jiang Ziya must return
to Beihai immediately.
Once his mind
is free of illusion.
He may return
to his rightful place
as leader of the gods
and protector
of the Three Realms.
If I fail to save one life,
how can I save all?
Insolence!
You would put
one life above all else?
They're all connected.
Like drops of water.
Life is an ocean. In my eyes,
Jiu, and all living things,
are one and the same.
The great war ripped untold
soldiers from home and family.
I'm ashamed of my role.
I no longer want to be a god.
To have power.
All I want
is to save whoever I'm able.
I see. You are certain of this?
Once the Lock of Destiny
is fastened
it cannot be undone
in the same lifetime.
The only answer...
Is reincarnation.
Escort Su Daji
to the Ruins of Return.
Let her step into the light
and be reborn.
Thank you, Revered Master.
Is this it?
Nine Tailed! Run!
Go without me.
Shen.
- I...
- Just go.
Do what has to be done.
Save her...
and come home.
Of course.
Uh...
Don't
you want to be a god?
No. Go on.
You've stood by me long enough.
Report back to
the master.
- Ugh.
- Do as I say.
I came here
without his permission...
Jiang Ziya.
I used to be so jealous.
You were the Master's favorite.
Everyone loved you.
But I get it now.
You didn't become a hero.
You've always been one.
But this time...
it's my turn.
Jiang Ziya.
Yes?
Where are you taking us?
To break the lock.
You're going to be reborn.
Reborn as what?
How do you like that?
I'm right back
at where I started.
Empty-handed.
When I opened by eyes
all I could see were ruins.
Whoever I met.
Just wanted to hurt me.
I tried to tell them...
I said I wasn't a Fox Devil.
But they wouldn't believe me.
In the next life
you'll be
a perfectly ordinary child.
With friends.
Family.
A father who loves
and cares for you.
Don't do that.
Don't fill my head with lies.
I'd never do that.
Goodbye.
Huh.
Jiang Ziya.
Thank you...
Damn you, Nine Tailed.
Let it be finished!
The lock has been broken.
She is no longer bound to you.
Let her...
be reborn!
Reborn?
You're insane!
Surely you didn't think
I would release her so easily?
Stop this!
The world must know.
People must see what
the Revered Master has done!
Arise, my fox brethren!
Why the hell
is my eye twitching?
I've had two drinks. Maybe.
It's a sign of good fortune!
What the?
Behold.
These are my fox brethren.
Thousands of them!
Why are their souls restless?
Years ago
the Master made a promise.
He told me I would become a god.
But there was a price.
I had to bind
the Fox Clan to mortals
and launch a war that
would unite the Three Realms.
Little did we know.
When all was said and done
the master reneged our bargain.
He ordered our genocide.
We were thrown
into the bottomless pit.
Never again to see the light.
- Never to be reborn.
- Oh...
We were the true casualties
of the Revered Master's
ultimate war.
I believed him.
In a moment of greed,
I doomed my own kind!
This cannot be.
Today,
the Revered Master
shall know the pain
he wreaked upon the Fox Clan.
The Three Realms will tremble
at the sight of our true power!
Ah! Jiu!
Release me from this prison!
Kill her!
Undo the lock.
Jiu!
Whoa! Jiu!
Revered Master.
We beg you to reconsider!
What I do,
I do for the greater good.
Jiu. I won't.
As long
as the Lock of Destiny exists,
you cannot save anyone.
In times to come,
others will repeat our mistake.
When I'm reborn,
will I really have a father
who loves me?
No one
should be denied salvation.
Not gods.
Not devils. Not mortals.
We all deserve to live free
from the yoke of oppression.
We all deserve the truth.
The lock has been undone.
Father, Mother.
Can we go home now?
- Save me.
- Release me from this hell.
Jiu!
Ah...
Jiang Ziya.
Have I been reborn yet?
Don't do that.
Don't fill my
head with lies.
Head Disciple Jiang Ziya
has achieved merit by luring out
and vanquishing
the Fox Devil once and for all.
He may now reclaim his place
as leader of the gods.
One lock remains to be severed.
I, Jiang Ziya, herby vow
to follow the Master.
In everything.
To lead the gods,
and protect all life.
To become a true god.
Stand apart.
Forge your own path.
The Grand Duke has ascended.
All deities, fall back.
Approach, Jiang Ziya.
Kneel before heaven
to be cleansed and deified.
Kneel!
Impudence!
There was no choice.
The Fox Devil was pure evil.
Search your heart. My actions
were a gift to the world.
Henceforth,
may no one lose their home.
May no one
be deceived.
Let injustice...
be a thing of the past!
You've gone mad!
If the stairway crumbles,
the world shall be cut off
from divine protection!
What have you done?
And so,
Jiang Ziya
demolished the Stairway
and the Revered Master
was punished by Heaven.
The Swallow descended
and guided restless souls home.
Once again, the world saw peace
and hope restored.
When I grow up, I want
to be a hero just like that!
Master. Where does
the Swallow come from?
Where indeed? A place
far above even Jingxu Hall.
In the great beyond.
Where your master's
master dwells.
Wow. So the master's
master is the Revered Master.
And the Revered Master's
master is...
Great Revered Master!
Hush!
His name isn't for you to say.
He is the great deity far above
the Ninth Heaven
and sends the Swallow to earth.
Jiang Ziya sure is amazing!
Even the Great Revered Master
lent him a hand.
As expected of my "good friend."
Your good friend?
You can search all of Beihai
and find no one closer
to Jiang Ziya than me!
Cut the crap.
Your only good friend is drink.
Hard to believe
Beihai is finally at peace.
A bite of biscuit
A bite of sweets
Outside Beihai
Yellow fields
of wheat
Mother and Father
Sitting by my side
Humming a tune As I
drift into a dreamland
What are those
hanging from the tree?
What a pretty sound!
I want one for my doll too!
Hmm.
Speaking of Jiang Ziya,
where exactly
has he gone?
Far outside
the Three Realms.
To a place known
as the City of Tribulation,
is said to be a prison
built expressly for gods
of his stature.
My Lord...
the Great Revered Master
sends us...
We've been order
to take up posts.
PLEASE WAIT,
THERE'S A POST-CREDITS SCENE!
THANK YOU EVERYONE FOR WAITING!
LET'S MAKE UP
FOR THE YEAR TOGETHER!
Huh!
Humph.
Ugh.
Ugh...
Uh...
Mm...
Mm-hm.
Huh? Uh, huh...
May you live long!
May we meet again
when the storm has passed.
Wishing you peace
and good fortune
in the times ahead.
ONE WAR TO DEIFICATION
Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull