Directed by Ning Hao
A BEIJING GOOD PERSON
Sir, please stop sending
us disposable slippers.
Those are employee benefits from my hotel,
they are free.
You've been consulting with me
for two years,like I said,
you can be a part-time taxi driver
anytime as long as you buy a car.
Sure, I'm just telling you now
I've saved enough money for the car.
Well, good for you.
And I'm prepared to become
a fancy chauffeur.
I just need your approval.
Bring your car and get the paperwork
done then.
Just a sec.
I didn't order food.
I did, Erdan.
-- Who are you?
-- I'm your cousin.
Cousin?
Come on in. It's alright.
-- You're all grown up.
-- You're painting walls?
I felt it.
About the size of an egg.
If I had had it removed when it was
much smaller,
it would cost me 20 thousand, at tops.
Now, since it involves vascular
penetration,
the procedure will cost 70 to 80 thousand.
I heard that
thyroid tumors are not lethal.
Maybe the tumor won't kill me
but the money sure will.
You don't say.
It's about the cost of a car.
Erdan, you're buying a car?
I was just browsing randomly.
I thought you were gonna make a withdrawal.
I was cleaning things up. It's expired.
Erdan.
I haven't come visit you
since I came to Beijing.
And here on my first visit,
I'm borrowing money from you.
You don't have to come visit.
I'm fine.
Zhang Beijing, time to take
your medication.
What are you taking medicine for?
Same old problem.
Hypertension.
It must've cost you a lot.
I have state health insurance,
my employer paid for it.
Sorry I wasn't much of a help.
-- Take this with you.
-- No, no, no.
I came to ask you for a favor,
how could I take your stuff?
-- It's not right.
-- Please, it's the least I can do.
Okay, then...oh, I almost forgot.
This is for you.
It was your favorite. When we
were kids, we used to
fight over this,
and you made me cry every time.
Erdan, this hypertension thing.
You should take it more seriously.
Beijing is such a huge city.
Who knows when we will meet again?
You're not crying, are you?
We can see each other anytime.
I'm alright. It's the damn tumor.
It gets me edgy.
Cheer up, we'll figure something out.
Okay..
You should go back now. I'm out of here.
-- Take care.
-- Sure.
Hello, sir.
Could you please wait a bit longer?
I'm running a little late.
Please don't give me a bad review.
Son, I heard this ride-hailing thing
pays a lot, eh?
It's not bad. Thanks.
What a wonderful young man.
That'll work.
Yeah.
-- Is it open?
-- Yes.
Is it open?
Yes.
Because of the card or you?
The card.
A clean shave,
and you'll look just like me.
-- Not really.
-- You're my cousin.
Of course you do.
Erdan.
I've never lied to get anything.
I don't think I can do this.
State health insurance is a social benefit.
It doesn't matter who benefits from it.
Your disease is my disease.
And my card is your card.
It'll work.
No.42, Ma Ke, please go to
consulting room 226.
No.48, Zhang Beijing, please go
to consulting room 225.
Is No.48, Zhang Beijing, here?
Is Zhang Beijing here?
Hey, bro, is that you?
Are you Zhang Beijing?
Yeah.
This way.
Hold on.
Come back here.
Come back.
Is that yours?
That.
No.49, Jia Tianlong,
please go to consulting room 229.
Swallow.
Do you always sweat like this?
It's the disease.
Where are you from?
Bei…
Beijing.
I live in Xili Complex, Hujialou Street,
apartment 7-8.
Why are you lying to me?
What makes you say that?
The accent.
You're obviously from Hengshui.
So am I, and…
wherever we go, bro, we must
not forget where we are from.
You need surgery ASAP.
Go do a blood test first.
Sure.
Are you paying cash
or do you have health insurance?
Insurance.
Your card, please.
Where's my card?
Maybe I should come another day.
Wait.
What's that in your hand?
You're looking for the card
while holding it?
It's all soaked in your sweat.
If I didn't know you have the tumor
I'd say you're using someone else's card.
Zhang Beijing.
You're from Hengshui, bro,
why is your name Zhang Beijing?
It should be Zhang Hengshui.
Right?
Here.
-- What's wrong with your neck?
-- Nothing, it's just numb.
You sure are one interesting fella.
Come here, let me take a look.
-- Turn around.
-- Doctor Cao!
I've found you finally.
You gave me a second life.
I think you've mistaken me
for someone else. I'm not Doctor Cao.
My name is Ning.
I'm thankful anyway, Doctor Ning.
You, doc, are also a life-saver.
You know what? Keep up
the good work here.
I'll go thank Doctor Cao now.
I was looking all over for you,
what happened?
I'm not cut out for this.
Let's just forget it.
Man, you're such a wuss.
You tumor must be bigger than your balls.
You've done well so far.
Now it's just a blood test,
which requires no use of the card.
As long as they don't see it,
who knows which is you
and which is me?
Zhang Beijing!
Lingzi? What are you doing here?
I work here.
Why are you here?
I came for a checkup, with a relative.
The doctor told to me to get a blood test.
Great, you're all mine now.
Follow me.
Hurry up.
Patients trust us with their lives.
The hospital shall repay them
with love and care.
Your disease is my disease.
-- Let me see the order.
-- Order.
Why are you examined for this?
What's wrong with your thyroid?
There's a tumor.
No worries.
You'll live.
What are you guys doing?
It's hunger.
Gets me dizzy.
Help me sit down.
You must have hyperthyroidism, too.
Look how your hand shivers.
Stop it.
Stop it now.
You did like using needles on me
when we were in school.
I got nervous every time I saw you.
That's bullshit.
Always joking around.
You haven't changed a bit.
But your hand sure has.
You're damn right.
What's your skin-care secret?
I look like I could be your dad.
Cut it out.
Make a fist.
Let me make a fist.
I see you're still mocking me.
Now this is gonna sting.
I stung him, what are you groaning for?
He has blood phobia.
You are good.
That didn't hurt at all.
Maybe this is the way it should be
Don't wait till you're an old man
To start seeking the freedom you want
Thanks, boss.
Erdan.
You're the man.
I applaud you.
Just like that, you pulled
this whole thing off.
You're a natural, man.
You should be a movie star.
Once,
Zhang Yimou
came to our hotel to shoot a scene
and he insisted that I should be an extra.
I…
Turned it down.
Acting…
is all about emancipating your true nature.
And that, my friend
simply means
being reckless and shameless.
True story.
You were always the
most shameless man in the village.
You don't even blush when lying.
Here, let's drink to you.
Like you said, I'm a natural.
Now, the first half
was a complete success.
As for the second half,
the surgery part,
I can't do that for you.
But what if I screw up?
You screw up and my
health insurance is gone.
That's why you need…
practice.
Emancipate your true nature.
How?
You there.
Come here.
Come on.
Let him have a go.
No, no, no. I can't sing.
Look at you,
what a textbook loser.
Now let me show you
what emancipation means.
-- Pick any song you like.
-- This one.
-- The Tiger Hunt.
-- Behold the fearless hero!
Cool. Here we go.
This is a tough song.
-- What's that old man doing?
-- Through the forest...
Bravo.
Over the snowfield
My spirit erupts
to the cloud
You can do it, man.
He won't hit the note.
To the cloud
Come on.
You can do it, man.
Stop filming.
Erdan, are you okay?
Don't you scare me like that, cousin.
This is not good.
I need my medicine.
I'm going to faint.
-- Zhang Beijing.
-- Got it.
Did you print that out?
Is it really that hot?
Calm yourself.
Sir, he was here this morning.
Hyperthyroidism caused by thyroid tumor,
triggering hypertension.
We need to bring down the BP first.
Go get the paperwork done.
Be smart. Let's lower his BP.
Play with it all you want, just don't eat.
You're awake.
Group consultation starts in the morning.
Surgery will soon follow.
You just need a good sleep tonight.
Bro, relax.
It's just a thyroidectomy.
No big deal.
Are they blind?
Hey, come quick, this is
getting out of control.
They mistook me for you.
Come here and take my place now.
I kept saying that
and they wouldn't let me in.
Maybe I should come tomorrow.
Tomorrow? They'll cut me
open by then.
Huh?
Let me think of something.
I'm just going to
smoke a cigarette outside.
Go back to your bed.
You can't leave
without the doctor's permission.
I just wanna pee.
I don't now.
Come here...sir, could you come
over here and clean the hall?
Hurry up. Please.
Can I at least answer the phone?
Is this your partner in crime?
You listen to me.
Confess now
you'll beat the other guy to it.
I've told you.
I was there to see someone.
See someone…
Now, look at me
Can't you see who I am?
Sir,
what were you thinking?
Someone from you family got into trouble,
you should help him, yes or no?
Yes.
So, people helping each other,
is that wrong?
Of course not.
If so, then why are bad things
happening to him?
Irritation, typical symptom
of hyperthyroidism.
-- Calm down, please -
-- I am calm.
I just don't get it.
He's a good man,
why should he be the one who suffers?
It's just a minor surgery. And Doctor Mei…
he's so proficient.
-- It'll be gone before you know it.
-- I don't want myself to be gone.
I'm not even Zhang Beijing.
Delusion caused by hyperthyroidism.
Fine.
You're not Zhang Beijing.
You all know I am actually Zhang Beijing
but you're telling me I'm not.
You just don't believe me no matter what.
Sir, we do believe you.
-- Don't we all?
-- You're just saying that,
but you don't meant it.
We all believe you and we mean it.
Sir, have another one.
Hyperthyroidism makes you crave for food.
You're still not believing.
Whatever.
You got anything for hypertension?
I think I'm about to pass out.
Quit touching it.
Your thyroid is fine.
So, what's the story here?
That's enough.
Bring him in.
You two,
what is your relationship?
How did your health insurance card
wind up with him?
He's my…
cou…
What are you talking about?
I don't even know you.
I only took his card,
nothing else.
I was delivering food to his apartment and,
while he wasn't looking,
I just…
took his health insurance card.
I thought…the card is
for people who need treatment
and I'm people, too.
How should I know that he
would need it today?
No, you're not doing this.
Doing what?
Don't interrupt me.
I just couldn't afford
to go to the hospital.
So you think what you did was right?
It's not right.
Just emancipation of true nature.
Yep.
Your health insurance card.
Keep it well.
And I'm sorry.
What are you waiting for?
Take me down-town.
Through the forest
Was that what we talked about last night?
Euphoria caused by hyperthyroidism?
He was euphoric for sure.
You're euphoric.
Thank you, sir. You're a great driver.
I know this car too well.
-- I see! Bye!
-- Bye.
Erdan,
Isn't this the car you were checking out
the other day?
I have just called the precinct,
and you're out already?
The cop was nice.
He said it's merely a failed attempt,
so he just let me off with a warning.
You got lucky.
Now let's go to the hospital.
-- Take this.
-- This is...?
What did you…
I just, um…
paid for your surgery
But…
What about the car?
How do you know I'm buying a car?
I'm your cousin.
I know exactly what you're thinking.
On second thought, this car…
is not that perfect.
When you pay me back in a couple of years,
I'll get
its newest model.
I'd give them some time to upgrade it.
No.
I can't take this.
I read an article online,
this thing can be cured
by eating dandelion.
And we have plenty of that back home.
I'll ask the missus to find
as much as possible.
And I'll eat it every day.
It's all I'll eat for every meal.
That ought to do it.
You do know this is nonrefundable, right?
And you left your motorcycle.
How is it nonrefundable?
The surgery was a success.
That's great news
for all the dandelions in the village.
Now I see.
Can I have a quick look at your card?
You two don't even look remotely alike.
You got some balls pulling such a trick.
Damn, you're right.
How come you have a card, too?
I got it for him.
Cousin,
so you have insurance all along?
What's this? How come I didn't know?
Of course you didn't.
You're not even paying 18 bucks
for a new wok.
Let alone 200 for insurance.
You would never have agreed.
Even putting vinegar in noodles
is a luxury to him.
Checkmate.
-- Does this card work the same as mine?
-- It sure does.
The rural health insurance
works just as well.
Government will take care of the sick.
Are you sure the spending
can be reimbursed?
Right at the Village Council.
What time do they close?
Zhang Beijing.
You really do hate
keeping contact with old classmates.
Why didn't you come to me
for the health insurance problem?
Did you forget you know someone
who works in a hospital?
My hometown is Puning, famous for
its traditional Chinese medicine.
My hometown is Shiyan City, Hubei.
One of the sources for the South-to-North
Water Diversion Project.
Hainan is famous for its durian.
Jiuzhaigou, giant pandas.
My hometown is famous for its apples.
Changchun, the city of cars.
My home is Afu Village in Guizhou.
There's an UFO in our village.
And aliens, too.
It's true.
Not only is the timing perfect,
but the location is even better.
That the UFO would land, of all places,
in Afu Village, South Guizhou.
And it's just 15 kilometers away from FAST
So, even aliens have come
all the way from outer space
to congratulate us.
Maybe they have holidays
during this time, too?
With this smart translation device,
you'll get any hot date you want.
The full moon is best appreciated
from home,
but the best lipsticks come
from alien planets.
Worry not about your pick-up lines
and haggling skills,
I promise, with this lipstick,
even aliens will fall for your appeal.
The aliens would go crazy for you.
An ominous legend popular amidst
the Chinese people says that...
So, what are you waiting for?
Buy! It! Now!
(Director of The Wandering Earth - Guo Fan)
For a spacecraft of such size
to traverse dozens of light years,
(Director of The Wandering Earth - Guo Fan)
Even with a warp drive,
the energy would be too great
for the craft to endure at such speed.
Mr. Guo, speak Chinese, please.
Could there really be UFOs?
Scientifically speaking...
-- ...there is the possibility.
-- Yes!
Except the possibility is close to zero.
It's nearly impossible.
A UFO Falls From The Sky
My dearest fans,
here in the terrace fields
transplanting rice seedlings
is exhausting work,
which causes chronicle lumbar strain.
That's why...I invented this
transplanter robot.
Put the seedling in there.
Alright, it's done.
Isn't it convenient?
Isn't it labor-saving?
Thank you so much for another gift
packet, my baby love knot,
who's truly my biggest fan.
What?
Do another one?
Welcome the "Step Into Science Again"
TV Crew to Afu Village
You guys made it.
-- Hello, Mr. Wang, sir.
-- I'm Qin.
Don't call me sir.
Just Wang is okay.
Wang.
I think I'll stick to sir.
Here, I'd like you to meet the man.
From our film crew,
this is Mr. Tang, chief director,
chief cameraman and chief producer.
Mr. Chief, what an honor.
You're more than welcome here.
I'm Tang.
Chief producer, chief cameraman
and chief director.
Gentlemen, I'd like you
meet someone too.
From our village,
Mr. Wang, the boss man, the big shot
tourism developer.
Who drove his fancy limo
all the way here to pick you up.
He wants nothing
but good publicity for this village.
If you know what I mean.
We came to Guizhou to
investigate the UFO,
not to help you make a commercial.
It's the same thing, don't you think?
-- No, it's not.
-- Of course it is.
Sir? Sir? Everyone's here, let's go.
-- Yeah, let's.
-- No, no, please wait.
Just a sec. Someone else is coming.
-- What are you talking about? Who?
-- Me.
Gentlemen, allow me to introduce
Dong Axue, the child prodigy from CAS,
and also a native of Guizhou.
I've been friends with Mr. Wang for years.
I'm just here to see
what this alien fuss is all about.
That's okay, as long as you
stay out of our investigation.
You're all our guests.
Your presence here will
only bring grace to Afu Village.
-- Amazing grace!
-- Let's go!
-- Come on, hold it up!
-- Up, up!
Stay in line with me.
Come on.
Welcome to the Profound
Province of Guizhou
So much has changed here.
Guizhou used to be known for
bad weather all year long
and inaccessible from all directions.
I certainly don't feel any of that now.
I still remember back in the day
my sister had a thing for this guy
from across the canyon.
Technically, they were just
one kilometer away.
But somehow they broke up
over the distance.
In Southeast Guizhou, there used to be
many villages that were
just one kilometer apart.
But since they had to climb
over a mountain,
people never got to meet each other.
-- That's just the case.
-- Great changes have happened since then.
Now every county is connected to
the superhighway system.
And every town the highway.
Concrete roads lead to every village.
Afu, however, is located so remotely
that we're missing out on
all the perks of development.
That's why we're left behind.
But ever since the UFO came,
it changed everything.
Please.
This way, please.
Mr. Chief, look...hold on guys.
A tourist group!
Now we're in Afu Village, the Alienland
where the UFO first appeared.
You can buy alien-themed souvenirs
over there,
or take pictures with them here.
Then come to the village square by four
for the stage performance,
a fantasy musical.
Alien Love Story.
Business is good.
You betcha.
Some places have mountains,
others have rivers.
We have the UFO,
so we serve alien dishes.
That's ridiculous.
You can't eat aliens.
Please allow me to show you
an invention of mine.
The FAST Sour Fish Hotpot.
With special alien service.
There's nothing else like this
in the entire universe.
See?
Does it look exactly the same
as the FAST telescope?
-- Where's the fish?
-- And the aliens?
Have some soup first.
It'll boost your vigor.
Make you the king of the solar system.
Then you eat the fish,
which is good for your brain,
making you smarter than
the rest of the galaxy.
Roses are red, aliens are blue,
the pot is hot, and so are you.
The FAST Sour Fish Hotpot,
authentic alien flavor.
Come on now. Let's dig in
gentlemen.
Wait.
Before we eat, I have a question.
Is there a Huang Dabao in the village?
Guys, since the mountains here in
Guizhou aren't suitable for running,
and there aren't so many gyms around,
I designed this
mandatory treadmill.
-- How is it mandatory?
-- Let me demonstrate.
Activate.
Set your goal in life.
A little ambiguous.
Maximum life.
Okay.
Here comes my baby love knot again.
No rush with the gifts, though.
I do hope that you're attracted
not to my good looks
but my inventions.
What is a mandatory treadmill anyway?
It means,
unless I've reached the goal
I set for myself,
this door will not open whatsoever.
Well, this is too fast.
No.
Oh, damn it.
Third Uncle.
Second Cousin.
Huang Dabao.
What the hell are you doing?
We have to buy tickets
to see an internet celebrity now?
Dabao! Huang Dabao!
Dabao, what's wrong?
Dabao! Dabao! Dabao,
are you okay?
I'm alright.
I did it for exercise.
Just ran a marathon.
You don't need to run a marathon.
Just eat some goji berries.
Who are these people?
Allow me to introduce.
This is Qin and Mr. Chief.
They're here to promote our village.
Satellite TV?
Excuse me, I'll go redo
my makeup.
-- Wait.
-- Mr. Huang,
we're actually from Rediscover Science,
the documentary program,
and we're here to investigate the UFO.
UFO
They suspect that you built it.
I built it?
Qin, give this ball a close-up shot.
It could be the tool he built it with.
Take a hike.
What's with the attitude?
That's the name of it.
It's called Take-A-Hike
I came up with that.
How come?
Guizhou is famous for its
mountainous terrain.
It's not easy walking around here.
So, when you need to go down the mountain
and there is no ride,
it can be really irritating.
My dearest fans,
this is Take-A-Hike.
An invention that
provides a permanent solution
for the downhill trip,
swift and convenient.
Cut it out.
This is not one of your
live-streaming sessions.
Let me ask you something.
Why didn't you go to the movie on the night
of the Mid-Autumn Festival?
Mr. Wang, the village head,
said the movie sucks.
I never said that.
What I said was the actors were ugly.
Where were you then?
I was home, inventing things.
With no alibi.
Now you're leaving me with no choice
but to use the exclusion method.
Mr. Wang, would you please
summon everyone.
Who didn't go to the movie that night?
I need to question them one by one.
-- All of them?
-- All of them.
Mr. Chief, is your show
called Rediscover Science
or Law and Order?
That doesn't matter.
What matters is the truth.
-- Name?
-- I've eaten
-- Age?
-- Three bowls.
What were you doing on movie night?
Noodles.
Next!
Mr. Wang, do me a favor and
summon no one of this age.
But you said you needed to question
everyone who didn't go to the movie.
Investigations should be elaborate.
Chief director,
shall we go check out the crime scene?
Where is that?
Look, I built a 3D map of the
surrounding area on my laptop.
Given the approximate distance,
as well as the trajectory of the thing
from the video,
the landing site
is most likely here.
What are we waiting for then?
Let's move!
Wind speed on the night
was four meters per second.
Plus, there was mist in the mountain
and artificial light.
That means the landing site
should be in this location.
We'll check out both, then.
Let's go now!
Mr. Chief, it'll be dark soon.
You should probably wait till tomorrow.
-- No!
-- Well you see...
I have a meeting to attend,
so I think I'll just take off.
A car can't get there.
Then how do we get there?
Huang Dabao.
He has a tractor.
Can the tractor go any faster?!
Safety first.
Well, this is too safe!
Huang Dabao.
Mr. Chief would like to go faster.
Show them your invention.
For this tractor specifically,
I invented
the All-direction Multi-dimensional
Stereo Acceleration Sensor.
It would, instantly, make you feel like
you're dashing through air.
Mr. Huang, bring it on!
Is there a safety belt on this thing?
We don't wanna get tossed out.
Sit tight. Don't move.
Now, get ready to feel it.
Here we go.
It just got a bit bumpy.
According to the coordinates,
it should be here.
-- The aliens are real.
-- Why would you say it's Huang Dabao?
Forget about coordinates,
what you need is a doctor.
Guys, come quick.
So, the aliens are real.
See?
I told you.
That's not right.
What is?
It's definitely not right.
Something smells funny.
It's diesel.
The UFO...
runs on diesel?
Diesel is just hydrocarbon alkyl.
Energy conversion require combustion,
which requires oxygen.
And there's no oxygen beyond
the earth's atmosphere.
Even my cousin's tricycle runs on gasoline.
This is forged.
By you, you mean?
-- No.
-- It is you.
It's not me!
It's most certainly you.
-- It's most certainly not me!
-- You forged this!
It's most certainly not him.
Judging by the traces here,
this place was recently incinerated.
Huang Dabao has been with us
this whole time.
He couldn't possibly have the time
to set fire to the grass.
Also, it is against my idea
of environment-friendly inventions.
Chief director, chief director!
You need to see this.
Chief director.
Two more people didn't
go to the movie that night.
Who?
Who do you reckon would benefit the most
from the discovery of the UFO?
I see.
-- Are they asleep?
-- Yes.
Go, go!
Dabao! Huang Dabao!
Dabao.
Huang Dabao!
Where is he?
Dabao, where are you?
I'm at the gate.
Be right back.
Where were you this late?
Where were you?
I had to think something through.
Like what?
Sir, the Take-A-Hike.
It's moving.
-- You're delusional.
-- It's really moving.
Chief director is inside!
Why would he steal my invention?
Who's stealing your invention?
Get him out now!
Mr. Dong.
-- Chief director!
-- Go after the ball!
Get the ball!
Mr. Chief!
Catch the ball!
Block it!
Mr. Chief!
-- Quick, stop it!
-- Stop the ball!
Stop it!
Mr. Chief! Mr. Chief!
Slow down.
See? It's okay.
Mr. Chief!
Are you alright?
Mr. Chief.
I'm fine. Not bad.
You can't even stand.
I'm okay.
Huang Dabao, this thing is no joke.
Extremely safe.
I spent most of the year developing it
and I didn't even have the balls to try it.
Sir, you are the man!
If I were rolling down like that,
I'd puke my guts out!
Oh, that reminds me!
-- It's okay.
-- Alright, everyone.
Show's over.
Go back to sleep.
You've all seen how the big ball
rolled down.
Now go back to sleep.
Come on, off you go.
Alright, I'll just cut the crap.
Did you forge that thing out there?
What thing?
Burn a fake circle in the meadow
with diesel
to make it look like an UFO.
Dong's analysis wasn't necessary correct.
Why can't an UFO run on diesel?
Of course it can't.
What evidence do you have?
Because…
I am the alien.
And I'm your daddy.
That there is the thing you're looking for.
You invented it too?
It is my…
biggest invention ever.
I did the first flight test on the night
of the Mid-Autumn Festival.
I didn't expect it to be a success.
Although the cruising power
is obviously inadequate.
But I'm still happy.
Who knew things would get out
of control after that?
Why didn't you tell us earlier?
How was I supposed to know
it would make the news
and bring those TV people here?
Fair enough.
Now I can't hide it anymore.
-- I'll just come clean with them.
-- And say what?
Take a hike.
I mean you...
...you make this public,
what about tourism?
Yeah.
Dabao,
don't you want everyone in the village
to have a better life?
Where's your heart?
But, I decided to tell the truth
because…
because I have a heart.
Truth? The truth is other villages
are blessed with natural beauty
and the town of Kedu has made a fortune
off the telescope.
What do we have?
-- Only aliens.
-- Who's there?
We still can't fall asleep.
Quick! Hurry!
-- Get it up there!
-- No!
-- I'm begging you, please.
-- No.
-- Huang Dabao! This is an order!
According to article 11 of the Civil Aviation
Law of the People's Republic of China,
Manufacturing of aircraft of any kind must
be approved by the civil aviation authority.
We can have you arrested.
Come on, give me a hand.
Give me a hand.
One. Two.
Three.
Gentlemen,
still awake, huh?
Yep.
So, what are you doing?
Discussing, playing poker, talking.
We are…
discussing and talking
about whether we are going to play poker.
That's right.
It's true.
You guys have had a tough day.
And now you're playing poker?
I wish I had your energy.
You're not so bad yourselves,
still staying up at this hour.
Huang Dabao,
why don't you tell us more
about the things in your yard?
They're right there.
Be my guest.
Just tell us more.
May I?
I know more about those things in the yard
than he does.
It's true.
What's that sound?
I was burping.
That was some funny noise you made.
Mr. Huang,
I'm feeling a little funny in the stomach.
Where's the bathroom?
The bathroom? In the yard.
Where in the yard?
Outside.
You know what?
I'll show you the way.
Great.
Let's go.
What is it?
You're sweating.
What's wrong?
I'm a little weak.
-- Have some water.
-- No.
-- Come on.
-- Really, I'm good.
-- Just drink it.
-- No.
-- Drink.
-- I'm not drinking it.
Fine, don't drink.
No need to get mad.
Jeez.
-- Is this another invention of yours?
-- Don't touch that.
It's not what you think it is.
What do I think is it?
No, don't touch that.
Relax,
you're not gonna go to jail for this.
All you need to do later
is say you're sorry to the camera.
What did you build the UFO for?
It was a tragic love story.
Many years ago,
I fell in love with this girl
in the village across the canyon.
She is a fair maiden with a heart of gold
and the most beautiful eyes
I've ever known.
Plus a long thick pigtail.
Is her name Xiaofang, as in the song?
It's Ａhua.
Her name…
is Dong Ahua.
How did you know?
My name is Axu
and hers is Ahua.
The hamlet across the canyon
is our home.
Xiaofu Village.
You two
were separated by the distance
of merely one kilometer.
It is the greatest regret of her life.
So, you are…
her younger brother.
Brother.
Long time no see.
It's been 11 years, brother.
You've all grown up.
What about your sister?
-- She got married.
-- Good.
That's good.
Fantastic.
Then divorced.
That's too bad.
-- She really got divorced?
-- Yeah.
So, what did you invent that thing for?
Deliver love letters?
Actually I was thinking about
logistics.
You see, here in Guizho,
we have gorgeous scenery
and good people, too.
The lack of infrastructure
is the only thing
standing between us and the outside world,
preventing lovers and products
from leaving the mountains.
With improvement in logistics
life would be a lot easier for us.
Well, with that crappy UFO of yours,
it'd be a long shot.
No, no. Actually I think
it's pretty close.
There are problems in power and cruising.
I'll help you figure that out.
-- Really?
-- Yeah.
That'd be great.
Thank you so much.
Brother, I should thank you.
For letting me do something
to help my home province.
And also,
a chance to visit my sister.
You sister?
Axue.
Ahua?
You're sort of an internet celebrity now.
What don't you call me by my screen name?
Your screen name?
It's you.
My baby love knot.
You guys are too cute.
Well, you didn't know,
but there was once a chance
that I missed because of
long distance.
If I were given a second chance,
then believe me,
I'd never let her go.
-- Yeah!
-- Make it tight!
A small village in South Guizhou
is the place I call home
Amongst big mountains it lies,
secluded and remote.
Visitors from outer space in the UFO.
A sight that everyone can't wait to behold.
Alien civilization, dope technology.
It's all local invention,
you better believe me.
Soaring up, diving down,
it goes wherever you want.
Maybe someday it'll fly up
the mountains and beyond.
The one thing I remember about my
hometown is the misty pines in winter.
The one thing I'd never forget
about my home is the Torch Festival.
During summer it is extremely hot.
Hulun Buir in winter is extremely cold.
There's snow everywhere outside the door.
The tasty Hot Dry Noodles.
I ran to play by the sea holding a tire.
Temple Fair on the first day
of the Chinese New Year.
I can't remember.
ONE LAST LESSON
St. Gallen, Switzerland
Dad.
Dad, are you up?
Yeah.
Coming.
Alright, kids. Breakfast is ready.
Put your toys down.
Dad,
maybe you should sit this one out.
I don't want you to end up
like the other day.
I'm fine.
Why don't I call the hospital and
move your checkup forward?
No need. I know my health
better than anyone.
Dad should really consider retiring.
He wouldn't even go to the hospital,
let alone quit teaching. It'll kill him.
University of Berkelin
Screenplay by Lulufu Bu, Keke Hu,
Weilin Hua & Zheng Xu
Hello, Professor Fan.
No, no, no.
Like this.
Professor Fan, Professor Fan.
Call an ambulance, go, go.
He is awake.
Pa.
How do you feel, Pa?
The wetch.
Time.
My wetch.
Your watch.
Veight o'clock, the class.
I'm running late.
Pa, you can't go to the class.
-- You passed out.
-- Who passed out?
Class begins at veight,
and I'm not there yet.
Bullshoot.
Pa, you can't teach anymore.
The doctor says you have
a cerebral infraction.
-- I have what?
-- A stroke.
Stone color.
Or maybe scarlet.
-- Well...
-- Dad, no!
I'll bring all the colors.
Doctor!
Doctor, doctor!
Pa, where are you going?!
What are you doing?!
Old Jiang, he is about to crow.
Who is about to crow? Only roosters crow.
What rooster? Old Jiang.
Jiang Dazhong.
Before the class, clang, clang, clang!
Clang, clang, clang! He needs to crow!
-- What are you even talking about?
-- The students are waiting for me.
The paints. The boat is about to sail off.
Pa, stop it.
Call me Sir.
And wipe off your snot.
You still don't get it.
Two plus two equals veight.
Your bum is going to be spanked.
Where is the bum?
The bum.
The paints.
Sorry.
-- Here they are.
-- No, no, no!
Calm down.
This.
I got the paints.
It began to rain.
And then...
Cerebral infarction is a common cause
of dementia in the elderly.
It is often accompanied by severe
behavioral and language disorders.
Based on your father's symptoms,
he has already developed alternating
periods of cognitive impairment.
We call this 'fluctuating cognition'.
Your father's speech does not suggest to me
the classic signs of memory lapse
from cerebral infarction.
But the phrases and words that he's using
suggest to me that his memory is stuck
at a specific moment in the past.
You mean he is living in the past?
Yes, yes, you can say that.
But how does the modernness of this world
or the outside buildings not freak him out?
Think of it this way.
Imagine he is in a room,
and he is trying to put together
the pieces of a jigsaw puzzle.
Now, the elements that
match his memories are the pieces.
And the picture will tell us a story.
And the story will be something
very significant that happened in his past.
Tomorrow,
Dazhong,
go find some nails.
And fix the desks and chairs.
Jiang Dazhong
I knew I'd heard that name before.
When my father was teaching
in Wangxi Village,
he was the school janitor, the bell ringer.
Clang, clang, clang, that's him.
So his memory is stuck in
when he was teaching
in the elementary school.
Are we bringing Pa to that shabby village
go give one last lecture?
Qiandao Lake, China
This Mid-Autumn festival, there might be
an overflow of tourists, [Wang Xi Village]
putting the accommodation
of our village to a test.
Now is the time.
But all the guesthouses
in the neighbourhood
are booked up.
Village tours are so popular now.
Go check the forest oxygen bar,
find a clearing, pitch a few tents
put up a couple of tree houses,
there you go.
Try to get some RVs here.
Boathouses on the river is also an idea.
International call.
Hello.
Chief, I need to tell you something.
Family trip this way up.
Okay.
Are you here for the tea picking festival?
Please sign in first.
Come on, this way.
Inside.
-- Where is your boss?
-- Jogging with the guests.
It's getting late.
Hasn't she gotten back already?
One, one.
Xiao Lai.
So you just leave your business unattended.
Guess which year?
2001, Shanghai Translation
Publishing House.
-- Amazing.
-- How about this one?
1998, People's Literature.
Hi guys.
What you see here is a very special
experience offered in our village,
soya beans grinding.
You get to pick the beans
and then grind them.
It gives you such a sense
of accomplishment.
This is our 2nd generation beehive.
Intelligent beehive.
Temperature change at the push of a button.
Temperature up,
dancing bees.
Temperature down,
all in peace.
And the yield doubles.
Everyone, why is it that moss
can break down rock?
I know, I know.
Tell me.
Hey, I heard you are about to
expand the cocoonery.
I have to. The number of orders is
getting overwhelming.
That's major.
Tell everyone in the group chat
to gather for meeting.
Group send it is.
A meeting.
Calling us together.
Now can we please quiet down?
I want to know if it is possible that
based on this old photo,
we recreate a class
to help Mr. Fan out.
Listen to me.
I remember that in 1992, when
Fan was giving his last lecture,
it was raining cats and dogs,
coming down in buckets.
Just cut the crap.
Listen to me.
I would love to help,
okay?
But how are we supposed
to go back to '92?
Exactly.
This house used to be a pigsty.
Mother pigs and baby pigs were
running wild.
That's correct.
The spot that you're sitting on is where
the mottled black sow in village
gave birth to so many piglets.
I know that.
Back then the village was
plagued by flies, right?
Now you can't find one single
mosquito, can you?
Back then,
all the houses were roofless.
And now, even the pigsties are
separated rooms with a ceiling.
How can we go back to '92?
Right.
Knock it all down?
Knocking down the village?
I'm the first to say no.
-- No way!
-- Me too!
I never asked you to do that.
All I suggested is to restore a classroom
and make this last lecture happen.
What about the students then?
We can't go back to 7, 8 years old.
Yeah.
1992? I wasn't even born yet!
Should I restore myself to nothing?
We will just find some kids.
His mind is all muddled.
He won't know the difference.
Exactly.
Things have changed so much.
We can't go back.
That's enough.
My turn to speak.
In 1982, Mr. Fan was transferred
from the city to here,
he could have left in 1985
when his term ended.
And why didn't he leave?
He was a hard worker and no whiner.
He stayed here till all of us
could go to town for school.
Ten years. One teacher for ten years.
He taught us math, Chinese,
and then PE.
Wearing a pair of worn leather shoes,
he led us to kick shuttlecock.
If it were not for him,
you, your father and your father
would be illiterate.
It's true what Da Lei said.
Right! Let me ask you -
two plus two equals what?
What was your answer then?
Tell us.
Eight.
You said eight, and I said six.
Now you are the secretary,
and I'm the head of village.
And Xiao Feng, who used
to play with dirt all day,
is now an accomplished architect.
Right.
So now it's time to show our gratitude,
our gratefulness.
Wait. Even if we could recreate
this classroom,
he is coming back from Switzerland.
There are bridges and cars
along the way that he can't not see.
The Swiss doctor said that
now Mr. Fan is making a jigsaw puzzle
in his head,
which is the image of 1992,
the image of the last lecture, get it?
Mr. Secretary,
If he ever runs out of the room,
then it won't be 1992 anymore.
- Right!
-- Right!
-- You're not telling it right.
Enough!
Mr. Fan's brain is turning into a puzzle,
a puzzle about us.
Can't we just figure out a way
to help him?
Jiang Dalei.
The cocoonery that you are expanding
is exactly the place
where the old classroom used to be.
Plus, he has people
working on it now.
That's handy.
Wait, what does my cocoonery
have to do with it?
-- Even handier.
-- What?
In Switzerland, Mr. Fan keeps saying that
his father is ringing the bell.
-- My father is long gone.
-- You can play him.
Look at you, all cocky and stuff,
you look just like you father.
-- Am I right?
-- Yes, he does.
It's a deal then. Applaud.
Hey!
Hey! Hey, what are you...
You promised me,
you will help me restore everything
once this is over.
We are pulling all the people
and resources for this.
There is no turning back.
We fight till the end, we fight to win.
There is no second chance.
Now kids,
Let's turn the clock
back to 1992.
Your mission is most glorious
yet arduous.
So dear students,
let's go to Bullet Point 13.
What was 1992 like?
You weren't born yet.
Keep it light on the drama, though.
You've gone through all the key points?
Yes, we have.
The most important thing is to remember
the name of your character.
Gently, gently.
You two, podium to the side.
That's right.
Give me that chair.
Kid, hand me the chair.
I'll wipe it clean.
Xiao Jiang, quick.
Get this water hose in place
and running.
-- And patch up the roof tiles!
-- Got it!
The rain should be pouring
in right through there.
Roof tiles stay still, no misplacement.
I said we need chicken around.
I didn't say they have
to be in the classroom.
What are the bees for?
We couldn't find flies.
But the drones don't sting.
Get them out of here now.
Not one left inside the room, quick.
We need to keep it realistic.
Mr. Secretary, the roof is done.
Then go pick up them
at the village entrance.
They are arriving.
Come on, guys, hurry up.
Does the mustache look real enough?
Real? Yes.
-- Stuck? Not really.
-- Don't tangle that.
If it has to be really real,
I'll be driven nuts.
They are almost here, hurry up.
Take that away, don't let him see it.
What are you two up to?
Raising the national flag.
Going back in time wouldn't
do better than this.
Greetings, passengers.
The train has now arrived
at its destination.
On the boat now.
But this is not a boat.
We should travel by water.
This is a waterway.
Look, it's all water outside.
Have some rest.
Attention, attention.
Target is arriving at the
dummy entrance of the back hill.
Get ready.
Pa, wake up. I think we're here.
I love this smell.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
Wait, Fan.
Who am I?
Goodbye.
Who are you.
You are the man who drove me here.
Class begins.
Don't make me ring a second time.
Dazhong,
I told you before.
Put some straws over the roof.
It becomes a rain when it waterfalls.
Okay.
Dazhong,
why has your head gotten bigger?
It's the stress.
I've been stressing over the roof thing.
It's pointless to stress.
There is a problem to every solution.
Take care of yourself.
Chief, chief, and Mr. Secretary.
He's here.
-- I'm so sorry for the trouble.
-- We do this because we're thankful.
Chief.
Thank you for the hard work.
My father is getting really sick.
He doesn't even recognize me.
Let's try and see.
Everybody assume your position.
He's here.
Class.
-- Stand up.
-- Good morning, Sir!
Sit down, please.
Mr. Monitor,
Get up, you're the monitor.
Why are you
shorter than before?
Where did your dimples go?
I smoothed them out
by blowing bubbles.
Fragile dimples.
Everyone,
our village school
and town school
are going to be merged.
Why?
Right, by then there will
better teachers to teach you.
So this is
my last lecture.
There are things that I
dread I might remember,
so I forget them in my notebook.
Shouldn't it be that he
is afraid he might forget
so he writes them down in his notes?
He is babbling.
Jiang Xiaohong,
your rubber shoes are leaky.
After class ask them to find me,
and I will mend you.
Jiang Qianfang
Your math worries me the most.
Two and two equals what?
-- Four.
-- Veight.
Black pig from south village
gives birth to 2 white piglets.
White pig from north village
gives birth to 2 black piglets.
How many piglets are there?
Veight.
Correct, veight of them.
Jiang Weian
Yes.
Tell your father.
I'm not going for diner tonight.
As long as he works hard in school,
It will be a gift to me.
It should be me working hard in school.
Everyone,
Today, I will
go off the textbook.
I would like to know
what you think our hometown
will look like in the future.
If you want to draw, then write.
If you want to write, then draw it.
The title is Me and My
Town
Home village.
It should be Hometown.
Sir, it should be Hometown.
Hometown.
Home
Ten years ago,
when I for the first time
stepped into the classroom.
There were only
two students and one piglet.
A piglet.
I wanted to turn away and leave.
But I couldn't bear the sight of
so many children
feeding pigs while
they should be in school.
So I talked to one family after another.
Finally,
the desks and chairs
started to fill up the classroom.
The sound of you reading
got louder and louder.
You all know the boy named
Jiang Dongfang, right?
Yes.
When he was here he once asked me,
he said, Sir,
I don't want to eat dried radish everyday.
Will studying bring me good food to eat?
A couple of days ago,
he came back from senior high to see me.
He told me that
there is a good chance that he
will enter Shanghai Jiao Tong University.
It's said that the food
in the canteen is so good.
When I heard that,
I felt the past ten years I spent here
are worth it.
What? Give it back.
Let go.
What's happening?
Sir,
he took my drawing.
It's not a drawing. It's starch.
Show me the drawing.
It's splashed mud.
The monster spider's cave.
No.
No nonsense.
Tell me what it is.
This is a school I drew.
You want the school to be like this.
Why?
This is a window.
This is the roof.
What about this?
It's a slide.
It's red here,
and blue here.
Beautiful.
Why don't you color it?
I don't have them.
Who among you has paints?
No.
Sir, I have a blue pen.
I will find some paints for you.
Who is it? Why does he have a cellphone?
-- What noise is it?
-- Your student.
Didn't you take all their phones?
What's going on?
What's this?
It's a cellphone.
You don't know what cellphone is?
What the hell?
Your drawing isn't supposed to have colors.
Why can't I do colorful drawings?
Because you don't have color pens.
No, no, no.
-- What?
-- Red, blue,
green, I have them.
I got all the colors.
I
Hey.
There's no water.
No water. Go check for any blockage.
Blockage somewhere.
You're stepping on it.
It's a mess now. Go check it.
Calm down. Calm down.
Good morning, Sir.
The book is wrong.
The chair is wrong.
You are not Jiang Xiaofeng.
What's your name?
Peter.
What happened to you, sir?
What's going on?
I have to go inside.
Don't go.
What now?
How did this happen?
That way.
Sir, why are you leaving?
The class isn't finished.
Come back.
Mr. Fan fell down.
Mr. Fan!
Mr. Fan! Mr. Fan!
This is for you.
Mr. Fan...Mr. Fan...
Do you remember me?
This is a school I drew.
It's red here,
and blue here.
Gently I lift up your face
Jiang Xiaofeng.
Hey.
Your drawing,
now,
I get it.
Tell me you'll never be alone.
Looking deeply into your eyes.
No need to say another word.
Holding tightly onto your hands.
This warmth will never ever change.
Together we share joy.
We share the same sorrow.
And we have the same aspiration.
If I were to compare my hometown to a scent
it must be that of the ocean.
To me the taste of home is like cured meat.
The taste of home is salty.
The smell of hotpot in the air.
It's definitely the potatoes.
The taste of Songhua River.
-- It's sweet.
-- Like clams.
-- Salty sea water.
-- Like lamb hotpot.
Hot oil poured on chilli.
Like sand.
Rough, dry and bitter.
The taste of home to me
is nothing else
but the mouthful of sand
on a windy day.
THE ROAD BACK
Many have asked me the same question.
With all my popularity now,
what do I usually sell?
The answer is a supreme lifestyle.
The best and freshest food in the business.
Could you look at me for a change?
Stop bugging me.
This Yan Feiyan
is not that great a saleswoman.
She just has a hot body.
Like a trophy wife.
Man oh man,
I used to be just like her.
Jia Yuling,
I love the way you look now.
Yue Longgang, quit bullshitting me already.
No, I meant it.
That's…hey, look, that's...
-- What?
-- That one.
-- Which one?
-- That's her.
-- That woman.
Who?
Get me the best hotel they have.
With a freezer.
-- Isn't that you know who?
-- What are you talking about?
Can't you finish the sentence?
It's that woman who…
-- That's her.
-- Who?
-- What are you doing?
-- Sister, can I get a picture?
-- Oh my god, I'm your biggest fan!
-- The Queen of Live Commerce!
I watch all your streams,
don't you remember?
Take a selfie with us, please.
Three, two…
What's the point of taking a selfie
if no one can recognize us?
You might wanna go easy on the beauty cam.
It's too much.
Let's switch to original mode then.
Got it.
Three, two…
Yue Longgang, original mode?
Do you realize how I'd come off?
Or yourself?
Staff ID 9438 and 9601,
in about 20 minutes
your supervisor will have a word with you
about harassing passengers.
Based on my personal experience
you'd both get a level-two penalty.
Let's go, Jessica.
There's nothing to negotiate.
Stop playing games with me.
We need to be at Shaligou
Central School at 3 P.M.
for the school anniversary gala.
Okay.
I don't want another incident
like what just happened.
You must protect me.
Ms. Yan, I love you.
Me, too.
There are con men out there
who would pose as a classmate
or a fellow countryman
to get close to people.
It's all part of the fraud.
If I run into one,
I'll give you a sign,
and you need to come over immediately.
Okay, okay.
What are you talking about?
Twenty million is nothing.
You think I care about such
a small sum of money?
You listen to me,
I have one goal.
That is to provide everyone in China
with the best apple in the world.
Big sis?
Going back to Shaligou
for the anniversary, too?
Yeah.
What are the chances?
It's me.
Qiao Shulin.
You must have been too busy studying.
We were six years apart.
Hi, sir, excuse me.
You're in my seat.
I just ran into a relative.
I'm sorry. Can we switch seats?
Thanks.
How time flies.
One year,
we were performing together
on a windy day with sandstorm.
It's a musical.
"The Girl Who Collects Mushrooms."
You were in it?
I was the girl.
I was one of the mushrooms.
Sir,
excuse me.
That seat is taken.
What's the matter with you?
This is ridiculous.
If you have a problem,
talk to a stewardess.
Hurry up, off you go.
Sis, you see,
I sell apples. And you
do live commerce.
I can give you really good prices.
Just friend me on WeChat.
Scan your face.
-- Jessica.
-- No need to see a card.
Just give me your number.
Hey, sis.
What's up?
Something wrong with your eyes?
Excuse me, Ms. Yan
needs to rest now.
-- Sorry.
-- I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Sir, may I see your boarding pass?
Here.
Sir, this is an economy class ticket.
Please go back to your seat.
That's impossible. I...
My assistant booked me
a first class ticket.
Please go to your seat.
The plane is about to take off.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Thank you.
Say hello to the captain for me.
I'm sorry.
Call me.
Say hello to the whole crew, too.
I thought you were flying first class.
I don't want to bother big sis.
So I paid to have my seat downgraded.
Downgraded?
Repeat after me.
Where there is a will,
there is a way.
One more time.
Where there is a will,
there is a way.
Keep Up Your Discipline
Study hard.
Learn something useful.
Make this a better place.
It's no using pushing me now.
I don't have the money to pay you back.
Just give me another day.
I've found a new fish.
Quiet, please.
And I'm reeling her in today.
Take a grab of the yellow soil
and put it against my heart.
Greetings, everyone. I am Han,
your tour guide for the trip.
Also a Chinese teacher at
Shaligou Middle School
and the editor of our official
WeChat account.
On our way to the school,
I'll interview each one of you,
digging up some stories of our alumni.
And the theme of the interview is
A Taste of Home.
I wanna go first.
Here.
Qiao, Qiao.
What's the taste of home to you?
Crispy and sweet.
As the apples from our hometown.
Big sis, have a bite first.
We'll talk later.
These apples make grandmas
square dancing queens…
-- Thank you.
-- …and children slay those online lectures.
Here, I've got a QR-code.
A Taste of Home.
The wetland is right ahead.
We'll take a 15-minute break.
Ms. Yan,
didn't you say your hometown
is on the Loess Plateau?
Where is the loess?
How come it's so different now?
The official term is returning
farmland to forests.
Sis, you should take a
a look around Shaligou.
We've turned some four million
mu of Maowusu Desert
all into oasis now.
Seems like
you've done a lot for our home.
I'm a very successful man.
What's the point of making billions
if you don't give back?
Sis, I need to confirm something with you.
You're staying at the
five-star hotel in town, right?
Right.
And you, brother Qiao, are staying
in your old cave-house by the school.
In my dreams I weep my eyes red
remembering the coziness of the cave-house.
Here.
Han,
please get us a cave-house as well.
Sure, I'll make the arrangement now.
That's not really necessary, boss.
You city folks would never understand
how we feel about our home in the country.
You must know, Fluffy.
That deep heart-wrenching nostalgia.
What did you just call me?
Fluffy.
You had inverse eyelashes
that made you blink all the time.
You were the baby raised by Madam Gao.
Sis.
Listen to me,
I'd rather not talk about that.
Seriously. I hope that our cooperation
is based on our business resources,
instead of this special bond from the past.
Why don't you tell me more
about those apples of yours?
I got everything on my phone.
Thanks, sis, thank you.
Boss,
that guy, Qiao,
is definitely a con man.
I had a sneak peek of his phone
and saw lots of messages
from debt-collectors.
I doubt he even has a
decent amount of cash on him.
Is that so?
That'd be more fun.
Do I look at this?
Right here,please.
Go.
So, what did you bring with you
on this homecoming trip?
I'd say it's love.
Unlike tangible gifts,I believe,
spiritual ones are priceless.
Two bowls of mutton scraps
Sure, no problem.
Two more noodle soup here.
Gouzi.
The bus is here.
Watch out.
Lunch time, everyone.
Brother Qiao's treat.
Buckwheat noodles.
Sesame rice stew.
Steamed pumpkin.
Bread soaked in mutton soup.
My mouth is watering like crazy.
Wow, they even have lamb offal.
-- Fluffy.
-- Yes?
These are authentic foods from home.
We have to try everything.
You got it.
Plus, how expensive
can a bowl of lamb offal soup be?
280 yuan.
For a bowl of lamb offal soup?
What did you put in there?
A special elixir?
Or sea cucumber?
Both.
It's our new special.
How did you know?
-- Fluffy?
-- Yes?
-- Sis?
-- This is so good.
Can I have another one?
Just swipe them all.
Next stop Shaligou, let's go.
All passengers to Shaligou.
I'm used to carrying no cash nowadays.
Hey, sis. You go ahead.
Don't wait up.
It's okay.
I'll wait.
Thanks for lunch, Mr. Qiao.
Still not working? Did you
update your POS terminal?
Brother,
I don't think even the latest update
would allow it to access a metro card.
Qiao Shulin.
I recognized your
shameless face at first glance.
Wei Peng?
But Han said no one
from my class is coming.
That's bullshit.
Why didn't you tell me?
You big-shot billionaire.
What are you doing back home?
Mr. Billionaire,
could you pay up first?
-- Let me.
-- No, no, you don't have to.
-- Please.
-- Come on, I'm not letting you do this.
-- Don't be pretentious.
-- You're home now.
-- How much do you make a month?
-- None of your business.
I got this.
You don't want to fight me.
-- Alrighty then.
-- Good.
What the hell did you order?
Where is he?
Why are you lying down?
You and your classmates must know him well.
Actually,
we don't have that privilege.
Qiao here is a billionaire.
He…
Big sis.
Are all the famous alumni here?
I know this is not the
fancy limo you're used to
but I can take you guys for a ride.
Have ourselves a desert safari.
Why do you keep touching me?
Guess there's no need for formalities then.
We can catch up on the road.
Let's go.
Your metro card.
About two thousand years ago,
this used be to a pasture for the Huns.
It was larger than Hainan Island.
And by Tang Dynasty,
it became a desert.
-- Say, Fluffy…
-- Yes, sis?
Didn't you say you made a huge contribution
to afforestation of the Maosuwu?
Nothing worth mentioning.
I can prove that. About ten
years ago,
Qiao made a donation of
200,000 to the school.
No dig deal.
He said he could grow apple trees in sand.
Now the dunes are covered by orchards,
with the most exuberant
fruits and trees.
That must be a wonderful sight to see.
What don't we go have a look?
We can't, because…
the show's about to start.
It'd be quite a detour.
Nonsense.
It's just outside the sand area.
It used to stretch
from over there
to right here,
with fruit trees yea tall.
It just so happened that last year
they had them all dug up.
Mainly because the fruit
turned out to be of poor quality.
Sis,
if you have the time,
I'll take you to the new plantation,
which is absolutely magnificent.
Why are you staring at me like that?
I'm telling you the truth.
Over that ridge ahead
is our school.
Stop the car.
What's wrong, sis?
Is that the path leading to the hilltop?
Sister,
say, you make a hole with each step.
It's like planting seedlings
with high heels.
Slow down, sis.
Boss, try to stay under the umbrella.
All that skin whitening is going to waste.
Slow down, please.
You walk surprisingly fast, sis.
Are we there yet?
We are.
Madam Gao is buried under the tree.
See? The new school.
Look how great it is.
Too bad
the old lady didn't get to see it.
I've come home to see you.
You told each one of us…
Learn something useful.
Make this a better place.
Now that I'm back.
I did learn something useful.
But you're not around anymore.
Am I a good student or what?
These past few years
I kept dreaming of you.
I dreamt that you lost me.
Coming through, watch out.
Why are you holding a big vase?
It's my gift for the school.
I had it custom-made.
In honor of the 40th anniversary
of Shaligou Central School,
let the show
begin now.
Go.
The man I want to become
is someone I've never met.
He talks big.
Always bragging.
Many think of him as a liar.
But he was an orphan.
He was just 18 months old
when he got acute typhus fever
and was abandoned on a mountain trail.
Madam Gao, our old principal, took him in.
Later, he made a fortune selling fruit.
He donated lots of money
to build us a new school.
Mr. Han said
back then the sand storms were so bad
that everyone was driven away.
And that on Madam Gao's dying bed
she said the one thing
she couldn't let go was the kids.
So, Mr. Qiao told our parents
to quit their jobs in the city
and come back.
He also said that he had
this new technology
that would make everybody rich.
To maintain the moisture
you must wrap it up to here.
Got it? Yeah.
He lived a simple life
for he put all his money in the project.
And he said if they could improve
the quality of the apple,
they'd make a lot of money in the future.
But little did he know…
Why are you crying when
you get paid no matter what?
Worst comes worst,
we'll just reclaim the land
and develop a new breed.
Don't worry about the cost,
I'm a billionaire.
More and more people
came to help with afforestation,
as well as education and
building the new school.
Our school got bigger and bigger
while the sand storms
got smaller and smaller.
This year, the sandy apple
is finally a success.
My dad said as long as
they can sell apples,
he'll be able to pay off all the debts.
Mr. Han said
everyone can be changed by someone else
but only a few can truly
have an impact on others.
That is the man I want to become.
Qiao Shulin
of Shaligou.
Qiao Shulin is my buddy.
We've been best friends forever.
Shulin.
We're here, Shulin.
Fluffy.
The kids wanted it to be a surprise.
It kills me having to
hide it from you all the way here.
Brother Qiao,
on behalf of myself,
my students,
and everyone in the village,
thank you.
For god's sake,
stop crying.
Thank you.
Shulin, here. Let's
take a selfie together.
Sure.
Jessica,
we're staying tomorrow,
got some live-streaming promotion to do.
With one new product.
I know.
The sandy apple.
The sun hanging above sand dunes
Shines ever brightly
Upon sand slopes underneath the sky
Holes are being dug
Hey-yo hey-ah hey-yo
One sapling after another
Are planted in the holes
As they look up to gaze upon the sky
And they look up to gaze upon the sky
I now live in Hainan,
some 1240 kilometers from Guiyang,
my hometown.
I'm about 300 kilometers away from home.
Over 10,000 kilometers.
In a way I've never really left.
2446 kilometers.
I can only go back during
the Chinese New Year holidays.
I'm an artist, studying at Repin Academy
of Fine Arts in St. Petersburg, Russia.
The distance from my hometown,
Xihulu Village, Ximilu Town,
Xiqin County, Xihong City,
is 6,240 kilometers.
Sweetheart, would you just calm down?
Be the master of your emotions.
Not the other way around.
Can you be more rational?
You're such a scene maker.
Go ahead. I don't care.
You need to trust me.
I can fix it myself.
This would look really bad for me.
Please, I'm begging you.
Please. Please.
-- Hi, Mr. Ma.
-- Hi, Mr. Lee.
-- Getting hot water?
-- Yeah, for a foot bath.
What a shame.
People respect me here.
Impulse is a demon.
Don't ruin it.
If you're getting in there,
at least knock first.
You've been rattling on and on.
Do I really look that immature to you?
Of course not.
Ms. Qiu?
Allow me to introduce.
This is Ma Liang's wife,
Chief Couch of our city wrestling team.
Comrade Qiu Xia.
Mr. Curator, there is something
I want to ask you.
My husband Ma Liang is being
dispatched to help the poor in rural areas.
Did you arrange that?
You don't have to thank me for that.
Send someone else.
He can do nothing but paint.
Comrade Qiu Xia.
This can't be Ma Liang's real thought.
When we first got involved in this
poverty alleviation program,
I asked Ma Liang about his opinions.
And his exact words were
"I'd love to."
I think what he meant to say was
"I don't want to".
This is a serious task that
shouldn't be joked about.
We should have our eyes on the big picture.
-- Right?
-- Right!
Ma Liang is preparing to into
Repin Academy of Fine Arts in Russia.
A phoenix
can not lay in a chicken
coop his whole life,
can he?
A man
should have his own mind over his wife.
She is your wife,
not your mother.
In your family,
who rules?
Go home.
In my family,
strength rules.
Screenplay by Damo Peng, Fei Yan,
Wenxiong Xing & Xiaoxian Sun
Directed by Damo Peng & Fei Yan
Letter of Admission from Repin Academy
of Fine Arts of Russia to Ma Liang
(One year later)
I got the sausages you sent to me.
The whole family thinks that
they taste better than Chinese sausages.
That's for sure.
The Russian recipe is so different.
Honey, what is that you are painting?
It doesn't look like the
Russian painting I imagined.
It has the style of
production brigades back in the old days.
I'm experimenting with different styles.
You've been watching me for a while.
-- Why don't you go downstairs for a walk?
-- No.
Be good.
A pregnant woman should stay active,
it helps the fetus develop.
You develop first.
I want to watch you having breakfast.
I'm already over-developed.
You're waking up my roommate.
Go. Go take a walk.
Wait.
This Mendeleev guy,
does he have a girlfriend?
Why do you ask?
I find him weird.
The way he looks at me
is so sneaky.
Oh my. Can he understand
what I'm saying?
You're crazy.
I'm warning you, Ma Liang.
I heard that foreigners can
be rather loose,
especially you artists.
Keep your distance from him, you hear me?
What is this nonsense?
I said I don't wanna come,
and you made me to.
Now that I'm here,
you're being super paranoid.
-- Then what?
-- I go home.
I just listen to you and go home.
Alright.
I'm gonna take a walk.
Is your wife
getting suspicious of us?
It can't be.
Pregnant women are just super sensitive.
What if she finds out?
If found out,
we might be on Topics in Focus.
Be quiet.
Sweetheart, what again?
Yeah.
Do you receive the sweater I sent to you?
Sweater.
The sweater
is in the reception office.
I haven't gotten it yet.
Then go and get it.
I want to see if it fits.
Why the rush? I'll show you tomorrow.
You're not going to get it.
If so, then I'll sit here all day.
Okay. I'm hanging up.
Shit!
Hello Brother,
You received the sweater
from my wife. Right?
Take a picture and send it to me.
ASAP.
Quick!
What takes you so long?
Oh my, honey.
You're such a deft knitter.
It's beautiful.
Even Mendeleev likes it.
（Russian） Very good.
（Russian） Thank you, my good friend.
I'm the hot one now.
Stay still. Let me look at it.
Did I knit it too small
or you've gained weight?
It looks so tight.
I indeed put on some weight.
But tight is good.
I can wear a jacket over it.
-- That'll be cool.
-- Well, the cuffs look so weird.
It's a sweater, don't worry.
It will become loose over time.
Nah. Turn around.
-- I want to see the back.
-- There is nothing different.
It's basically the same, back and front.
Just turn around.
It's the same. See?
Stop messing around.
-- It's the same.
-- Ma Liang!
It does fit. You see it?
Ma Liang.
Shitty network, get stuck again.
What a crappy connection in Russia.
That's it. I'm taking a walk now.
Try to lose some weight.
She hang up.
-- I burned my chest.
-- Are you alright?
Chief, you've sacrificed so much.
You owe me no apology,
we're in the same boat.
-- Go get changed.
-- Okay.
-- Oh my.
-- Such a pickle I dragged you into.
It's not a big deal.
You're not removing the makeup.
Nah.
In case of your wife calls by surprise.
Double-fold eyelids are tricky to make.
My trouble of a wife.
Sit tight.
-- What happened to your motorbike?
-- The clutch cable fell loose.
-- Use mine if you're in a hurry.
-- It's okay, Mr. Secretary.
Please go about your work.
Get to the side when cars drive by.
Don't play on the road.
Mr. Secretary, going to work?
Yeah, Uncle Qi.
The paddy field tableau is our tourist
attraction to the tourists.
You have to put lots of work
and heart into your lot.
-- Follow the exact design when planting.
-- Got it.
You're not only a farmer now,
but also an artist.
Well I don't have your talent.
-- Mr. Secretary.
-- Yes, Auntie Li?
I heard you and your wife are in crisis.
When are you going to get divorced?
A niece of mine is
recently divorced.
What are you babbling about?
Have some compassion for others, would you?
His wife is pregnant.
Brother, I need two
cases of soda.
Help yourself.
You two are finally back home.
You are the unique pride of our village.
Remember to help your family
with the chores.
Mr. Secretary, we're accustomed to
the depravity of afternoon tea in the city,
We might need a few
more days to acclimate.
They give away tea to bricklayers?
You spend your days slacking,
and what's that haircut?
So trashy and indecent.
Pot calling the kettle black.
I scan to pay the soda, brother.
Cut it out.
Go about your business. Go.
Can't we just do business the proper way?
It's a disgrace if I take your money.
Just go. Get out. Out!
-- Do you want me to come back or not?
-- I don't care.
Stop scanning.
Oh god! Mr. Secretary!
Are you alright, Mr. Secretary?
Brother, is this really necessary?
You...
Is this really necessary?
You overpaid. Come back!
It's settled.
（Russian） Nice to meet you.
Mamma Mia, that's a lot of trills.
Say it again.
（Russian） So nice to meet you.
Folks, take a break from your work.
Have some soda, Mr. Secretary's treat.
Thank you, Mr. Secretary.
Hi, Mr. Secretary.
What is this all about?
This hour
your wife will most likely call you.
So we all volunteer to help
you fool your wife.
Yes.
It seems everyone knows
about my family matter.
In the countryside, even
the walls have ears.
So I went ahead and told them in advance.
I've heard so many times
the touching story of Ms. Qiu
rescuing your husband by
wrestling with the curator.
Now I finally get to admire
the work of Mr. Ma
and the talent overflowed from it.
An unspeakable sensation seizes me.
I find this piece particularly brilliant.
With minimal composition,
it conveys such a profound meaning.
It's a plastic film.
I just bought this new frame online.
（Russian） Good afternoon.
Where are you?
I'm painting outdoors.
Meng Meng and her boyfriend are here.
Her boyfriend, Chang Mao.
Remember him?
Hi, Mr. Ma.
Of course I remember him.
The photographer
who specializes in animals.
One of your works won a prize
in our cultural center.
-- What's the name of that piece?
-- Melancholy Donkey.
Melancholy Donkey, yes.
Chang Mao offered
to take some pregnancy photos for me.
Well isn't that a treat.
He won a prize taking photos of donkeys.
-- With you, it'll be much easier.
-- That's for sure.
Come closer and look.
The suburbs of Russia
is much nicer than ours.
It really is.
Of course.
They've developed for so many years.
Why does the signal tower
have Chinese characters on it?
That is the evidence of
the mightiness of our country.
Not only do we install
base stations abroad,
but also put Chinese Characters on them.
Not minding that the foreigners
can't read it.
This is the confidence when we are strong.
Oh my. What's that?
The Russians
have hair-loss issues.
（Russian） Hair.
What are you wearing?
Why are you wearing the sweater
underneath your shirt?
It's not neat. Take it off
and change it to the outside.
Well,
Ma Liang.
Why is it stuck again?
Is it because my signal in the house?
Probably because you two are too far apart.
He is right under the signal tower,
there is no way he has signal problem.
Ma Liang.
What kind of lousy signal is this?
Over.
Incoming call!
Sweetheart.
Take a look.
Look at those baby hands.
Young man, have you seen
an art exhibition before?
-- No.
-- It's your lucky day then.
Come on. It's my treat for you
to see my husband's collection.
-- I have things to do.
-- It'll only take three minutes.
Come on.
Very good. Bye.
Huixang Village Archway
Completion Works Ceremony
The turnover of my grocery store
has doubled.
I decided to open a branch
in the east of the village.
Mr. Secretary, the young people who
had migrated to the big cities
are now returning.
The farms are no longer
short of hands.
Mr. Secretary, we sold more
than 100 kilos of
homemade sausages this week.
-- I will bring some to you.
-- Well, I...it's my wife.
Shush.
Hello?
Honey,
you 're still in bed.
Check out my makeup.
I'm about to get my pregnancy photos taken.
Who is this? So attractive.
Is she my wife?
You're so annoying.
So full of it.
Don't wear anything revealing.
It might affect the baby.
Rest assured, Mr. Artist.
We'll take good care of your wife.
Good. Where are you now?
Don't wander too far.
Not very far from our home,
there is a new tourist resort.
Let me show you.
You see, it's quite popular.
It is.
Okay, you take care.
I'm getting up.
Meeting dismissed.
Keep Our Mission Firmly In Mind
It's really good.
They sell everything here.
I want that one.
No, too many additives.
-- Barbeque.
-- Barbeque, in your situation?
You're such a bummer.
Ice cream. I'll get some.
Hi, kids.
Was she my lover from a previous life?
Mr. Chief, ice cream for you.
-- I really shouldn't take it.
-- Thank you.
What are you doing?
So reckless.
-- What?
-- It's me. Ma.
It's bad. My wife is here.
-- Where?
-- See?
-- Those three.
-- Yeah.
No wonder she looks so familiar.
Guard the viewing deck.
Don't let them see the paddy field tableau.
My wife has seen my sketches.
-- Okay.
-- Let me think.
Careful, careful.
Popcorn alert!
I've got an idea.
Let's do a petal throwing set.
We shouldn't pick flowers.
No, we won't.
I prepare it beforehand.
Throwing rose petals in a sunflower field?
That's dumb.
It'll look like we're spitting blood.
It will look very pretty.
Cut it out. Go away.
Go away.
Go away. Quick.
Go play over there.
Brother Goose, could you
help us take some photos?
Don't be shy.
It won't take long.
Come on.
Your costume is mad cute.
Come on. This way.
Come.
Now I got a new idea,
Let's do an animal set.
Wow, the big goose
So cute.
Hello.
Look, he's being shy.
Let's take a couple of photos.
I will just stand here.
Okay.
Beautiful.
Good. Another pose.
Another one.This time,
not shy, just happy.
Yeah
Make a heart sign.
Good.
This is a good one.
Now, hold.
The lighting is amazing as well.
I'm holding him.
That's really good.
Brother Goose.
Thank you.
Bye bye.
Turn around.
You are unparalleled.
Sit down and have some rest, Xia.
Thank you, Goose.
Thank you for the food.
Here. Take a sip of this.
How much is it? Give him the money.
The level of service in this village
is unparalleled.
Xia, let's go back.
You can't exhaust yourself.
-- Yeah.
-- I'm fine.
It's just low blood sugar.
I'll be fine after I eat something.
Thank you. Come.
It's too hot, take off your head wear
and have some water.
You're such a devoted mascot.
You guys have made this place
really nice.
Meng Meng, hand me the phone.
I want to call my husband.
Why is it so dark on your side?
Sweetheart,
I keep the light off.
I don't want to wake up my roommates.
What time is it?
There should be daylight already.
Daylight is short over here.
Let me tell you something really weird.
The place I am taking pictures today
looks exactly the same
as the place you do outdoor paintings
in Russia.
I'm not kidding.
Look.
Same, right?
No,
Not a little.
Look harder.
Don't they look alike?
Even the signal towers are
exactly the same.
Honey,
I suddenly feel that you're
very close to me,
like right by my side.
Sweetheart,
you miss me so much that
you're having an illusion.
Sweetheart,
I just had a bad dream.
Guess what?
I dreamt that you fell from a high place.
So today,
high places like rooftop,
water tower
and viewing deck
are off limits. You hear me?
-- Especially viewing decks.
-- I'm pregnant.
What high places do you expect me to climb?
Alright. I'm hanging up.
There is a viewing deck.
Let's go see the paddy field tableau.
What's wrong? You forget to
bring toilet paper?
(Pregnant woman, long hair photographer,
as well as accompanies are now allowed)
Damn.
This is specific.
We're completely ruled out.
The 'as well as'
must be referring to me.
Why aren't pregnant women allowed?
Up there
has been freshly painted.
Formaldehyde is above
the maximum level.
Photographers?
The paddy field tableau
involves business secrets.
Professional photographers are
not allowed to access for the moment.
What about the long hair?
According to international conventions,
photographers with long hair tend to be
more professional.
And the 'as well as',
how did you predict that?
Aren't you traveling together?
-- Yeah.
-- Then that's it.
A country has its laws
and a village has its rules.
After your baby is born.
After you cut your hair,
and after you grow up,
I will welcome you with gongs and drums,
guiding you through every corner
of this village.
Now, go home.
Did we offend anyone?
This is going too far.
As an apology
we offer some local products
for the three of you.
After all, there aren't many
tourist groups
that meet all the criteria.
Congratulations.
This village has a fair amount of rules.
But I do appreciate the way
they handle complaints.
I love my dancing hair.
Honey, look, the photos
I took today.
Are they beautiful?
This sausage is really tasty.
Xia, try it.
The sausage from that village is so yummy.
This sausage tastes the same
as the ones sent by Ma Liang
from Russia.
It does?
It's from the guy in the village.
Turn around.
We haven't left anything behind.
What happened?
Say something?
Isn't that Mr. Ma?
Xia.
Thank God, I was cool at the time.
With a few boxes of local products,
I sent them away.
Wow!
In order to deal with this tigress,
I spent so much time
practicing trilling words
with Mr. Secretary.
Do you know how to say Tigress
in Russian?
（Russian） Tigress
Teacup.
（Russian） Teacup
Nice to meet you.
（Russian） Nice to meet you
If you are meeting people
for the first time, then you --
No tipping off!
Freeze!
You move, you get a photo.
Calabash Dolls.
Who's that?
Outrageous.
Give the toilet paper back.
Where are you?
We are here.
I'm here.
Qiu Xia,
there is something that
I have been hiding from you.
I meant to confess to you
after our baby's birth.
You know I grew up in a small village
where I believe is the
most beautiful place in the world.
But now,
many villages are getting old,
all the young people have left,
and I've been thinking
what can I do for this?
So,
So what?
Ma Liang, you got new skills.
You led the whole village to fool me.
Please forgive him.
Please.
You gave up Repin for this.
I thought the first secretary
must be having a good time.
But I heard that
you don't even have time for proper meals.
You're not making much money.
And you give your wage
together with the allowance I sent you
to the old widows
and young widows in the village.
And widowers too.
No. Don't beat him.
I've been bragging to everyone I met,
telling them that my husband
got accepted by Repin.
The only one in Northeast China.
My parents used to say
that you were unaccomplished.
Now they all call you a late bloomer.
But now,
I'm sorry.
I will ask my parents
and all my friends
to come here and see it for themselves.
I'm going to tell them proudly
that my husband
got admitted by Repin
but he chose not to go.
Because he chose a much nobler cause.
To satisfy the needs of the people
Hui people, and people of all
ethnic groups across the country...
Enough, Honey.
This is a viewing deck,
not a rostrum.
Sweetheart
you are the greatest artist in the world.
I wish the best for my hometown
and a good life for everyone there.
I hope my hometown would soon
get rid of poverty.
And become a glamorous metropolis.
Our beef meatballs would take
the world by storm.
I want them to be sweet.
I heart Xinjiang.
Mom,dad,you guys don't have
to worry about me.
I'm a grownup now.
I've always wanted to go to the Nadam Fair.
Now I'm at the Nadam Fair everyday.
Hopefully, we don't have to leave
our home for big cities.
And small towns could
also have a better future and soon.
I wish my mom back home
would enjoy her life every day,
waiting for me to return.