Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
Lulu!
Mmm.
Lou.
Stop!
- Lou, it's up time.
- Mm-hmm.
Up time.
- Huh?
- Yeah.
Come on.
Come on, stop that.
We got to get right to it
for grizzle.
- Remember?
- Okay.
Yo, I got some
smoothie for you.
You're gonna fuckin' hate it.
But it's healthy.
Want some?
I wouldn't recommend it.
- It's disgusting.
- Mm-hmm.
Okay, poops.
Dance time.
Yes!
No?
Nah? No?
Okay.
♪ And I would do
anything for love ♪
♪ But he won't do that ♪
What's the thing that
he won't do in that song?
What's left for him to not do?
Anal.
- ♪ No, no, but I won't do that ♪
- ♪ He won't do that ♪
I used to imagine
Jeff Goldblum was my dad.
Saw him in "The (fucking) Fly",
I was like,
"That must be what
my dad looks like."
Also explains a lot 'cause
the dude's fucking weird.
But he looks like me, man.
It's true, yeah.
Yeah!
You kinda look
like Jeff Goldblum.
Why is it okay to use a
toothpick in public but not floss?
Have you ever tried that?
- To floss my teeth in public? No.
- To floss in public.
Like you're just at the dinner
table, you just pull out some...
I used to imagine
my funeral a lot
when I was a kid...
...at school in math.
Fun!
I used to daydream
about my funeral.
Then I'd make myself cry!
Uh, yeah, I think
I'd get cremated.
- What about you?
- Cremated...
or, like, just fed to the birds,
ya know?
Well, you know, now you can get
ashes put into
tattoo ink.
My face on your back,
where the clown is.
- What?
- Yeah.
♪ Scary clown face ♪
Yo, we don't need to,
we don't need to put 'em all out.
I know, but we just need
to fill 'em up a little bit.
Okay.
You want to put out
some different ones?
Hmm?
The face of a sale.
Okay, this one costs, uh,
50 bucks extra because...
- It's an original artwork.
- I'm gonna spit on.
Okay, a hundred bucks.
Ten grand.
Did you guys sound check?
No, not yet.
We're going on at...
- ...five?
- Did Margaret sound check yet?
Yo, you sound checked yet?
No.
Not looking forward to it.
Terrified.
Half my shit is broken down.
Ah.
It's... it's probably
a two out of ten
in terms of his hearing.
He can't...
He's having trouble even
communicating with me.
It's...
I gotta see a doctor?
He...
He can see you now.
- What?
- He can see you right now.
- Now?
- Yes, I...
Hey, Lulu.
Uh, sorry I had to run out, baby.
I gotta
deal with some shit, okay?
Don't worry about anything,
okay?
Mr. Stone?
Oh. Oh, yeah.
Ah.
Okay, how is that volume?
Is the volume loud enough?
Good.
Can you hear me?
What?
You can hear me okay?
- Volume wise?
- I can hear you.
Okay.
I'm gonna say these words.
I want you to repeat them
back to me.
I'm gonna start
with just your right ear.
Okay?
Bass.
Mess.
Mace.
Car.
Crave.
Mop.
Noisy.
Search.
Throat.
Ditch.
Fish.
Talk.
T...
Ring.
Broom.
Germ.
Life.
Team.
Lid.
This is your chart, Ruben.
Now, as far as the volume
that you can hear,
you... on your right ear
were twenty-eight percent,
and on your left ear,
you were twenty-four percent.
- It's what?
- In the left ear,
- you came in at twenty-four percent.
- Okay.
No matter how...
loud I made the test,
I could have put it at eleven,
you were still going to miss
seventy to eighty percent of the words
that I said.
Okay.
That is not good.
Yeah, I see that.
So what...
What can we do about it?
How do I get it back?
Well, um...
You have to understand
something here.
Whether or not this is related to
your exposure to noise
or it's an autoimmune issue
doesn't really matter.
I understand I got a problem.
I'm asking you what I can do
about it.
Well, what you can do
about it first
is to eliminate all exposure
to loud noises.
And then we can run some tests
and we can determine exactly
what is going on with your ears.
And if we do, then we can have
our other conversations.
We can have what?
Well...
there are implants
that bypass the cochlea.
You said implants?
- Yes.
- Those work?
For people with severe
hearing loss or
complete deafness,
yes, they help.
Well, then let's do that.
Well...
it's not that simple.
Uh, it's a very involved process
and it's quite costly.
How much is it?
Well, they can run between forty
and eighty thousand dollars
depending, and...
they are not covered
by insurance.
Okay.
And, um...
Like, when,
when can you do it?
You got 'em in stock now?
Mr. Stone,
your hearing...
is deteriorating rapidly.
Am I right?
And over the next few days,
or even hours,
it's going to continue.
And the hearing that you have lost
is not coming back.
You have to understand
your first responsibility
is to preserve
the hearing you have.
Ruben, what the fuck?
Yes, it'll come back.
I have to...
There's like a surgery.
What?
It's simple.
It's all it is.
There's an implant.
They put it in your shit.
It's like a...
Okay, it'll come back.
It's fine, Lou.
It's like forty grand,
eighty grand, whatever,
but it's...
...it'll come back.
Till then, Lou,
we just keep going, okay?
- No.
- Lou?
- Listen to me.
Let's play tomorrow,
let's see what it's like.
Let's try it, okay?
I'm gonna be like a click track.
You can play to me.
No.
Huh? You can adj...
It's different,
but it is what it is, Lou.
Lou, we have a t...
Lou, we have a tour booked.
It's not safe...
We have a tour booked.
- We have a tour booked, Lou.
- No.
It doesn't matter. It doesn't matter.
- Yes, we do.
- It's not safe, it's not safe.
We have a tour booked!
- Ruben.
- I don't fuckin'...
Yo!
You got a smoke, please?
This is ridiculous.
He's sleeping.
Hi.
Hi, Hector?
Hi, this is Lou.
Ruben's having a bit of...
a bit of trouble right now.
- He's...
- Hey, Hector, what's up?
He's got some hearing
problems.
Yeah, I mean I can put him on,
but he won't be able
to hear you.
Okay.
Talk to him.
Hey, Hector,
what's going on, man?
It's Ruben.
I'd say it's good
to hear your voice,
but I can't hear a fuckin' word
you're saying right now.
So this is completely pointless.
Lou wanted me to call you
because I had a cigarette.
Uh...
you know...
not great, not ideal, but...
considering the circumstances,
which are pretty fucked up.
You know, understandable.
I'd say understandable,
for everyone apart from Lou,
it seems.
Um...
I got this, bro.
I know you'd probably be asking
me if I'm steady right now,
if I'm feeling level.
Not completely,
but I'm cool.
You'd tell me serenity
is something you get
when you, uh,
stop wishing
for a different past.
Bro, I love you, man.
Oh, my manager wants the phone back,
so I gotta go.
Okay, love you, bro.
Hey.
Yeah, he can't hear a word.
Well, if you get him to a group,
then how is he gonna hear?
Okay.
Okay, tha... thanks, Hector,
thank you.
When? When?
Okay, yeah,
I'll make sure it's on loud.
Okay, thank you so much,
thank you.
Okay, bye.
He's gonna call back.
What did he say?
Write it down. Tell... What did he...
"Call back."
He's gonna call back... that's all?
Fuckin' Hector.
What are we gonna do now?
What do you wanna do, Lou?
Huh?
Fuck this.
It's Hector.
Hey.
Yeah, he's here.
Not so good.
Oh...
Okay.
Uh...
yeah, what, what,
what is it and...
What?
What's the plan?
Uh...
Well, we're, we're in Missouri,
so that's gonna take
a few days.
I don't... I don't really know.
No, no...
No, we'll leave right away.
Okay, yeah.
Okay, thank you. Thank you so much.
I really, really appreciate it.
Thank you.
No, yeah, I'll tell him.
Okay.
Bye.
What?
He's found a place.
Is that him?
Ruben.
Hi, I don't...
I'm sorry, I don't know that.
I'm Ruben.
This is Lou.
Hi, I'm... I'm Lou.
I'm sorry, I read lips.
My name is Lou.
- Lou. I'm Joe.
- Hi, Joe.
You mind if I borrow him
for a minute?
No.
All right, you mind
watching my beast here for me
while we have a talk?
Well, okay.
- Lou, this is Louie.
- Oh.
He's my hearing dog.
He let me know you were here.
I named it after Louie Aparicio
from the White Sox in '59.
You want to be
best friends with him,
- give him one of these.
- Oh, sure.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
Yo, what about...
Lou, you coming?
No, no, you.
- You sure?
- Yeah.
I won't be long, okay?
Okay.
You be a good boy!
Uh...
Test.
Oh.
Okay.
So,
it works.
Is this okay for you?
Yeah, can you hear me?
No. No, I'm gonna read your lips.
I might miss some things,
but I'm gonna try, okay?
- Okay.
- Just try, try to speak clearly.
Yeah.
How are you, Ruben?
I'm okay.
You're an addict?
Yeah.
What sort of drugs?
What'd I take?
Mm-hmm.
Everything.
Um...
Mainly heroin.
Heroin.
Have you thought about using
since you lost your hearing?
Today is not a good day.
I'm not thinking clear today.
Let's talk about me.
I'm an alcoholic.
I lost my hearing in
the Vietnam War
when a bomb exploded near me.
I still remember the music
I was listening to
when that bomb went off.
After that,
I lost everything else...
my wife,
my kid.
Not because of being deaf,
mind you, Ruben.
It was the beer.
How long you been clean?
Four years.
- Four?
- Mmm.
And you need some help
right now?
Yo, I should check on Lou.
How long you two
been together?
Four years.
You play music, right?
- No.
- No?
No, not anymore.
Not until I get the implant.
Implant?
Yeah. Sorry, you know about
these implants they got now?
It's like... it's like, uh...
they have implants.
I know. Yes.
Expensive.
Yeah, thank you,
yes, they are.
So...
You should understand
that, uh...
this is a Deaf community,
not just my program,
but we're part
of a larger Deaf community.
And my program,
and the people in it,
they benefit
tremendously from that Deaf community.
We work with them
and they work with us.
But...
it's very important,
if you want to be here,
to understand
that we're looking for
a solution to...
to this...
...not this.
Why don't you go
invite Lou in here?
Sure.
Lou!
This guy wants to
talk to you.
Okay.
Well...
I think it's important that you stay here
with us right now, Ruben,
learn some sign language,
find some solid ground.
What do you think?
Man, it sounds great,
but we don't have
a lot of money right now.
Well, sometimes our church
sponsors deaf people in need, and
right now,
you fit the bill, Ruben.
We're really not
- churchgoing people.
- Sorry, I... I read...
Sorry, Ruben, I read lips.
I can't...
What'd you say?
We're not religious,
either of us.
Very much not into religion,
no offense, you know.
Religion plays no part
in this, Ruben.
The church helps
people in need,
not religious people.
The important thing is that
you want to stay here.
Mmm.
Yeah.
Lou?
Do you think Ruben
needs help right now?
You understand, if, uh...
Ruben were to stay here,
he'd have to do it on his own.
Members live in a house
separate from the outside world.
No contact to the outside world,
no phones.
I've found that
in all cases,
that's the way it works best.
Yo, hold up a minute, okay?
Let me catch up.
Okay?
Can you help Ruben commit
to that, Lou?
You want, you want to
try this for a couple days?
We have our own home.
We can stay in the RV.
No, I'm sorry to say,
that's not the way
that it works here, Ruben.
Well, that's a problem, then.
Do you have anywhere you can
be during this time, Lou?
Yo, that's that, man.
We're done.
Thanks a lot for
your time, bro.
Appreciate it, okay?
We're out, baby.
Let's go.
Hey.
Lou...
I'm thinking
we should still go hit
our fuckin' show
in Dayton.
Okay? I can, I can
fuckin' watch you
for cues.
I know it was rocky last time
but we did...
we weren't on the same page.
Now you know what's up,
I can fuckin' watch you.
And I know this shit
inside out.
Okay, yo.
I can fuckin' make it work
until we have enough
for surgery.
Okay?
We're gonna get there.
Yo, seriously,
we're good to go.
Lou.
Hmm?
Hey, I'll deal with this shit.
I'll deal with it.
You know I fucking will.
It's just money.
You know that, right?
Huh?
Come here.
Ruben!
Stop it!
Lou, look at me,
I'm not going back
to that fuckin' place,
okay?
I know.
I'm...
Well, then fuckin'
support me.
How's about that?
Fuckin' support me, Lou.
Huh?
You don't want to be here?
Of course I do.
I knew it.
I fuckin' knew it.
I fuckin' knew this was coming.
This is about
the fuckin' album, huh?
What happened?
You get a better offer?
- What are you talking about?
- Huh?
- What are you saying?
- I can't hear,
I can't hear you.
I can't fucking hear you!
Do you understand me?
I can't, I'm fuckin' deaf.
I'm fucking deaf!
No fucking hearing!
Okay?
No, what I need, what I need is
a fucking gun in my mouth.
What I need is a fucking gun
in my fucking mouth!
Okay?!
Look, I'm sorry.
Lou, I'm just fucked up a little.
I just need a little...
I need a minute to think.
Okay?
There's gotta be another way.
Lou?
Hello?
Hey.
Oh, really?
Oh.
Who is that?
Okay, well,
I need to get ready. Okay.
No, I'll get a cab.
Yeah, it's fine.
Okay, bye.
What's going on?
Huh?
I'm getting on a plane
and you're gonna go back to that place.
Just slow down, okay?
Slow down!
Yo, chill dude,
we're gonna be a minute.
Just chill.
Okay?
Just slow down a minute.
Lou.
This is so fucked up.
Who's gonna be looking out
for you over there?
Hmm?
- Who's gonna look out for you?
- It's okay.
- Don't say that guy.
- It's okay. It's okay.
Lou, I need, I need more
of a plan, Lou.
- Ruben.
- I need...
I need more from you, Lou.
I need more of a plan, Lou.
You can't just fuckin'...
Ah, Jesus.
Lou, come on.
Ruben.
You hurt yourself...
Ruben. You hurt yourself,
you hurt me.
I'll hurt myself, too.
Don't say that.
Promise.
Say it, Rubi,
or all of this is for shit.
Say it!
Promise!
Go back there right now.
Promise, say it!
I'll promise if you...
No, say it, promise.
Go back to that place.
I, only if, I need...
I need you to wait for me.
Okay? You're it for me, Lou.
You're my fuckin' heart.
You're it for me.
Okay?
You gotta wait for me.
Fuck.
Listen to me, listen, listen.
When you get there,
I need you to,
I need you to write to me, okay?
Yeah?
Will you write me
and tell me you're okay?
Huh? Promise me?
And listen, if it's...
If it's bullshit, you just get
your ass back here.
I'll fix it, I swear to God.
You know
I'll fuckin' fix this.
This is not that hard, okay?
Just come back here.
- I love you.
- You're my fucking heart.
Okay?
Motherfucker.
Oh, motherf...
Fuck.
Motherfucker.
Oh.
Fuck.
Motherfucker.
What's up?
Yo.
Hey.
You want my car keys?
If I ask for 'em back,
I want 'em back, okay?
We're not doing that.
Your name.
My name's Ruben.
I'm an addict.
I have four years clean now.
I'm sorry I don't...
talk sign language.
That's it.
Oh...
Fuck.
What?
Okay.
Um...
I don't...
Sorry.
Ruben.
Ru-ben.
Oh.
Okay.
Yeah.
Uh, I'm coming.
Okay?
One minute.
I'll be back.
Oh, hey, Joe.
What was that
all about, Ruben?
Oh, with your roof?
I was fixing your roof.
It's like, one of the eaves is...
I was trying to fix your roof.
You don't need to fix
anything here.
Okay.
I've got a little, uh...
assignment for ya.
Okay?
You get up early, right?
Yeah, pretty early, yeah.
I'll have hot coffee
waiting for you
at 5:30.
Early enough for you?
I don't know.
I guess.
Okay, 5:00.
And I'll, uh,
provide a room for you.
What for?
And there's nothing that needs
to be accomplished in this room.
All I want you to do
is just...
...sit.
All I ask
is if and when you
cannot just sit,
you turn yourself to the
pen and paper
that I'm gonna supply for you.
And I want you to...
...write.
Doesn't matter what you write,
how you write,
whether it's spelled correctly.
Or if it's just a big...
...mess.
I don't care.
No one will read it, okay?
But I want you to keep writing
continuously without stopping
until you feel like
you can...
sit again.
Does it have to be writing?
Writing, yes.
No drawing.
And if...
...sometime in the future,
it feels like it's a little bit
too difficult for you,
you should come and find me.
I'll be in my apartment
doing the same thing as you,
okay, Ruben?
I'll be writing, too.
Okay.
Ah!
Mmm, nice.
Nice, nice, nice.
So fuckin' stupid.
It's so fuckin' stupid.
You fuckin' idiot.
I'm a fuckin' idiot.
Hey.
You think he's okay?
You okay?
No.
Not feeling better? Come on over.
Look at those flowers.
He's quick.
Alright, come here, my friend.
See, I knew he had it.
A, B, C, D, E, F, G,
H, I, J, K, L, M, N...
R, S, T, U, V,
W, X, Y, Z.
He won.
-No, no, he won.
-It was close.
No, he won. You can go
again if you want to.
Again! Again! Again! Again!
A, B, C, D,
G, H, I, J, K, L,
T, U, V,
O, Q...
R, S, T, U, V, W,
X, Y, Z.
Yes!
See?
Good job! You did it!
No, I thought...
I thought you said you were smart.
But your wife and your daughter
are better, right?
See?
He knows!
He already knows.
I don't like it completely shaved.
I prefer it with a little hair.
Whoa, not too much.
Natural, got it.
Trimmed and all, ya know?
Lovely.
Who is she?
Okay, okay.
Where do you want it?
Right here.
I like it.
Cool. Thank you.
My bad.
Watch me.
Slowly.
I feel a little bit old today.
- You are old.
- Yeah.
I love your name sign...
...Ruben.
That first day you were here
you reminded me of an owl.
O-W-L?
Owl.
Fuck you.
And you've become very important
to a lot of people around here.
You know?
It's true.
Thank you.
I'd like to offer you a...
...a way that
maybe you can continue on here
with us.
I imagine you're starting
to think about the future
a little bit?
- Future?
- Future.
I know I am.
But, uh...
I do think there's a way
you could maybe stay
and work here,
maybe with my program,
maybe...
...with the kids at school.
Maybe both.
Anyway...
you, uh...
you think about it,
you know?
What the fuck?
Her?
Yeah.
Sexy.
Cute.
What do you think, huh?
Yo, what do you think?
This?
Yeah.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Wait, yo, it's easy.
It's easy. Just...
...slowly.
Yo...
...It's for her, huh?
It's for her.
We need money.
Huh?
It's for us.
I'm leveling with you.
It's for her.
Yo.
For this... for this?
For this,
remember it's, uh... it's, uh...
cash.
Okay? Not check.
Cool.
Yo?
You okay?
Sure?
Hi, is that Prince Audiology?
Can you hear me?
It's Stone, Ruben Stone.
R-U-B-E-N,
Stone, S-T-O-N-E.
I'm confirming an appointment.
Yeah, I can hold.
So, listen.
- What did you say? Write it down.
- Yeah, yeah.
I can't hear you.
Write it down.
I got a proposition for you.
What's that?
What if I give it to you
at this price...
...but on one condition.
I have the option
of coming back to you
within eight weeks.
Okay?
I get to buy it back off you
for ten percent more than this.
But everything has to be
in its current condition.
Everything has to be exactly
like it is now.
Hmm?
What do you think?
Why would you want
to do that?
Dude, I can't hear you.
I'm deaf.
So... It's...
take it or leave it.
What's it gonna be?
You're back?
Have a seat here.
Thank you.
Um...
...I did the deed.
The deed?
Surgery.
How'd you get the money?
I sold my RV
and other shit.
- Okay.
- Look, Joe,
I really
don't want to explain myself
right now.
Okay?
It's time.
I gotta do something.
Right?
Trying to save my f...
fuckin' life.
So, that's what
I'm doing.
Okay? No one else is gonna
save my life.
Right?
If I just sit here and diddle around,
what am I gonna have?
Nothing.
Okay?
And all this shit?
Like, what does it matter? What does it matter?
It just passes.
Yo.
If I disappear,
like, who cares?
Nobody cares, man.
Seriously.
Yo, and that's okay.
That's life.
No, for real. Okay?
It just passes.
It just fuckin'...
fucking passes.
I wonder, uh...
all these mornings
you've been sitting in my study,
sitting,
have you...
had any...
moments of...
...stillness?
Because you're right, Ruben,
the world does keep moving,
and it can be a damn...
...cruel place.
But for me...
those moments of...
...stillness,
that place,
that's the...
...kingdom of God.
And that place
will never abandon you.
But...
I see you've made your
choice.
Right?
Yeah.
And I sincerely hope
that it brings you happiness, Ruben.
Thank you.
I was wondering, Joe.
I don't know if it's possible,
but, uh...
I need money,
to, uh...
just to buy back my RV.
You know?
You know, me...
me and Lou.
This is where we live.
It's our home. Our home.
And I can...
I can totally pay you back.
Just, uh...
Now I got an issue with time.
Ruben.
I don't understand the situation
that you've put yourself in.
But...
from where I'm sitting...
you look
and sound
like an addict.
No, I don't.
Yo, no.
I'm not...
It's not...
Not an addi...
It's fine. Okay?
My situation,
it's cool.
Okay?
Seriously, my girlfriend's dad is rich,
he can give me...
give me the money.
Okay?
This is nothing.
You can't imagine how nothing this is.
Seriously.
I'm fucking stupid...
I'm... I'm sorry to ask.
I'm sorry.
Okay?
Okay.
Please can I stay here for just...
three, four weeks?
Till they...
activate?
Ruben.
As you know,
everybody here
shares in the belief that
being deaf is not a handicap.
Not something to fix.
It's pretty important
around here.
All these kids...
all of us,
need to be reminded of it
every day.
And my house
is a house built on that belief,
and built on trust.
And when that trust is violated,
things happen.
And I can't have that.
There are too many others
to consider.
And so,
in your current state,
at this time,
I'm going to have to ask you to pack up
your bags, today,
and find another place to be, Ruben.
Cool.
Ah.
Are you ready?
Okay.
Here we go.
Can you hear me?
Say again.
- Can you hear me?
- Whoa.
How does it sound?
Uh, sounds weird.
Okay, well, let's try
making an adjustment.
How about now?
How's that?
Oh, that's bad.
Um...
It's... bad.
Do you want to describe
what you're hearing?
It's, um...
It's like...
...high.
High.
Um...
Can you change the...
Well, I can try and make
another adjustment.
How's that?
Okay.
Ruben, this is not sound
like you remember,
and it's the implants
in your head that's
tricking your brain
into thinking that you're
actually hearing,
when
in reality your ears
aren't working still.
So, uh,
I would suggest that you
take it easy
for the next few weeks and...
just...
get adjusted to...
how things sound.
And just...
...take your time.
Oui?
Bonjour?
Yeah, hi, is that, um...
Is, is Lou there?
Hein?
C'est qui?
Who... who is this?
This is Ruben.
Qui?
It's Ruben.
Oh.
Hmm.
Hey.
Bonjour, uh...?
Ruben.
Come in.
You are hungry, Ruben?
Yes?
Uh, Louise is not here.
Uh, you are hearing?
Y... You are hearing?
Yeah.
I... I had an operation.
Wow!
Yes?
Oh!
What is this?
Oh, that's very good.
Louise told me
your wish for this.
Oh.
And so, uh...
So, you're back to your drums now?
Uh, not yet.
I gotta, I gotta, um,
I gotta deal with some stuff first,
you know?
Just gotta...
gotta settle some things.
Yes, settle...
...like what?
You know, just like
getting back into it
- and also some financial stuff.
- Yes.
You know,
I just gotta figure it all out.
Mm-hmm.
Yes.
And Louise knows
that you're here?
No.
So, it's a big surprise, oui?
Well, Louise has been
quite busy, you know?
Mm-hmm.
We're doing a party, so...
...she'll be back home tonight, that's
most certainly.
Oh, you want...
I'm going to make you some eggs.
Oh, no, I'm good.
Do you need any help
with any of this?
No, no.
You need some eggs.
Thanks.
Where did you grow, Ruben?
Where did I grow up?
- Yes.
- Um...
like, all over.
You know, Texas, California,
Arizona, Virginia.
Yeah.
All over.
Why so many places?
It was...
like, uh...
my mom was a nurse in the military.
- Mm-hmm.
- You know.
So she kept moving around.
And your father, too?
No.
I mean, I don't know.
I see.
Uh, I must be honest, I...
did not always have good feelings
for you, Ruben,
all these years.
I confide it is like if one...
had stolen something...
...precious.
You understand?
But I know it's not you that took
Louise from me.
Her mother did that.
She took Louise
when she left me.
And she took her again
when she killed herself.
And Louise must have
come back home then,
but she was hating me so much.
What could I do?
And you...
you...
Well, you gave her a place
to go.
Then, and...
...this is a good thing.
Don't you see, I didn't like you
much at the time,
but now I thank you.
I want to say to you that.
But anyhow,
you're gonna be
so happy to see
how Louise
is going great now.
And that's the most important.
Isn't it?
Hmm?
Okay.
Whoa.
Whoa!
Hi.
Can you hear me?
Yeah.
Loud and clear.
Oh, look at you, Lulu.
Holy shit.
Look at you, huh?
What?
You look different.
Whoa, no scratching, huh?
Oh, yeah.
That's good.
Does it feel weird?
Yeah.
Does it look weird?
No.
No, it doesn't.
It looks really neat.
Mmm.
So crazy.
Mm-hmm.
How'd you do it?
Just worked some magic.
I have to talk to you about it.
I had to just move
some things around.
Louise, tu desends?
Um...
Did Richard tell you
about this party thing tonight?
Oh, shit, yeah.
Yeah, I just have to go
and sort some things out.
- No, it's great. It's cool.
- Yeah.
- Go do your thing.
- Okay.
Do you need anything?
No, I'm good.
I'll just be downstairs.
Hey.
Ruben, mon petite ami.
What's up?
- Come again?
- How are you?
How are you?
- Did you get some food?
- Hmm?
Get some food?
Yeah?
I would like to make a wish.
I would like my daughter to
sing a little song with me.
Papa, no.
This is my right... It's my birthday!
Come.
Oh!
Some of you knew
Louise's mother,
and know that I wrote songs for her...
...many.
And this was your favorite
when you were little.
Do you remember?
Hey.
You okay?
- Hmm?
- Yeah.
Um, sorry.
I just need some water.
Are you okay?
- Mm-hmm.
- Yeah?
Yeah, it's just
a little dry in here.
Hey, that was, uh...
pretty cool tonight.
You sounded fuckin' great.
- Yeah, right.
- What?
You're telling me
you weren't feeling it?
- You were in it.
- Well, yeah, well, that's...
Straight up, you sounded
amazing singing like that.
It's my dad's stuff, but...
And you're
speaking French now?
- Oh, my God, barely.
- I didn't know you could do that.
Well, I've mostly forgotten, but...
it's coming back a little.
Yeah, I was thinking, like,
do you remember,
you remember this place
at all?
I didn't, but...
...so disconcerting the things that
your memory holds onto
without you knowing.
I don't know, my...
my mom and I never really
talked about this place.
It was always some
weird, dreamy idea, but...
I mean...
now it's come back a little.
Right.
Yeah.
I told everyone about our
little gypsy life together.
I miss it.
We gotta get back into it.
You know?
We gotta get back on it,
we gotta get back in the fuckin'...
in the groove, huh?
Don't you think?
I gotta go get the Airstream sorted.
What do you mean sorted?
I just, I just got a shit ton
of things to do.
- You know?
- Right.
Like with the tour and stuff?
- Yeah, the fuckin' tour, everything.
- Yeah.
Like, we just gotta
get back on it,
- you know, everything,
- Mm-hmm.
the album, the tour...
...the, the...
...you know?
Yeah.
Hey.
It's okay, Lou.
What?
It's okay.
What's okay?
You saved my life.
You made it...
you made it beautiful.
So it's okay.
What?
Why are you saying this?
You saved my life, too, Rubi.
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org