Oh, but this is great.
- Wow!
- Thas incredible.
There's gotta be at least seven
or eight feet up there.
And 80 years of dust.
Look at all this height.
We could put our bedroom upstairs,
and that will leave us with all this space.
- For what?
- Just space.
One, two, three!
- And four?
- Come on.
Four.
And five.
Watch... Watch this.
God, this place is huge.
- Is beautiful.
- God.
- You guys, is absolutely incredible.
- Incredible.
A little paint.
I'd say you could sell this tomorrow
and double your money.
- Carl, you're obsessed.
- A little bit.
Whoa, look.
Hey, is an Indian-head penny.
1898.
- Is a good omen.
- You're the good omen.
Oh, is so great.
I had Rose move your 3:00
with Bob Kahan to 4:00,
'cause Gary Alan called
at the end of the day yesterday
and said he has to see you
about the final painting bids for the loft.
3:00 is the only time he could make it.
Is that okay?
Sam?
What are you doing?
- Would you relax, man?
- Oh, I'm sorry.
This is not brain surgery
you're going into.
Pitching these Japanese guys
makes me so nervous.
Sam, you're going to be great. Okay?
I mean, what am I supposed to say?
I mean, I can't very well tell them my
Swedish pom-pom girl joke, you know.
Those are great.
Where'd you get those?
Nice, huh? Molly.
What do you think? Are they me?
Oh, man, look at that. A Testarossa.
I think you ought to pay off
your Mustang first.
How you feeling?
Whad the doctor say?
He said that it was contagious.
That it was really...
- No.
- Yeah.
He said that I shouldn't even
be coming in today.
- What about the rash?
- The rash?
The rash is also incredibly contagious.
- He said they've both been spreading.
- No.
- On your genitals again?
- Yeah, yeah. Right on the genitals.
Basically everywhere.
He said that I shouldn't touch anyone.
Excuse me. I'm sorry.
- You're sick.
- I know.
- Good morning, Paul.
- Good morning, Carl. Sam.
Hey, Paul.
- Morning, Mr. Wheat.
- Morning, Susan. You are looking good.
Sam.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Here it is.
- Thanks.
- Good morning, Sam.
- Good morning, Rose.
- Oh, listen, the Kobiashi people...
- They're already here.
- They're early.
- I know.
Come here.
Oh, and Andy Dillon called...
- How long have they been here?
- About 10 minutes.
Andy Dillon called and he says
he needs $900,000 transferred
to Albany by 10:00.
- By 10:00?
- Yes.
Excuse me.
- Carl?
- Yeah?
- Good morning.
- Carl.
Bill, hang on one second.
Dillon needs $900,000
in Albany by 10:00.
Can you transfer it
to his payroll account?
- Yeah, I'm gonna need your MAC code.
- Okay.
- Discretion, right?
- Got it.
- You bet. I'll do it right now.
- Okay, thanks.
Yeah. Bill, I'm going to
call you back. Okay.
Okay, okay, thas fine. Is fine. Is fine!
Man, is too far out.
Can you get this, man?
Where are you guys from,
the New York City Ballet?
Almost.
- Saved your life.
- You shit. You scared me to death.
Why did you do that?
Is better than seeing this gorgeous
body splattered all over the place.
Look out. Look out.
Grab it.
- Sam, Mol, are you guys home?
- Thas Carl. Did you invite him?
- Slave labor.
- Carl.
- What?
- Hurry, help.
Oh, my God.
- Near the bottom.
- I got it.
- Now go down.
- What? Just down here?
Yeah.
- Just right here?
- Watch your toes.
I got it.
- Hey, where do you want this?
- In the bedroom.
Good girl.
- God, this place looks great.
- Yeah.
- You like it, huh?
- Like? Like is hardly the word.
I had no idea id be this beautiful.
Is incredible.
Molly, what about her?
Well, why don't we just leave her there
until we get the other stuff in?
- We can figure out...
- What are these?
Oh, let me show you.
Hey, you wanna help me lift this up?
- What, here?
- Yeah.
Wow.
- I just finished it. What do you think?
- Is fantastic. I love it.
Sam, whas this chair doing here?
- What do you mean? I love that chair.
- I know you love this chair.
- But we discussed this and...
- Yeah, I've had it forever.
I mean just, when I watch TV, I sit in it.
- Baby, this chair is ugly.
- So?
- And it doesn't go with anything.
- It goes with me.
You're right. It does.
- We'll paint it.
- We'll what?
- You okay?
- I'm fine.
- Whas the matter?
- Nothing.
Are you worried about the promotion?
No, not really.
- Then what? Is it moving in together?
- No.
I don't know. Is a lot of things.
I just don't want the bubble to burst.
It seems like
whenever anything good
in my life happens,
I'm just afraid I'm going to lose it.
I love you. I really love you.
Ditto.
The pilos first report of trouble was
that he blew the number two engine,
the one in the tail of the plane.
It was fully loaded.
Oh, Jesus, another one.
Oh, don't watch that.
I should cancel my LA trip.
These things always happen in threes.
Sam, get serious.
Besides, you lead a charmed life.
Oh, yeah. So did they.
Is amazing, just like that. Blackout.
- What are you doing?
- I couldn't sleep.
Boy, I really must have passed out.
- What time is it?
- Is 2:00 a.m.
Oh, no. I hope it wasn't a masterpiece.
Well, is not now.
- Can I help?
- Yeah.
Put your hands up here. Get them wet.
Now, just let the clay slide
between your fingers.
Oh, no.
- Whas the matter?
- A glitch. Whas up?
The Mark Greenberg
and Larry White accounts.
I can't get in.
The MAC code doesn't work.
- No, I changed it.
- You changed it? Why?
Nothing. I just want
to nose around a bit.
Is something wrong?
- Can you keep a secret?
- Yeah, sure.
Whas up?
There's too much money
in these accounts.
Too much money?
Thas impossible. How could there be...
C72273.
Sam, this is going to take you hours.
Let me do this.
It already has taken me hours.
Well, let me take it back
and figure it out for you.
No, no, thas okay.
Is... Is like a vendetta now.
- Thanks, though. I appreciate it.
- Okay.
- Lf you start to go blind, just shout.
Listen, I was wondering,
what are you and Mol doing tonight?
We're going to the theater.
She wants to see Macbeth.
I think she likes the guys in tights,
personally.
- You want to go?
- No, thanks.
I want a full report, though.
- Later.
- Yeah.
Wonderful.
Excellent. Great.
- Well, I loved it.
- Yes.
I was spellbound the whole time.
I could tell.
And so could the rest of the audience
with that resonating snore of yours.
Did I tell you what Melissa said?
- Yeah, about six times.
- It wasn't six times.
- Now quit being so blasé about this.
- Okay.
Now, this is really important.
I'm gonna have two pieces
in her gallery.
The New York Times
reviews her gallery all the time.
Molly, The New York Times
is just some frustrated little critic
with pimples on his ass
who flunked out of art school.
So who cares what they think?
About eight million readers, thas who.
Nah, they're just reading
the sports page.
- Your work is really beautiful. It really is.
- Thanks.
And it shouldn't matter what
anyone else thinks. Just what I think.
I want to marry you, Sam.
What? What?
Yep.
I've been thinking about it.
I've been thinking about it a lot,
and I think we should just do it.
- You're serious.
- Yeah.
Whas that look for?
You never wanted to talk about it.
- Do you love me, Sam?
- Now, what do you think?
Why don't you ever say it?
What do you mean,
why don't I ever say it?
- I say it all the time. I feel like...
- No, you don't.
You say, "Ditto,"
and thas not the same.
People say "I love you" all the time,
and it doesn't mean anything.
You know,
sometimes you need to hear it.
I need to hear it.
Les go.
- What should we do?
- Let me handle it.
- What do you want?
- Shit.
Your wallet. Give it to me!
- Sam, just give it to him.
- Okay.
Just take the money. Just leave us...
No, no, Sam!
You son of a bitch!
Sam, no!
Somebody help us!
Jesus Christ! Sam!
Just get off!
Somebody! Somebody help us!
Sam, just let...
Sam, just stop it! Stop it, Sam!
Molly?
Molly? He got...
Oh, baby, hold on.
You're gonna be okay.
Somebody! Somebody!
Somebody help us!
Sam. Oh, my God.
Oh, Sam, come on. Hold on, baby.
Someone's gonna come.
We're gonna be okay.
Somebody! Somebody help me!
Please, anybody.
Help me, please, help me.
Is okay, lady. Take it easy, all right?
Oh, God!
We'll help you, okay?
Molly? Molly? Molly?
Molly.
What should we do?
What? Whas happening? Whas...
Is he breathing?
I don't know if he's breathing.
Oh, God, Sam, hold on.
Hold on, baby. Hold on.
Oh, my God.
Come on, man.
All right. Okay, come on, is all right.
Here we go.
All right, there you go. One, two...
Sam, don't you leave me! Sam, hold on!
Sam!
Oh, Sam!
...emergency room.
All right. Right away.
Miss Jensen,
if you'll step this way, please.
Cardiology, please dial extension 255...
- So, what happened to you?
- What?
You're new, huh? I can tell.
- Are you talking to me?
- Hey, relax.
It ain't like before, you know.
Is a whole new ball of wax.
- Who are you?
- Oh, I'm waiting for my wife.
She's in 4C, cardiac wing.
She's fighting it.
Shot, huh? Thall do it every time.
Poor bastard.
Hey, you may as well get used to it.
You could be here for a long while.
Come here, I'll tell you a secret.
Doors ain't as bad as you think.
Zip, zap, they ain't nothing at all.
You'll see. You'll catch on.
This patiens fibrillating.
Where's the paddles?
Get them up here.
He ain't gonna make it.
I've seen it a million times.
He's a goner.
- He's still fibrillating.
- Clear.
Clear.
You see? Here they come.
Lucky bastard.
It could have been the other ones.
You never know.
Who are...
Nursing supervisor,
dial the operator, please.
Nursing supervisor, dial the operator.
No!
Help me.
Oh, God, help me.
"I am sunk in the abysmal swamp
where there is no foothold.
"I have reached the watery depths.
"The flood overwhelms me.
"I am wearied with calling."
As we say farewell
to our friend Sam Wheat,
we are reminded of his kindness,
his generosity, his buoyancy of spirit.
All that we treasure, our loved ones,
our friends, our body, our mind,
are but on loan to us.
We must surrender them all.
We are all travelers on the same road
which leads to the same end.
As our loved one enters eternal life,
let us remember that love too is eternal.
That although we will miss him,
our love will light the void
and dispel the darkness.
I picked up your shirts today.
I don't know why.
Mr. Reynolds told me to tell you hello.
I broke into tears.
Is like I think about you every minute.
Is like I can still feel you.
I'm here, Mol.
Floyd, whas the matter, kitty?
Whas the matter?
Crazy cat.
Sam?
Thas really stupid.
- I love this picture.
- Is great.
Office.
Oh, let me see that.
Is...
- Sam's address book.
- Right.
Dave Brubeck, Newport, '88.
- Should I toss them?
- No.
No? Molly, we hated that concert.
Hey.
- Oh, you wanted to save those?
- Rolaids?
Molly, what are you doing?
- I just miss him, Carl.
- Me, too.
- Carl?
- Yeah?
Wait a minute. Wait.
- What?
- Not that one.
Which? Oh, I'm sorry.
- I didn't mean to put that on there.
- Thas okay.
Hey, Molly, why don't you come?
Is like summer outside.
No, I really don't. I... I'm not up for it.
Come on, Mol, just for a walk.
- Id be good for you to get out.
- I don't want to.
Molly, you can't stay in here all day.
- Is not healthy for you.
- Look, Carl, I can't do it!
Molly, you're not the one who died.
- I'm sorry.
- Don't apologize.
Shit.
Maybe you're right.
- Maybe just a short one.
- Attagirl.
- I'm sorry.
- Don't worry about it.
Molly?
What are you doing here?
You bastard.
You son of a bitch!
What do you want?
Molly?
Molly, get out!
Oh, my God.
No, Molly. No, Molly, no, no. Please, no.
Molly, Molly, he's got a gun. Molly!
Hi, kitty. Hi.
You hurt her, I'll kill...
Molly.
Shit.
Is somebody there? Hello?
Hello?
What are you doing?
Let go! What are you doing?
No!
Like trains?
Stay out! This is mine!
Shit.
Is me. I couldn't get it.
She came home.
In a couple of days, man. I'll go back.
Relax, I'll get it.
Get what?
Who are you?
What do you want from us?
No. You stay away from her.
Do you hear me?
You stay away from her!
Rosa Santiago?
Please be seated.
Our sister will be with us soon.
Sister Oda Mae, grant us the gift
of your all-seeing presence.
Appear before us now.
Mrs. Santiago?
I'm Oda Mae Brown.
I understand you wish
to contact your husband.
I believe he'll be with us today.
Oh, thank you. Thank you.
But you know, Mrs. Santiago,
there's no telling about that other world.
So you've got to be a believer,
Mrs. Santiago.
- Are you a believer?
- Sí. Sí. I believe. I believe.
Then let us begin.
I can't. I can't. Is too difficult.
I just can't seem to make contact.
I... I don't feel his... No, wait!
I'm feeling something.
Did he know someone
by the name of Anna?
Consuelo? Lucita? Julietta?
Josephina? Linda? Maria?
Sí, sí. His mama. She is Maria.
Yes. Praise God!
I knew he was with his mama.
Oh, my God.
Is too difficult. Is two of them.
I'm not sure I can do that.
- Is so trying... Is...
- Oh, I pay more.
- How much? How much?
- $20.
Oh, way to go. Milk her for every penny.
Yes, I believe we can start again.
Praise the Lord. Thank you, Jesus.
Welcome, Mrs. Santiago.
You're fortunate today.
The spirits are churning.
- My husband?
- Have mercy!
Oh, yeah? Where?
- Julio?
- Yes.
I feel his vibration.
I see him!
How is he? How does he look?
Oh, he's a handsome man.
Handsome?
Mrs. Santiago, in our Father's kingdom,
we're all handsome.
Oh, Julio.
Julio's coming towards us. I see him!
He's coming! He's there!
He's dressed in a black suit.
Black suit?
Could be blue.
What a crock of shit.
- Who is that?
- Julio?
- Where are you?
- Julio? Julio?
Did you hear it? Damn.
- Where are you?
- Julio?
- Who are you?
- Who?
Julio? Julio?
- You can hear me?
- Don't you hear him?
I don't believe this.
Hey, you! Hey, you!
My name is Sam Wheat.
Listen, can you hear me? Sam Wheat.
Say my name. Say it.
- Leave me alone! Stop it!
- Say my name. Say it! Sam Wheat.
Say my name. Sam Wheat. Say it.
Talk to me, Oda Mae. Say something.
Sam Wheat!
Jesus.
- Sam Wheat?
I swear, no more cheating. I promise.
I'll do anything. I'll do penance.
Give me penance,
but make that guy go away.
No way.
Is okay.
All right, Sister.
- I can't...
- Yeah, you're all right.
My mother had it.
And my mother's mother had it.
They... They both had the gift.
And they always said I had it,
but I never did. I never had it.
They told me what it was like.
They told me all about it.
But now that I got it, I...
I don't think I want it.
So, do me a favor, just go away.
Find somebody else.
Somebody else?
You're out of your mind.
Yeah, I'm getting there fast.
Well, I think she hit her head
harder than we think.
Well, she was talking to nobody
that wasn't there
before she even hit her head.
Well, I know she is.
But you know, Sister can do that.
- Where exactly are you?
- I'm standing right beside you.
- Oh, you're standing right beside me?
- Well, honey, we're right here.
- Are you white?
- What?
- White?
- You're white, aren't you?
Oh, God, you know what I think?
Yes, I'm gonna call the doctor right now.
- I knew it. Is a white guy. Why me?
- Listen, damn it.
You are going to help me.
There's a woman.
Her name is Molly Jensen,
and she's in terrible danger.
The man who killed me broke into
our apartment and he's gonna go back.
So you've gotta warn her.
Just what makes you think
she's gonna listen to me?
Is just a phone call.
Look,
you're all I've got.
Now, I'm not leaving until you help me.
I don't care how long it takes,
'cause I can talk forever.
She's talking to white people
in the room.
- Hello?
- Hi.
- Is this Molly Jensen?
- Yes.
Well, my name is Oda Mae Brown.
I'm a spiritual reader and advisor,
and a friend of yours gave me
a message for you.
Now, I know this
is gonna sound a little crazy,
but is not, and you gotta believe me.
Just don't be afraid.
Who is this?
I got a message from Sam.
What?
Sam Wheat. He asked me to call.
- I told you.
- You gotta go there.
Forget it. I'm not going anywhere.
I don't care what you do.
Second verse same as the first
I'm Henry Vlll, I am
Henry Vlll, I am, I am
I got married to the widow next door
She's been married seven times before
And every one was an Henry
Henry!
She wouldn't have a Willie or a Sam
No, sir!
I'm her eighth old man, I'm Henry
Henry Vlll, I am, I am
Henry Vlll, I am
Second verse same as the first
I'm Henry Vlll, I am
Henry Vlll, I am, I am
I got married to the widow next door
All right, all right, all right! Stop singing!
I'll go anywhere you want to!
Just don't sing anymore!
I can't believe this.
I can't believe I'm doing this.
What am I doing down here?
I never come downtown.
I hate downtown.
She's probably not even there.
Where are you?
Which building is it?
- Which one?
- Push three.
- See? Nobody's there.
- She's there. Just wait. Just wait.
Look, no. I came down here,
I did everything I said I was gonna do.
I pressed the button. She's not there.
I'm gone. Goodbye.
- Just wait one minute.
- I'm sorry.
Ninety-nine bottles of beer on the wall
Ninety-nine bottles of beer
Take one down and pass it around
All right, don't sing!
All right, all right, all right!
- Hello?
- Yes, hi.
She can't hear you.
Hi, I'm Oda Mae.
You know, I called you last night
about your friend Sam Wheat.
I told you.
Hey, Molly!
Molly Jensen, I know you're up there!
I know you hear me! I'm down here!
Sam wants to talk to you!
This is for real!
Hey, you remember the starfish
in Montego Bay?
How would I know that
if he wasn't here?
Hey, Molly!
I know about the green underwear
that you wrote your name on!
I'd never get over that, I'll tell you that.
I know about the picture in Reno.
Hey, Molly!
Ask her about the sweater she knitted,
in the closet, thas too big.
He just asked me
to remind you of the sweater
thas in the closet
that you knitted is too big!
Four sizes!
Hey, you hear me talking to you?
- I hear you.
- Oh, shut up. Nobody's talking to you.
Didn't you ever hear of a phone?
Wanna kiss my butt?
- I'm not gonna stay down here all day!
- Thank God.
Oh, man, shut up!
Molly!
I'm gonna count to three,
and then I'm out of here.
One, two, three.
- No, Oda. Wait.
- No.
Is Molly.
Molly?
I'm Oda Mae Brown.
I don't know you.
I don't know this guy, Sam.
But let me tell you what he did to me.
He kept me up all night singing
I'm Henry Vlll, I am.
Thas how he got me
to go out with him.
Look, I'm sorry.
I just don't believe
in this life-after-death stuff.
- Well, tell her she's wrong.
- He says you're wrong.
- You're talking to him right now?
- Yeah.
He just asked me to tell you
that you were wrong.
- So, where is he?
- I can't see him. I can only hear him.
I'm right here.
That doesn't help, Sam.
I'm holding her hand.
He says he's holding your hand.
What are you doing?
What do you think you're doing to me?
Hey, look, if you think I'd come
all the way down here for my health,
you're out of your mind.
Sam's dead. Okay? He's dead.
- Tell her I love her.
- He says he loves you.
Sam would never say that.
Ditto! Tell her ditto.
What the hell is ditto? Ditto!
Man, to tell you the truth,
I don't know how I'm doing this.
You know, confidentially, nothing like
this has ever happened to me before.
I mean, nothing.
And now I can't turn it off.
Is this him? Is this you?
- Yeah.
Cute. White, but cute.
What I don't understand is
why did he come back?
- I don't know.
- Why is he still here?
He's stuck, thas what it is.
He's in between worlds.
You know, it happens sometimes.
The spirit gets yanked out so quick
that the essence still feels
like it has work to do here.
- Would you stop rambling?
- I don't think I'm rambling.
I'm just answering her question.
- He's got an attitude now.
- I don't have an attitude.
Yes, you do have an attitude.
We're having a little discussion.
If you didn't have an attitude,
you would not have raised
your voice to me, now, would you?
- God damn it, Oda Mae.
- Don't you "God damn it" me.
Don't you take the Lorïs name in vain
with me, you understand?
- I don't take that.
- Would you relax?
No, you relax. You're the dead guy.
You want me to help you?
You better apologize.
- Because I don't take that from anybody.
- Jesus Christ!
- Thas it, I'm leaving.
- What are you doing?
I'm leaving. Nobody talks to me like that.
You understand me?
- Now you better apologize.
- I'm sorry. I apologize. Okay?
Now would you sit down? Please?
He's apologized.
I need you to tell Molly what I'm saying,
but you have to tell her
word for word, all right?
- Word for word.
- Yes.
He wants me to tell you
what he's saying word for word.
Molly, you're in danger.
Now you can't just blurt it out like that.
And quit moving around, will you?
'Cause you're starting
to make me dizzy.
I'll just tell her in my own way.
Molly, you in danger, girl.
What are you talking about?
I know the man who killed me.
He knows the man who killed him.
His name is Willie Lopez,
and I know where he lives.
His name is Willie Lopez.
He's Puerto Rican.
He knows where he lives.
- Write it down.
- He wants you to write it down.
- You write it down.
- I ain't no damn secretary.
Just do it!
He's so testy.
What is it you want me to write?
Is 303 Prospect Place, apartment 4D.
- 303 Prospect Place?
- Yeah.
Thas my neighborhood.
Molly, he's got my wallet,
he's got my key, and he was in here.
He's got his wallet and his key,
and he was in here.
Yesterday when you came back
from your walk with Carl,
you went up the stairs,
you talked to Floyd,
- you went in, took off your clothes...
- All right, all right.
When you came in yesterday
from your walk with Carl, he was here.
You took your clothes off.
He saw everything.
Molly, you got to go to the police.
It was a set-up.
I was murdered.
He wants you to go to the police.
He said it was a set-up.
He was murdered.
- There's somebody else involved.
- Look, forget it.
- I don't know who, but...
- I don't want no more
- to do with this, okay?
- Wait.
- Where are you going?
- What do you mean, where am I going?
I'm leaving.
I did everything I said I was going to do.
And don't be following me,
'cause I'm finished. And I mean it.
Have a nice life.
Have a nice death. Goodbye.
Molly, there's no one
on earth besides you
who'd want this to be true
more than me.
But you've got to be rational about this.
I mean, Sam is no more
in this room than...
Look, I understand the need
to hang on to him.
I really do. But this is absurd.
I know this seems absurd.
But it had to be real.
How could you believe
some fortuneteller from Brooklyn
who just shows up at your door?
I sat there and watched her
have a conversation with him.
I don't buy it, Mol. Not for a minute.
- What about the things she knew?
- What things?
The photo that Sam took of me
on our trip to Reno.
Carl, we were alone.
And the green underwear
that I wrote my name in.
- She said Sam knew who killed him.
- Yeah.
- That he was set up.
- This is getting deranged.
We're going off the deep end here.
- She had a name and an address.
- Good, Molly, good.
Willie Lopez.
303 Prospect Place, apartment 4D.
This is sick.
Oh, Carl.
This is really sick.
Oh, God.
Molly, I don't understand how you could
swallow this crap.
I mean, this guy may not even exist.
This woman, maybe she's just trying
to use you to set someone up.
You're right. You're absolutely right.
No.
Thas what I got to find out.
What do you mean, find out?
How are you gonna do that?
Well, she said Sam wants me
to go to the police.
Sam wants you to go to the police?
Jesus, Molly.
Are you out of your mind?
I mean,
what are you gonna tell the police?
Are you gonna tell them
that some storefront psychic lady's
been communing with the dead?
I mean, do you have any idea
what that sounds like?
You're talking ghosts here,
for Chriss sake.
I'm sorry.
Is just this stuff just really gets to me,
you know.
Is okay if you don't believe me.
I'm trying to, Molly.
Look, if ill make you feel any better,
I'll go check this out, okay?
Now, why don't you try
and get some sleep?
Okay? All right?
- I'll call you in the morning.
- Okay.
All right. Good night.
Be careful.
Carl. What the hell are you doing here?
Who have you been talking to, Willie?
Talking to? What the hell do you mean?
Some woman knows
all about you, everything.
- Now where's she getting it from, huh?
- I haven't said a word to anybody.
She knows your name, God damn it.
She knows where you live.
- A lot of women know where I live.
- This is not a joke!
She knows about the murder.
Now I want you to find this bitch,
whoever she is.
And I want you
to just get rid of her, okay?
I've got $4 million stuck
in a goddamn computer.
If I don't get those codes,
if that money is not transferred soon,
I'm... dead. We're both dead.
Why don't you tell them
you only launder money
on the first of the month?
What the hell is wrong with you?
Is everything a joke? You killed a man.
You were supposed to steal his wallet.
Was that a joke?
Man, I did you a favor, man.
That was a freebie.
Look, these are drug dealers, okay?
Just don't blow this for me, Willie.
I'd lose my job. I could go to jail.
$80,000 of that money is mine.
Look, just let me have the key
to Sam's apartment.
I'll get the address book myself, okay?
Bastard! You goddamn bastard!
Why? Why? You were my friend!
I had a life, God damn you. I had a life!
Look, I don't even believe
in this stuff myself.
But she was real.
What? You think I'd come down here
if it wasn't real?
You know, you told me if I had
any new information that I should come.
So here I am.
I know how this sounds.
I mean, I hear myself saying it
and I want to cringe.
But this woman knew things
she couldn't have known.
Things Sam only said to me.
Okay, according to this psychic lady,
there are ghosts and spirits
all over the place,
watching us all the time, huh?
Well, hell, I'm never gonna
get undressed again.
Excuse me.
I've got more important things to do.
The guy's name is Willie Lopez.
All I'm asking you to do is check it out.
Okay.
You just wait here and let me see
if the guy's got a record, all right?
Great.
What are you doing?
- Where's the file on Willie Lopez?
- There's no file for a Willie Lopez.
He was probably some old boyfriend
she was trying to get even with.
Now, this psychic woman's got a record
that goes back a long way.
1967, Shreveport,
forgery, selling false ID.
Served one year in 1971.
Baton Rouge, arrested for fraud.
Numbers racketeering,
served 10 months, 1974, and...
Look, this is impossible.
- It goes on and on.
- She knew things. Private things.
Now, how could
she have known all that?
A lot of times they read the obits.
All she had to do
was see the word "banker." Boom.
Hell, they even go through your garbage
to find things they can use.
Letters, old papers,
it doesn't take much.
No.
It was real.
She knew about a sweater I knitted.
And songs we sang.
Our trip to Montego Bay.
I'm sorry. I know this is hard.
People want so much to believe.
They're grieving. They're vulnerable,
and they will give anything
for one last moment.
Believe me,
these people know what they're doing.
And I know how you must feel,
but you know you can press charges.
No.
Thank you.
Oh, God, let this be it.
Yes.
Hello?
- Eddie?
- Yeah.
- Is Carl Bruner.
- Whas up?
I'm fine. Yeah, everything's fine.
Just, we're all set.
Good.
Just let me know
what you want me to do.
Okay, I want you to transfer the money
from the 12 separate accounts
into a single account
under the name Rita Miller.
Okay.
Tomorrow at five minutes
before closing, 3:55 p.m.,
transfer the full account
to the First Island Bank of Nassau,
registry number 4869580.
- Call us when is done.
- Okay, I've got it.
Just tell Mr. Balistreri that there
won't be any more problems, okay?
- Yeah, I'll do that.
- Thank you.
Good work, Carl.
Molly, why can't you hear me?
I need you.
- Who is it?
- Is Carl, Molly.
No. Don't open it, Molly.
Don't open the goddamn door.
He's a murderer.
- Hi.
- Hey.
Listen, sorry, I know is late.
I'm sorry to disturb you.
I just...
I've been thinking about you all day.
And I feel really lousy about...
About what happened last night.
This supernatural thing just really...
Listen, don't worry about it.
Really, is okay.
No, is not.
You needed me to hear you and I didn't.
I wasn't there for you, and that was...
That was wrong.
Is just I... I just...
I want you to know
that I'm your friend, Mol.
- Thanks, Carl.
- You were never our friend.
- That really means a lot to me.
- Me, too.
So I brought you
some Japanese apple-pears.
I know you like them.
Thanks. Thas very sweet.
Could I come in for a second?
I won't stay long.
Is just been one of those days.
- Maybe a cup of coffee or something?
- Yeah.
- Come on in.
- No, Molly.
- You seem a little tense. Are you okay?
- No, I'm fine.
Is just, God, what can I tell you?
Is been tough.
Is... I mean, you know,
it just still hurts so much.
You lying snake.
And then on top of it, is stuff at work.
They've given me my own accounts,
which is good.
But I just haven't really had time
to adjust,
kind of absorb everything.
Is no big deal.
Yeah.
- Can I have just a little more cream?
- Yeah.
Oh, shit. Jesus. I can't believe I did that.
- Are you all right?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
Oh, God.
- Here, let me throw that in the washer.
- No, don't worry about it. Is okay.
Is just...
- You want me to get you another shirt?
- No, is fine. Ill dry.
- Just take a minute.
- Here you go.
So where were you today?
I thought you were gonna
come into the bank
and sign those papers.
Well, I was supposed to,
but I didn't have time.
I went to the police.
You did? Wow, what did you tell them?
What did they say?
It was awful.
I felt really stupid.
They brought out a file on this woman,
and... At least 10 inches thick.
- A rip-off artist, huh?
- No, Molly.
You know, the sad thing
is that I believed her.
Molly, sometimes we need to believe.
Why? Whas the point?
Molly, it is not easy
to face the realities of life.
Sometimes you've gotta
give yourself that.
What you've got to remember is
the love that you guys felt.
I mean, thas whas real.
You've got to remember
how good Sam was,
how much he loved you.
You were everything to him, Molly.
You were his life.
I feel so alone.
You're not alone, okay?
You've got your work.
You're incredibly talented. You're young.
You're fantastically gorgeous.
I don't know whas real anymore.
I don't know what to think.
Just think about Sam.
Think about the time
you guys had together,
how wonderful that was.
Yeah.
Let your feelings out, Molly. Is okay.
Life turns on a dime.
You know?
I mean, people think that
they have forever,
that there's always gonna be tomorrow,
but thas bullshit.
Sam taught us that.
You have to live for now,
for today.
- I can't. I'm sorry.
- Is okay.
- I can't. Is just too soon.
You've been great, Carl.
- But I need you to leave.
- Is okay. I understand, totally.
Please.
Could we just have dinner
tomorrow night? Just talk.
Can I interest you in that?
- Yeah, sure.
- Great.
Hey.
- Get off my train.
- No.
Get off! Get off!
Get off! Get off! Get off!
- Get out of here. Get off.
- No.
Show me how you do that.
I want to learn,
and I'm not leaving till you teach me.
- Get off!
- No.
Get off!
You stubborn asshole.
What are you doing?
What the hell are you doing?
What do you mean, what am I...
You're trying to move it with your finger.
You can't push it with your finger.
You're dead.
Is all in your mind.
The problem with you
is you still think you're real.
You think you're wearing those clothes?
You think you're crouched
on that floor? Bullshit!
You ain't got a body no more, son.
Is all up here now.
If you want to move something,
you've got to move it with your mind.
You gotta focus.
You hear what I'm saying?
How? How do you focus?
I don't know how you focus.
You just focus.
- How did you do that?
- You gotta take all your emotions,
all your anger,
all your love, all your hate,
and push it way down here
into the pit of your stomach.
And then let it explode like a reactor.
Okay, okay.
Don't laugh!
Way to go, kid!
I did it.
- I did it.
- Way to go.
From your gut, like I told you.
Give it time. What else have you got?
How long have you been here?
Since they pushed me.
- Someone pushed you?
- Yes, someone pushed me.
- Who?
- What, you don't believe me?
You think I fell? You think I jumped?
Well, fuck you!
It wasn't my time.
I wasn't supposed to go!
I'm not supposed to be here!
Oh, I'd give anything for a drag.
Just one drag!
Are you all right?
Who are you?
Why are you hounding me?
Who sent you?
Leave me alone! Leave me alone!
Leave me alone!
Yes!
...so you need to concentrate,
'cause if you concentrate,
you'll probably rouse him.
- Now whas his name again?
- Orlando.
Orlando.
Orlando, Orlando,
is there an Orlando here?
- I'm here.
- He's here.
- Oda Mae, I...
- Sam!
- What the hell?
- Excuse me, I'm Orlando.
The line's over there.
Oda Mae, where did
all these ghosts come from?
- You can hear them, too?
- Hear them? Can I hear them?
I hear them in the morning.
I hear them in the evening.
They're coming into the shower.
Sam, what the hell did you do to me?
Did you tell every spook in the world
you met about me?
I got spooks from Jersey
coming in here.
Jesus.
There's stuff going on
you wouldn't believe.
I don't even believe it.
- Is amazing. You're really doing it.
- Yes, I know.
How do you like that?
- Can you two please hurry this up?
- Oh, chill out. Chill out!
Listen, I need your help again,
Oda Mae.
- There's something we need to do.
- No.
I'm not doing anything else
with you, Sam.
Look, you're holding onto a life
that doesn't want you anymore.
It doesn't want you. Give up the ghost.
Are you speaking to me?
Does it look like I'm speaking to you?
You'll know when I'm talking to you.
You supposed to be concentrating,
aren't you?
Now, you want to try it?
Thank you very much.
Now, Sam,
are you gonna get out of here?
'Cause I got work to do.
Fine, then stay there.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
You ready now?
Les do it.
Oda Mae, listen.
I got to talk to you now. I've got a plan.
You see, I figured this thing out.
There's something we can do.
All we got to do is...
Oda Mae?
Ortisha?
Orlando? Is that you?
Ortisha, where are you at?
I can't hardly see.
- Here. She's here.
- In front of you. I'm right here.
Damn, baby!
Whad you do to your hair?
Orlando, you like it?
Is Autumn Sunrise.
Get out of me, you son of a bitch!
Don't you ever do that to me again.
Orlando!
- I can barely move.
- Now, you should know better than that.
Jumping into bodies wipes you out.
Everybody out!
What happened to Orlando?
Where's the insurance policy?
Are you deaf? I said everybody out!
Everybody out! Get out, get out, get out!
Everybody get out!
Get out!
- You the fortuneteller?
- Who are you?
Thas an interesting question.
Why don't you tell me?
- Willie.
- Willie?
Prospect Place Willie?
Get out of here! Fast!
- Sister! Sister!
- Oda Mae!
I'm all right. I'm all right.
Oda Mae, we're in trouble,
so you've got to help me.
What do you mean we? Who's we?
You're already dead.
Don't you understand?
These people are trying to kill me.
Yeah, you're right. And they'll be back.
Look, why don't you just find a house
to haunt, you know?
Get some chains and rattle them
or something.
Will you listen to me?
I have a plan and it will work.
But you've gotta get
some of your fake IDs.
Forget it.
If you do this, they'll never
bother you again, I promise.
Scouts' honor.
All right.
What do I have to do?
What exactly do I have to do?
You got a nice dress?
I don't see whas wrong
with what I'm wearing.
I'm sorry I made a joke.
I love your shoes.
No, I don't think you do.
You know, I think I'm gonna go home.
I'm going home because
I don't know anything about banking.
I don't know that this is gonna work.
- Oda Mae, would you just relax?
- Listen, I'm nervous.
Please donate.
I know you're nervous,
but I will get you through it.
- And the fake driver's license is great.
- Oh, Sam, I don't think I can do this.
You can do it. Straight ahead of you.
A stairway that says, "New Accounts."
- Thas where we're going.
- I'm not giving them no money.
- Just do what I say and don't talk.
- Okay.
Tell her you're here to fill out
a signature card for a new account.
Can I help you?
Yes, I'm here to fill out
a signature card for a new account.
And do you know your account number?
92631043.
- 926...
- 31043.
...31043.
- Rita Miller.
- Who?
- What?
- Tell her Rita Miller.
Rita Miller.
Didn't they have you sign a card
when you opened the account?
Tell her Carl Bruner opened it for you
by phone
and asked you to come in today.
You see, Carl Bruner,
he opened it for me by phone,
that account, and now he's asked me
to come in today.
I see.
- Is that right?
- Yeah.
All right.
Just sign this card
on the bottom line, please.
May I use your pen?
Thank you so much.
No, no, no! Rita Miller.
I'm so sorry.
You know, I... I need another one.
I signed the wrong name.
Now, tell her to make sure
it goes straight up to the third floor file,
because you have
a transaction to make.
Please make sure this goes right up
to the third floor file,
because I have a transfusion to make.
- A what?
- Les go.
You know what I mean.
Can I keep this pen?
- Yes, sure.
- Thank you so much.
Bye-bye.
- I just love these pens.
- Then keep the pen.
- Why are you always making me...
- What do you want to keep the pen for?
- Carl Bruner speaking.
- Hi, Carl.
- Mr. Balistreri.
- Balistreri?
- Carl, is me, John.
- John, John. Sorry.
What... What... Whas up?
I've got the info on the Bradley portfolio.
Oh, right, okay, look, I'll just...
I'll pick it up later. All right?
- All right. I'll be here till 6:00.
- Good.
This is it.
I don't suppose I can talk you
into losing the hat.
You keep messing with me,
you'll be here by yourself.
Tell the guard you're here
to see Lyle Ferguson.
Lyle Ferguson.
Hi. I'm here to see
Lyle Ferguson, please.
- Do you have an appointment?
- No, I'm here for my health.
Don't say that.
Tell him Rita Miller's here.
You just tell him Rita Miller's here.
Just one moment, please.
Don't embellish.
Excuse me?
Now, listen.
This guy Ferguson's a real jerk.
I've known him for five years,
and he still thinks my name's...
- Why are you whispering?
- Just be quiet and listen.
He's a social moron, so you don't have
anything to worry about.
Just tell the guard Ferguson knows you.
You spent time with him
and his wife, Shirley,
at the Brewster's Christmas party
last year. Got it?
- What is this in regards to?
- What?
He doesn't remember me?
Oh, we spent all that time at the
Brewster's Christmas party last year.
He and his lovely wife, Shirley.
It was beautiful.
A big old tree and thousands
of presents everywhere. It...
Gas.
I get a little gas from time to time.
Thas all. Gas.
- Quit poking me!
- Well, don't overdo it.
Now, listen, this'll be easy.
Ferguson was so drunk at that party,
he coulïve had a conversation
with Tina Turner
and he wouldn't remember.
- I don't know, Sam.
- Here we go.
Hello. Hello. Yes.
Of course, yes.
Well, is been a long time.
Oh, a long time.
Ask how Bobby and Snooky are doing.
By the way,
how are Bobby and Snooky doing?
Fine. Fine. Thank you.
Thank you for asking.
And how is your family?
Oh, couldn't be better.
Well, wonderful.
Tell him you've been wondering
how they did on the Gibraltar securities.
I was just wondering, how did you do
on the Gibraltar securities?
The Gibraltar securities?
Well, it looks like we topped out
on that one, huh?
- We sure did.
- That was a very useful tip.
- Good old Randy.
- Right.
Got a good old head on his shoulders.
- Her shoulders.
- Randy.
Yeah. So, what...
What brings you here today?
- You're closing an account.
- I'm closing an account.
Well, wonderful.
Do you have your account number?
- Yes?
- Yes.
- 92631043.
92631043.
- Is that right?
- Yeah.
Good.
Well, Rita, it looks like
you'll be withdrawing
$4 million from us today.
- $4 million?
- Say yes. Say yes!
- Is that correct?
- Yes.
Yes. Yeah. Yeah. Yes.
- Thas correct. Yes.
- Easy, easy.
Yes.
Well, how would you like that?
- Tens and twenties.
- Pardon?
Cashier's check.
Tell him a cashier's check.
I think better, a cashier's check.
A cashier's check. Fine.
Well, of course, you know,
we require identification from everyone.
- Is just procedural.
- Oh, ID! Yes.
You know, I...
Thank you. Well, I'll be right back.
$4 million!
Yeah, get me the First Island Bank
of Nassau. Is on the Rolodex.
Well, we have some things for you
to sign here.
This officially closes the account.
And here you are.
Now, sign Rita Miller.
Rita Miller. Thas my name.
My name. Rita Miller. My name.
My name.
- Molly, hi. Is good to see you.
- Hi.
- Oda Mae, I'll be right back.
- A few more if you would, please.
Just anywhere?
Right here.
Fine.
The check.
This... Here you are.
The person you need to see
is right down at the end.
Okay, thanks.
Mama took the money
that she made in the oil wells,
and she sunk it into gas pumps.
You know,
how they have at the gas station?
And those gas stations
have five or six of those things,
so is very, very lucrative.
- Oda Mae.
- It really adds up.
- Oda Mae, we've gotta go. Say goodbye.
- Well, gotta go now.
Is been a pleasure doing business
with you, a real pleasure.
Now, may I keep the pen?
Say good night to Bobby
and Snooky for me.
I'll see you. Bye-bye.
Why are you rushing me?
What is wrong?
- Excuse me. Lyle?
- Oh, yes...
- Molly Jensen.
- Molly.
The woman you were
just doing business with.
- Yeah?
- What did she want?
I mean, did it have anything
to do with me or with Sam?
Sam? Why, no. No.
- That was Oda Mae Brown, right?
- No, her name was Rita Miller,
and she was closing an account.
- Why? Is there a problem?
- No. I guess not.
Thank you.
Carl, is something wrong?
Is somebody playing
with the computers?
- What?
- One of my accounts is closed.
Which account? Whas wrong?
You want me to call someone?
No, is okay. I can do it. I got it.
$4 million!
Oh, my God,
what am I gonna do with this money?
I... You know,
I'm gonna buy the building.
No, no, wait. I'm gonna buy the block.
I'm gonna make my sister
go to a fat farm,
because, you know, she's way too big.
Whoa, wait! What are you gonna do...
Then I'm gonna...
Yeah, I'm gonna buy the building.
Wait, wait, wait, Oda Mae,
I've got an idea.
- Take the check out of your purse.
- Oh, you're right. You're right.
I should take it out.
I should put it where nobody can get it.
No, no, no. Endorse it.
No, if I endorse it, then if I drop it,
somebody will get it. No, I'll just...
Is not your money.
I never said
you were gonna get the money.
This is blood money.
I was killed for this money.
- Now, endorse the check.
- I know, but...
Well, Sam,
what are you gonna do with it?
Look over there, to your left.
I know you don't think I'm giving this
$4 million to a bunch of nuns!
Oda Mae, if you don't do it,
they will track you down.
Your only protection is to get rid of it.
Oh, Sam, come on. You're killing me!
Is $4 million!
Just think of it this way,
you'll go to heaven.
I don't want to go to heaven!
I want to go to a bank
and cash the goddamn check!
- Hello.
- Yeah.
- You'll thank me later.
- How are you doing?
- Now, endorse it Rita Miller.
- I know.
Make it out to St. Joseph's Shelter.
I can't believe you're making me do this.
Now, give it to her.
I will, I will. I just want to feel it
one more time in my fingers, thas all.
- Just give the lady the check.
- I will!
Hand her the check. You can do it.
- Give her the check.
- I will.
Bless you, child. Bless you.
Give it to her. Let go. Let go!
Shit.
I'm proud of you, Oda Mae.
You know something, Sam?
I don't care if you're proud of me.
You stay away from me from now on.
What is that nun going to do with it?
She can't even buy underwear. Nothing.
I hate you. Leave me alone.
Never talk to me again.
I think you're wonderful, Oda Mae.
Go ahead, search. You'll never find it.
They're gonna kill you, Carl.
You and Willie,
you're gonna be fertilizer.
They're gonna bury you
right next to Jimmy Hoffa.
Who's doing that?
- Hey.
- Hi.
Where were you?
I thought we were having dinner.
I know, Mol. I'm sorry.
Things got a little crazy. I just forgot.
Yeah, had a little trouble at the bank.
- You forgot?
- Yeah.
You know, I wish you would have
called me,
because I've been really worried.
Listen to me, Molly,
I gotta ask you about something.
Yeah, he needs to borrow $4 million.
When you said that you thought
that Sam was here,
that he was talking to you,
what did you feel?
What did he say to you?
Why? What does that have
to do with anything?
Is just... Listen to me for a second.
This psychic lady,
I want to know what she told you.
- I wanna know exactly what she said.
- Carl, let me go. Carl, stop this.
It doesn't matter. It wasn't real.
What the hell happened to you tonight?
Does this have anything to do
with her being at the bank today?
The bank?
Yeah, Ferguson said she closed
an account.
Her name isn't even Oda Mae Brown.
Is Rita Miller or something.
Carl, are you all right?
Is just my stomach...
Jesus.
Do you have any, like, I don't know,
some Pepto-Bismol or something?
- Cyanide.
- Yeah. Is upstairs.
Why don't you sit down, and I'll get it?
Whas wrong? Does little Carl
have a little tummy ache?
What are you doing to me?
Now do you believe in ghosts?
I'll set the place on fire, I swear to God.
- I'll cut her throat.
- Carl.
I swear to God. I'll cut her throat.
I need that money,
and I want it tonight at 11:00.
If that psychic lady
does not bring it here,
Molly is dead. Okay?
- Carl, who are you talking to?
- Nothing. Now, Molly, listen to me.
I have to go, okay?
I can't explain this now,
but there is a problem, okay?
- Something's going on at the bank.
- Carl, you're really scaring me.
I'm sorry, Mol.
Look, I don't have time to talk now,
but I'll come back about 11:00.
- Why? Why not now?
- Molly, I can't talk now.
Molly, look, I'll come back.
What do you say? Like, 11:00, okay?
I'm sorry to do this to you, Molly,
but is really important.
I gotta go. Okay?
- 11:00.
- Oda Mae!
I'm Arsenio Hall.
Don't try to adjust your television.
I'm black.
- I want to watch Love Connection.
- I love Love Connection.
- I love that man on there.
- Leave that! Thas Arsenio.
- So?
- What do you mean, so?
You love Love Connection,
you ought to send your picture in there.
She did already.
They just haven't answered yet.
- Oda Mae?
- Sam?
- Oh, no. Not again.
- Oda Mae, we're in trouble.
They want the check,
and they're coming for you.
So you gotta get out of here.
What do you mean,
they want the check?
The check you said
they would never know about?
- Oda Mae, whas happening?
- Sam.
They're here! They're here!
Get out of here! Now! Go!
- Come on. We gotta go!
- Whas the matter?
Come on, come on!
Just knock on the door here.
Help! Help!
- Is an emergency. You gotta let us in.
- Who are you kidding?
Open up!
What are you doing?
You can't come in here.
The cat don't like visitors.
She'll pee all over that...
They're gonna get us.
Where's Sam?
- Shit! It looks like the bitch just left.
- I'll check downstairs.
Carl?
Shit!
Willie!
Hey, man,
you got a serious problem, man.
Help me! Help!
That dude is dead.
You're dead, Willie.
No! No! No!
Help me!
Tell the driver to hurry.
Yo, man, you wanna step on it, please?
Listen, lady, I'm driving as fast as I can.
Problems?
- Carl, is that you?
- No, is me, Oda Mae.
Listen. Molly,
I know what you think of me.
I know what you think of me,
but, look, you gotta talk to me.
You are in serious danger.
I got Sam here with me.
- We got to come in and talk to you.
- Get the hell out of here.
- I'm calling the police.
- Good.
- Tell her to do it.
- Fine. Thas what we want you to do.
We want you to call the police.
- But you've gotta let us in.
- No.
Look, don't you get it?
Sam was not just accidentally killed.
He was murdered.
He found out that Carl
was laundering money at the bank.
Now, this guy Carl is dangerous.
I'm telling you, he tried to kill me.
He's gonna try to kill you, too.
You are in deep, deep trouble.
Why are you doing this to me?
Do you hear me?
I can't. I just... I just can't.
Oda Mae, Oda Mae,
tell her she's wearing the shirt
that I spilled the margarita on
and the earrings
I gave her for Christmas.
Molly, Sam says to tell you
you're wearing the shirt
that he spilled the margarita on
and the earrings he gave you
for Christmas.
Don't you see?
I'm not a fake, not about this.
- Give me a penny, quick.
- What?
Push a penny under the door, now.
What you be talking about,
push a penny under the door?
Just do it.
- Tell her is for luck.
- Sam says is for luck.
We're between Greene and Mercer
on Prince.
Is the gray building right across
from the post office.
Thanks, Sergeant. Please hurry.
We'll be waiting.
- All right. They're on their way.
- Good.
- So, what do we do now?
- Just wait.
Is Sam here?
Sam?
I'm sitting beside her.
He's sitting right beside you.
Sam, can you feel me?
With all my heart.
He says with all his heart.
I'd give anything
if I could just touch you once more.
He says he wishes
he was alive again,
so he could touch you.
Me, too.
Okay. Okay, look. You can use me.
- Use you?
- You can use my body.
Use your body?
Just do it quick
before I change my mind.
Molly?
Molly, are you home?
Is Carl.
Molly!
Fire escape.
Whas happening to me?
Molly?
Molly!
Son of a bitch.
Come on.
Molly, look. Look.
Oh, les go. Les go.
Molly!
Just get away from us, Carl.
- Molly!
- You're just a liar. Liar!
Molly, you got to listen to me.
This woman's a thief.
- She's a con artist.
- Why?
- Why are you doing this?
- Don't listen to her, Molly.
Stop!
Just get away from us, Carl.
I've called the police.
Molly!
Shit.
- Carl, why are you doing this?
- Don't interfere, Molly. She's a thief.
All right, the check.
Just give me the check.
- Carl, no.
- Stay out of this, Molly!
Son of a bitch!
Keep out of this, Molly!
Get off of me!
Where is it? Where is it?
Where is it, God damn it!
- I gave it away.
- You're lying to me.
Don't lie to me, God damn it!
The check.
I'll kill her, Sam.
I swear to God, I'll kill her.
Just... Look, just give me the check,
Sam. Okay?
I promise you I'll let her go
if you'll just give it to me.
Okay?
Sam?
Sam.
- Oh, Carl.
- What?
No!
Are you two all right?
Sam?
Molly?
I can hear you.
Oh, God.
Sam? They're waiting for you, Sam.
I'll miss you.
Your mother'd be proud.
I'm gonna miss you, too, Sam.
You're all right.
Bye, Oda Mae.
Bye, Sam.
I love you, Molly.
I've always loved you.
Ditto.
Is amazing, Molly.
The love inside, you take it with you.
See you.
Bye.