Well, it has to be approved from downtown.
It's handled through this office,
but it requires downtown approval.
I don't know.
It has been submitted.
Sylvia, can you help me with this?
Coming.
Closing time. Going in?
Yes, sir.
Okay.
You the manager?
It looks...
Just keep talking like nothing was wrong.
Listen...
Let me call you back.
Sonny, I'm getting really bad vibes.
What are you talking about?
Maybe we should take
something smaller, Sonny.
You crazy? He started already.
He's got the gun out.
Go on, go over by the door.
Get over by the door.
Freeze!
Nobody move! Get over there!
Okay.
All right. Get away from those alarms.
Now get in the center.
He moves, take his head off.
Put the gun on him!
Get out in the center!
Sonny.
I can't do it, Sonny.
What?
I'm not going to make it, Sonny.
What are you talking about?
Put it on him.
I can't do it, Sonny.
Fuck me. Sal!
- Sal!
- What?
Where are you? He can't make it.
Fuck him. Let him go!
Come on, Sonny!
All right, let him out. Let him out!
Do what the gentleman says, Howard.
Let him out!
I'm sorry, Sonny.
Shit!
- Stevie, don't take the car.
- How will I get home?
Take the subway. We need the car.
Stevie! The keys!
I'm sorry, Sonny.
All right, lock it.
What do you want?!
Sonny, there's a girl
under that desk over there.
All right. Come.
All right. We got rid of him.
So now we just move it along. All right, Sal?
- You got them?
- I got them.
Okay. Now what did he say to me?
Wait a minute.
Anybody here? What's this, a squirrel?
Hey, you! Hey!
Come on. Come on.
In the back there.
No one's going to hurt you.
Go ahead, get to the back.
Pull the drapes! Pull the drapes!
Now! You! To the back. To the back here.
Go to him. Right there.
Okay. We're going to move this now.
Just moving along. Come on.
Gotcha! Gotcha!
We're moving right along, folks.
We're going to get this thing done
in half an hour.
We just got to block....
Knock out the TV.
Here we go.
See?
No replay, folks. No alarms.
Let's get you all fixed up and on your way.
- Right. Okay. Is the vault open?
- I can take care of that.
That's good. Let's go. Take care of it.
Hey! Wait a minute.
What are you trying to do?
Trip the alarm? Use the spot key?
I must have been out of my mind.
Yeah! Well, you get your mind right!
I'm a Catholic and I don't want
to hurt anybody! Understand?
- Yes, sir.
- No alarms!
No alarms!
- Okay.
- No games. All right?
Use the other one.
Miriam...
Open the safe.
Put it in this.
What?
That's all there is.
What are you talking about?
They picked it up this afternoon.
There's only $1,100.
- She's telling you the truth.
- He'll shoot me!
I can't believe it.
I can't believe it!
There's no money here.
- Come on, Sonny, let's do it!
- I'm doing it! I'm doing it!
Too much. This is too much.
This is too much.
All right, come on. Let's go.
Somebody...
You answer it. Watch him, Sal.
You, come with me. Watch him!
- Sit down. Sit down!
- Who's the head teller here?
I am.
Open it up.
No, not all of it!
Look, I worked in a bank.
I know the alarms. All right?
Don't play games with me. See?
You take one of these, you go like this,
in here, and out it comes.
You got your hundred.
I'll call you back.
No, no, no. It's decoy money. It's marked.
It's shit.
See?
Cheer up, girls! You're going to be
the veterans of a robbery.
You know the bank sends you
a dozen red roses?
Sal...
Let him answer it.
Hey, you, manager! Fucker!
Don't get ideas.
I bark, that man there, see him? He bites!
Believe me, I'm on your side.
On my side, shit.
Listen, we got young girls here.
You could watch your language, you know.
I speak what I feel, you know.
Watch my language!
Empty the drawer out.
I don't know. You'd have to find out from him.
Traveler's checks.
And the register.
The register!
You've got it. All right, let's go.
I'll take that from you.
All right, Sal, here we go.
Shit!
Come on.
Shit.
Sonny, what the hell are you doing?
I'm burning the register here.
Moving right along, folks.
Okay.
We're leaving.
Let me have the keys.
Howard, give him the keys.
- Come on.
- Howard.
Nobody's going to hurt you.
We're going to leave.
Sonny!
Who's that?
It's the insurance guy from across
the street. He probably saw the smoke.
Please, put out the fire.
I'll get some water.
Stay right there!
Please, don't do it! Don't do it!
- I'll call you back later.
- Get rid of him.
Get rid of him!
Howard.
Hey. Hey!
- Use your head.
- I can handle it.
- Everything's all right there?
- Yeah.
A cigarette butt got in the wastebasket.
It's all okay now.
Then you're okay.
- Thanks for keeping an eye out.
- Okay.
Could you please go now?
We gave you everything we've got.
Okay, we're going.
Answer the phone.
Sal, get them in the vault.
Come on, in the vault. Come on. Let's go.
- Where is the money?
- I'm getting it! Got it.
He's going to come with us. Okay.
Please, don't close the door.
How can we breathe?
Right.
Oh, wow. Wait a minute.
- Wait a minute. Listen.
- What?
I'm never going to make this.
I'll have to go to the toilet.
It's no joke!
I've got a terrible fear of being locked in.
All right. Who has to go to the bathroom here?
I do too.
You see? Now they all want to go.
Look, do you want to check it out?
It's the first door on your right.
All right, mouth, let's go.
First door on my right.
It's Maria!
Listen...
I forgot she's in there.
It's not her fault, you know.
She's always pulling this.
She's supposed to have 10 minutes.
She takes 15--
Shut up! Let's go! Out!
Nobody goes to the bathroom!
- Let's go! Out!
- We're having a bank robbery.
Mulvaney speaking.
Mouth! Mouth!
- Here's your toilet.
- It's for you.
What?
Telephone call.
For you.
Yeah.
- What are you doing in there?
- Who is this?
This is Detective Sergeant
Eugene Moretti, asshole!
We got you completely by the balls.
You don't believe me?
I'm looking you right in the eye.
Right now, I can see you.
- Who is it?
- Cops.
You come to the front door...
Hang it up.
How'd that happen?
Did I do anything to hurt you?
Did I treat you badly?
Look, I'm on salary. I'm not going be a hero!
Did you have a plan or what?
What did you do?
Just barge in on a whim? Huh?
Why did you have to light a fire?
Look, I told you to get out of here
when you could,
but, no, you just had to hang around.
He don't have a plan.
It's all a whim. Rob a bank!
I had a plan. I had it planned!
Only the money was supposed
to be delivered, not taken away!
That fucking Jack, downtown, he gave
me the wrong information, that fuck!
What is this Jack supposed to be?
A mastermind or what?
We're all in the barrel together
and we want to get out of it.
Right, I got to have time to think now.
I got to think.
Oh, shit!
All right. Listen bastards!
You keep away from this bank
or we're going to start throwing bodies out
the front door, one at a time. You got that?
Who is this?
Is there a Jenny here?
Who's Jenny here?
That's me.
It's the squirrel. You got a husband?
Yeah? Well, he's on the phone.
Go ahead.
What could I tell him?
I don't know. Tell him whatever
you tell him. Tell him the truth.
What a fucking comedy!
WNEW plays all the hits.
Listen. Now, don't hang up.
- First off, is anybody hurt in there?
- No, nobody's hurt.
You keep away from this bank
or we're going to start throwing bodies
out the front door, one at a time.
You got that?
Listen. Don't do that now. Wait a minute.
Let me talk to you for a while, huh?
How many people you got in there?
No, you call me back.
- Call me back.
- Excuse me.
He said he wants to know
what time you'll be through.
What? Girlie, please!
- Where's the back door?
- It's locked on the inside.
Where is it?
Through the passageway to the right.
Sal! Cover them! Cover them!
You could just go ahead
and cook whatever's there.
Oh, yes, I will. Yes, I will.
- Let's go, come on.
- Honey, I got to go now.
I got to go.
I love you too.
All right. All right, inside there.
Sal, I don't know what happened.
Maybe somebody tripped an alarm
or something. I don't know.
But there's a way out of this.
I'm telling you, there's a way out of this.
- Were you serious about what you said?
- About what?
About throwing...
About throwing those bodies out the door?
- That's what I want him to think.
- I want to know what you think.
'Cause I'll tell you right now,
I'm ready to do it.
Right. Okay.
- I mean it. I mean it.
- I know.
All right.
Now listen, everybody.
I know we got a problem here, right?
But there's a way out of this thing.
I'm telling you, there's a way out.
Now, all you got to do
is cooperate with me.
Stay cooled out, and we're going
to get out of this thing, all right?
Nobody will get hurt,
if you listen to what I say.
First off, we'll do things a step at a time.
Now, you got to go to the bathroom, right?
Right, she's going to have a chance
to go to the bathroom.
Everybody who has to go to the bathroom
is going to go to the bathroom.
We're going to do things together, okay?
Now stay cool...
What's the matter with him?
He's got asthma.
Asthma?
Asthma! Shit!
I'll take care of that.
- You... What's your name?
- Mulvaney.
Mulvaney, come with me.
He's got asthma,
and they make him a guard?
They go to guard school.
To learn how to shoot?
He don't even have a gun.
They earn a $105 a week
to fold the flag in the morning,
straighten up...
I don't know what they learn.
All right. I want to block that door.
In case they try coming in, I can hear it.
Let's move this.
Wait a minute. Hold it, hold it!
Let's get rid of this.
You got kids?
I got two kids and I'd like to see them again.
Don't worry, you'll see them again.
Look, you're being very cooperative
with me. I got no complaints
against you, whatsoever.
Whatsoever. You got bank insurance?
You know I do. You seem
to know a lot about bank procedure.
I know a lot about a lot of things.
- I just want to get you out of here safe, right?
- Right.
What if I take you with me?
If you take anybody,
please take me.
They'll shoot you, you know?
The cops...
They don't give a fuck
about your bank insurance.
See what they did in Attica?
42 people they killed.
The innocent with the guilty.
Anyway.
I won't take you with me.
I'll take one of them girls,
a married one with some kids.
Cops don't like it in the papers
when they shoot a married woman,
especially if she's got with kids.
You're all right.
You won't fuck with me, will you?
There's the FBI.
How're you doing, Sheldon?
Why didn't you wait
and try to take them outside?
I made an error in judgment.
I thought the sons of bitches would be a lot
more remorseful at the sight of a police officer.
And you know something?
Nobody said "hostage" yet,
you understand?
We got a bank robbery around here.
How the hell did those press guys
get through the barrier?
We don't know what's all about yet.
We're setting up communications right now.
This is Ron Cummins from CBS.
Sir, can you tell me what the situation is?
We're setting up communications.
Our perpetrators are in the bank.
That's all I can say now, fellows.
When I get it, you'll get it. Okay? That's all.
Hey, what are you fellows doing
on the fire escape?
I said on the roof.
Now get up on the roof, will you?
- Did you get the phone company?
- Yeah, it's being set it up now.
This phone is going to be
a direct line into the bank.
- Mulvaney speaking.
- Moretti here. Let me talk to him.
Yeah.
- This is Detective Sergeant Eugene Moretti.
- Yeah.
Okay. You're in there, we're out here.
What do we do now?
- I don't know. What do we do?
- Listen...
First off, we want to know
if the people of the bank are okay.
They're okay.
- You alone or you got confederates?
- I'm not alone.
- I got Sal.
- Sal?
- What's that for, Salvatore?
- Yeah. Sal.
He's a killer.
We're Vietnam veterans. So killing
don't mean anything to us. You understand?
- In the army?
- In the army, yeah.
Okay. So you, what's your name?
Why? What do you want to know my name for?
Give me a name, any name.
Just so I got something to call you.
Come on, let's be reasonable, okay?
Just give me your name. All right?
Call me Sonny.
- Sonny.
- Yeah.
Okay. Now listen, Sonny.
I want to see if the people
in the bank are okay.
- Right.
- Yeah.
Then what I want to do is work out
a way to get them out of there.
I want to come over there.
I'll come over there without a gun.
You can frisk me, so you can see you can trust me
so we can talk and find a way out of this mess.
Right.
I just want to find some way
that I can trust you too, right?
I don't want to just thrust me body out on the
street where you could just shoot me, right?
- Some sign, right?
- Right. Like what?
How about let the people out of the bank?
Come on, now. Hey, wait a minute.
Who do you think you're dealing with?
A fucking idiot here?
They're keeping me alive.
I'm going to let them out?
Why don't you talk to me?
Just talk to me straight.
- I'm ready to talk.
- Okay. Okay. Okay.
How about you give us the women?
No, I've got women.
That's all I've got here.
Okay. Well, give me something.
Give me one of them, anyway.
- What do you want one for?
- Well, it's like a fair exchange.
I'm going to come over there.
I'm not going to be packing nothing.
Oh, yeah?
I don't know if you're going
to keep me as a hostage.
It's a sign of trust, right?
How do I reach you?
How the hell do I call you back?
We got a direct line here.
You just pick up the receiver,
and I'm here. Okay?
He wants one.
Him, right?
Right!
- Right?
- Right.
- Okay?
- Okay.
He goes.
What are we dealing with here?
You have to keep checking me out
all the time?
Yeah.
He'll need the keys.
You got the keys?
- Just the one, Sonny!
- Right.
Hey! Don't fire! Don't fire!
- What are you doing?
- Get away from him!
- That's a hostage!
- Don't fire, damn it!
- Hold your fire!
- Don't fire!
Don't fire! Don't fire! Hold your fire!
Hold your fire!
We voted to send him out!
- He's one of the hostages!
- Get away from him!
What's the matter with you?
He's a hostage!
He's one of the hostages!
Get away from him!
What the hell's the matter with you?
I don't give a fuck, goddamn it!
Get away! Get out of here!
Come on! Get away!
Hey, Sonny! Wait a minute, Sonny!
Sonny, that was your fault, Sonny.
You know we had the communications
set up here.
We haven't set it up properly.
We have 250 cops here.
We don't know what the fuck
is going on in there.
- You almost killed him! Are you crazy?
- That was smart!
You told me you got nothing but women,
and you throw out a guy.
What the fuck's going on in there?
You wanted a hostage,
I brought one out for you.
- Are you going to deal with us or not?
- I told you I'd give you one, I gave you one, right?
You did, but you should have
picked up the phone!
Come on out, Sonny. Look!
I ain't packing nothing, see?
I ain't packing nothing.
You can come out and frisk me.
You can tell. Huh?
- So, what do you want me to come out for?
- I want you to take a look at something. Come on.
- I want you to see what you're up against.
- I can see. Why do I got to come out for?
I want you to come out and see it all. All right?
Come on.
All right?
I got Sal in there with the other people.
Anything happens to me, they're
going to get it. You understand me?
I don't forget about Sal. I want you
to come out and take a look. Okay?
Come on. Okay?
- I got to check with him first.
- All right. You don't need that artillery.
Sonny. 5 minutes. You tell him that.
Take it easy.
All right. He's coming. Get them back.
He's got a white flag.
All right. Okay. Everything's all right.
Come on. Right. Yeah. Okay.
Come on out, Sonny.
He's too close here.
Come on! Get back!
What the fuck are you doing? Get back!
- Get them back.
- Get back! Okay?
Come on out.
Take a look at this. Come on.
Here, look! Look up here. Look.
Look over here. Huh?
Over there, right?
We got everything here, okay?
You got the militia out here, huh?
Let Sal come out and take look, all right?
What hope have you got, huh?
Come on. Quit while you're ahead.
- All you've got is attempted robbery.
- Armed robbery.
All right, armed, then!
But nobody's been hurt.
Release the hostages. Nobody's going
to worry over kidnapping charges.
The most you're going to get is 5 years.
You'll get out in 1 year, huh?
- Kiss me. Yeah.
- What?
Kiss me.
- When I'm being fucked, I like to get kissed a lot.
- Hey, come on. Come on. Come on.
You're a city cop, right?
Robbing a bank is a federal offense.
They got me on kidnapping, armed robbery.
They're going to bury me, man.
I don't want to talk to somebody who's trying
to con me. Get somebody in charge here.
I am in charge here.
I don't want to talk to some flunky pig
trying to con me, man.
- You're not to call me pig.
- What's he doing?
- Will you get back over there?
- What are they moving in there for?
Will you get the fuck back there?!
Get back there, will you?!
Come on! Get over there!
- Go on back there, man!
- Get over there, will you?!
He wants to kill me so bad, he can taste it!
- Okay, nobody's going to kill anybody.
- Attica!
Attica!
Remember Attica!
Your word don't fucking matter!
No, no, no! Come on! Come on!
Calm down, will you? Calm down.
Put your guns down!
- If it wasn't for the TV guys, they'd kill us all!
- Come on! Will you get back?
Put your fucking guns down!
Tell them to put their guns down!
All right! Will you get back?!
Put those guns down! Get back!
Put your fucking guns down!
Put those guns down!
Put them down! Put them down!
Put those fucking guns down!
Put those guns down!
Attica!
You got it, man!
You got it!
...headquarters in Washington...
- Robbing a bank?
- ...has produced the information...
...as to the identity of one of the men in the bank.
- Why didn't he tell me he needed money?
- As to previous pubic record, he served in Vietnam.
- He should have come to me if he needed money.
- His name is Sonny Wortzik, it look like here.
- I couldn't believe it.
- So far...
...we know that 8 people
are still being held in the bank.
The situation inside the bank
is totally unknown to us other than...
...descriptions that have been
obtained from Howard Calvin.
- Why rob a bank when you got a sucker for a mother?
- He reports...
We'll switch you now to Ron Cummons
at the bank in Brooklyn.
Miss Benson, what's it like inside?
- They're holding up. What can you say?
- Just keep it cool.
- The guy in there,
- Got a deal?
who's got a gun on them, is the quiet type.
Is there enough confidence
in Detective Moretti?
Well, they don't know Detective Moretti yet.
I got to go now.
What's this with the hands?
She's out, let her stay out.
Come on, stay out.
They're my girls. I'm going back in there.
- Howard. How is he?
- Howard's all right.
Put the TV on.
Girls, I was interviewed!
Sal, it looks good.
They got everybody out there.
They got the whole media.
Television people.
- What?
- Television people.
They want to talk to you. They're out there.
Yeah?
Hello, Sonny. Sonny, you're on the air.
Would you mind answering
a few questions for us?
Yeah.
Why are you doing this?
- Hello?
- See?
No, I just saw myself there. What?
- Why am I doing it?
- Yes.
- Doing what?
- Robbing a bank.
Oh!
What? I don't know what you mean by that.
I'm robbing a bank, 'cause they got
money here. That's why I'm robbing it.
No, no. What I mean is, why do you
feel you have to steal for money?
Couldn't you get a job?
No. Doing what?
You know, if you want a job,
you got to be a member of a union.
See, if you got no union card,
you don't get a job.
What about non-union ocupations?
What's wrong with this guy?
What do you mean non-union?
Like what, a bank teller?
You know how much a bank teller
makes a week?
- Not much.
- Not much. $115 to start, right?
You're going to live on that?
I got a wife and a couple of kids.
How am I going to live on that?
What do you make a week?
- I'm here to talk to you, Sonny.
- Well, I'm talking to you.
We're entertainment, right?
What do you got for us?
What do you want to get for it?
Do you expect to be paid, because--?
No, I don't want to be paid.
I don't need to be paid. Look...
I'm here with my partner and 9 other people.
See, we're dying, man. You know?
You're going to see our brains on the sidewalk.
They're going to spill our guts out.
Now, you're going to show that on television?
Have all the housewives look at that?
Instead of "As The World Turns"?
I mean what do you got for me?
I want something for that.
- Sonny.
- Yeah.
- You could give up.
- Give up?
- Right. You ever been in prison?
- No.
No! Well, let's talk about something
you fucking know about, okay?
How much you make a week?
- That's what I want to hear.
- Ladies and gentlemen...
- You're going to talk to me about that?
- ...our transmission has been temporarily interrupted.
Please stand by. We will return
to our special news cast very soon.
Hey, hello?
What the fuck happened?
Hey!
Guess he didn't appreciate
your use of language.
Fuck him!
Sal.
Sal!
I don't know, they might deal with us.
You know. I mean I don't know
about that guy out there.
But if I get the FBI involved in this,
you know, they might deal.
What do you think?
No.
- Sal.
- No!
What's the matter with you?
You made a promise, didn't you?
Did you promise me something, huh?
Yeah.
Did you say either we get away clean,
or we kill ourselves? Did you say that?
- I'm not talking about--
- Did you?
- I'm not talking about that.
- Did you not?
- I do believe--
- Do you believe in keeping your promises?
- Yeah, but I'm not--
- Does it still go?
- Yes, it still goes.
- Then what the fuck are you talking about?
I'm trying to...
I ain't going back to that prison, Sonny.
- Yeah.
- Kill them all now.
- Take your bayonet and jam it into their--
- Fuck you! Fuck!
We ask for a jet. What do you think?
We get a helicopter.
We get a helicopter here,
it lands on the roof,
and takes us to a jet,
and we fly the fuck out of the country.
Sal...
Sal, we can do it.
Sal, Sal.
Look. We got them.
We don't even know it, you know.
We've got the hostages.
You know, we've been looking
at this the wrong way.
We make the demands!
They're going to give us anything we want.
I'm flying to the tropics. Fuck the snow!
Hey, where is the mouth?
- You ready to go to Algeria?
- Algeria? Yeah, sure!
We're all going to sunny climes!
Sal, I can make it happen!
I can make it happen!
I've made it happen so far, right?
I can make it happen.
Yeah.
Give me Moretti.
Sarge!
All of you, go ahead, make phone calls.
Call home or whatever.
We're all going on a trip.
- Yeah, Sonny.
- Yeah. I want to talk to you.
- I'm coming out.
- Good, good. Okay. We'll be there.
Let's go. Come on. He's coming out.
Sal.
Now. You got to understand something.
If we leave the country,
there's no coming back here.
You know what I mean?
There's no coming back.
So if there's anybody now
that you want to talk to,
you want to say goodbye to,
do it now.
No.
Is there any special country
you want to go to?
Wyoming.
No, Wyoming... That's not a country.
That's all right. I'm going to take care of it.
Yeah!
All right. Put them down! Yeah?
Put them down! You hear that?
What do I have?
See this here? Look!
I got nothing up my sleeve!
I got nothing here either! All right?
You want to see my pockets? Here!
You need that gun, right!
Right Moretti?
Tell them to put their guns down!
Hey, you! See that?
Put it in your holster!
Put the guns down!
You know what it means
to put a gun down? What's this?
What's this?
Right! Thank you very much!
Thank you very much!
You got it, right?
You got it, baby! Hey, Moretti!
You made it happen!
You got Maria in there!
Maria!
He's got a gun in there!
Maria! Maria!
Get him the fuck out of here! Jesus.
How the hell did that happen?
- Hey, Sonny!
- I got Sal in there!
All right. Take it easy! Take it easy!
Notify the precinct. All right?
Who the fuck is that?
It is one of the Spanish kids.
- Who's Maria?
- You got her inside.
Sal wants to see Sonny!
He says he'll shoot unless he sees Sonny!
- Sal!
- He's serious! Sonny, he means it!
- He means it!
It's all right. It's all right.
It's all right.
- Hey, man, I'm sorry.
- How'd that happen?
You got his girlfriend in there.
You know the Spanish. Are you okay?
That fuck tried to kill me.
- You look all squeezed out.
- Squeezed out. I'm squeezed out!
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Okay. Let me see.
Let me see your head, all right?
- I'm bleeding!
- Let me see it.
Let me see.
Oh, Jesus. Oh, Jesus. Yeah, yeah.
It's all right. You want to talk
to me about something?
Should've heard that phone call in there.
Calls up some creep, says, "Kill everybody".
Everyboydy wants to kill everybody.
I think you're going to get
assholes like that any how, right?
Yeah, I want to talk to you. I got an offer.
I want a helicopter out of here.
And a jet to go wherever I want to go.
So I don't want a little jet, I want a big one.
One with a bar, a piano lounge, 'cause maybe
I want to go out of the country, you know.
I don't know Sonny. I don't know whether
a helicopter would fit in here or not. You know?
- I'll check it.
- It could land on the roof.
No, no, no. That's asphalt, you know what'll
happen there, you know, it'll break through.
Look, I'll call my superiors, you understand?
Why not bring your superiors here?
Let me talk to them.
Why am I talking to you for,
if you got to call superiors?
- We don't always see eye-to-eye.
- Yeah, so I'll talk to them.
All right. Let me call them
and see what they'll say.
I'll talk to them and I ask them, all right?
Then we'll see.
Anything else I can get you?
Yeah, I want you to bring my wife down here.
- Okay. What do you give us?
- What do you want?
The women hostages.
Oh, man, you know.
There's no talking to you!
That's all I got in there.
I told you, there's women.
You're going to talk to me or what?
I give one hostage for each thing
you give me, see?
If you give me the helicopter,
then I give you a hostage.
If you give me the jet,
You give me my wife, I give you a hostage.
And then the rest come home on the jet.
I'll see what they'll do, all right?
In the meantime, you pick out
who you want to give us,
and you tell me where your wife is, all right?
I'm sitting here minding my own business,
I hear the transistor go "Sonny what?"
I can't believe my ears! I grab the kids!
I'm telling you right now, Sonny didn't do it!
It ain't him to rob a bank!
It ain't him to steal or hurt anybody
or threaten anybody or do nothing wrong!
'Cause he's never done nothing wrong
since the day I know him!
Night before last, we're at Coney Island.
I'm looking in the glove compartement.
He's got a gun with bullets in it.
Things are adding up in my head
how crazy he's been acting lately
and in with a bad crowd.
So I look at him.
Go on, get in bed.
He's yelling at the kids like a madman.
And then he wants me to go on this kiddie
ride for the little kids. I don't want to go.
He starts screaming at me.
Shh, sweetheart. Shh, shh.
He's screaming and screaming
and screaming.
It's in the car. I say to him, "Sonny,
what are you going to do with the gun?
"You're going to shoot me and
dump my body in the river? What?"
I mean, I was scared of him.
I've never been scared of him.
You know, his mother says we was always
fighting. The cops was always at our house.
Well, I hit him with a jack handle
once in the car.
Only I didn't even hit him. I hit myself.
You should've seen the bruise on my leg.
From here to here.
You know what he'd do? He'd put on
his hat and coat, he goes out the door.
So they tell me he did it.
But I don't believe it.
Mrs. Wortzik, please, listen to me.
They want you down at the bank.
He might've done it, his body functions might
've done it, but he himself, he didn't do it!
"Dear Abby, lately I've been dreaming
about falling into water
"and not being able to reach the surface.
"I begin to breathe heavily
and I wake up in a cold sweat.
"A friend tells me that my problem
is one of sexual repression."
Margaret, are you all right?
Yeah.
Are you doing anything
to any of those girls on there?
He's back again.
Well?
Who is this?
Sonny, look at Margaret.
What's the matter with her?
There's no air in here.
What happened to the air conditioning?
I'm sorry, Syl.
Where's the air conditioning?
In the basement.
Sal, I'm going to check the air conditioning.
I'll be right back.
Sonny.
What?
I never been up in an airplane before.
So? I mean...
It's safe. It's like a car.
It's safer than a car.
It's all right, Sal.
- I'm going to go check it now.
- Okay.
- Sal!
- What?!
They're coming in the back!
In the vault! Come on!
Get in there! Move!
- Back! Get back!
- No, no, no, no! Don't fire!
That's it, Sonny!
Get her in there!
Who fired that shot?
Pick her up and put her in.
Who fired the shot?
Come on! Move!
Okay, legs!
Sonny!
Hey, Sonny!
Get me a bullhorn!
Sonny!
You got that bullhorn?
Hey, Sonny!
Come on out, Sonny!
Sonny!
Shit, that's all I need.
Go take care of that, will you?
Sonny, come on out!
Go straighten that out, will you, Carmine?
Sonny!
Sonny, come on out.
Sonny?
Sonny!
You son of a bitch,
you want to get those people killed?
Come on out, Sonny.
Sonny, come on out.
Come on out here, now.
Come on out, Sonny.
Sonny!
Sonny?
Come on out here, Sonny.
All right, I see you, Sonny. Come on! Come on!
All right, get back.
What the fuck is the matter with you?
- What?
- Why'd you fire that shot in there for?
- What were they doing back there?
- We got 250 cops here, for Christ's sake!
- Fuck you! What were they doing back there?
- What goes in there?
What the hell's the matter with you? Huh?
- What's the matter--?
- Are we dealing or aren't we?
- They were trying to get in there, right?
- Who?
Come on, don't give me that shit.
You know who.
- What the fuck is going on here?
- You're full of shit!
Go around and find out
what's going on back there!
- Honest to God, Sonny,
- Oh, yeah?
- I don't know what the fuck is going on here!
- Bullshit!
- Our communications aren't set up yet.
- I just sent somebody back there. Goddamn it!
- You get someone to talk to me!
Get somebody to talk to me.
I'm not talking to you anymore.
- Let me talk to you. Let me talk to you. All right?
- Yeah, you tell me one thing,
- then you do another.
- Now wait a minute. Hold on a second.
What were they doing back there?!
I don't know what the fuck
they were doing back there!
Yeah, you don't know. You're full of shit!
That's another force back there.
A tactical force!
They like to shoot, they like to jump on ropes,
they like to climb in through windows!
They like that, right! Without your orders,
right? Without your orders.
- No! Yes! Without my orders! Yes!
- Yes?
How do I know you're not going
to come through the roof?
'Cause I'm telling you that we are not.
Yeah? You're telling me a lot of things,
but you're not doing them.
- Oh, goddamn it, when I told you--
- What were they doing back there?!
- That's what I want to know!
- I don't know what they were doing back there!
- And you can't answer me!
- I'm out here!
- You can't answer me!
- What?
- You can't answer me.
- Yes, I can answer you!
- So tell me what they were doing there.
- They were setting communications up there.
No communications! We got them set up.
I just sent somebody back there.
I got a guy in there who's going to kill somebody.
That's your responsibility. You understand?
- Not mine, that's yours.
- Now wait a minute. Hold on a second. Listen.
We got everything you wanted.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
We can't get a helicopter in here,
but we got a bus is coming.
We got a jet coming into Kennedy, all right?
Okay? All right?
Now, we got ahold of your wife.
Your wife is coming.
We reached her,
and she's coming here, all right?
Okay?
- Where are you going?
- I'm right here.
I'm right here, all right?
I thought we were going to talk.
I thought so, too, but we're not talking.
- I'm talking now, all right?
- We're trying to get in through the back door.
That's what we're doing.
We reached your wife.
She'll be here in about half an hour.
Okay? Okay?
What are they doing? They're still pointing.
They love to point.
Holster that weapon! Holster it!
Holster that weapon!
You too!
All right, come on.
- What do you want?
- What else do you want me to do, huh?
I don't know how could you do any better.
We got everything you wanted. Everything.
I'll do anything I can to stop
anything I can. All right?
Anything else?
- Yeah.
- What?
- I got some people in there that are hungry.
- Uh-huh. Okay?
- Can you get some food for them?
- No problem. What do you want?
- Want some pizzas? Pizzas?
- Yeah, all right.
Hey, Carmine!
Get some food here, some pizzas, all right?
Can we get some beer, you think?
No, no. No beer. No, no.
Let's keep it to soft drinks, all right?
Come on. All right? Carmine!
Some soft drinks too, okay? Cokes!
- What else?
- I need some aspirin too.
- Some lady's not feeling well.
- Some arpirin, all right. Some aspirin!
You got it. Anything else?
Just don't fucking con me. That's it.
I'm not conning you. Why the hell
would I want to do that, for Christ's sake?
I'm in trouble enough as it is.
I'm not trying to create any trouble.
All right?
It's okay.
They can't bring a helicopter in here, Sal.
'Cause they can't land it here.
But they're going to get us a limousine bus,
a big bus, so that we can all get in.
And that's how we get to the airport.
It's good. It looks good.
You people, I just ordered you some food. So...
I even got her some aspirins.
Okay? So we're moving it along now.
I got to pay for the food.
Where's the marked fives?
That was a foolish thing you did back there.
Foolish thing.
We're going to get the ball rolling?
Yeah, we're going to get the ball rolling.
What do you think I'm doing?
I'm working on it, right? What's it look like?
You think it's easy?
You know, I got to keep them cooled out.
I got to keep all you people happy.
I got to have the ideas
and got to do it all alone.
I'm working on it. You want to try it?
Your food is here, Sonny.
You're starting to get on my nerves.
You just go on with him there.
You'll be all right. Go right ahead.
- What do I owe you for this?
- It's all paid for.
- It's all paid for?
- No, no, no. I've paid for that. It's all right.
No, no, no. I got it. I got it.
Here.
Keep the change.
What?
- You want this?
- Yeah.
- You like it?
Moretti, could you use five?
I got a lot for you.
Get back, goddamn it! Get back!
More!
Could you open it?
Thank you, man.
See you later.
I'm a fucking star!
Kick. Out. Turn.
No, just pick her up and hold her is all.
She'll be okay.
You kick good. Here.
Kick. Out.
This is where it gets stuck!
Miriam's making a fool of herself.
- Anybody got a cigarette?
- Yeah, I do.
Sylvia, you don't smoke!
You don't smoke?
No.
Why do you want to start now?
- I'm scared to death, that's why.
- What? You don't smoke?
- No.
- How come?
- I don't want the cancer.
- Oh, my God!
Give me the cigarette.
Go ahead. Do what you want.
I just think you ought to take care
of your body, that's all.
My body? What for?
Your body is the temple of the Lord.
You're serious!
So you rob a bank,
but you keep your body pure. Is that it?
You're going to smoke the cigarette or what?
Yes.
If I die of cancer, it'll be half your fault.
No, it's because you're weak.
Right, I'm weak.
Where's your bullets?
Mulvaney speaking.
It's Moretti.
Yeah.
Will you guys hold it down back there?
Sonny, they're bringing in your wife.
Step back. Step back.
- Where's Moretti?
- Probably at the bar.
In the barber shop.
What's that?
We went to Bellevue where you told us.
Said he was his wife.
They were married in a church.
Jesus Christ!
Leon!
Hey, Leon, over here!
Leon! Hey, Leon!
Leon, over here!
Leon!
Happy birthday!
- Give us some room!
- His head! Watch his head!
He's a queer?
Hey, Sarge! Sarge, he wants you!
Come on! Get the goddamn shield
out of here. I don't need it now.
Where the fuck were you 4 hours ago,
when I needed it?
He's not going to shoot.
Yeah, Sonny, what? Yeah.
What happened? Is he all right?
He's a little groggy right now, okay?
No, let me talk to him.
Let me get him on his feet
and I'll call you back, all right? Okay.
Shut the fucking door!
Stop the noise!
I don't want to hear a fucking sound!
Typewriter!
Get off the fucking phone!
Now!
Give me some water.
Leon?
Leon.
You all right, Leon?
What's the matter? They give you a shot
down at the hospital or something?
Oh, God! They shot me with, like, unreal!
Now you got to get ahold of yourself, Leon.
So you can talk to him,
and see if he'll come out of the bank.
He's got 8 people in there. He's a kid in there
in the name of a Sal. Do you know him?
- No, not really.
- He says he's going to shoot these 8 people.
I can't help it. I can't stop him from anything.
If he won't listen to you, who will he listen to?
I can't talk to him. He won't listen to anybody.
He's been crazy all summer.
He's been trying to kill me since June.
He put a gun to my head.
And he cut me with a knife.
- He beat up my friends.
- Did you try get in touch with the police?
What good would that do?
It'd just make him mad. They don't
know him. And it wouldn't stop him.
Somebody's got to stop him.
- He's making threats in there.
- You don't understand. He's crazy.
He's got a wife, children.
He's a wonderful father.
His mother...
You should see her. His mother and father
together are like a bad car wreck.
It just rolls off his back.
He sees them, he pays the rent.
Unbelievable!
I was the one who wanted to get married.
He didn't really want it, but...
...he did it. I don't know why.
Why did you want to get married, Leon?
I thought it would help me.
But it didn't.
I was so confused. I was doing...
...insane things.
What sort of things, Leon?
After the wedding,
I ran off for 10 days to Atlantic City.
Sonny was frantic.
He knew I'd been drinking. He didn't
know where I was, who I was with.
I couldn't explain the things I did.
So I went to a psychiatrist,
who told me
that I was a woman
trapped in a man's body.
Well, so right away, Sonny wanted to give
me money for the sex change operation.
But where was he going to get it?
$2,500?
My God, he was in hock
up to his ears already.
He needed the money
for the operation for you?
It drove him crazy.
He would fly into these rages.
And I got more depressed than ever.
I knew I'd never get my operation.
So I tried to kill myself.
I took about a half a pound of pills.
Blues, reds, yellows, screamers,
uppers, downers, you name it.
And I wound up in the hospital.
And Sonny comes there,
and he just looks at me.
And he says...
"Why, Leon?
"When things were going so good?"
Don't you think, Leon...
Don't you think he sort of did it for you?
Yeah, I guess so.
Don't you think you sort of owe it to him
to see if you can get him out of there?
I can't talk to him.
You're up to your neck in it, Leon.
You're an accessory.
- No, no. They can't hold me responsible.
- I wonder if you could help us.
- A little understanding and you're out of here.
- No.
- Come on.
- I'm afraid.
- Just talk to him for a minute, all right?
- No, please.
- Come on.
- I can't talk!
- How's he going to hurt you on the phone?
- No.
All you're going to be is on the phone.
- I can't. I don't know what to...
- Just talk to him.
- Right over here. On the phone.
- I can't.
You think about it now.
Yeah.
He doesn't want to talk to you.
What do you mean he won't talk to me? Why?
Let me work on it.
I thought that was what you were going to do.
He don't want to talk to me.
Police are questioning Leon Schermer,
a 26-year-old admitted homosexual,
who claims to have been married to one of
the bank robbers in a ceremony last November.
According to our sources in the
barber shop where Leon is being held,
Leon has been reported as saying
that they were married in an
official ceremony by a Father Burke.
Leon 's story has been confirmed.
7 bridesmaids, all male, Sonny's mother
and 70 about other guests,
all members of the gay community
were present.
We've been able to obtain
a still photograph of Leon in his gown.
Leon has confirmed
that the gowns for himself
and his bridesmaids cost $700.
We have not been able to confirm the story
with the priest who performed the ceremony.
However, we are told
that he was subsequently defrocked.
Phone calls have begun to arrive at our switchboard
from various factions of the gay community.
Some in full support of Sonny and his actions,
others totally condemning the present events
and calling the marriage a farce, and,
quote, "A case of sheer
exhibitionism.", end quote.
Our coverage of the bank robbery where
2 homosexuals are holding hostages
- for their demands of a helicopter, a jet...
- Sonny.
Sonny, they said on the TV,
"2 homosexuals in the bank."
Right on TV. You hear what they said?
What difference does it make? It don't matter.
They're going to say anything they want.
Let them say it.
Well, I'm not a homosexual.
You tell them to get that right now.
That's going out on the TV.
Sal, what am I supposed to do, you know?
I can't control what they say on television.
What do you expect me to do? I mean
I'm doing everything I can, I can't do that.
Look, Sal.
Forget about it. It's just a freak show
to them, anyway. It don't matter.
Whatever they say, it don't matter.
It'll be all right.
What's the matter with you?
You shouldn't let something like that
spoil your fun, you know.
You've got to get fun out of life.
Where's the goddamn jet?
They're always screaming overhead,
going somewhere,
when you don't need them, you know?
What are you going to do? What are you going
to tell the pilot when you get on the plane?
Did you know that Holland's pretty good.
- Holland?
- Yeah. They sheltered people during the war.
They're good people.
Where's Holland?
It's right up...
It's right over there!
Get in the vault. Get in the vault. Come on!
Quickly!
They're waiting for us
to do something, I think.
Sonny.
Come on out for a second, please.
It's him. It's him, Sonny.
Come on out here.
I want to talk to you a second.
- Come on, Sonny!
- Sonny.
Sonny.
Come on out, Sonny.
Sonny?
Come on out a minute.
That's it, Sonny.
Moretti!
What the fuck is going on?
Get the lights back on!
Moretti!
Who are you?
FBI, Sheldon.
Oh, good.
About time. Maybe we can
get this thing started, huh?
Look, get the lights back on
and the air conditioning.
We got no air conditioning in here.
No more favors. That's all over, Sonny.
Favors?
You been doing me favors all night?
I have a jet, I'll have a limousine here
in half an hour.
I want the hostages.
No, no, no. Bullshit.
I'd like to work with you on this,
Sonny, not against you.
Yeah, well, the hostages are
what's keeping me alive.
When do I get them?
Didn't anybody tell you anything?
I'd like to hear it from you.
You get one hostage for the
limousine that you bring me in.
One hostage for the jet.
Then I get to the airport,
I go into the plane, check it all out,
and if it's okay, then they all come out.
- I want to go inside.
- Why?
See if everybody's all right.
They're all right.
No, I have to see.
You got guts.
What you think of me and Sal slit
their throats, we're going to let you out?
I have to see.
I got to check with my partner.
The FBI, Sal. It's coming in.
You'd like to kill me, huh?
I bet you would.
I wouldn't like to kill you.
I will if I have to.
It's your job, right?
You know, the guy who kills me,
I hope he does it because he hates
my guts, not 'cause it's his job.
All right. You can get in.
Okay. Nobody give your right name.
It's the FBI.
I just want to make sure all you
young ladies are all all right in here.
Look.
They asked for the jet hours ago.
Now, what are you doing out there?
That's being set up. We'll have you
out of here in a couple of hours.
- A couple of hours?
- Why don't you just give them what they want?
They'll get what they want. We want
to make sure we get what we want.
Let's get you all out of here safe.
You two boys too.
That's close enough.
Tell the TV to stop saying
there's 2 homosexuals in here.
I will, Sal.
Outside for a minute, Sonny?
You handled yourself real well, Sonny.
A lot of men would have choked.
We might have had a death or
a multiple death on our hands.
But you handled it. I respect that.
Don't you try to take Sal. We'll handle him.
You just sit tight and you won't get hurt.
Wiat a minute. Wait a minute.
What are you talking about?
You just sit quiet.
We'll handle Sal.
You think I'd sell him out, you fuck?!
What'd he say?
He was just talking to me
about the arrangements.
I talked to him about the TV, Sal.
It's going to be all right.
That's all?
Yeah.
Why couldn't he say that in here?
I don't know. He wanted to show me, you know,
how it's going to come in, how the bus is coming in.
What's the matter?
Somebody get a glass of water.
Got a hankie over there?
They poisoned the pizza.
It's not the pizza!
He's got diabetes.
He had some Coke before.
Don't give him anything. I'll hold it for you.
What can we do for you,
Mr. Mulvaney? Tell us.
Is there a doctor out here?
We need a doctor in here.
We need a doctor.
What's wrong?
The manager, he's a diabetic.
He don't look good.
All right. Come on.
I got to search you.
Okay.
Just him.
Sonny.
I've convinced Leon to talk to you.
He's on the phone now.
He's coming on.
Hello?
Hello, Leon?
Hello. Hello, Sonny.
What happened?
How are you doing?
Well, I'm out of the hospital.
Yeah, I know. You know,
I thought you'd never get out.
I never thought I'd get out this way, I'll tell you.
Yeah.
So how're you doing?
- I'm a little shaky.
- Oh, yeah?
Moretti told me, you know,
that you were all drugged up,
so I figured that's why you didn't
want to talk to me, you know.
'Cause I was wondering
why you didn't talk to me.
It was really terrible, you know?
I mean, you walk in, and right away
they say you're crazy.
And then they start sticking
things in your arm. I mean...
How do they expect you to get uncrazy,
if you're asleep all the time?
I'm just starting to come out of it now.
- So?
- Well!
So, how are you?
I'm fine.
This is something, huh?
Yeah, yeah.
I don't know, Leon, you know.
I'm dying here. I'm dying.
Don't you ever listen to yourself
when you say that? That you're dying?
- Huh? Did you ever listen to yourself?
- What? What are you talking about?
What do you mean, what am I
talking about? "You're dying."
Do you know that you say that
to me every day of your life?
"I'm dying." You're not dying. You're killing
the people around you is what you're doing.
Come on, Leon. Don't give me that shit.
You know, I don't need that deep shit now!
Well, I don't think you realize what it means,
Sonny. You know? The things you do?
Yeah?
I know what I do.
You stick a gun to somebody's head.
- Well, I don't know what I'm doing sometimes with that.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Obviously, you don't.
"Go to sleep, Leon,
so it won't hurt when I pull the trigger."
What do you think
I've been doing in the hospital?
I mean, I take a handful of pills
to get away from you.
- Right? So...
- Yeah?
Now I'm talking to you
on the phone again, right?
I've got no job. I don't have friends.
I can't live. I have to live with people.
This death business, I'm sorry.
I don't know, Leon, you know? I don't know
what I'm getting here with that shit, you know.
What am I supposed to say to that shit?
You know? This is going on.
- And you're giving me that shit.
- I'm sorry.
You know what's happening with me.
You know that.
You know the pressures
I've been having. Right?
I mean, I got all these pressures and you
know about it. You're in that hospital there,
with all them tubes coming out,
and you want that fucking operation, right?
You're giving me that shit.
Everybody's giving me shit.
Everybody needs money.
You know what I mean?
So you needed money,
I got you money. That's it.
Yeah, Well, I didn't ask you
to go and rob a bank!
I know you didn't ask me.
I know you didn't ask me. Look.
You know. I'm not putting this
on anybody. You know?
Nothing on nobody!
I did this on my own. You see?
All on my own, I did it.
But I just want you to know something.
I want you to know that I'm getting out of here.
I'm getting a plane out of here,
and I just wanted you to know it. That's all.
And I wanted you to come down,
and I wanted to just say goodbye to you.
Or, if you wanted to, you could come with me.
I mean, you're free to do what you want.
That's just what I wanted to say to you. That's all.
- I'm free to do what I want, huh?
- Right.
Yeah, well, I've been trying to
get away from you for 6 months
and I'm going to go with you
on a a plane trip, huh?
Where? Where are you going?
I don't know where yet.
We said Algeria. I don't know.
So I'll go to Algeria. I don't know that.
Why are you going to Algeria?
I don't know why. They got a Howard
Johnson's there, so I'm going.
Howard Johnson's! You're warped,
you know that? You're really warped.
I'm warped. I know I'm warped.
God! Algeria!
You know they walk around, they got
masks on, they got things on their heads.
- They're a bunch of crazy people there.
- So what am I supposed to do?
Well, I don't know.
- You could have picked a better place.
- Like where?
Sweden? Denmark?
Yeah, like that. Yeah.
You know what?
Sal wanted to go to Wyoming.
I had to tell him it's not a country.
He don't know where Wyoming is.
See, I'm with a guy who don't know where
Wyoming is. You think you got problems?
So, Sal is with you, huh?
Oh, boy!
You'd be better off giving up.
I'm not going to give up, because why have
I done this so far? You know what I mean?
I've gone so far with this,
and why should I give up now?
I can't give up.
- Would you do me a favor then?
- Yeah, what?
Well, these guys that have me down here,
you know, they think...
They think I'm part of it, you know?
They think I'm part of the plot to rob the bank.
That's crazy, Leon. That's crazy. They're just...
They're bullshitting you.
They're giving you a snow job.
- Now they told me I was an accessory.
- No!
That's just a con job on you, Leon.
Don't listen to that shit.
- I have to listen to it.
- No!
I can't survive in prison, Sonny!
- Oh, Leon! You're not going to prison.
- How do you know?
Because I know. You're not
going to prison. Believe me.
- Look, please, just tell them.
- What do you want me to do?
Just tell them what?
That you didn't do it? Where am I...
Are they on the phone now?
Yeah.
That's great, Leon, you know.
That's really terrific!
You talk to me with them on the phone.
That's really smart!
- Well, I don't have a choice!
- What do you mean you didn't have a choice?
What am I supposed to do?
They're standing all around me.
There are 7,000 fucking cops all around me.
- Who's on the phone now?
- Don't lay it on me!
I'm not laying it on you, but you knew
that was going on, right?
What are you talking about laying it on you?
You knew what was happening, right?
Yeah! Yeah!
I want to know who's on the phone now.
Moretti! Moretti, is that you on the phone?
Hello?
Will somebody talk to me?
Somebody's going to talk to me or what?
They on the phone now?
They won't talk to you.
All right. He didn't do it, okay?
He had nothing to do with it.
All right? Will you get the fuck off the phone?
Are they off the phone?
- Yeah.
- All right.
That was terrific, Leon. That really convinced
them. That's what they wanted to know, right?
Did I do it for you or what?
Yeah. Yeah, thank you very much.
So now what? What are you going to do?
Well, I thought...
I thought that I would go back to the hospital.
You know, they're really nice there. I mean
they really seem like they're trying to help me.
So then, that's good, then, right?
You found something.
Well, I don't know if I have or not.
Are you still going to have the operation?
Yeah! Yeah!
So then, what am I supposed to say to you?
Thanks a lot and...
bon voyage.
Yeah, right. See you sometime.
Yeah. I'll see you in my dreams.
Right, I'll write a song.
- I don't know, you know. Life's so funny.
- You said a mouthful, sweetheart.
Well, goodbye, huh?
All right.
- Yeah.
- Give me... Can I have...
- Moretti. Moretti!
- Look. Hey. Hey!
You cut off the incoming calls.
Can I have a line?
I want to talk to my wife.
I want to talk to my kids.
He wants an outside line, is it all right?
- Hey, I want a line.
- Yeah, Sonny. Sonny, I'm getting it.
You know, I could call anybody,
they'd put them on the phone.
The Pope, an astronaut,
the wisest of the wise.
Who do I have to call?
I just don't know what to do.
- Hello?
- Angie.
- Sonny! Jesus! I was watching it on TV.
- Yeah.
- So, where are the kids?
- They don't know. I sent them to the neighbors.
Sonny, I can't believe! I can't believe!
I mean, it ain't like you.
I know.
You've never done anything like it. You've
never hurt anybody before in your whole life.
I'm dying, you know that? I'm dying here.
Sonny, I blame myself. I noticed you've
been tense, like something is happening.
Like that night before last, you're
yelling at the kids like a madman.
And then you want me to go on that ride,
the caterpillar, from here to there,
full of those kids.
It's ridiculous. I'm not about to go
on the ride, so you yell at me.
"You pig, get on the fucking ride!"
Everything fell out of me. My, heart, my liver
just fell to the floor. I mean everything!
You know what it felt like? You yelling
at me in front of all them people?
I mean, 'cause you've never talked
to me like that before, Sonny.
I think, "He's going to shoot me.
He's going to dump my body in the river."
I mean I was scared of you! I was scared!
Will you shut the fuck up
and listen to me?! Just listen to me!
You see? You see that?
With the language and everything?
Well, I'm trying to talk to you, and you--
A person can't communicate with you!
I mean, what am I here?
I'm your wife. I'm your wife!
You know something? You hurt me.
You hurt me, you know that?
Can you imagine, marrying another man?
Did I ever do anything to make you do that?
I mean did I ever turn you down or anything?
I know I let myself get fat.
- No, don't call yourself fat. Don't call yourself fat.
- I know you can't stand me to say I'm fat.
Like I can't stand you being a bank robber,
Sonny. That's what love is.
Yeah? You know what love is, right?
So if you know what love is so much, why
didn't you come down here? Where are you?
Talk to me about love. Go ahead.
Sonny, I'm scared.
I'm scared. Are they going
to shoot me or something?
No, they're not going to shoot you!
You should see it on the TV.
They got cannons, they got machine guns.
They're after me, Angie, not you, you know?
It's late already by the time I find out.
It's just you and Sal. I mean I can't get
a babysitter. What am I going to do?
Listen, I think I better take him back
for a cardiac check.
What's the matter?
Is he going to die or what?
No, no. We should just get him out of here.
It's just a precautionary measure.
It's awfully warm in here.
All right, then. Let's go. Let him out.
I'm not going. I'm okay.
I just needed the injection.
What's the matter with you?
You're trying to be a hero or what?
You don't look good. Look.
Let's go. We'll let you out.
I'm not trying to be anything.
I just want to be left alone. Okay?
- No one is bothering you.
- I wish to fuck you never came into this bank!
That's all.
Don't try to act like you're some
angel of human kindness.
Out of the closet and into the streets!
Sonny all the way!
Ladies!
I want to apologize for my use
of language back there.
Why? What did you say, Mr. Mulvaney?
What did he say?
He said the "F" word.
- What?
- What did he say?
He said the "F" word.
- Fuck.
- I know, Miriam, I know.
Well, I'm a Christian,
and my ears are not garbage cans.
- Come on!
- Oh, Edna!
- Maybe we shouldn't go after them.
- Then we won't.
- What's that?
- Sonny?
Could you come out, please?
- Shit!
- What?
- It's my mother.
Sonny?
Someone here to see you. Sonny?
Could you come out, please?
Sonny.
Sonny, could you come out, please?
Mom, what are you doing down here?
- I don't need you down here.
- Oh, Sonny!
All of Brooklyn is out here.
Three networks of television.
- I got it all worked out, Ma. Don't worry Ma.
- Liaten, I talked to the man from the FBI.
- And he says...
- Who? No, don't talk to anybody.
He says if you come out now,
everything is going to be all right.
- Everything... I'm trying to get you out of this.
- Don't talk to the FBI, Ma.
- I know you are, but don't talk to them.
- I told them everything.
I told them how you were in the war in Vietnam.
I told them you always had good jobs.
I told them you were with Goldwater
in '64 in the convention and--
Listen to me, I'm getting a plane
out of here and I'm going to Algeria.
- I'll write you from there, Ma.
- Algeria?
- Yeah. I've got to get out of here!
- I don't understand.
If I stay out here and talk to you,
they're not going to send me that
limousine to take me to the airport.
They're going to think
I'm going to come out with you.
- What would be the matter if you came out with me?
- Because I'm not coming with you, Ma. Please!
- Listen, the FBI understands everything.
- Yeah.
They understand that it is not you
that is doing this.
It's the pressures from your home life!
Ma, don't get on Angie now.
Don't get on her.
- Did I say one word against her?
- You were going to.
- Ma, she has nothing to do with it. It's me!
- Everything in your life was sweetness and roses.
And you...
You wouldn't need Leon, if Angie
was treating you right, you know that!
I don't understand. I don't understand
why you want to sleep with her anyway.
You got two kids on welfare now.
What do you want to sleep with her?
- You got a wife and two kids on welfare.
- Please, Ma, not now!
- Now you want three kids on welfare?!
- I can't talk to you about this now!
- Ma, Please!
- What are you going to do, all right?
- Come out. Come out!
- I can't come out. I can't.
Because Sal is in there with the people, see?
- If I come out, he's going to kill them.
- Oh, my God!
Run! Run!
Run? Where am I going to run?
Ma, I can't run!
- Maybe...
- There's no maybe. No maybes, Ma, please.
You got to go home now. Where's Pop? Did
he come? He didn't come down here, did he?
Is he pissed off at you!
He says he doesn't have a son.
- He says you're dead.
- He's right.
- Ma, look. Ma!
- No, no, no.
I'm a fuck-up and an outcast, and that's it.
You come near me, you're going to get it.
You're going to get fucked over and fucked out!
Now, I got to go, Ma. Please.
Get her home, okay?
Just take her home!
- How beautiful you were when you were a baby!
- Go home, please. Go home.
Go home now. Go home.
Get her home now!
All right.
(Ten minutes.)
Being of sound mind...
...and body...
You know and all that they...
To my darling wife...
...Leon...
...whom I love...
...more than any man...
...has loved another man...
...in all eternity.
I leave...
...$2,700...
...from my $10,000 life insurance policy...
...to be used...
...for your sex change operation.
If there is any money left over...
...I want it to go to you...
...at my first...
...at the first anniversary of my death...
...at my grave.
To my wife...
...to my sweet wife...
...Angela...
...5,000 from the same policy.
You are the only woman...
...that I ever loved.
And I repledge my love to you...
...in this sad moment.
To little Kimmy...
...and Timmy.
I hope you remember me, Timmy.
You're the little man of the family now.
And I hope you look after them for me.
To my mother...
...I ask forgiveness.
You don't understand...
...the things I said...
...and did.
But I'm me and I'm different.
I want a military funeral.
And I'm entitled to have one, free of charge.
God bless you...
...and watch over you...
...till we are joined in the hereafter.
Yeah, I'll sign. I'll spell that last name.
Come on, Sarge, just one picture, huh?
Back, back, back, back!
- You the driver?
- Yeah.
I want to check it out.
Tese seats come out?
No, they're bolted.
All right, here. Light me on that side.
Give me light over there.
Jesus! You're the man, huh?
I was watching. I saw you, man!
You should see yourself,
you wouldn't believe it!
I believe it.
Sheila ain't gonna believe it!
- Who's Sheila?
- It's my old lady!
They just called and said,
"Gas up a stretch, run it down...
- Give me some light over here.
- "...to 285 Prospect Park West."
I said, "Shit, another load of elephants
from the massage parlors!"
It's okay.
My man, I'm going to remember you.
This is Agent Murphy. He'll be your driver.
No, I want him.
Give me the black guy.
No, hey, man, I ain't into that shit.
Come on! Nobody's going to hurt you.
Hey, nobody's going to shoot. If they were
to shoot, they would've shot already.
- I can't allow that, Sonny.
- You can't allow?
What makes you think you can say
shit to me? I'm running this. Come on.
I'll pay you. What do you want?
$100? $200? $1,000?
Come on.
Don't look at him, I'm running this.
Hey, look, it'll be an adventure.
You men that shoot, aim for white meat.
Take a walk.
Give me him.
You think you're dealing with a fucking idiot?!
Take a walk, cop!
Everybody is a con man. Come on.
I want everybody across the street.
I want them all back, on the sidewalk!
Let's go!
At least I know who I'm dealing with now.
Here's a pen for you. Come on.
Don't move, okay?
Sonny, here's your document.
- Thanks.
- Oh, yu've got to sign it.
We're taking off.
We're going now.
Okay, Sal. Where is he? Sal!
Sal?
That's it, we're going.
Yeah, people, let's go. We're going.
Can I get my sweater?
Get whatever you got when you came in here.
Sal?
Sal.
How're you doing?
- Good. Yeah.
- Good?
We're going to do it. Right?
We're going to do it. Sal see?
You got to keep your eye on him.
Keep your eye on him. He's the driver.
- I need it.
- No, it's mine. Here.
You got to keep your eye on him, Sal, see?
All right, where am I now?
All right, hold it, hold it!
All right, let's go.
Swing around now. Swing around.
Just keep holding hands.
Hold it!
All right. Break it on "three", okay?
Not yet, don't break it.
One...
Two...
Three, go!
Oh, fuck! We did it!
We did it!
Wish us luck!
Bye-bye.
Okay, you got your one.
Follow my car.
Sheldon here. Get me Kennedy.
Sal.
We did it!
I'll be a son of a bitch! We did it!
Okay, let's move. Come on, honk the horn.
Hey, Sal. Do me a favor, will you?
Keep the gun pointed up.
We hit a bump, and it's going to go off.
All right, you set out there?
We're leaving now.
We want no trouble en route.
- Intersections check?
- Check.
- Right. We'll be starting up right now.
- 10-4.
It's going to be all right.
Sal?
Sal, you just have to remember
to keep the gun pointed up.
What's he doing over there?
He's still got some arrangements to make.
- That's it?
- That's it.
Sal, see it? There it is.
Oh, I forgot!
I forgot to ask if they got any food on board.
Are they going to have any food on board?
There's your jet.
We get one more now, right?
That's the deal.
Right. Okay, who goes?
Sylvia?
Maria.
I'll pray for you.
Sal?
'Cause this is your first plane trip,
don't be scared, okay?
Hey, I just realized. I didn't eat all day.
Is there going to be any food on board?
There'll be hamburgers on the plane.
You ready?
- Sal?
- What?
Ready to go?
Yeah.
Okay. Let's move.
Sal.
We don't want any accidents
at this point, right?
Keep your gun pointed up.
You ready to get out first?
I'm ready.
Don't shoot me.
Now spread them!
We're all secure here.
Murphy will report from the car.
You make the report.
Put the gun down.
Back off.
Get up now, Sonny.
You're under arrest.
You have the right to remain silent.
You have the right to an attorney
to be present during your interrogation.
Anything you say can and will be used
against you in a court of law.
If you cannot afford to hire a lawyer,
one will be appointed to represent you
before any questioning if you wish one.
Agent Sheldon, would you
please remain on the apron,
until the hostages are
well inside the terminal?
Repeat.
Agent Sheldon, would you
please remain on the apron,
until the hostages are
well inside the terminal?
Yeah, I got you. We'll hold here.