You've got to climb Mount Everest...
... to reach the Valley of the Dolls.
It's a brutal climb to reach that peak.
You stand there, waiting for the rush
of exhilaration, but it doesn't come.
You're alone.
And the feeling of loneliness
is overpowering.
I never meant to start that climb.
I took the first step when I left
New England and headed for New York.
It wasn't easy to leave
that wonderful house.
My grandparents lived there
and theirs before them.
It was standing during the Revolution.
George Washington didn't sleep there,
but he did dip water from our well.
I can still see them
standing there waving.
Aunt Amy, Mama and Willie.
Poor Willie. He didn't know
I was leaving his life forever.
I'll never forget the night I told them
I was going to New York.
They said it was a dreadful place
for a vacation.
I announced I was going to work there.
Willie took it well.
He said he'd give me a month...
... and I'd run for home
ready to settle down in Lawrenceville.
I remember the day Willie pinned me.
He said it meant
we were engaged to be engaged.
I wanted a marriage like Mom and Dad's,
but not yet.
First I wanted new experiences,
new faces, new surroundings.
Lawrenceville would be there forever.
The cab driver kept complaining
about the sleet and slush.
I told him he should see
one of our New England blizzards.
He took me to the
Martha Washington Hotel for women.
Aunt Amy had stayed there.
She said it was as safe as you
could be in a city like New York.
The desk clerk warned me
they didn't allow men in the rooms.
I confessed I didn't know any.
Before my feet were dry,
the agency sent me on an interview.
I had butterflies, but I acted like
I'd done it all my life.
At least I thought I did.
I knew it. She had that look.
- I'm to see Miss Steinberg.
I knew she was pregnant.
Certainly I should have kept an eye
on her, doctor, but she sneaks out.
I haven't any idea who the father is.
It could have been one of several.
All right. I'll start her
on vitamins tomorrow.
Queeny's pregnant again.
My Siamese.
I hope it isn't that beat-up black tom
with the one eye.
A black Siamese should be very pretty.
I'm Anne Welles.
Oh, yes. The agency phoned about you.
B.A. At Radcliffe? Mr. Bellamy will like
that. He'll think it gives the office tone.
- The agency said he's a lawyer.
- A theatrical lawyer.
He handles actors, writers
and directors. Important ones.
He advises them and draws up
their contracts. No loopholes.
- Sounds fascinating.
- It isn't.
- Will I work for Bellamy or Bellows?
- There is no Mr. Bellows anymore.
Only his nephew, Lyon Burke.
You can tell when he's in the office...
...by the girls around that water cooler.
- How's your shorthand?
- Weak, but I type 60 words a minute.
Okay, I'll take you in to see the boss.
Mr. Bellamy, this is Miss Welles.
She's here about the job.
- She's too good-looking.
- Mr. Bellamy, that's not fair.
I'll just get her broken in
and she'll get married.
- I'm already engaged.
- There, see?
Lots of secretaries are married,
aren't they?
Not in this office. Some days
you'll work until midnight...
...having dinner with me and a client.
I'll drink too much...
...and won't remember a word. You'll
have one sherry and remember it all.
- I have a good memory and love sherry.
- Can you handle it?
- I'm sure I can.
- Could she start right away?
- Stop running my life. I'm not convinced.
- Couldn't you please give me a trial?
All right. I'll try you out for one week,
starting as of now.
Here. Take these contracts to Helen
Lawson at the rehearsal hall on 44th.
Take a cab. See that she signs them.
- Let's see if she can handle that.
- I'll be right back.
And don't give her that "I loved
you when I was a little girl" routine...
...or she'll stab you in the back.
Helen Lawson?
Mr. Bellamy, that was wicked.
Twelve bucks an hour for 80 people,
are you kidding? Come on.
Excuse me.
- Yeah.
- I have some contracts for Miss Lawson.
- Go down the hall and turn left.
First dressing room on the right.
If you're a Capricorn, watch your step.
Yeah, Harry, it's a good company.
Come on.
- Why? Why? Why!
- That's it.
- Five, six, seven, eight.
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight.
Two, two, three, four, five, six,
seven, eight. One, two...
You're sorry?
No good.
Lousy. A beast.
Out.
What kind of a press agent are you?
Why did they send me some green kid
fresh out of NYU?
- Who in hell are you?
- I'm Anne Welles. And I...
Look, I'm tired and I'm busy.
What do you want?
Mr. Bellamy sent some contracts
for you to sign.
You, out.
Come on.
Give me a fountain pen.
And not one of those lousy ballpoints.
Come on.
Sit down. You're making me nervous.
That girl who is singing out there,
she's very good, isn't she?
Yeah.
How do you think the kid's song works
in the new spot? Great, huh?
The song goes.
- What?
- You heard me, the song goes.
- And the kid with it.
- Come on, Neely O'Hara can't hurt you.
You bet your ass she can't.
Because she isn't gonna get the chance.
The only hit that comes out of
my show is Helen Lawson.
And that's me, baby, remember?
- She has a run-of-the-play contract.
- I know about run-of-the-play contracts.
This won't help you in the business.
Right. Nor you, either.
So get Bellamy to do it.
He knows how. He's done it before.
You, go back and tell that son of a bitch
to get off his butt and earn his oats.
- But you haven't signed the contracts.
- And I don't intend to.
Not until Bellamy ties a can
to that little broad's tail.
Mr. Bellamy.
I've thought it over
and I don't think I...
- Oh.
...want this job.
Excuse me. You must be Mr. Burke,
the one with the water cooler.
- I mean...
- And you must be Miss Welles.
Mr. Bellamy told me all about you.
Tell me, why are you
dismissing us so soon?
- Because I think show business is cruel.
- You're quite right. Have a seat.
- People do despicable things.
- Yes, they certainly do.
Like firing a girl because a crude person
like Miss Lawson resents her ability.
Please, have a seat.
Miss Welles, a raw recruit always dives
for cover at the first burst of enemy fire.
But don't let that happen to you.
Don't you throw in the towel just yet.
This is a rather cruel business. But it's
also a great and rewarding business.
For every Helen Lawson, there's always
a Helen Hayes or a Mary Martin.
Now you think about that.
- Well, may I have the contracts?
- Yes.
- They are signed?
- Oh... Well, one is.
Yes, yes. One is.
And legibly too.
I almost forgot. She gave me
a message for Mr. Bellamy.
- Yes?
- She said...
- Well, she said, "Tell that son of a..."
- Gun?
- Gun. "Tell him to get off his..."
- Yes, I think I know that message.
I'll see to it that Mr. Bellamy gets it.
Thank you very much, Miss Welles.
- Bye.
Miss Welles, you forgot your purse.
Thank you.
- Sorry.
- It's all right.
I'm afraid I haven't made
a good impression.
On the contrary,
you've made an indelible one.
- Goodbye.
"Barely Pink."
Hey, look at Jennifer.
Hey, Jennifer?
Six hundred bucks for a headdress
and not a soul will see it.
- I feel a little top-heavy.
- Honey, you are a little top-heavy.
All right, that's fine, dear.
Thank you.
Hold it. Hold it!
Cut the song?
- The show is a little long.
- Wait a minute!
That's the best piece of music
in the show.
- Take out one of Miss Lawson's songs.
- Miss Lawson is the star.
- The public pays to see her.
- But I'll have nothing but a few lines left.
- I'm sorry, Neely. We have no alternative.
Don't listen to him.
He's protecting Old Ironsides.
This was her idea.
She can't stand the competition.
- Let's skip the personalities.
- You've got a run-of-the-play contract.
They'll pay me $200 a week
to sit in my dressing room?
They've got to, Miss O'Hara.
If that's the way you want it.
Personally, I'd walk away with dignity.
There'll always be another show
and a better part...
...providing you have talent.
Talent? You know damn well
she has talent!
Believe me, by next week every producer
in town will be after you.
It gives you stature
to walk out on Helen Lawson.
Don't listen. They want you to quit
so they can save 200 bucks a week.
- Call your agent.
I know her agent.
I can tell you what he'll say.
"Take whatever crumbs are offered."
He's not about to give up
his lousy 10 percent.
If she were my client, I'd advise her
to leave the show with dignity.
Well, he's not gonna get
his lousy 10 percent.
Because I won't settle for crumbs.
I'll leave this stinking show...
...with dignity.
You can call Helen Lawson.
Tell her the SOB earned his oats.
We could all use a little fresh air.
Come on.
I had such big plans.
I was gonna be a big star.
I was gonna take acting lessons
and dancing lessons.
Now I don't even have a job.
All I have is my dignity.
Honey, I'm sorry.
That old witch ought to be boiled in oil.
Thanks, Jen.
Honey, listen. It's a rotten business.
I know. But I love it.
- That poor girl. And she was so good.
- I know.
After she signs the release the song
will go back in. With the understudy.
Go to the office. On my desk
you'll find a musical arrangement.
Get it to Miss O'Hara
and tell her to learn it fast.
- She'll be singing it tonight.
- Suppose she won't do it?
- I wouldn't.
- Then make her.
One of the nice things
about doing this telethon...
...in addition to raising money,
is discovering new talent.
I think you'll love our next performer.
Let's have a nice reception...
...for lovely Neely O'Hara.
Everybody, let's hear it out there.
Thank you very much.
You're right. It is an exciting business.
How about that? Where are you going?
Neely, you'll raise a lot of money for us.
Tell Frank, Dean and Sam
they're gonna have to wait.
Thank you.
- Dom Perignon, 1959.
- Fine.
The closest I ever got to champagne was
seeing it broken on a ship in a newsreel.
- Welcome, folks.
- Hello, Frank.
- Lyon.
- Hello.
- Miss O'Hara.
Hello.
I caught the telethon. We're doing
great business with Tony Polar.
So I see.
Excuse me.
Frank.
There's Jennifer with one of her
rich boyfriends. Doesn't she look great?
She's lovely.
- I bet beads pop off when she moves.
- Vodka and tonic.
- Same for me. Make it two.
Neely, I have some good news. You're
following Tony Polar in the club here.
- Oh, Lyon!
- Neely, how wonderful.
You'll have to build an act fast,
because I exaggerated a bit.
- I told Frank you already had one.
- I will. I will.
- Miriam's not gonna like that.
- Who's Miriam?
- His sister. Over there.
- She manages him.
She does very well.
He won't make a move without her.
He's making one now.
- Friend of yours?
- Never saw her before.
- But I'm gonna see her again.
- How many times do I have to tell you?
- At night, all cats are gray.
- You worry too much.
You ought to be ashamed of yourself.
I haven't snitched milk
since I was a kid in Pittsburgh.
There were six of us
and I never got enough.
I can't stop thinking
about that audience tonight.
You don't know how it feels, Mel,
when they all applaud and whistle.
- They did whistle, didn't they?
- They sure did.
I felt like they were all taking me
in their arms and holding me.
It's like when you
put your hands on me...
...only it was double-triple.
This place is too small.
I'm gonna get a bigger place.
Maybe two rooms and a kitchenette.
Mel, let's get married.
I thought you'd never ask.
I'm not kidding.
I'll be making good money.
And with your 150 a week, we can really
live. We can get a maid to clean up.
We can get a mink coat.
Well, right now you better get
a good night's sleep.
So give me a double-triple.
Hello?
Yes, I'll accept the call.
Hello, Mother. I just got in.
I thought it was too late to call you.
But I just sent you $50
last week, Mother.
Okay, I'll send you $50 as soon
as I get my paycheck.
You told me Gran's been sick,
and I know about the oil burner.
I'll take the mink to Uncle Ayers' again.
He'll give me a couple hundred for it.
Mother, I know I don't have any talent...
...and I know all I have is a body
and I am doing my bust exercises.
Goodbye, Mother. I'll wire you
the money first thing in the morning.
Oh, to hell with them. Let them droop.
Look, the models have goose bumps.
Yes, and come July
they'll be sweltering in mink.
You must be frozen.
- Are you sure you wanna walk?
- Positive.
Oh, how beautiful.
Oh, no. Sorry. Jewelry's not for you.
Maybe one single strand of pearls.
But not creamy.
Pink, to match your skin.
And don't expect flowers either,
because only white lilacs suit you.
And they're very difficult
to come by in New York in February.
But make a note,
remind me to send you some in May.
- Are you wooing me, Mr. Burke?
- If you wish to be wooed.
What about that fraternity pin you wear?
That's Sigma Chi, isn't it?
- Deke.
- Oh, Deke. Yes.
It can mean everything or nothing.
Then I'll settle for nothing.
Did you know you are the most beautiful
girl that ever left lipstick in my office?
- You like women, don't you?
- I like career girls. We're compatible.
- It's said they don't make good wives.
- I'm not looking for a wife.
Some men just don't pull well
in double harness.
You're fortunate. You know yourself.
I don't know who I am or what I want.
I only know I have to find out.
Off-stage I hate her,
but on-stage I'm madly in love with her.
- Do you think it's a hit?
- It is with me.
But we'll have to wait until
4 a.m. For the reviews.
4 a. m? Good heavens,
what do we do until then?
We could go to Helen's hotel suite,
listen to four-letter words and wait.
I have a better idea.
My father used to come here
when he was at Yale.
Well, I'm an Oxford man myself.
I know all about you.
You do?
- I know your mother was English...
...she was an ingénue at the Drury Lane
Theatre and you look exactly like her.
Well, not exactly, I hope.
And when your uncle died,
you took over his business.
Oh, good old Steinberg.
Well, what would you like to have?
- Sherry, please.
- Good. Two sherries.
Did she also tell you that I once
thought that I could write?
Oh, I'm sure you could. You turn
a very neat phrase when you dictate.
Oh?
You know, I'm beginning
to like the agency business.
Every man a potential Henry Higgins
waiting to discover his Eliza Doolittle.
Thank you.
It's funny.
I used to come here weekends,
but tonight it's not the same.
No noisy students,
no drinking songs.
It seems the two of us
are alone in the world.
We are. You know that.
I've known it for a long time.
Beautiful.
Now, you call this acting?
Actually, this is a celebration.
I've been talking with the Coast.
They wanna test you
and Tony out there next week.
Oh.
I have the scenes right here.
And a song, a really good one.
- Yes?
- Excuse me.
- Telephone for you. It's your Aunt Amy.
- I'll call back.
She says it's very important
she speak to you.
Something must be wrong.
Excuse me.
Mother's not been well.
Miriam, here's a copy for Tony.
Incidentally, where is Tony?
Well, I know who he's with, but I don't
know where. I can't reach him.
Well, find him.
I know you owe Miriam a lot, Tony...
...but I wish we didn't have to meet
in such out-of-the-way places.
I'll bet I'm the only showgirl who's
ever been inside the Statue of Liberty.
Honey, it's just that Miriam
doesn't want me to get serious.
Are you serious, Tony?
You know I am, baby.
But Miriam's got this thing
about marriage.
She thinks it'll destroy
what she calls my image.
And there's something else.
I've never quite been able
to put my finger on it.
Maybe she's jealous.
No, not Miriam. She raised me.
Did without.
Worked like a dog
to get me my singing lessons.
Maybe that's why
she's so careful with money.
We always had so little.
Yeah. It's the same with us.
When my father died, my mother and
grandmother thought I was such a drain.
All I ever heard was how much I ate
and how much it cost to buy me shoes.
It got so I panicked when I thought
my shoes were getting too small.
- It's freezing here.
- It certainly is.
Let's go to your place. We'll unhook
the phone so Miriam can't bother us.
How's that? Come on.
Oh...
My mother said
I should've held out...
...and made you marry me.
- Oh, baby.
But when did I ever do anything
my mother told me to?
A telegram for a Miss Polar.
One second. You have to sign this.
Thank you.
Dr. Eberhart, this is Miriam Polar.
Yes. I called you
because I'm worried.
Tony just got married.
No, I never told him.
I know I should have, but I couldn't.
I couldn't do that to him.
After all, it might not ever happen.
Well, the point is that...
...we'll be leaving for California
next week and...
...you'd better give me the name
of a doctor there.
I wanted to come for your
mother's funeral. Why didn't you let me?
It's my own grief.
I didn't wanna put you through it.
From what you said,
she's a wonderful woman.
Yes, she was.
Anne, it's a dream town.
I can almost hear
Paul Revere's hoofbeats.
He passed us by.
There was a scandalous rumor
going around we were pro-British.
I'm sorry you missed Aunt Amy. She's
gone to the cousins' in New Hampshire.
Everything is better here. It
really is. I don't know how you ever left.
- Be careful.
- Hot!
I have an idea. Why don't we leave
the rat race and move up here?
I could write my book.
Or at least try.
- You really think you'd be happy?
- Of course I would.
Woods to tramp, river to fish.
This wonderful old house.
And you beside me on that marvelous
old four-poster upstairs.
Well, it's a marriage bed, Lyon.
- You were thinking of marriage?
- Well, you know how I feel about that.
When you fall in love,
you belong to someone else.
We've gone through this before.
How do you think I feel sneaking out of
your apartment at 4:00 in the morning?
But you don't have to sneak.
And don't tell me I knew
what I was doing.
But you did. You knew.
But I loved you.
Does it make any difference how
or why it happened? It happened.
And for that I'm grateful.
Come on.
You think I could sleep with you,
here in this house?
No, I guess you couldn't.
I guess I should've known.
You're afraid of ghosts.
I'm not. And none of them ever loved
each other more than I love you.
- But not enough to marry me.
- But that's beside the point.
I'll get you a cab.
You can stay at the hotel.
All right.
You do that.
- Lyon Burke, please.
- I'm sorry, Miss Welles. He checked out.
He left this for you.
Johnny was just going to bring it over.
Dear Anne, thank you
for the moment of reckoning.
You once said I knew
who I was and what I wanted.
I've always wanted to write.
So I'm going back to England...
... find the counterpart
of Lawrenceville and see if I can.
Somewhere in your wonderful New York
there is the right man...
... just waiting for you to find him.
Thank you for the loveliest winter
of my life.
Lyon.
- How was lunch?
- I wasn't very hungry.
- Mr. Bellamy wanted cigarettes.
- Oh, not now.
He's got a big new account in there.
Say, I still have one of Queeny's kittens
left. Would you like to have it?
It's a male, honey.
It won't give you any trouble.
A male in the
Martha Washington Hotel for women?
You could always move.
- Yes, Mr. Bellamy?
Send in Miss Welles.
- Who's he with?
- Kevin Gillmore.
He made a mint
with that new hairspray.
Miss Welles.
Take this down, please:
Point number one.
The girl who introduces our products
on our show will be called the Gillian Girl.
Two.
She must be beautiful,
but more important, she must be refined.
Cultured.
A girl like Miss Welles here.
- That's not a girl. That's my secretary.
- We don't want artificial beauty.
We want the kind
that our audience can identify with.
College girl.
Young matron will think she'll
look like you if she uses our product.
- I'm flattered, Mr.?
- Gillmore.
- But I'm not an actress.
- I don't want an actress.
I want an unknown. A girl to be identified
with Gillian products exclusively.
- I will start her off at $300 a week.
- Gillmore, that's sabotage.
It's also very tempting.
Why don't we have dinner
and talk it over?
Okay, but bring the contract to me
before you sign it.
KNBC, Los Angeles.
Celebrating the second anniversary
of the Gillian Girl...
... Gillian products offers
a Gillian Girl's birthday special.
Gillian high-fashion makeup.
Gillian high-fashion lipstick.
Helps soothe natural curls
as it sets your hair.
After your shampoo just comb,
roll up, then brush out.
Gillian makeup gives grace and elegance
to that high-fashioned look.
Gillian makeup gives you just enough
accent to that flawless complexion.
Hello?
Yes, I'll accept the charges.
Hello, Mother? How are you?
Yes, I'm watching too.
Remember, the beautiful people
use Gillian's.
She looks lovely.
She's coming to California next week.
I'll be seeing her.
I know she's making big money.
Mother, I can't send you
any more money this month.
Miriam has me on a strict budget.
Of course she's still living
with us. You know that.
If that's long distance, don't hang on
the phone. You know how much it costs.
Mom, I've gotta go now.
I'll write you tomorrow.
Okay. Bye.
Continuing our presentation...
... of the Grammy Awards,
coming to you...
... from the Grand Ballroom of the Hilton
Hotel in the heart of New York City.
Presently on the stage,
about to present a major award...
... is the toastmaster general
of the United States, Mr. George Jessel.
And now... Now a special award
for Miss Neely O'Hara.
Hey, Miriam. Come and look.
It's old home week.
Just a few short years ago you're an
unknown little girl singing for her supper.
And now, because of the warm,
plush, lush notes that emerged from...
... your fair throat, you've become the
idol of movie fans and record buyers...
... all over the United States of America.
With the same elation that I felt when
I shook the hands of the great Caruso...
... I happily present to you this Grammy
Award for your warm contribution...
... to the recording industry.
Thank you, Mr. Jessel.
I'd like to thank all of you here...
... and all of you out there
who made this possible.
Don't forget to see my new film Love and
Let Love at the Music Hall this week.
- I sing some great new songs in it.
- Oh, good.
- Goodbye.
- Bye.
Neely.
- Annie!
Congratulations.
- Thank you. How long has it been?
It's been too long. I'd like you to meet
Kevin Gillmore. This is Neely O'Hara.
- How do you do?
- And her husband.
- We're going to the Coast.
- Maybe we can get together.
- Give me a call.
I'd like to see how Gillian's hairspray
reacts to smog.
- Good to see you, Anne. Mr. Gillmore.
- It's nice to have met you.
Hey, you know something?
I've never carried you across
the threshold.
Oh.
Thanks, I need it.
Hold that, honey.
- You have a hard day?
- A brute.
Sit down, will you?
I might as well give it to you
all at once.
The studio dropped my option.
So what? There are other studios.
You should've never done Westerns.
You're a romantic lead.
Sure, sure.
Look! You're a singer.
You can always go back to nightclubs.
- I don't wanna go back to nightclubs.
- Will you do me a favor?
- Will you not worry about it?
- He doesn't wanna go back.
- He wants to make pictures.
- I'm gonna heat up the lasagna.
Boy, can I go for a drink.
Me too. It's charming.
Would you care for cocktails?
- Two martinis.
Ma'am?
- Glass of red wine.
I'll have a scotch and soda.
Thank you.
Pardon me, Beth.
Hello, Anne. Welcome to California.
- Jennifer.
- Lyon.
- Tony, good to see you.
- Nice to see you again, Lyon.
- Lyon Burke, Kevin Gillmore.
- Hello.
How do you do?
- Well, how long will you be in town?
Not half long enough.
Just two days,
then I'm taking Anne to Hawaii.
Wonderful. You'll love it.
- Incidentally, how did you like my book?
- I haven't read it.
Oh, you should.
It's dedicated to you.
I'll send you a copy.
Well, I hope you enjoy your stay.
If there's anything I can do
while you're here, please let me know.
You're too late, Lyon.
We saw them first.
Thanks just the same.
- Not at all.
Goodbye.
Well, I think I'll have
the butterfly steak.
Hi, Mel!
- The door was open.
Jenny, how are you?
- It's good to see you.
- Oh, lovely to see you.
Sit down.
Neely's at the studio.
- Oh, I thought she had a few weeks off.
- Two weeks until she starts shooting.
And wardrobe fittings, makeup tests,
publicity stills, you know.
You don't suppose there's a part
for Tony in the picture, do you?
You can ask her, Jen,
but I wouldn't count on it.
She'll be home any minute. She's with
Ted Casablanca trying on new clothes.
Only in Hollywood do women faint...
...because some queer
deigns to design their clothes.
Maybe you could put
in a good word for Tony.
Me? She doesn't listen to me.
I'm the last person to ask her.
She's changed, Jen.
She starts at 5:30 in the morning still
punchy from last night's sleeping pills.
So she takes a red pill to pep herself up
and at midnight she's still flying.
- I try to talk to her, it's like a brick wall.
- Well...
...I guess that's one of the drawbacks
of being a big star.
Hey, you know what these are?
One month's check she has to sign.
All the dough she makes, we still
had to borrow to pay the income tax.
Attorney, agent, manager,
secretary, doctor, maid, masseuse...
...voice coach. She sings like a bird.
- Psychiatrist.
- Psychiatrist?
Oh, yeah, the studio wants her
to find out why she's so exhausted.
They say they think
it must be emotional conflicts.
Conflicts, my foot.
There aren't enough hours in the day.
The headshrinker says she's insecure.
That she needs mass love.
Maybe I'm lucky
I don't have any talent.
Hi, Jen.
- Mel, get me some skim milk, will you?
- Want something?
I'll have a Coke.
Jen, I don't know what I'm gonna
do about Mel. He's changed so.
He just can't seem to get with it.
What do you mean, Neely?
He's gotten you lots of good publicity.
That was the studio.
They told him to butt out.
They don't even want him on the set.
They say he makes me self-conscious.
Ted Casablanca says
he's the joke of the town.
I wouldn't pay any attention to that.
You know how bitchy fags can be.
He's not even 30
and he's made over a million bucks.
- Here we go.
- Mel, hand me my bag, will you?
Thank you.
Well, I've lost 5 pounds already.
These pills are really great, Jen.
They kill your appetite.
Only trouble is,
they pep me up so much I can't sleep.
Well, what nice, fattening thing
did you tell Arlene to make tonight?
Arlene quit this morning.
She said you yelled at her. That's
three cooks in three months, Neely.
She was a louse anyway.
You said yourself she was
taking home all the booze.
Other people have loyal help,
why can't we?
You don't know how to talk to them.
That's your job. You better start
running this house properly.
I'm not the butler, Neely.
You're not the breadwinner either.
I'm afraid I better be running along.
- See you soon.
- Bye, Jen.
That was a rotten thing
to say in front of Jenny.
Why?
She knows the facts of life.
You two sit around on your rumps
all day while Tony and I slave.
I can get off my rump
and go back to New York.
- I can always get my old job back.
- Suit yourself.
I'm too tired to argue.
I've got to take a shower
and get back to Ted's.
You know you're spending a lot more
time than necessary with that fag.
Ted Casablanca is not a fag.
And I'm the dame who can prove it.
Thanks for making up my mind.
I should've left long ago...
...but I kept remembering the old Neely.
She was quite a girl.
Now you're just like all the rest of them.
Success is too big for you.
If you ask me, my success
is too big for you.
Yeah, sure.
Sure it is.
I'll just take this. It's the only thing
around here that belongs to me.
I wrote about the things I knew.
My own experiences.
But I guess I only had one book in me.
- Was I really that naive?
- Naive and wonderful.
I missed you, Anne.
Oh, I went back to the agency business.
And I like it.
- Incidentally, Neely's one of my clients.
- Really?
I don't know. England's changed.
Or I've changed.
The nightingale somehow
just sounded off-key.
I used to pretend you'd
gone bald and fat.
I pictured you at a sink full of
dishes. And a baby tugging at your skirt.
Are you really going to marry Kevin?
I was, but now I realize
it's impossible.
I'm glad.
You know, every girl
I met always washed out.
Just couldn't stand up to your image.
I am not taking you to a bistro.
I'm taking you home to bed.
- As in sleep, which you need.
- Miss O'Hara?
Yes?
- Would you autograph my program?
Of course.
There's Neely with Casablanca.
- Where?
- Over there.
Let's try and catch up to them.
- Thank you.
- Darling, let's leave.
Here comes Tony Polar.
He's gonna put the bite on me for a job.
I could've sworn Neely saw us.
Well, she's near-sighted, darling.
She can't see 10 feet in front of her.
Yeah.
Tony! Are you okay?
I don't know.
My legs just seemed to give way.
- Happened the other day on the set.
- I think you ought to see a doctor.
No, I'm all right. Come on.
Tony!
- Jen.
- Tony! Tony.
Tony.
There.
- He'll sleep for a while.
He didn't know me.
- He didn't know where he was.
- Go out. The doctor will explain it to you.
It's called Huntington's chorea.
It's relatively rare.
Unfortunately, there is no cure.
The symptoms of physical and mental
degeneration first appear about age 30.
There's a loss of muscular control.
Chances for inheritance are very high.
Tony's father had it.
I kept hoping it wouldn't hit Tony.
Now you can see
why I was against his marrying.
- Will he be able to walk again?
- As soon as the sedation wears off.
But the motor disturbances
will occur again.
And there will be periods
of blankness and hallucination.
It may take a year before he reaches
the point of complete incapacity.
- Are there any further questions?
- No.
Good night, Mrs. Polar.
If he becomes unmanageable,
we'll keep him sedated.
He probably won't remember
any of this tomorrow. Good night.
Good night.
Jen?
Maybe you'll understand now why
I've been the way I've been.
Money, for instance. I've put away
every cent I could get my hands on.
We'll keep him at home
as long as we can.
- What about you?
- Tony and I had different fathers.
I know how you love him.
I'm not blind. I thank you.
Miriam, I'm pregnant.
This way, Miss O'Hara.
This way.
Another.
What about Casablanca?
- Miss O'Hara has nothing to say.
Are you gonna marry?
Any comment?
- What about Ted Casablanca?
- You heard me. No comment.
Have any marriage plans?
What's your next film?
Tony didn't realize where he was.
The next day Miriam arranged a meeting
with a quirky European movie producer.
Mr. Chardot, this is my sister-in-law.
Mr. Chardot is from Paris.
He's out here looking for talent.
Mademoiselle Polar has shown me
your photographie.
I am interested
in a young lady with your...
- How you say?
- Measurements.
In general, the French girl
is inclined to be flat in the bosom.
I see. Just what kind
of pictures do you make?
I make art films.
- I've seen a few. They're pretty raw.
French subtitles over a bare bottom
doesn't make it art.
Evil is only in the eye
of the beholder.
- My films are shown in your country.
- Jennifer...
...you've posed undraped on the stage.
- That was before I married Tony.
It's up to you.
Tony wouldn't know the difference.
Well, I would.
I realized I had to give in
and take the job.
The sanitarium was very expensive.
All right, sheriff, you win.
You ran my father out of town...
...now you're trying to run me out.
The Durneys don't give up that easy.
- It's too hot!
- Cut.
Stand by.
- Well, it's too damn hot.
- The cameraman's frying me.
Neely?
- Shut up!
- She's full of sauce.
It's not booze, it's pills.
Send for her husband. Look, Neely...
...we've got to finish this take.
- Get lost. I'm through for the day.
Get off the floor.
You're making a spectacle of yourself.
- Zip up your dress.
I can't.
- It's bloat from those pills and booze.
I haven't had a drink all day.
You're going out there
and doing the scene.
How long do you think
you can get away with these antics?
Come on.
Give this to the hairdresser.
Miss O'Hara will be ready in a moment.
I wanna see Mr. Burke.
- He's not in, Miss O'Hara.
"He's not in." That's all I've heard
at his office for three days.
He's ducking me. He's giving me
the treatment, just like all the others.
- Where's Miss Welles?
He is in San Francisco, Neely.
Tell me something.
How come the boss of a big agency...
...spends three days in San Francisco
with a lousy nightclub singer?
He's working overtime.
Why doesn't he look after my interests?
- I'm the one who pays his rent.
- You're being obnoxious.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I want Lyon to talk to that director.
He's crucifying me.
- When's he due back?
- I'm not sure.
When a man says he won't do a scene,
that's called integrity.
When a woman says it,
she's temperamental.
They say I'm difficult.
They say I'm drunk even when I'm not.
Sure, I take dolls, I gotta sleep.
I gotta get up at 5 in the morning
and sparkle.
- It's bad to take liquor with those pills.
- They work faster.
Here. With that guy of yours in
San Francisco you could use a few dolls.
No, thanks.
Suit yourself.
You should make him marry you.
- Have you heard from Jennifer?
- Yeah.
She called me about six months ago.
You know what she asked me?
She wanted to know
where she could get an abortion.
An abortion. How do you like that?
She was the one who wanted kiddies
and the vine-covered cottage.
Then I heard she went to Paris
to make art films.
Art films.
Nudies, that's all they are. Nudies.
That's her problem. She doesn't care
about me, so why care about her?
- Nobody cares about me.
- That's not so!
Nobody cares if I live or die,
just so long as I write the checks.
Stop feeling sorry for yourself.
You're a big star. You have everything.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, yeah, I'm a big star.
I'm a big star.
I tell myself that, Annie,
but I don't feel it.
I don't feel anything anymore.
I haven't slept with Ted in weeks.
And that psychiatrist? Dr. Mitchell?
Dr. Mitchell says
that I am self-destructive.
So what?
What do I do about it?
The hell with them. The hell
with all of them. Who needs them?
Let them talk. Even the bad publicity
helps when you're as big as I am.
- And, boy, am I getting the bad publicity.
- You've had enough of those.
- Now, try to calm down.
- Leave me alone!
I can't even remember when somebody
wasn't nagging or pressuring me.
You're upset.
Why don't you lie down for a while?
No...
...not alone...
...not anymore.
I need a man to hold me.
I need Mel.
I mean Ted.
I'm going home, Annie.
I'm going home to Ted right now.
Thanks for listening.
I really got a lot off my chest.
Ted? Honey, it's me.
It's not cold, huh?
Do you think she can hear us?
- Relax. She's so full of pills and booze...
...the San Francisco Earthquake
couldn't rouse her.
Having fun, kiddies?
Don't mind me, go right ahead.
I'll watch.
You'd better run, you little tramp.
How dare you contaminate my pool?!
Here, maybe this will disinfect it.
All right, faggot, start explaining.
You need glasses, Neely.
She's hardly built like a boy.
- I could take that better.
- I'm sure you could.
- You almost made me feel I was queer.
- You're crazy.
- Am I?
- Yes, you are.
You want me to fight your studio battles,
take you to openings...
As a man, you're always too tired
and too full of those damn dolls.
You've got guts. I catch you
red-handed with a naked broad...
...and you sermonize me!
- Not a sermon, just a few cold facts.
When I come home, I'm exhausted.
How can I think of sex?
Then why'd you sign the new contract?
You don't have to work. I make enough.
You've got your new deal
and I have my sanity back.
With that little whore?
That little whore
makes me feel 9 feet tall.
- Please don't. I need you.
- You're damn right you do...
...but not as a man.
You can go to hell.
Go to hell, you bastard!
I tried to wake her, Mr. Burke,
but she wouldn't budge.
All right, thank you.
Neely. Neely.
Neely, wake up.
Come on, wake up.
You were due on the set
three hours ago.
- What set?
- Why didn't you show up?
I couldn't, Lyon. I had a rotten night.
- I want to tell you something.
- Stop yelling.
- They're replacing you.
- They can't do that.
- It so happens they can.
- My last picture grossed a fortune.
It cost more than it grossed,
because of you.
And now you've been out six days
because of pills and you walked out.
And you've been boozing and eating
all through the picture.
- I'm the biggest box-office draw there is.
- Come on, get some sense in your head.
Stockholders are only interested
in one thing: Profits.
They're gonna replace you
with a younger girl.
- Younger? Lyon, I'm 26.
- And you look 36.
Look at that face. It's all puffy.
Your eyes are bloodshot.
Thank you very much.
I'm sorry, but I can't stand by and watch
a talent like yours go down the drain.
You're my agent.
You're supposed to take care of me.
I'm trying to,
but you've gotta cooperate with me.
What do you want me to do?
I want you to go
to a sanitarium and dry out.
- A sanitarium?
- I'm sorry. It's the only solution.
Look, you just have to beat this thing.
You just have to beat it.
All right.
- All right. If you want me to go, I'll go.
- Good.
Anne and I will come by
and pick you up at about 3:00.
United Airlines?
What time is your next flight
to San Francisco?
Yes, one. O'Hara.
- What do you say, baby?
- What do you mean, "baby"?
I'm Neely O'Hara, pal.
That's me singing on that jukebox.
What are you, kidding? That dame's
great. You sound like a frog.
Like a frog...
- Take it easy. She's stoned!
- Get out of here!
Who's stoned?
I'm merely traveling incognito.
Well, get out of here, will you?
Go on, get out of here.
Jennifer, shame on you.
Still got that mole on your keister?
Nope. They covered it up with makeup.
Boobies, boobies, boobies.
Nothing but boobies.
Who needs them?
I did great without them.
Who the hell are you?
Who are you?!
Neely?
Neely.
- How do you feel, honey?
- Fine.
It's a hospital.
- What am I doing in the hospital?
- You took an overdose of pills.
Oh, God...
- Did it get in the papers?
- Lyon told them it was accidental.
- Well, it was. It was. Honest.
- I know.
But the next time
you might not be so lucky.
What am I gonna do?
We want you to go
to a sanitarium in Los Angeles.
- A nuthouse?
No.
- It's the same place Tony is in.
- I'm not nutty. I'm just hooked on dolls.
- It's not a nuthouse.
- Getting off them is worse than dope.
I'm scared. I've forgotten
how to sleep without dolls.
I can't get through a day
without a doll.
Please, Lyon, don't send me there.
I need a doll.
Lyon, don't leave me here!
Get me a doll. Just one.
Well, this is by far the best
we've made.
Fox would like to release the film
in the United States.
They have also offered
to buy your contract.
- Does that mean I can go home?
- I'm not sure I wish to sell.
- Look, Claude, you'll make lots of money.
- True, but you will get half.
- I just want to go back and see Tony.
- What use is a man...
...who is no longer a man? A vegetable.
- Claude, please, stop it.
I've hated this.
Go find yourself another girl.
Yes, I can. Younger. A real actress.
- For what will you settle?
- Settle? I want my half.
Then I will not sell.
All right, I'll settle for a third.
Anything. Just let me go home.
Anything? Well, perhaps
we can make some arrangement.
We'll talk about it later...
...at the apartment.
I cursed you out at first,
but then I realized you did the right thing.
It was the only thing.
- I couldn't sleep that night.
You should have taken a doll.
No. I'm really very grateful.
Nobody else gave a damn.
That's not true. There was a flood
of letters and telegrams from all over.
We saved them for you.
Thanks.
At first it was awful,
like living in a zoo.
The stuck me in this little room
with a big nurse with orthopedic shoes...
... who never left my side.
I asked for a cigarette.
- Give me a cigarette.
- Two a day during social hour.
I told her I had no intention
of socializing with kooks.
I couldn't sleep. I needed a pill.
I started screaming. I figured
they'd give me something to calm me.
They sure did.
Get off me, you...
Let go of me!
Let go!
They ordered me to take off my gown.
I told them to drop dead.
They took it off for me.
No!
Then they stuck me in this big tub
and hooked a canvas around me.
This young nurse sat there and
wrote down everything I said.
I used words that sure aren't
in medical books.
You stupid-ass nurse!
What are you looking at?
Actually, the water felt great.
It kept coming in and going out.
I wanted to lie back and relax.
But that was what they wanted.
I spotted this small hole in the canvas.
I started working at it with my toe.
I got half my foot through it,
then I yanked my knee up to my chest.
Ow! Ow! Oh, God, it hurts.
The nurse sounded the alarm.
In the afternoon
we had recreation hour.
You never saw such a bunch
of well-bred kooks.
They all acted as normal as apple pie.
I started playing checkers
with this cute little girl.
All of a sudden she gets me
in a half nelson...
... and accuses me of telling the rest
of the inmates she's a latent homosexual.
You won't believe what happened next.
Once a week, we have a dance.
It's really camp.
I knew Tony was here
under an assumed name...
... but I'd never seen him,
until one night...
- Do you know "Come Live With Me"?
- Yes, I do.
- Would you play it, please?
- Surely.
Tony. Tony?
When I saw that poor guy being led back
to his cell, I knew I was gonna make it.
You have made it, Neely.
And we're proud of you.
Now business. How would you like to do
a Broadway musical for David Merrick?
- You think I could?
- You know you could.
Merrick believes in you.
And so do I.
Lyon's checked with the doctors here
and they say you can do it.
What about the bad publicity?
It'll create sympathy.
People love to forgive.
Lyon, I'm really in great shape.
I've changed. I've learned a lot of things.
I used to work my heart out,
kill myself.
Not anymore.
There are things I want, Lyon.
And I'm gonna get them.
Know something, Annie? One of the
first things I'd like to have is your fella.
You better watch out.
- How soon can I see him?
- You should remember him as he was.
I want to see him, Miriam.
All right.
I've booked you into a hotel
near the studio.
Why did you write me
for a doctor's appointment?
He's already told you
everything he knows.
It's not about Tony, it's for me.
It must have been a shock
to discover it.
Lots of lumps mean nothing.
Some are only cysts, aren't they?
Yes, but this one wasn't.
The doctor took a biopsy
and it's malignant.
- Jen, I'm sorry.
- It's pretty hard to take.
Tomorrow they have
to perform a mastectomy.
Doctor says it's not
the end of the world.
He says lots of women live long
and happy lives after breast surgery.
- The point is to catch it in time.
- I'm sure they will.
Afterwards you can come to the beach
with us and recuperate.
I'd love to.
You know, it's funny...
...all I've ever had was a body
and now I won't even have that.
Jen, stop talking like that.
How am I gonna keep Tony
in the sanitarium?
When I saw him,
he didn't even know me.
Lyon will find you a job.
I know he will.
Anne, let's face it, all I know how
to do is take off my clothes.
Jen.
Hello? Yes, I placed a call
to Milwaukee.
Anne, I'm all right, really I am.
Run along.
I'll stay with you tomorrow.
And don't you worry.
- Bye.
Hello, Mother, I had to talk to you.
There's something I have to tell you.
I'm sorry Mrs. Gottlieb
was shocked at my pictures.
No, I won't be undressing
in public anymore.
What did I have to tell you?
Nothing.
Hello, Mother. I just got in.
I thought it was too late to call you.
But I just sent you $50
last week, Mother.
Okay, I'll send you $50 as soon
as I get my paycheck.
Tony!
- Jen.
- Tony!
Tony! Tony!
Let's go.
- You were the last one to see her alive?
Why would she take her life?
- Was she depressed?
- She was in good spirits.
Any reason why she'd take her own life?
None. She was excited
about a new contract.
- So it was accidental?
- Yes, I'm sure.
Her measurements?
- That's enough. That's enough.
Break it up.
Come on, break it up. Break it up
- A drink, a drink, a drink.
- I made one for you. Here.
Thank you.
- What's that?
- Neely's.
Neely's? Well, get rid of them.
Do you have to go
to New York with Neely?
Of course. You know I do.
I have to do my best for her.
- Couldn't someone else go?
- No, she wants me.
- She's scared. She needs someone.
- I know.
- Darling, I'm worried.
- Why?
- Neely spells trouble. She thrives on it.
- Yes, but she deserves a comeback.
- I hate to think of you getting involved.
- Don't worry about that.
I can handle her.
I'm not so sure.
Hello?
Annie. Hi, how are you?
Lyon?
I'm sorry, he's in the shower.
I'll have him call you back.
- Where are you going?
- A press party for Helen Lawson.
- Her show's opening on Thursday.
- A party? Without me?
Definitely without you. I'm keeping
you under wraps until your opening.
- How's my tie?
- Bend down.
I hear the Lawson show
laid a big egg in Philadelphia.
- I wanna go to the party too.
- You're the cutest and the cruelest.
Does anybody else have
a better right to gloat?
Baby, you may have a great talent,
but not for ties.
Okay.
Curl up with your favorite news analyst.
I'll be back early.
A little closer together, please.
- Have you made many changes?
Oh, yes, quite a few.
Miss O'Hara. You look lovely.
- Thank you.
- Who invited her?
- Nobody.
It's great to have you back
in New York. You look marvelous.
I thought you were keeping her
out of sight.
Should have kept her in a straitjacket.
- I'm very sorry, Helen.
- I think I'll sit this one out.
What are your plans?
That depends on Lyon Burke...
I said, that depends on Lyon Burke.
He takes care of my affairs.
- And the rumors about you two?
- Marriage plans?
Well, we're both available.
Good evening, Miss Lawson.
Can I help you?
No, thank you.
Who are you hiding from?
The notices couldn't have been that bad.
- The show just needs a little doctoring.
- Don't worry. If it flops...
...you can always understudy
for my grandmother.
Thanks. I've already turned down
the part you're playing.
Bull. Merrick's not that crazy.
You should know.
You just came out of the nuthouse.
- It was not a nuthouse!
- They drummed you out of Hollywood...
...so you come crawling
back to Broadway.
Well, Broadway doesn't go
for booze and dope.
Now, get out of my way,
I've got a man waiting.
- That's a switch from the usual fags.
- At least I never married one.
- You take that back, you old fag hag.
- Get your hands off of me.
- Oh, my God! It's a wig.
- Give me back my hair.
- Her hair's as phony as she is.
- Give me that.
Give me that, damn you!
What the hell are you doing in there?
Giving it a shampoo.
Goodbye, pussycat.
She threw it in the can.
I'll kill her!
- It won't even go down the john.
- Give me that wig!
Okay, you want it back?
Here it comes. Special delivery.
So long, granny.
I'll tell your boyfriend not to wait.
How do I get out of here?
You can go through the kitchen.
It's right next door.
Sorry, Miss Lawson. What an awful thing
to do to a great star like you.
I'll go out the way I came in.
Not a word about quitting.
The going gets rough,
they all talk about retirement.
Not me. I've had it rough before.
I'm a barracuda.
I don't need pills like Neely.
Sure, I know you dried her out,
but it won't last.
Neely hasn't got that hard core
like me.
She never learned
to roll with the punches.
And in this business
they come left, right and below the belt.
Neely has no class.
No real down-to-the-gut class.
But she's talented, Henry.
She's really got it.
I knew that when
I kicked her out of my show.
She'd never believe it,
but I'm sorry for her.
Nothing can destroy her talent...
...but she'll destroy herself.
And you, Lyon, you'd better watch it.
Sure, everything's rosy now.
You skip from one dame to another.
But watch it, my friend.
Find yourself a good girl.
Have kids.
Or one day you'll wind up
alone like me...
...and wonder what the hell happened.
Allison's gotta go. I will not let her steal
the show. She almost did at rehearsal.
- It's too late. It can't be done.
- She hasn't got a contract.
She can be fired right now.
I want her out.
The old star sickness begins to appear.
No more gratitude, just power.
I'm not gonna do it, Neely.
You don't fool me, you're scared.
You wanna stay in good with Merrick.
I should've known this was
gonna happen. Anne warned me.
What the hell does Anne know?
I didn't get dough handed to me because
of my good cheekbones, I worked for it.
She's gone through life on a pass
because of her damn looks.
I wanna tell you something.
Everyone gets payback. Everyone!
I'm not everyone. I don't have to live
by stinking rules for ordinary people.
I licked pills, booze and the funny farm.
I don't need anybody or anything.
That's good, because I'm leaving.
Who needs you? I'm sick of you.
You're just an agent.
And you're just a Helen Lawson.
And not even that,
because she's a professional.
They love Helen Lawson,
then they love Neely O'Hara.
Come on, you guys. Move it.
Come on. Let's go, girls.
- Where's Miss O'Hara?
- She's in her dressing room.
Come on, move it down.
Curtain time, Miss O'Hara.
- Miss O'Hara?
- Where is she?
- She won't open up the door.
- Neely?
Open the door, you're on.
Neely?
- Hi.
- That's your costume for the second act.
- I'll do the second act first.
- Quick, get the understudy.
I'm ready, Mr. Hamilton.
You get lost, sister, I'm fine.
I'm just dandy.
Let go of me, you big jerk!
It's getting late.
I think we ought to go.
The understudy was great.
Thank you.
What happened to Neely?
Are you kidding?
They said she had laryngitis.
- Who had laryngitis?
That new girl was terrific.
She sure was.
It was a lovely evening, nevertheless.
My beautiful little dolls.
Just one, and one more.
We're closing now, Miss O'Hara.
All right, Edward. All right.
Here. Keep the change.
Shall I call you a cab?
I don't need it.
I don't need anybody.
Because I got talent, Edward.
Big talent.
They love me.
Hey! Where is everybody?
Hey, everybody, where are you?
Where are you?
Gone.
Everybody's gone.
The hell with them.
Who needs them?
The whole world loves me!
Where are you?
Lyon?
Anne?
Jennifer?
Ted!
Mel.
Oh, God...
God...
God?
I'm Neely.
Neely O'Hara!
Oh, Neely.
Neely! Neely!
For so many years
I prayed for this moment.
Now that it's come,
I don't feel a thing.
Does that mean you won't marry me?
It wouldn't work, Lyon.
Isn't there anything I can do
to change your mind?
No, Lyon, not now.
Anne.
Perhaps someday, Lyon.
I don't know.
Goodbye.