Head north!
Resist U.S. aggression and aid Korea!
Defend our country!
I'm the 135th soldier
of the 7th Penetrating Company,
Mei Sheng.
The 221 st soldier,
Yu Congrong.
The 280th soldier,
Ping He.
The 17th soldier,
Lei Suisheng.
Tan Ziwei, the 3rd Battalion's commander.
Bazooka!
Name?
The 677th Soldier,
Wu Wanli.
The 162th Soldier,
Wu Qianli.
The U.S. troops from Sinhung-ni
is retreating at full speed
towards the airstrip at Hagaru-ri,
to assemble with
the U.S. 1st Marine Division.
We must seize the airstrip
and cut off their retreat
in case they escape by plane.
We must annihilate Smith.
Harder!
One, two, three, pull!
BYO,
which unit do you belong to?
Where did you come from?
Yudam-ni,
the 20th Corps.
What about you?
The 7th Penetrating Company
of the 1st Storming Regiment.
We're almost at the airstrip.
Their heavy firepower
is set at a 3—kilometer radius around them.
Be careful.
You, too.
Okay-
Press ahead.
Wu Qianli.
The Artillery Battalion.
You're finally here.
Ping He, sit here.
Didn't expect to see you here.
Commander Yang.
I miss you so much.
You're here.
You miss me?
The U.S. 1st Marine Division is retreating.
The HQ ordered us to press forward non-stop.
Do you have enough ammunition?
The Americans are very generous.
They'll give us as much as we want.
Use however much we need.
You have a lot of ammunition?
Bombard them a few more rounds
towards where the 7th Company strikes.
You think the ammunition belongs to you?
Where's Lei?
Artillery battalion, fall-in!
Ready for departure!
Fall in.
Ya 118'
bombard them one more round
towards where the 7th Company strikes.
Hold tight.
Did you bring all the ammunition?
Yes, sir.
Target Hagarwri.
Enemy coming in from nine directions.
Clear them out!
Full attack on those nine assigned targets.
Out.
Targets ahead.
Copy that.
U.S. planes!
Enemy planes!
Spread out!
Enemy Planes! Spread out!
Spread out! Spread out!
Platoons, spread out in squads!
Find cover now!
Spread out! Spread out!
Take cover! Take cover!
New enemy target sighted.
10 clicks out from the assigned target.
Request order for action.
Over.
Save the GP's.
Just execute basic strafe.
Roger.
Lead wing, ready for general strike.
Proceed.
Strafe completed.
We are moving on to the assigned target,
OVQI'.
Count the wounded here.
3rd Squad of 1st Platoon safe!
5th Squad safe!
1st Squat of 2nd Platoon safe!
4th Squad safe!
2nd Squad of 3rd Platoon safe!
They are heading towards the Artillery Battalion!
Double time!
Platoons, stay close!
Enemy planes!
Commander, U.S. planes!
Commander!
15 seconds,
get ready to drop.
Spread out and take cover!
Protect the equipment!
Get off now.
Enemy planes! Accelerate!
Move out of the way!
Spread out to either side!
Spread out!
Just leave it. Get off!
Maximum damage inflicted.
We are going to neutralize the next target.
Corpsman!
We need corpsman here!
Save him now!
Help me, quick!
How many cannons do we have left?
Commander, they were all blown up.
Goddammit!
Save the wounded!
Hurry! Save the wounded!
Those 're your own stuff!
Yang!
Is everyone alright?
The cannons we seized got all blown up
before I could play with them.
All of your cannons
were taken from the enemy, weren't they?
Go take more of them.
7th Company.
Present!
Go seize cannons for the Artillery Battalion.
Yes, sir!
Keep going 1.5 kilometers south.
Take the U.S. artillery position.
Are we Artillery Battalion
going to fall behind the 7th Company?
No!
Come with me to seize more cannons!
Yes, sir!
Charge forward!
Advance!
Step over them!
2nd Squad, hang on!
Charge!
Back up!
Grenade!
- Grenade!
- Fire!
Take cover!
One, two, three, again!
Ping He!
Bazooka!
Here!
Who in Sam Hill are you!
Yang!
Turn the cannon around.
Aim at the Hagaru-ri airstrip!
Stop.
Put it down.
7th Company!
Yes, sir!
Hagaru-ri,
continue to attack.
Yes, sir!
Thanks.
Why keep this shabby pistol when you have a cannon?
How stingy of you!
Commander Yang,
please.
Surround the airstrip
and blow up their planes!
Wu Qianli,
don't worry.
Charge!
Maintain the formation!
Give me an update on the situation down there.
The enemy are surrounding us.
They are coming from everywhere
and they are coming fast!
1st Platoon, charge down there
with the commander!
Keep a safe distance.
And follow the points of impact!
Charge!
Towards where the 7th Company strikes,
keep a 150—meter distance.
Creeping barrage,
5 Site up!
Leftward 17 mil.
5 site up! Leftward 17 mil!
Fire!
All medical staff,
assist wounded to airlift point.
Move fast.
Red alert.
Proceed to Whiskey tower west side.
Direction enemy.
Wait departure orders.
Get him up! Let's go!
Move it!
I want that runway protected at all cost!
Get me the line to Tokyo.
Yes, sir!
Ladies and gentlemen,
we're honored to be here today
to celebrate a very special event
here in the Congressional Hall.
We're here to celebrate 5 years since 1945.
And for that we have only one man to thank.
Urgent news from the front, sir.
And whose vision has
brought these glories to fruition.
General Douglas MacArthur!
MacArthur here.
Sir, Tokyo on the line.
Yes. General.
Task officer O.P. Smith reporting.
As of right now,
Hagaru-ri airstrip is the rear line.
We don't have enough troops to hold off the enemy.
I'm requesting reinforcements
to support our withdrawal route.
General, our troops need to get out of...
Smith!
This is war!
Retreating is treason!
I repeat!
You think he knows we can hear him?
Stop all retreating maneuvers!
- General!
- That's an order!
Your request is denied!
Can that plane take off?
No, sir.
They are stuck
right in the middle of the fire line, sir!
God!
Go! go!
This way! Get up there!
Fire!
- Reload!
- Fire!
Fire!
Go! Let's go!
We got everybody on board, Captain.
Got it! Get ready!
Fire!
Turn the other one around!
Have it take off from the main road!
C°PY that!
Move!
Send reinforcements out to the Sumun Bridge
as soon as possible.
Call the bombers to clear the route right now!
I'll go ahead and take command
of the 1st Marine Division.
Lead them out on the road to
Hungnam Harbor, clear?
Yes, sir!
Gmgo!
We made it.
We gonna be okay.
All units, full retreat!
Get your men and get out of here!
Everybody in the trucks!
Evacuate! Move it! Move it!
Watch out!
Wu Qianli!
Go seize four more cannons for us!
2 site down!
Okay-
Fire!
The U.S. forces at Hagaru-ri
have already given up
and started to evacuate towards the south.
According to our reports,
the U.S. doesn't have enough cargo capacity.
Smith is taking the rest of the troops
and retreating towards the Hungnam Port
through the Sumun Bridge.
The Sumun Bridge is their only route to retreat.
Only if we bomb it
can our units get a chance to besiege them.
Yes!
Send a unit to launch penetration attacks.
We can't let them escape!
Order assigned forces to block them
and cut off their retreat.
The 9th Company is already close
to the Sumun Bridge.
The 7th Company of the 1st Storming Regiment
is qualified for the mission.
However, the 7th Company is at the airport now.
Order the 7th Company to withdraw from battle
and head towards the Sumun Bridge immediately.
Blast the bridge!
When our reinforcements arrive,
annihilate the U.S. 1st Marine Division.
Yes, sir!
Notify the 7th Company now.
7th Company, keep "P!
Check the room in the south.
Beware of ambush.
Put the ammo box here.
There's more here.
2nd Squad, count them. Hurry!
The retreat route has been cleared of the enemy.
Are there any wounded remaining at the airstrip?
Hagaru-ri,
do you copy?
All units,
the retreat route has been cleared of the enemy.
Confirmed 500 reds wiped out over.
I repeat...
Are...
Those who can still walk, go over there.
Get the wounded into the room.
Put the medical supplies in the tent.
Put him on the bed.
Check his condition later.
How many?
Almost 207
Never mind.
I'll make sure you all go home alive.
We will.
Your frostbite is too bad.
This will hurt a bit.
I'll apply some ointment to it.
I'm alright, Commander Zhang.
Stop pretending.
We know it hurts.
Take the badly wounded to the front line hospital.
Yes, sir! I'll notify the corpsman.
Come, it's less windy here.
It's not that cold.
Bro, is it ready?
Almost.
Wait a second. I'll be done soon.
There's more here.
All commanders, time for meeting.
Each platoon report your casualties.
1st Platoon downsized by 23 men.
2nd Platoon downsized by 21 men.
3rd Platoon downsized by 18 men.
4th Platoon, 16 casualties.
Only 9 Party members remain in our company.
This is a critical moment. Get yourself together.
Yes, sir!
Commander,
it's the HQ.
This is Zhang Zhuang speaking.
HQ here.
7th Company march south
to approach the U.S. Army.
Stay at 1081 Highland when you
reach the Sumun Bridge.
Wait for the order
of blasting the bridge.
Do you copy?
COPY-
This thing
that can go straight up and down
is their new equipment.
In the future,
we will have our own planes
way better than theirs.
Just a matter of time.
Get ready for departure.
Yes, sir.
Come in please.
Mr. President,
telegram from Far East Command.
General MacArthur is still pushing for
use of the A-bomb.
He believes this will bring the turning point
we need to win the war.
He is awaiting your response.
MacArthur must be reminded
that this war is bigger than one man.
Yes, Mr. President.
We will take whatever steps are necessary
to meet the military situation
just as we always have.
Mr. President,
Does that include use of the atomic bomb?
perhaps it would be better if we are allowed
to quote your remarks on that directly?
Does this mean that we
wouldn't use the atomic bomb
except on a United Nations authorization?
The action against communist China
depends on the action of the United Nations.
Mr. President...
Grab him.
Pull him up.
Stand up back there.
Someone fell into the snow.
We can't see the road ahead
in such heavy snow.
One, two, three, pull!
Tell back row to stop!
Back row, stop!
Does the compass still work?
Damn, it's frozen.
We've gone so far
and still can't see a sign of the Sumun Bridge.
Everyone stay alert!
1st Platoon, stop and stay alert!
3rd and 4th Platoons, stop and stay alert!
Yu Congrong, the radio transmitter.
Wanli, give me the radio transmitter.
This should be the Sumun Bridge.
Is that the 9th Company blasting the bridge?
I can't tell.
The 9th Company should have
received blasting orders before us.
Can you reach the HQ?
The batteries are frozen.
It's down.
Save them first.
Co!
You protect the radio transmitter.
I'll leave it to you.
Okay-
3rd Squad, move!
Keep "P!
Yes, sir!
3rd Squad, follow the commander to the south side.
5th Squad, to the north side.
Yes, sir!
Save them!
Cover them!
2nd Squad, charge forward!
Hurry!
There are landmines.
Be careful, everyone!
Throw that frag back!
Save them!
Fill in their positions!
Cover us!
We're the 9th company.
Carry him down.
Hang on.
Hang in there.
Knock out their fire point.
Commander!
Take the commander away.
Don't mind me.
Split and save them.
Yes, sir!
Don't leave anyone behind.
Commander; all the wounded were taken away.
Check again.
Carry him down.
Commander,
we checked again.
All the wounded were taken away.
Retreat!
All units retreat!
Retreat now!
Hey'
hang in there.
216,
Liang Youtian.
308,
Fang Qiang.
412,
Fu Fengshou.
423,
Xiang Chungeng.
The 9th Company...
2nd Squad...
Have they pulled...
BYO,
the 2nd Squad has pulled out.
They've pulled out already.
Don't waste it.
Listen.
Save the gauze for someone who can survive.
Cut and distribute to everyone.
The wounded first.
Come over here.
We seized the U.S. canned food from the airstrip.
Instructor,
you have it first.
Do as you're told
and stop that nonsense.
Open your mouth.
It's an order.
Don't chip your teeth on the beans.
Changgui,
what are you chewing?
This is good stuff.
It's a bit sticky,
like plastic.
(Chewing Gum)
269;
Wu Haifeng.
281,
Sun Yong.
Take cover!
Take cover now!
Hide the bodies!
' Hurry!
1 Enemy Planes!
Hurry!
Carry them into the cave!
Wanli!
Where's Wanli!
Commander!
Commander, take cover!
Qianm!
I'm here.
Squat down
and don't move!
I see what you mean, sir.
The air is ours.
Call the fly boys
to back up our troops with some more fire power.
Yes, sir.
How did you guys
manage to blast the bridge last night?
What tactics did you use?
Which part did you blast?
Yang, tell them about it.
Yes, sir.
We used the old tactics
of creating a diversion.
Our 2nd Platoon
made a feint attack on the
north side of the bridge.
We dragged out their formation,
blocked their bullets,
and restrained their heavy weapons.
All these distracted the enemy's attention.
On the south side,
the 1st Platoon disguised as wounded U.S. soldiers
while being covered by the 3rd and 4th Platoons.
By infiltrating into the enemy,
they could blast the bridge.
However, they all got caught.
But they managed to take the dynamite pack
onto the bridge before they were killed.
At the crucial moment,
the commander fired the Bazooka
and it blew up the dynamite pack.
But there weren't enough explosives
to collapse the bridge.
The operation failed.
Over this way, boys, over this way.
Took those assholes a whole night
just to crack this little hole?
The bridge is our only option.
And must be.
Can't we just fly these boys out?
It will be faster than try to fix this.
We are talking about something we don't have.
The runway is gone.
Are we all clear on
the enemy's deployment of firepower?
Are the troops in position?
Yes sir, as requested.
Stay alert.
There's nothing stopping these guys
from attacking during the day.
Understood.
All units are in position, sir.
The ground is hot
after bombed by incendiaries.
Bury the batteries in the ground.
Our batteries might have come back to life.
Yu,
our border is over there.
That is home.
Exactly.
That's our motherland.
Our scout is coming back.
He's from the 9th Company.
Commander, Tian Xiangnan is back.
He's from the 9th company.
Commander,
I have found
their headquarters.
You want to raid their HQ?
It's too cold to stand up.
We can't even pull the bolt from our rifles.
With ten dynamite packs
and two bazookas only,
how could we fight them?
Even if you catch their commander,
can we blast the bridge successfully?
What if the plan fails?
The 7th Company continues to blast the bridge.
They would certainly call for reinforcements.
Then it'll be harder to fight them.
Tell me.
Is there any easy battle?
The harder it is,
the more determined we should be.
Our army has already set a strategic plan.
It's to cut off their only route to retreat.
So they'll have
nowhere to run.
Remember,
there is no if.
Commander.
Where is the wound?
Our commander was shot last night
during a mission.
The plane opened its butt end
and poured down bullets and bombs.
After that, our men in yellow uniforms
dropped one after another.
What should we call those brothers
who were sacrificed?
What should we call those who froze to death
after marching for 6 days and 6 nights
without any food or sleep?
There aren't any heroes
who will never freeze to death,
let alone ones who will never be killed.
A soldier only lives for honor and glory.
The heavier the enemy's firepower is,
the stronger we will be.
We must show them
we're not to be trifled with.
What's the ammo situation at the secondary location?
last time we checked,
we had double the amount we requested.
76 AP, 30.
105 HP, 60.
30 CAL heavy machine gun, 2.
B.A.R, 6.
60mm mortar, 6.
MK2 pineapples, 500.
30 CAL carbine bullets, 5000.
Test 123...
Good afternoon, sir.
Good news, sir.
Reinforcements are on their way.
It won't take them more than 18 hours.
Sir,
we are waiting the next order.
We are maintaining hourly contact.
3rd Battalion, 7th Regiment,
on the move.
Minimal enemy activity detected.
Reinforcements reassured. Arrival on time.
Over.
On time.
Well, Brad.
That's a blessing.
Have you ever played hide and seek?
Played hide and seek, sir?
— Yep.
- I haven't done so for a long time,
certainly not at Christmas.
Well, we're gonna have to do it here.
We're gonna surprise them.
Go invisible,
lure them on the bridge,
then jump out like jack Rabbit
and squash them roaches.
Call it a day.
Based on the old commander's plan,
the 7th and 9th Companies shall cooperate
and split up in 4 units.
I'll take Yu Congrong and Wanli
to raid the U.S. HQ,
capture their commander
and force them to surrender.
Mei Sheng and He Changgui
will attack the south and north side
of the bridge,
knock down their watchtower
for attrition.
Ping He
will lead the 9th Company
to go through the pipes
and seize the Pump House.
Once the bridge is under control,
wait for my osprey whistle
and blast it.
What's the Pump House?
The Pump House...
The Pump House is their heart.
You're the best bazooka shooter
in the 7th Company.
Remember.
Don't move before the first firing point
is blown up.
Yes, sir.
Commander,
I have something to tell Wanli.
Save them
until we've finished the battle.
Wanli,
Commander Baili
died because of me
back then.
I'm so sorry for that.
Baili is my brother
and you're my brother too.
All of the soldiers in the 7th Company
are my brothers.
My brother died protecting his comrades.
If I were him,
I would do the same thing.
Thank you.
Brother.
Wanli.
Commander.
What?
I...
Well...
What I told you before
might not...
might not all be correct.
You...
I know.
You care about me.
I didn't let you run around before
as you might cause trouble.
But now,
run as you wish
and fly
as you like.
Do it fast.
Throw the grenades
as far as possible.
That's our motherland.
Long live the People's Republic of China.
Look,
is that a radio CV?
Yes.
The radio CV
should be very close to the HQ.
The lights are on
in all five blockhouses.
Only one of the houses is not lit-up
with a sniper staying on guard.
I bet that is their HQ.
Yang Wenjian,
was their defense on south side
looks like this last time?
All of the fire points
at the south end of the bridge
have been removed.
Looks like a trap.
The south fort armed with heavy firepower
must be there to protect the bridge.
We must capture it first.
Xiao Laoxi.
Yes?
Go to the north side of the bridge.
Tell them no matter what happens,
do not fire
- without my signal.
- Yes, sir.
(Searchlight)
(Down)
(Leave now)
Bravo 1 to Command,
North Tower down.
Over.
Password.
Steel.
The Instructor said
something's wrong on the bridge.
Do not fire
without his signal.
Take care of his wound.
Yes, sir.
If we can capture their commander
before Ping He's team
and force them to surrender,
we will be half way there.
Do you see that blockhouse?
Blow it up
and we'll commence our operation.
Yes, I saw it.
Can you throw a grenade over there?
No problem.
I myself am a cannon.
Go ahead.
Where are you going?
Not like that.
Didn't you tell me to fly as I like?
You have to coordinate with your teammates too!
Grenade!
It's a signal from the commander!
Artillery Platoon, get ready.
Load it up.
Fire!
Full alert!
Don't panic!
Wait for orders!
Bravo 1 to Command,
enemy assault!
South Tower down!
Repeat!
Enemy assault!
South Tower down!
Permission to respond.
Over.
This is Command here.
Keep the rest on full alert.
Wait to spring the trap,
copy?
Copy, out.
This may be a decoy.
The main assault may even be
coming from the north.
Stay put.
Keep your eyes open
and let them take the bait.
EDIOY, boys'
Out.
Game on.
Let's phy-
It was indeed a trap.
Aim for the heart!
What was that?
Everybody stay calm.
Quiet.
Are you 0k?
What was that?
There has been an explosion.
Ask south tower to contact HQ!
Full alert!
Tian Xiangnan,
bring two of your men
to scout inside.
Yes, sir.
Zhong Dingyi, Shen Hailong.
Let's go!
Alpha Team to command.
Red alert.
Pump house hit!
Wait one!
Request permission to defend!
Repeat!
Over!
Well, that didn't take them
long to take that bait, did it?
Not exactly, sir.
The explosion went off inside the Pump House.
Where about?
Inside the Pump House!
Oh, shit!
Goddamn it!
Entrances on both sides.
- Block them.
- Yes.
Move it, move it!
Everybody stay alert.
All clear.
Take cover!
Did I miss something, sir?
Was this part of your plan, sir?
It was.
If we win.
Command, Command.
Enemy detected in south-east.
Over.
Command to Bravo,
cut out enemy's retreat with two troops.
Relay my command,
OVQI'.
Over.
South Fort, South Fort.
Provide suppressing fire
to cut out GHGITIYZS FGtFGZt.
Hold the rest on full alert.
We're going to wait to spring the trap.
Over.
Enemy at 11 o'clock!
Open fire!
Let's go!
Get some men in there.
Go, go, go!
Move it, move it!
Tanks, Swanson, take the lead.
Smoke, watch the corners.
Right wing, downstairs.
Evacuate now!
Get everybody out!
Let's go!
I can't breathe.
See anything?
No,
there's too much smoke.
They blew over the pipe!
Use the grenade!
Fire in the hole!
Grenade!
Dodge!
Load me up!
Get those men out of here!
Move it, move it!
Let's go!
Zhong Dingyi, blast the north gate.
Yes, sir!
Zhong Dingyi.
Yu,
He Changgui didn't attack from the north side.
There must be a reason.
I'll go down to find their HQ.
You guys go take down the key point.
Especially you!
Don't be reckless.
I'll behave.
Tell us before you go anywhere.
Okay-
Alert! South Fort under attack!
Enemy at 12 o'clock!
Ammo loaded.
Ready to fire!
Jesus Christ!
Target engaged.
Fire!
Enemy contact! Get into positions!
That was our command headquarters, you idiot!
They got us!
They blew our HQ!
Leave now!
Fire in the hole, 30 seconds!
Move!
Clear out now! Move, move, move!
Hurry up! Move!
Everybody, run! Run!
We are attacked!
We are unarmed!
Don't shoot!
Who's your commander? Step forward!
He doesn't understand! You don't see?
We are unarmed!
Bomb!
- Where's your commander?
- Bomb!
I'm asking you. Where's your commander?
Let's go! Come on!
Seize the second floor.
Take down that wall.
So we can get to the surface of the bridge.
Here's the blind spot.
Need to go over there.
- Yang Wenjian.
- Present!
Can you discern their firepower deployment?
One M9 Bazooka.
One recoilless rifle.
Two mortars.
That is to say
there's a ten-meter space between each fire point.
That should be where
they keep their ammunition.
Use semaphores!
Fire on both sides!
Yes, sir!
(Semaphore: Attention!)
(Semaphore: Attack forward!)
(Semaphore: Against both sides!)
(Semaphore: Over.)
15 degrees from the muzzle.
140 meters.
Yang Wenjian.
Here!
Take this!
Watch for me!
Watch very carefully!
Okay-
Fire!
Incoming!
Supplies got hit!
Right on target.
Co!
Cross their line of fire!
Take me along!
Yes, sir!
Intensify firepower!
Cover for the commando for attack!
Full force!
Reset position!
- Urgent supply refill!
- Yes, sir!
Move, move, move!
Open fire!
Soldiers, crush your enemies!
Ammo suPPW!
Destroy their fire point
and let the commando enter the fort!
Bazooka is ready to fire!
Knock down their M9 Bazooka]!
Charge forward!
Enemy in the blind spot!
Use everything you got!
Grenade!
GO up!
Front line down!
Let's get some more help over here!
We got them!
Get up there!
Co!
Take cover!
Move!
Fire!
Gu Cangzhou.
Pull Wanli to safety.
Yes, sir!
- Wanli.
- Get up!
Come with me.
I'll cover you.
I'll blow it up.
Cover him!
Be careful!
Yu Congfflng!
Bravo 1, Northern Special Force.
Commanding counterattack.
Over.
Message received.
Reinforcement on the way.
Over.
It's a tank!
They are pulling out the tank.
What are we waiting for?
I can't stand it anymore.
Out of the heavy weapons we seized
we only have a recoilless rifle.
And these ammunition left.
It's all written in English.
I can't understand it.
Down!
North!
Tank!
Blow the bugle.
All-out assault now.
We'll wait for the commander's signal.
It's a signal to attack.
Destroy the tank.
Enemy!
Return, fire!
Crush it!
Get over here!
0P9" up!
Swallow this damn thing!
Let go!
Are you alright?
Qianli, get down!
What the hell!
There's a grenade in my shirt.
Let me get it out!
Or we are all going to hell!
Are you okay?
Qianli.
Yu Congrong was shot up there.
Let's go now.
Dammit.
Their commanders wear these types of caps.
He is
the comannder we want to capture.
Get into position!
Get ready!
Move!
Fu Sheng!
Destroy it!
How are He Changgui and others doing?
They're pinned
by heavy firepower.
They can't even lift their heads.
Cover me with the cannon!
Fire!
Here! Get ready!
He Changgui occupied the north side.
Clear the fire points on the roof!
Yu Congfflng!
Wake up!
I'm okay, commander.
That helmet saved me.
Retreat!
Get on, fire!
Go! Notify Ping He to blast the bridge!
They didn't take down the tank on the north side.
The tank is on the bridge now.
It'll block our bursts.
Wait for the signal!
Shoot it with recoilless rifle!
The bracket is broken.
Load it!
Ready for aiming!
Ready!
Fire!
Did we hit the target?
Yes!
I can't read the foreign label.
We loaded in smoke shell instead.
Move the gun ahead!
Hurry!
Hit it with a different shell!
Forget about the signal.
Get ready to blast the wall.
This is the last shot.
Hit the roof with suppressive fire!
Cover us!
If we go out now,
we'll be within the range of their tank.
If we don't destroy the tank,
we can't blast the bridge.
It's loaded.
We'll put the dynamite under the tank
and blow up the tank too!
We can't hang on much longer!
Need to find a way out.
You two go to the south of the Pump House.
I'll find a way to go in.
Yes, sir!
Co!
It stopped.
Proceed with the mission!
Got it!
Commander!
Ping He!
How are you doing over there?
Commander!
We can blast the bridge now!
Carry out the mission!
Yes, sir!
I'll put this under your tank.
Ten, nine, eight, seven, six, five...
Ping He, are you okay?
Commander,
I'm okay.
Yu Congrong will come to
your aid on the south side.
Proceed to blast the bridge.
Fire!
We did it.
We successfully accomplished our mission.
Where are Ping He and others?
7th Regiment, Sumun Command.
Reinforce are positive.
Ready for counterattack.
I repeat.
Reinforce are positive.
Ready for counterattack, over.
Ammunition.
Yes, sir.
3rd Squad, come here.
Set up the gun
and knock down their commanding point!
Set up the gun.
It's aimed.
Fire!
Commander, it's from our cannon.
Let's go.
Where are our men in the Pump House?
Check the North of the bridge.
See if anyone is hiding in the pits
or playing dead.
Seize some useful supplies.
Take whatever you can carry.
Let's go.
Take cover!
Commander!
U.S. tanks!
Sir,
the bridge is under attack!
Bridge flag is down.
No radio response!
Attack with full force!
Tanks,
open fire!
Open fire!
It's the commander's signal for retreat.
The enemy's reinforcements arrived.
But we can't see how many there are.
Retreat!
Notify everyone of full Company retreat.
Commander,
it's the order to retreat!
Retreat!
Retreat now!
Hurry!
Co!
Listen to me!
This is the order!
Retreat!
Retreat now!
My brother is still inside!
That whistle is an order!
Co!
Commander!
- Qianli!
- Commander!
Qianm!
Commander!
Get out of here!
Don't come in here! Retreat!
Retreat!
- Qianli!
- Retreat!
Did you hear me?
Retreat!
Let's go!
Get down there.
Commander!
Qianm!
I told you to retreat.
Why did you come over?
Stop yelling.
Save your breath.
We're already here.
Where are the others?
Everyone has retreated.
Where's Ping He?
He has already fulfilled his mission.
The radio transmitter is working.
Getting into position.
Ready to proceed.
Wake up! Enemy planes!
Wake up!
Enemy planes! Hurry!
Wake up! Wake up now!
Where's Yu Congrong?
Get up! Get up!
9th Company, have you seen Yu Congrong?
He was just right here.
Quick, lean against the mountain!
8 incendiaries should take care of it.
COPY-
Thunder Bird unit,
proceed with the mission.
Take cover!
Commander!
They are coming for us.
Come on!
Farewell, 7th Company.
Enemy detected.
Shouldn't be just one man out there.
Let's burn these rats out.
Copy that.
Yu Congfflng!
Commander, they are back!
Everyone, take cover!
Don't shoot!
That should do it.
Let's get back to base.
Roger that.
Qiflgsheng!
Wanli!
Qianli.
I'm alright.
Qianm!
Mei.
I'm here.
Attention, all engineers.
H1C:
You have 3 hours to repair the bridge.
Consolidate C1, B3 sections. South side.
All units.
Condition 1 in operation.
Stay on point.
Jesus Christ.
If those bastards had gotten a yard closer,
this bridge would have been toasted!
You think we gonna make it out of here, Scotty?
I hope so.
God knows how many of them are coming next time.
Gee.
Gonna be another 3 days till our boys are cleared.
That's 10,000 of our guys
that we gotta watch out for.
You know, Smith said this is not a retreat.
We're just advancing in another direction.
That's considerate.
Better than advancing into hell I guess.
Sir, we've patched up the
north side over there with wood.
But it still needs some reinforcement.
And that's a problem because
we are all out of steel.
And we still need to fix that pipe over there too.
Make it happen.
Send another request to HQ.
And get me more firepower around this bridge.
If they blow it one more time,
we'll be up shit's creek without a paddle.
Yes sir.
Hurried up, guys!
Latest news from the front.
The Sumun Bridge,
the army"s main route for rear advance
has come under attack for a second time.
The 1st marine division is facing a major test.
General,
the main structure at the
Sumun bridge has been damaged.
If the bridge gets hit again, it may be unusable.
Damn Smith,
I told him not to retreat.
Doesn't he know he could face a court martial?
What's the UN's reaction
to the A bomb plan?
It engendered controversy, sir.
Contact all factories cooperating
with our military in Tokyo.
Make sure to get that damn bridge fixed.
Yes, sir.
Yang Wenjian, where did you get that vehicle?
This half-track was seized
by the commander at Koto-ri.
The weapon on the top is not working.
But it can still move.
No matter how many times they fix the bridge,
we will blast it
every time they fix it.
As long as the bridge is there,
our mission still stands.
I said,
we would win
and take them home.
My wife said,
when I go home again,
I must teach math to my daughter.
Let's say goodbye here.
Come back alive.
Wanli,
your mission
is to blow the whistle in every 3 hours
at different locations
on the south or north side of the bridge
so as to distract the U.S. Army.
The rest of the 9th Company and I
will do our best
to draw firepower onto us.
So that Qianli
will have 10 more seconds for his mission.
Remember,
you must do your best to survive
and accurately report the situation here
to OUI' reinforcements.
Stay alert!
— What was that?
— Get up!
Let's keep everyone awake.
And get them some coffee.
Yes, sir!
Stvp it!
There is no one there!
What are you shooting at?
Music, lieutenant!
Yes, sir!
Now that's more like it.
What was that?
Come on, you never heard of this song before?
I'm gonna buy a paper doll...
What a classic.
Can't believe I'm hearing this song
in this shithole.
Who are they kidding.
Reload!
Target truck!
Open fire!
Enemy truck coming down the hill!
Take cover!
195115!
What the hell!
Hold.
I don't like the look of this, sir.
Wait.
Let's keep him alive.
It'll be more exciting for us.
Anybody know the word "surrender" in his language?
No, sir.
Fire!
The U.S. army we are going to face
has the best equipment in the world.
This battle
will be extremely arduous.
But we need to strive for victory.
Qianli.
I didn't let you run around before
as you might cause trouble.
But now,
run as you wish
and fly
as you like.
Sir, there are no more enemies below the bridge.
Should I keep burning?
No, soldier.
We've burnt them enough.
It's time we go home.
Sir, yes, sir!
This is AFNK, bringing you the
latest news from the Front.
After 10 long days of battle,
more than 14,000 American troops
found themselves trapped on the Koto-ri Plateau.
Their only safe escape, the Sumun Bridge
had been destroyed in a fire fight.
The Far East Combat Cargo Command
dispatched a request to HQ in Tokyo
for emergency support.
At 9 a.m. on December 7th,
8 Air Force C-119 flying boxcars
appeared over Koto-ri.
Secured to each aircraft is
a section of M-2 bridge.
Each weighing nearly 2,500 pounds!
In fact, the innovative strategy
to repair the bridge
was the first of its kind in history.
Good work, boys!
This is Can as Richards, signing off.
What are you looking at, sir?
Could be a warning sign, soldier.
It's telling us
we don't have much time to pull out.
We really need to think this through.
It's gonna be a tough war, soldier.
We have to remember what happened here.
Time to go home, buddy.
Rest in peace, boys.
Merry Christmas.
Hurry! Assemble at Hungnam Port.
3rd Battalion,
hurry!
Keep "P!
Be careful! Take cover!
Commander, he is one of us.
I think he's from the 7th Company.
Where are the rest of them?
Commander!
Out of 135 soldiers in the 2nd Company.
21 are now reporting for duty.
Commander!
Out of 157 soldiers in the 3rd Company.
33 are now reporting for duty.
Commander!
Out of 152 soldiers in the 4th Company.
32 are now reporting for duty.
Commander!
Out of 128 soldiers in the 5th Company.
38 are now reporting for duty.
Commander!
Out of 221 soldiers in the Artillery Battalion.
107 are now reporting for duty.
Commander!
Out of 157 soldiers
in the 7th Penetrating Company,
1 is now reporting for duty.
Go get that flag for me.
Yes, sir!
Wu Wanli.
Commander!
Wu Wanli from the 7th Penetrating Company
reporting for duty!
Do you have any wishes?
Tell me.
Restore the 7th Company organization.
7th Penetrating Company,
Wu Wanli, stepping out!
Yes, sir!
Eleven.
Twelve.
Thirteen.
Fourteen.
Fifteen.
Wu Wanli,
didn't you brag about
being able to skip 30 times
with one stone?
I said I could skip 30 times
only when I find a very nice stone.
Do you know what a very nice stone is?
What is it?
What a very nice is
Qianli.
I miss you very, very much.