Would you put the bags
here, please?
Give me a hand
with this, will you?
Will there be
anything else?
No, thank you,
William.
Right you are. And
welcome back, Miss Kalman.
Thank you.
I'm glad to be back.
Will you be all right?
You know it's Doris
and Carl's day off.
Yes, certainly.
I'll be all right.
Very good, miss.
- Hello, Doris. Hello, Carl. - Hello
- Nice entrance.
I thought
it was your day off.
We thought
you were a burglar.
Lucky for you
that I'm not.
We heard a noise.
We didn't get a cable
you were coming back today.
That's why
we didn't meet you.
I didn't decide to come
until this morning.
Something the matter?
No.
Have a nice trip?
Mm-Hmm. All right.
Oh, that's
no meal for you.
I'll get you
something hot.
No, that's all I want.
Go on about your business.
We don't have
any business.
We were only going
to have tea
And then go
to the movies.
Well, then go.
I've got
some nice lamb chops
And some
little French peas.
Go to the movies.
No, no, Doris, tomorrow.
How would you like me to
give you a nice massage?
Tomorrow.
I'll get you
some hot milk.
No, no, no.
N- O, no. G-O, go.
I'm staying here.
Ring if you want
something.
Oh! I didn't expect
to see anybody.
I'm not back from the grave, you know?
Good evening,
Mrs. Munson.
What are you doing here?
Good evening, Doris.
Why aren't you
in Majorca?
Because I'm here.
How's Alfred?
Alfred is fine.
I can see you're here,
But you should be
in Majorca.
Mr. Munson and I
are changing here.
Just put out our evening
clothes, will you, Doris?
Yes, madam.
And then go.
Very well.
Aren't you and Doris
getting on?
We get on fine.
Now, what's wrong with you?
You planned to be away
for the whole winter,
And here you are,
back again after 10 days.
I didn't find it
interesting.
Is it possible that the
trouble isn't with Majorca?
Possible.
What happened
to the colonel
That you wrote to me
about in your letter?
The one who looked
like a Greek statue.
He talked like
a Greek statue.
I don't think he knew
more than a dozen words.
Scotch and soda
and one or two more.
You were impressed with
him when you first met him.
I hadn't heard
the dozen words.
I don't know what you expect from a man.
You know there's a limit to
how entertaining they can be.
Well, they should be able to
talk a little, simple sentences.
You told me that
he was good-Looking
And that he danced
beautifully.
That's all a woman's
entitled to.
You can always
read a good book.
Dear little sister,
Go wash your mind
with soap.
I'm not your little
sister. I'm the older.
This is a side of you
I've never seen before.
Sort of maternal
white slaver.
I'm not sympathetic.
You've plenty of beaus.
You're beautiful,
talented, and famous.
You're an actress
Who's the envy of
everyone who knows you.
But then they don't know me.
What about
David Wilson?
Why don't you
marry him?
I don't love him.
Why not?
I don't know why not.
I tried to love him.
I just don't.
Someone will turn up.
When?
Do a play.
You know you're much
happier when you're working.
I don't feel like it.
Come along with us.
Come on. You'll feel
much better in a girdle.
Where are you going?
To a banquet.
Oh.
Sometimes the speaker
is very interesting.
I remember
the last one.
The Dutch ambassador spoke
for an hour and 15 minutes...
in Dutch.
Well, we'll go on
somewhere afterwards.
Oh, why, lord?
Anna!
Well,
what a surprise.
Hello, Alfred.
Mmm. Delicious cold
cream. You get that brand.
You're looking bloomy.
So are you. How is
the foreign office?
Muddling through.
Well, dear, how's everything at home?
Fine.
Come along. I'll help you get dressed.
You're feeling sorry
for yourself.
I am not.
I feel sorry for you.
She's coming
with us.
Oh, she's not.
Well, you're
more than welcome.
The Dutch ambassador,
I think of him often.
I told you, he's not going
to be there this time. Is he?
Oh, no, no. That was
an official state dinner.
This one's going to
be quite interesting.
Ah. You see?
Who is it for?
Well, it's for
the hard-Currency countries.
There will be a number
of speakers who will, uh..
Well, speak.
On hard currency?
Yes.
The Dutch ambassador's
growing on me.
It's not that bad
as it sounds.
I go no place where
they don't speak Dutch.
Alfred, it might be better
if I stayed behind with Anna.
She's acting so gay
I know she's depressed.
She's not.
The door was open.
Hello, Philip.
Darling, I want you to
meet Mr. Philip Adams.
This is my wife.
How do you do?
And my sister-In-Law
Miss Anna Kalman.
How do you do?
Miss Kalman
is no stranger to me.
I've seen you often
on the stage.
I'm a fervent admirer.
Why, thank you, kind sir.
I once stayed over
an extra day in Liverpool
Because you were billed
to appear,
And then the performance
was canceled.
I'm sorry.
It turned out to be a fortunate
delay. I made some money out of it.
I'm glad.
I would've gladly traded the
money for the performance.
Would you care to see
the performance now?
I'll play all the parts.
How much money was it?
I asked Philip to come up
here and change his clothes.
He's in from Paris...
just for the dinner.
I had no idea
you'd be back.
Oh, that's perfectly
all right.
I could go to a hotel.
Oh. You're
more than welcome.
Well, it's rather
an imposition.
Well, I owe you something
for Liverpool.
And where is Mrs. Adams
going to dress?
There is no Mrs. Adams.
Oh. Well...
now, do we have to go
to this silly old dinner?
The speaker will bore us,
and they won't miss us.
They'd miss him.
He's the speaker.
This happens to me all the time.
I once asked a butler
at the French embassy
If he cared
to waltz.
He waltzed
divinely.
You're right about the speech
being dull. I've heard it.
Well, we can go on to some
other place afterwards.
It's the only hope
for the evening.
What do you say, Anna?
Oh, I couldn't go.
Why not?
Well, for one thing,
I'm not dressed.
Well, neither are they. We'll race them.
I couldn't possibly
be on time.
It doesn't matter
if we are late.
We've got the man
with the speech.
They can't start
without him.
Oh, she needs coaxing.
You coax her.
I'm an extra man. You'd make
the dinner come out even.
How many people are
going to be there?
600.
Yes.
599 people in a room
does look untidy.
You see? That's all I wanted
- An intelligent reason.
You change in there.
Last one dressed
is last.
Can I help you?
Whitehall 0-0-1-1.
Who in heaven's name
is that?
Stop breathing
so hard.
Oh, I didn't know
it showed.
Who is he? What is he? And speak slowly.
He's a very bright
gentleman
We are hoping will accept a job in NATO,
And we're not
having much luck.
Hello, Harris?
This is Mr. Munson.
One more
for our table.
Yes, a place card
for Miss Anna Kalman.
Uh, next to
Mr. Philip Adams.
Fine.
Well, what about
this Mr. Adams?
What do you want
to know?
Everything.
And I mean everything.
Well, I don't think he's
romantically attached,
Which is
what you're hinting.
I'm not hinting,
I'm asking.
How do you know
he's not attached?
Well, we've had dinner
together. He's been alone.
So were you. Presumably.
That proves nothing.
That's right.
Well, I don't know what
he does after he leaves me.
I'll follow him
next time.
Of course
he hasn't any money.
You'll notice we're giving
this dinner about money.
He's the speaker. He must
have some connection with it.
There must be something
the matter with his health.
Hardly. He beat the squash
champion at my club last weekend.
You've got to be
pretty healthy to do that.
There must be a catch in it somewhere.
He couldn't have
escaped this long.
Well, we're anxious
to get him into NATO.
There aren't many like him
available as public servants.
I'm not interested
in the public.
So you see...
we find ourselves,
I think
I'm permitted to say,
In a small dilemma.
We have spiraling inflation
on one hand
And contracting credit
on the other.
But even that
is no real cause for alarm
Since we are actually
the purchasing agent
And consumer
at the same time.
I therefore suggest
That we let the ratio
of block currency
Equal the long-Term
commitments
Of the participating
NATO countries.
He's as bad as the Dutch ambassador.
I can't understand one word.
The tariff considerations
would no longer be affected
By internal
evaluations nor-
And I can't emphasize
this too strongly-
Would any single currency
Be obliged to look
to another
For its health
and stability.
I submit this is only fair.
Good evening, miss
Kalman. Glad to see back.
Good evening, Oscar.
Nice to be back.
My, it's later
than I thought.
But you have time
for a drink.
Certainly we have.
It's early.
I'm afraid we haven't
time for that drink.
I have an early
appointment tomorrow,
And Philip here is meeting
half the French cabinet
At 10:00
in the morning.
He's sleeping
on the bullet train.
Thank you. I'll drop you at the station.
It must be
out of your way.
I can take a cab.
It's only a few minutes.
No trouble at all.
We'll get our bags
and run along.
Do you want
to change here?
No, no. I can change
on the train. Thanks.
Oh, isn't that awful.
What's awful?
Stop playing games.
Don't tell me
you don't like this one.
Why, he talks
and everything.
Mm-Hmm.
He's all right.
He's interesting.
Interesting?
All these years married
and never once,
And now I have
a confession to make.
At dinner,
I thought he was pressing
his knee against mine.
It turned out to be a table
leg. I was disappointed.
You're
a big talker.
Anna, we're off.
Good night,
Mr. Adams.
I had a nice evening.
So did I. I've never had a better time.
And I enjoyed your speech
very much.
I'm crazy
about hard currency.
I'm afraid
you're going to
Have to wait an hour at the station.
Just about.
What's that? You're not
going to sit in the station
For a whole hour.
I don't mind. I have
some papers I can go over.
Oh, that's ridiculous.
Well, wouldn't
it be all right
If you left
the door open?
Yes, we could do that,
And you can go over
your papers right here.
I would be
keeping you up.
I'm not a bit sleepy.
Alfred,
it's getting late.
Yes, well, I'm not going
to press you any further.
You know how badly we
want you to take the post.
Whatever you decide, the
secretary wants me to thank you
For the job
you've done already.
Oh, please don't. I'm flattered.
I'm honored to be asked.
Good night, Mr. Adams.
Anna, darling.
Good night,
Mrs. Munson.
Good night.
Alfred.
Good night, Anna.
They seem to
have forgotten.
Would you like to
take your coat off?
Like a drink?
Uh, yes,
a short one.
I seldom drink
after dinner.
What?
Uh...
scotch and soda,
please.
Are you going
to have one?
No, I don't think so,
but you have one.
I like a man with a glass in his hand.
It's becoming.
Oh, in that case,
I'll gladly hold it.
You have to sip it
once in a while, too.
That's part
of the picture.
I'm quite impressed
the foreign secretary's
Asked you to take a post you don't want.
Is it something
you can talk about?
Oh, it's not
that important, really.
I just finished a 30-Day job with NATO,
And they've asked me
to stay on.
I know
it's a public service,
And my conscience
bothers me a little,
But there's an exciting new
project in Mexico that attracts me.
Frankly, I'd prefer that
to being tied down
To a desk job
in Paris right now.
Have you ever
been in Mexico?
No, I haven't.
It isn't too bad once
you get used to the water.
So I hear.
Couldn't you try
the NATO job...
just for a while
to see if you like it?
Once I took it,
I'd be obligated to stay.
That's policy.
You can understand that.
I see.
Any advice?
Well, if you go to Mexico,
drink bottled water.
I'll do that.
I understand
where people slip up
Is in brushing
their teeth.
Bottled water
there, too.
Really?
That seems such
a lot of trouble.
Yes, it does.
Take the job with NATO.
Brush your teeth
with anything.
That might decide me.
Have you ever
lived in Paris
For any
length of time?
No, I haven't.
There's an interesting
social life
Once you adjust
yourself to it.
You, being single,
would be in great demand.
There's quite
a shortage.
Then, of course, you could
spend your weekends in London.
I've never really
enjoyed myself in London.
How dare you, sir?
London is
my adopted home.
I didn't mean
to be disrespectful.
I'm sure
it's all my fault.
May I inquire
where you are from?
San Francisco.
It's delightful, but it's
so far from everything.
That depends upon
what is everything.
Well, I mean,
our theater,
Our opera,
Our museums.
When were you
in a museum last?
I go daily.
Oh, well,
in that case.
We're not as isolated in
San Francisco as you think.
The stagecoach makes
it fairly regularly now.
We get
the New York shows.
Not the same year,
but eventually.
We have opera.
Not much,
but enough.
I take it you're not an opera lover.
No, no, no. Really,
it escapes me.
On the other hand, we
have a whole ballet season.
That does not escape me.
You like the ballet?
Oh, I do, indeed.
Very much.
Would you like to go
Saturday night?
I have regular seats.
I'm a married man,
miss Kalman.
I'm sorry.
I'm awfully sorry.
Oh, it's perfectly
all right.
You see, when I first
came in this evening,
I said there was
no Mrs. Adams.
I meant there was no Mrs.
Adams with me in Europe.
There's no Mrs. Adams
dressing.
It's been on my conscience all evening.
Yes, I must say,
You've been palming
yourself off as a single man.
I must've sounded
quite idiotic
Blurting it out
like that.
Oh, no, not at all.
It was very proper
and pertinent.
Rather vain, too.
Vain?
Why?
Well,
the implication was
That you wouldn't be able
to keep your hands off me.
That sounds
pretty silly, too.
Well,
you'll never know now.
That's right.
Well,
if you felt that,
Why did you
have to warn me?
Because
those are the rules
Between grown-Up
men and women,
Or should be.
Trouble is, the game is
so one-Sided for a man.
Yes...
I think it is, too.
Well,
you're a rarity.
I don't believe I am.
You are.
Oh, you are.
I speak from
vast experience.
Men usually don't mention
at all that they're married.
Or if it's
something you know,
Then they tell you that
they are misunderstood
Or separated
And can't possibly
get a divorce.
The last one is the
most popular this year.
Really?
Well, I'm afraid this changes
my status here morally.
Well, you're not
compromising me,
If that's what's
bothering you.
You'd have to
spend the night.
The law
is quite clear on that.
Ipso facto
if you spend the night.
I was in a play once
that had that in it.
It doesn't seem fair
to the woman.
I hope
there are loopholes.
You have a well-Developed
sense of chivalry.
I mean it
as a compliment.
I'll take it
I've had a...
very enjoyable time.
So had I.
You know,
I must tell you this.
I've been sorely tempted
to break the rules,
And I've been
debating it all evening.
Evidently your honor is
stronger than my beauty.
You see, I am separated
from my wife,
And I can't possibly
get a divorce.
That's the same line all the
others are pulling this year.
Well, how the devil could I say it
Without saying it?
You know, I can't help the fact
they're all using it so much.
There's no copyright
on it.
Well, I know.
So good night.
And thank you again.
The desk, please.
Hello, Oscar.
This is miss Kalman.
Has the gentleman
who left my apartment
Come out of
the elevator yet?
No, ma'am.
The elevator's just
on the way down.
Let me speak to him,
please.
Uh, excuse me, sir.
Miss Kalman would like to speak to you.
Thank you.
Hello?
Good seats to the ballet
are hard to get.
Will you come?
I'd like nothing better.
6:00 then.
Good night.
I'll take
the afternoon plane.
Good night.
Ooh, it's 6:00.
Dear, you've had
enough coffee.
Come on.
Drive carefully.
Yes.
Wipe your glasses
and hurry up.
Yes.
Good evening.
Hello.
You're very prompt.
Oh, am I?
Yes, you are.
I used to work
in a bank.
Some of it hung on.
Oh, thank you for
the beautiful roses,
But you sent
far too many.
Uh, I like yellow roses.
You're quite welcome.
Uh, well,
shall we go?
Oh...
it was rather muggy
in Paris today.
It was muggy here, too.
Really?
Yes.
I made
dinner reservations
At both the Mirabelle
and the white tower.
You have your choice.
Uh...
they don't suit you?
Yes, they do.
Ooh, they're very
nice restaurants.
It never
occurred to me
That you would make
reservations from Paris.
I arranged
something.
You did? Well, fine.
I hope you approve.
I'm sure I will.
A friend is taking us
to the players club.
Oh, I see.
It's quite a treat.
I thought it was
something unusual for you.
And since I'm
not a member,
I coaxed a friend
to invite us.
Thank you.
That's very
thoughtful of you.
It's unusual for the
weather to be so muggy
This time of year.
Yes, uh...
I read an article
the other day
That claimed the world's
weather was changing.
Oh, really?
That's interesting.
Yes, isn't it?
Evening,
Miss Kalman.
Good evening.
Here she comes!
Miss Kalman, please.
Can I have
your autograph?
Just one moment,
miss Kalman.
Oh, miss Kalman.
Miss Kalman, please.
Miss Kalman.
Excuse me.
Oh, miss Kalman,
Please,
for my daughter.
She lives
in Australia.
Would you write,
"To Kitty Kins"?
That's her name.
Well, it's her nickname, really.
Her name
is Catherine,
But we all call
her Kitty Kins.
She'll be just
thrilled to get it.
Oh, I am so sorry.
The pen leaks.
It's my husband's.
Oh, I am sorry.
Good evening,
Miss Kalman.
Good evening, Albert.
I have a message
for you.
Mr. Whitehead phoned
and asked to be excused.
His aunt is ill. Would you dine
without him and please forgive him?
Of course.
Poor man.
This way,
please.
Thank you.
Shall we have
something to drink?
Yes, please.
A scotch and soda.
The same.
Oh, Albert,
the ballet tonight.
Please get us out
in time.
It shall be
our responsibility.
I hope Mr. Whitehead's
aunt is all right.
He has no aunt.
Oh, a fabrication to get
around the house committee.
Do you think you're
putting it over on Albert?
No one ever puts
anything over on Albert.
I didn't think so.
Well, to the Alberts of this world
Who have shown tolerance.
Bless them.
Amen.
It's 7:25.
Why haven't you got
Miss Kalman out?
She's late.
I tried attracting their
attention half a dozen times.
They waved me away.
I was 12 years old,
And my father
took me to see
A performance
of Camille.
Well, that was the
experience of my life.
That poor
frail woman,
Dying of
tuberculosis,
Coughing into
her handkerchief,
Sending
her lover away.
Oh, I cried so loud,
You could hardly
hear the actors.
Well, the next day,
I convinced
the students
That we should give
Camille as our school play
With me playing Camille, of course.
Well, a 12-Year-Old
Camille,
And rather...
my mother believed in
four big meals a day
For growing children.
It wasn't exactly what Dumas had
in mind when he wrote the play.
Frankly, Henry VIII
would've suited me better.
Nothing else, Albert.
Thank you.
Excuse me,
but the ballet.
It's already 7:30.
7:30 now?
Oh, Albert, you should have told us.
Now we're going
to be late.
Good night.
It's all right.
It's on Mr. Whitehead.
Good night.
Thank you.
There can be
no one seated
Until the termination
of the first scene.
Oh.
Isn't she wonderful?
She looks beautiful.
She's a wonderful
actress.
Excuse me. Is there
any standing room left?
All gone.
I'm sorry.
Why don't you
try the gallery?
We did.
Just two,
perhaps.
All standing room's sold the
fire department allows. I'm sorry.
Ohh.
I know how Romeo and Juliet comes out.
It's sad.
Do you think
Mr. Whitehead can afford
This second
cup of coffee?
Thank you, Albert.
Were you always interested in finance?
No, no.
You see,
as a young man,
I didn't display any
banking tendencies at all.
As a matter of fact, my
allowance was always overdrawn,
Which is a very bad sign for a banker.
Believe it or not,
my first love was music.
I always wanted
to be a violinist.
Did you really?
Oh, yes.
And I worked at it.
And when I was
13 years old,
My professor thought I
was ready to give a concert
In our music academy.
Well, all my relatives
came to cheer...
and all the relatives of the
other students not to cheer,
And I was announced
from the stage.
Wild applause
from my relations.
I walked on
in my new blue suit,
Put the violin
to my chin,
And the audience
began to laugh.
Oh, small titters
at first, but it grew.
But they laughed
before you played?
Before.
But why?
Well, I'm left-Handed.
It seems that left-Handed
violinists make people laugh.
Miss Kalman, we've been following you.
We weren't sure
it was you.
May we have your autograph, please?
Did you ever try to play
the violin right-Handed?
Yes, yes, I tried,
But I found myself
moving the violin
Instead of the bow.
Shall I see you
to your elevator?
Yes.
Good night.
Would you like to come in for a drink?
Yes, I would.
Hello?
Regent 8-9-4-7, please.
Good morning.
How did you sleep?
Fine.
And you?
What are you doing?
I'm considering
getting up.
I'm going to take a shower and shave
And take you
to a lavish lunch.
Why don't you
come up here instead?
My talent is cooking.
I'll do that.
Come in.
The door is open.
I'm in the kitchen.
Servants' day off.
Look out.
The chef is very
temperamental.
Sit down.
Drink your juice.
Eat while it's hot.
I'll wait.
Start.
Good manners
spoil good food.
I've decided to take
the NATO job in Paris.
I'm glad.
Oh...
hello?
Hi.
10 seconds late.
Last night
it was seven,
The night
before, five.
I can see the handwriting on the wall.
You're cooling.
Hardly.
How was your day?
Fine.
How was yours?
Anything new?
No, no.
Nothing special.
Oh, yes.
Huh?
There was
a little something.
Yes?
What was it?
You're ready
to be impressed?
Ooh, fire away.
Well,
I just had dinner
With the president
of France.
No.
Yes.
What did you
have to eat?
Lamb chops.
Oh, no.
Why?
What did you expect?
Something
more pretentious,
Befitting
the occasion.
It wasn't
an occasion for him.
He eats every night.
Well, how did you
come to be invited?
The ambassador took me.
It's customary
for a new man.
Now, tell me everything that happened.
Small talk, really.
Well, you must have
discussed something.
Well, let me think.
Oh, yes.
Is it worthwhile putting
saccharine in coffee
Instead of sugar?
That took up
most of the evening.
The president
said it wasn't.
Well, he's wrong.
The finance minister
said he was wrong, too.
Of course it wasn't
an out-And-Out quarrel,
But it was a strong
difference of opinion.
That's off the record.
Off the record?
That's right.
Oh, you fit fine
in diplomacy.
Don't I?
Something else
happen?
No, nothing w-
Oh, yes.
Now, wait a minute.
Come to think of it,
Someone mentioned
your name.
Oh, really?
Who did?
Who was that?
Oh, yes.
It was the president.
It seems he's seen you
often on the stage,
And, uh...
he thinks
you're charming.
That was
his exact word.
Charming isn't
a very strong word.
Not in the theater.
Well, the president
isn't in the theater.
Oh, that's right.
Now, on the other hand,
The ambassador thought
you extremely talented
And exciting.
Well,
that's much better.
And I agreed
with both of them.
You see what a diplomat I am?
Mm-Hmm.
I...
uh, I found
a play I like.
I have decided
to do it.
I'm glad.
We are right
for each other.
We are good for each other, my darling.
We are, we are.
Sleep well,
my love.
Good night.
Good night,
dearest.
Now, come on.
Hang up.
Oh...
right.
Good night.
Good night,
dearest.
What are you
in town for?
Just some errands.
What are you doing
with yourself?
Rehearsing.
Is that all?
What more
would you expect?
I'm just curious to know what you did
With your day apart
from rehearsing.
Well,
if you're interested,
I get up in the morning,
and I brush my teeth,
And then I have breakfast,
and I read the morning paper.
What about
Mr. Philip Adams?
What about him?
Mr. Adams was here
last weekend,
And he's taken a permanent
suite one floor below you.
How do you know?
Alfred.
You mean, Philip told
Alfred he was here?
Not Philip.
Scotland yard.
Scotland yard?
Scotland yard doesn't
allow new members of NATO
To wander around without
knowing where they go.
Oh, for heaven sakes.
Anything else
they know?
Everything else
they know.
You can take
my word for it.
Well, the country's
come to a fine state-
Peeping toms,
Spying.
I didn't come here to show
you that I'd been snooping.
I've got something
unpleasant to tell you,
And I'm dreading it.
What is it?
Mr. Philip Adams
is a married man.
I know.
How do you know?
He told me.
He told you?
Is he getting
a divorce?
He never can.
Well...
are you doing
the right thing?
I don't know.
I have no choice.
I did have in the
beginning, but not now.
You love him?
Terribly.
Don't you hope
to marry him?
Yes.
It's never
out of my mind.
May I ask the purpose of your visit?
Business
or pleasure?
Pleasure.
Holiday?
That's it.
Darling,
I'll miss you terribly.
I'll walk into
a crowded room,
And someone will be
standing the way you stand.
He'll hold his head the
way you hold your head,
The way you hold
your knife and fork.
I don't hold my knife and
fork in any special way.
Yes, you do.
You hold your fork straight
up as a little boy does.
You do, Arthur.
Oh, hello,
Mr. Adams.
How are you
this week?
Fine, thank you.
How are you?
Ohh.
Now, here,
Here.
Ah-Choo!
Bless you.
Oh, this is terrible.
Oh, my gosh.
All right.
What's the purpose
of your visit?
Business or-
Hello, Mr. Adams.
How are you?
Hello, again.
How's everything?
Fine, thank you.
Now you stay down here,
And I'll go up
and be charming.
And keep your fingers crossed.
Why can't I go
with you?
Well, this is a very delicate
and diplomatic matter.
I don't want you to put your foot in it.
I deal with diplomatic
matters every day without feet.
Promise not to
say anything?
I won't say a word.
Now-Now wait a minute.
Does it have to be
the sea witch?
Why that
particular yacht?
Please, please,
it has to be.
I once was
a guest on it.
It must be
the sea witch.
And don't say a word.
Oh, I won't.
I won't.
How do you do?
Good day, miss Kalman.
Mr. Finley's expecting you.
Miss Kalman, sir.
Hello, Mr. Finley.
How nice to let me come
on such short notice.
My pleasure entirely,
I assure you.
This is
Mr. Philip Adams,
An American
friend of mine.
Mr. Adams is with NATO.
Really?
An admirable organization.
How do you do, sir?
How do you do?
Why, Mr. Finley
spoke to me.
I had to
say something.
Now, you're just in time.
Would you like some tea?
Oh, no, thank you.
Would you, sir?
Yes, please.
See?
He did it again.
I had to do it
again.
I saw you in your
present play, miss Kalman,
And I'd like
to take the opportunity
To tell you how very much
I enjoyed your performance.
Thank you.
As a matter of fact,
I saw it twice.
Several months ago
and only last week
When the duke
gave a theater party.
He likes you, too.
I like the part where
you stand in the doorway.
"Go, you foolish
young man,
And shut the door
behind you."
In the second act.
Why, Mr. Finley, you
missed your true calling.
You should be
on the stage.
Well, now...
what can I do for you?
Well, I've heard a rumor that
it is possible- Just possible-
To charter
the sea witch.
So I took it upon myself
to speak to the captain,
And he said it might
be possible,
But only for
the month of October.
But my vacation is the
first two weeks of July.
Is there-
Please, dear Mr. Finley,
Is there a chance
That the duke would let me
charter it for two weeks in July?
I'm terribly sorry
you didn't tell me
Your business on the phone. I
could have saved you the trip.
The duke's
not the owner anymore.
He sold the sea witch.
Oh, no.
I am sorry.
I couldn't be
more disappointed.
Oh, well.
Never mind.
Cheer up. It can't
be helped. Come along.
Here's the deed
not filed yet.
I didn't handle
the transaction.
The new owner's
a Philip Adams.
Well, at least you're assured it
for the first two weeks in July.
You bought it?
It was a bargain.
Well,
did you ever see it?
No, but I saw
the photograph.
Why did you buy it? We only
wanted it for two weeks?
Because it came
with a dock.
That's real estate.
It's very valuable.
I didn't own any
in England.
What's that got to do
with it?
You don't own anything in
Honolulu, Hawaii, either.
Yes, I do. Another fellow and
I own a canning factory there.
You don't understand these thing.
It's called scattering your risk.
You invest
in different places.
Thank you for the tea,
Mr. Finley.
But aren't you
Mr. Adams?
Give my regards
to the duke.
Goodbye, Mr. Finley.
I know why you spend
so much money on me.
Why?
Your conscience.
You feel you have
to make it up to me.
Oh, that's not true.
I buy you presents because
I like to please you.
I wish you didn't
have any money.
I wonder if
I would've said that
If you hadn't just
bought a yacht.
Well, let's believe
you would.
Well, what about this one?
I don't know.
I like the yellow one,
But there's a risk Mrs.
Williams has one like it.
Only thing, I don't know
if she's wearing it tonight.
Why, you'll soon
find that out.
How? You can't ask her.
I wouldn't give her
the satisfaction.
I simply drop in to
see Mrs. Williams' maid,
Chitchat with her while she
lays out Madame's things,
And there we are.
You're a genius, Doris.
Ask them what color
dress they're wearing...
she's so happy, Carl.
She's happy now...
but for how long?
What's the matter
with you?
Well, what's
to come of it?
What has to come
of it?
It can't go on like this.
Why not?
A man, a wife,
another woman.
I think about that.
Oh, what
a happy surprise!
You're two hours early!
I took an earlier plane.
Wasn't that
clever of me?
How nice.
Well, how are you?
How are you feeling?
Couldn't be better.
Everything's wonderful.
The play's
going beautifully.
Good.
Oh, when love is right,
everything is right.
Oh, how true.
What can I do for you?
Come have some tea.
No, thank you.
I had some on the plane.
Have some of mine.
Well, if I must.
Well?
Out with it.
What do you mean,
out with it?
The reason
you are early.
Ha ha ha!
You are the most
transparent man I ever saw.
I hope NATO isn't trusting
you with any secrets.
Oh, you'd be surprised.
Let's hear one.
Oh, you would be
surprised, Mata Hari.
Just tell me if it's
unpleasant or not.
I always look at
the end of the book.
I can never wait.
I know.
You have no restraint.
All right. Begin.
Well... well, the secretary
called me into his office,
Sat me down,
and gave me a cigar-
A good cigar.
Ooh, that's nice.
And then?
He wanted to know if I'd
accept a change of assignment.
New York.
New York?
Yes. That's what I said-
New York.
Give him his cigar back.
I told him we had an
understanding about my duties.
It would be away,
And it would be inconvenient
for me to change.
Very inconvenient.
Well...
they can't force you.
It isn't like the army.
No, they can't
force me to go.
Well, then
everything's all right.
Don't you dare to scare
me like that again.
You were definite about
refusing, weren't you?
No, darling,
I left it open.
But why?
I wanted your advice.
Well, you have it.
Yes, you see,
I omitted a sidelight.
You do want to hear the case
for both sides, don't you?
Well, not particularly.
The man I'd replace
is the author
Of a very complicated
monetary pact.
He's been working on it
for years,
And now it's just about
ready to be closed.
Let him close it.
Well, it takes
a lot of negotiating.
Well, let him.
Well, he intended to.
He was going to New York,
But... he's dying.
He's just found it out.
And now we know,
and we can't let him go.
Oh.
Now what should
I tell the secretary?
Send someone else?
I'm the only man capable
of handling the work.
You can take
my modest word for it.
How long would it be?
Three months.
Perhaps four or five.
Five months?
And you've already said
that you'd go.
It'll go by quicker
than you think.
Oh, that's not true.
Why do people
always say that?
It'll be longer
than I think.
Much longer.
I feel as badly
as you do, darling.
Want to bet?
When do you leave?
There's a whole
commission going.
We're sailing tomorrow
on the Elizabeth.
Tomorrow? It is
as bad as the army.
I know.
And I won't be with you for
your birthday tomorrow night.
And not for
the sea witch either.
You go, dear.
No, not without you.
Oh, I'll miss you so.
Oh, everything is
impossible for us this way.
Philip...
could you possibly get
a divorce and marry me?
Oh, I don't know why
I said... said that.
Oh, please,
please forgive me.
I... I don't know
what came over me.
Anna, please-
I'm so sorry.
I had no right,
and I know that.
Now you'll always
remember that I asked you.
No, no,
it's all right-
Promise me that you'll
put it out of your mind.
You'll forget
that it ever happened.
Promise me
it never happened.
It never happened.
I never said it.
You never said it.
And we'll never refer
to it as long as we live.
All right, darling.
Oh, I've done it again.
As long as we live-
That's the same thing.
Oh, Philip,
you are free.
You can go
when you please.
I have no strings
on you.
I do love you, Anna.
I don't see how.
Why don't you
get up and leave?
I wouldn't blame you.
Come on.
You're very beautiful
when you cry.
Oh, I'm sure.
Pink eyes... pink
eyes are very becoming.
Listen to me.
Tomorrow night at midnight,
Let's drink a toast
to your birthday.
Will you remember?
I'll drink, all right.
At the first stroke
of Big Ben, raise your glass.
Where will you be?
I'd like to picture you.
The fireplace.
That's usual.
I did it
in a play once.
I was wonderful
in it.
Well, that must be
Margaret and Alfred.
They know, of course.
Yes. Alfred feels
very badly about it.
He should.
He was the one who
tricked you into NATO.
Hello, dear.
Hello, Margaret.
Hello, Anna.
Hello, Judas.
There was
no other choice.
I could've given you
a list of names-
Yours on top.
As soon as he told me, Anna,
I said, "why can't you go?"
Her exact words were,
"why in hell can't you go?"
He told me he wasn't
bright enough.
Philip is supposed to be
very clever about money.
I haven't seen
any evidence of it.
I think he's going to
bankrupt England and America.
Never mind. We'll have
a lovely time tonight.
We don't want
you two to be alone.
Why not, may I ask?
You're taking
the wrong attitude.
The time will go much
quicker than you think.
I told you.
Everyone says that.
I'm going to get dressed.
Oh, women.
I wish I were
going with you.
Let's go
to the club.
No. I think I ought
to stay here.
They won't come out of that
room for a couple hours.
I'll give you
a game of snooker.
A game of what?
Snooker.
What's that?
Come on.
I'll show you.
The, uh, the group
that's sailing tomorrow
Is using the four days
on the ship for discussion.
I'm not in on that.
Would anyone object
if I fly?
No, certainly not.
Oh, dear.
Because I'd like to spend
those few extra days here.
Of course.
You see,
tomorrow at midnight,
Anna and I had planned to
drink a toast to each other.
She thinks I'll be
on the high seas.
And you'll
walk in the door?
Yes, that's the idea.
That ought to surprise her.
Yes. It should do.
Well, that's
very romantic.
I didn't mean that
disparagingly.
I envy you
your touch.
But it's my belief
that success with women
Is something that
you're born with.
You're not entitled
to any of the credit.
I hope I'm not
embarrassing you.
Not at all.
An interesting
subject.
Yes, and quite popular.
There's one thing
I'm very curious a.
I'm hesitant
to mention it to you...
for fear
you'll be offended.
Then perhaps
you shouldn't.
I'll just have
to chance it.
All right,
if you must.
Ah... ah... thank you.
As I said,
I'm just curious...
why do you pretend to be a
married man when you're not?
How did you know?
Well, they made quite
a security check.
Do you intend
to tell Anna?
Of course not.
What do you take me for?
Her brother-In-Law,
for one thing.
But I'm not
her guardian.
You must admit that it
doesn't sound honorable.
Then let me make
my position clear to you.
Actually, it's...
it's clear enough.
No, no, no.
Obviously it isn't.
Now, come along now.
Now just try
to follow this.
Let's just take a...
well, a usual case.
A man meets a woman.
He's attracted to her.
He courts her.
They're old enough,
and she, uh, favors him.
Eventually she'd
like to get married.
He then says
I am not the marrying kind.
Do you admire
such a man?
No, I don't,
but go on.
Well, I, too,
don't care to be married.
On the other hand, I don't
care to give up women.
I understand that.
Now, since I have no
intention of getting married,
I feel honor-Bound to declare
myself in the beginning.
But before the favors?
Certainly before the favors.
That's where
the honor comes in.
Now, how do I
declare myself?
By saying
I will never marry?
What woman
really believes that?
If anything,
it's a challenge to them.
What do you do?
Well, I say
I am married.
I'm married, and
I can't get a divorce.
Now our position is clear.
There can't be
any misunderstanding later.
It sounds reasonable.
Well,
it is reasonable.
I think NATO has got you
in the wrong job.
I know there's a big
hole in your argument.
I haven't come to it
yet, but there must be.
Why must there be?
You've got it all wrong.
You're the exception.
Most people
do get married.
I don't resent that.
That's very
tolerant of you.
I merely ask them
to respect my indifference.
You're just against
marriage for yourself.
Oh, indeed I am.
And whether you believe
it or not, I love Anna.
I love Anna
as I've never loved before.
But I wouldn't marry
any woman
If you held
a gun to my head.
I haven't got any gun.
Anyway, I don't think it's
a brother-In-Law's place.
It has to be
a blood relative.
Come on. Let's go home.
Hello there.
I'm back.
Where's Philip?
He's downstairs in his
apartment getting dressed.
When Philip gets
off the Elizabeth,
I'm going to meet him
on the dock.
I'll fly
while he's sailing.
What's that?
You heard me.
You heard her.
I was hoping
I didn't.
Well, you were wrong.
What about your play?
It's a big hit now.
They can get somebody else
less expensive.
They won't mind.
They'll be delighted.
Anna, be practical.
I am practical.
I will not be separated
from him for five months.
You're talking
like a schoolgirl.
A schoolgirl can afford
to wait five months.
See that expression
on her face?
The first time we saw
it, she was 4 years old.
We couldn't
budge her then.
Did Philip ask you
to come to New York?
Philip?
Oh, no, he'd never.
He'd be too concerned
about my reputation.
He's the most considerate,
unselfish, honorable man
That ever lived.
I'm burning
candles for him.
You say something.
You're a diplomat.
Talk her out of it.
What do you advise?
Be brilliant.
Just start me off.
Please, don't say
anything, Alfred.
Please.
Well... I'll have
to say this much.
There's no use your
flying over to New York
To meet the Queen Elizabeth
when she docks
Because he
won't be on her.
He won't?
He has his own surprise.
As you two are drinking
toasts to each other
At midnight tomorrow,
He's coming
through that door.
Oh, oh!
So you'll have another
three days together.
There, you see?
Three whole days.
That's enough, isn't it?
No, that's not enough!
He's so wonderful.
He's...
oh, Margaret.
Oh, Anna.
I'd like not
to have told you this,
And in some way, I shall get
the blame for it, I'm sure.
But there's no use
your flying over there
To meet him at the dock
If he isn't going to be on
the ship in the first place.
That's going to be
my story anyway.
Anna, darling,
pull yourself together.
I don't like
to be told secrets.
Whenever anyone
says to me,
"Would you like to hear
something confidential,"
I always say no.
And I've never
regretted it.
Oh, Margaret.
Oh, Anna.
This is going
to be quite a day.
Oh, he's
so wonderful.
No, he's not.
He's no good.
He's been fooling you.
Anna...
he isn't married.
What did you say?
He's single.
He's a single...
bachelor.
Yes, this is going
to be quite a day.
How dare you?
But it's true!
I know it's true.
How do you know?
I saw it in a Scotland Yard
report on Alfred's desk.
What the devil do you mean
by reading things on my desk?
You've no right
to take advantage
Of your position
as my wife
To endanger the security
of our government.
I forbid you
to come into my office
Unless you're announced
and I am there.
Oh, shut up.
I was down on my knees
asking his forgiveness
Because I asked him
to marry me.
On my knees!
How dare he make love to me
and not be a married man!
Damn!
Astonishing.
What was that?
Perfume bottle
through the mirror.
You know, when you
come to think of it,
It's all very strange.
It was perfectly all right
when he was married,
When you'd think
that it wouldn't be,
And now that we know
that he's single,
When it should be all right,
if you know what I mean,
Well, it isn't.
Do you follow me?
No, I don't follow you.
Well, I guess we better
call the party off.
I'll make our excuses.
I'll say-
No.
We'll not
call off the party,
And you're not going
to tell him anything.
We'll spend the evening
just as we had planned...
as if nothing
had happened.
Anna, dear, don't you
think it'd be much bet-
As if nothing
had happened.
That's what we
are going to do.
Oh, delicious steak.
Never tasted better.
How's yours?
Mmm. It's very good.
Good.
Margaret,
you're not eating.
I can't swallow.
Why not?
I'm just
not hungry.
Oh, that's a pity.
Nice to be in this
place again, isn't it?
This is where we spent
our first evening together.
Yes, dear.
Let's hope it won't
be the last.
Ladies and gentlemen,
take your places
For an eightsome reel.
Oh, we ought
to learn that.
Come on, darling,
let's learn it.
It's a party.
Let's celebrate.
Whoops.
Ah. Oh.
Wonderful.
Oh, I like that.
That's nice.
Hee!
Oh.
What about that?
Pretty good, huh?
Hoo! Uh-Oh,
look out.
Whoo! Oh.
Ooh. Slippery.
Ooh, sorry.
Slippery.
Swing it.
That's it.
Look out.
Over and change.
Hi. Hey,
where you going?
Hey,
wait a minute, fellows.
Hey, fellows,
Hey, fellows, hey.
Oh, well.
Like that?
What a performance.
Too bad the critics
can't see it.
You know, I'm too old
for this sort of evening.
I always was.
Margaret, how about
the next dance with me?
Feeling better, Alfred?
Yes, fine.
Good.
Your stomach any better?
No.
This drink I invented-
Bourbon and Bicetol-
It'll never catch on.
What impressed me
was the way
That you could swallow
anything at dinner.
That was acting.
I couldn't
eat a thing.
Now, he ate
for everybody.
Look at him.
He's certainly
in good spirits,
Dancing every dance,
singing.
You'd think that it
was his wedding night.
Oh, excuse me.
Anna, I should like to
say how much I admire
The way you're carrying
the whole thing off.
You're sweet,
charming, smiling...
just right.
When he's
in America,
You'll write him
a little note
Explaining that you can't
possibly leave your play,
And the whole relationship
will peter out naturally.
No scene, no fuss.
A gentleman asked me
to lay this on your table.
Thank you.
A red rose-
Who sent it?
David sent it.
He's here.
David? Your David?
Your old David?
My old David.
Where is he?
I didn't see him.
He was on
the dance floor.
Say, I liked David.
I even fancied him for a
moment as a brother-In-Law.
I always meant to ask
you what happened to him.
What's the matter?
Anna, what is it?
I'm sorry that was
such a short whirl.
You owe me another.
How's everything at this
table, may I inquire?
Everything is fine.
Just fine.
Uh, let's all go home now, shall we?
Well, if we must.
No difference to me.
Yes. It's getting late.
Call me at home
later.
Well...
I will now draw
the first clear breath
That I have drawn
all evening.
Did you see all that
signaling in the elevator?
Wigwagging
over our heads,
Asking to come up here
after we've gone.
Well, we'll just
stay the night here.
That's all there is
to it.
Well, I guess that's best.
That'll do it to him.
Anna, call downstairs,
Say we're
in the guest room,
And you couldn't
get rid of us.
Saying good night in
the elevator, smirking.
Really, he's not
very subtle.
He manages
to fool people,
People who think
they're rather bright.
You have nothing
to blame yourself for.
You're a woman,
and you were deceived.
It happens every day,
oftener.
Not to me.
Even our
staying here tonight
Doesn't settle
the whole problem.
He means to surprise you
at midnight tomorrow
Whilst you're supposedly
drinking toasts to each other
In honor
of your birthday.
I'd forgotten that. He's going
to be here for three days.
I can't stay
for three days.
I can. I shall have
some things sent down.
We'll make it a visit,
have a lovely time.
I don't remember
inviting you.
What are you saying?
You will please leave
and now.
Leave?
Leave.
Do you mean to let him
come up here?
I mean to let him
come up here.
But why?
Well, I mean,
what for?
I mean,
how could you?
Now, what have you
got in mind?
None of your business.
Anna, I want
to talk to you.
I've known you ever
since you were born,
And there's one thing about
your character I don't admire:
You go to extremes.
What do you mean to do?
Look, you're
a prominent person.
You have to think
of scandal.
Oh, you haven't got a gun,
have you?
Shooting is too good
for him.
That's how I like
to hear you talk-
No violence.
What do you intend
to do?
Just give us an idea.
We're family.
What is it?
A rose?
Yes, a rose,
a red rose.
David sent it
to our table.
I didn't see him.
Why didn't you
tell me?
Philip. He wants
to know if we're out
And if the coast
is clear.
Well, we're not, and it isn't,
and it's not going to be.
It's not Philip.
It is David.
I asked him to call.
Hello?
Hello, David.
Certainly I'm alone.
There is no sincerity
like a woman telling a lie.
It was nice
seeing you again.
Tomorrow night
would be fine.
Anywhere you say.
As a matter of fact, I'm
not very keen on going out.
This was a big evening,
and when I'm working,
I don't feel like
two in a row.
Why don't you join me for
supper here after the play?
For heaven's sakes.
Well, let's
make it 11:30.
Well,
that's 11:30.
You've got that
right now?
11:30 here.
All right,
David.
Bye-Bye.
Won't it be
a little crowded?
You haven't forgotten you've
another suitor coming at 12:00?
I haven't forgotten.
That's all
I've been thinking of,
His walking through
that door at midnight
And surprising me
with another man!
That's how I was able to
keep on smiling at him,
To keep from smashing him
over the head with a lamp.
Anna, what's
gotten into you?
Tomorrow night, I can see
the expression on his face-
The shock...
the unbelief...
the horror.
He catches me
with another man.
Him-So charming,
so handsome,
So generous,
And still
she took another.
How could she?
It'll be a nightmare
That he'll remember
the rest of his life.
He'll go over it and
over it a thousand times,
And each time, it will
burn deeper and deeper
Until he won't have
to recall it at all.
It will just be there.
How am I going to exist
until tomorrow night?
And to think how carefully
you were brought up.
Well, I'm against it.
It's my considered
opinion, Anna,
That you're
playing with fire.
Alfred's right.
You're overdoing it.
Let's all keep calm.
Let's sleep on it.
Tomorrow,
when we're cooler,
We'll discuss it
rationally.
After all, we're grown men and women.
Very well put, dear.
We're all overwrought now.
We're not thinking
clearly.
Well, I'm
thinking clearly.
No, you're not.
You have the feeling
that you're a wronged woman.
I am a wronged woman!
You know
what I mean.
You know what I mean.
I'm the wrongedest
woman you ever saw,
And I'm going to pay
him back with interest,
2 or 3,000 %
of interest.
Well, there he is now,
sooner than usual.
So impatient,
so flattering.
Anna, we're
staying over.
Hello?
Yes, dear,
they've gone.
How nice of you to call
and say goodnight.
Oh, by the way,
Why don't you come up
for a nightcap,
Just this once?
No? All right.
Good night.
Oh, good.
It's all right.
He's not coming up.
Of course he's coming up.
He says that so
the operator won't know.
So considerate
about my reputation.
Well, get going.
He'll be here any minute.
I'm not going,
and you can't make me.
Good night,
dear sister.
Anna, you're just
being impulsive.
I've only got your
interests at heart.
Good night.
I'll tell you one thing.
I shall telephone you
every 15 minutes,
If somebody doesn't
answer the phone,
I shall be right back.
Good night, Anna.
I'll send for our
clothes in the morning.
Remember,
nothing in anger.
Hurry, dear. If he catches
us, we'll be embarrassed.
Why should we
be embarrassed?
He's the one that's
sneaking up here.
Come on!
Remember mama!
Hello?
Good evening, darling.
It isn't the beginning
of the evening.
It is for me.
Champagne
for the occasion.
Some for you.
Some for me.
I'll swizzle it
with my nose.
May I?
Of course.
Ooh.
You dressed for bed?
Mm-Hmm.
I smell perfume.
Oh.
Well, what happened
to that?
Oh, just
a little accident.
It was very thoughtful
of you
Not letting the telephone
operator know you were coming up.
That was the least
I could do.
It's typical of you,
Consideration
in small things.
You don't think
we're fooling anyone?
Indeed, I do.
Oh, the whole building
will know.
Now, how could that be true?
How could they know?
The elevator operator.
I used the stairs.
Oh, did you, really?
Don't start
admiring me again.
It's only one flight.
Mmm.
Oh.
I have here a token
of my esteem and regard.
You've given me quite
enough presents.
Yes, but this is
your birthday present.
This must not be opened
before midnight tomorrow night.
I'd like to
ask you something.
What?
Did you give your wife
as many presents
Before
you were separated?
Well, that's not
much of a subject.
I'm very curious.
Tell me.
Well, yes, I guess so.
Why do you ask?
I'm trying to figure out
whether you are truly generous
Or if it is
your conscience.
Many people get credit
For doing admirable
things that they rarely do
Because they'd feel
uncomfortable if they didn't.
I hope that's from
a play you're in
Because
it's pretty silly.
It's from the play
I'm in now.
I don't remember that.
Oh. Now,
about this present.
It looks very expensive.
It's so small.
Well, it is expensive.
I'll take it.
I deserve it.
Anna, what is
the matter with you?
You've taken the best
years of my life.
Why are you
behaving so strangely?
You've been in a dozen
different moods,
Most of which
I've never seen before.
Mystery, that is
my stock in trade.
I'm a woman,
you know.
I know.
I'll testify to that.
I...
will you-Will you
get into another mood?
Something less, uh,
flippant, please.
I'll wait.
What kind of mood
would you like?
Nothing makes a man
feel more ridiculous
Than being sentimental
when a woman is not.
Oh, you want
sentiment, huh?
You sure it's expensive?
Well, then,
I can do that.
I'm an actress.
You couldn't deceive me.
Mmm. You'd be surprised.
Oh, darling.
Oh, I'll miss you
terribly.
I'll walk
into a crowded room.
Someone will be standing
the way you stand.
He'll hold his head the
way you hold your head,
The way you hold
your knife and fork.
I don't hold my knife and
fork in any special way.
Yes, you do. You hold
your fork straight up,
As a little boy does.
Now, that
is in your play.
You see?
Well, you are
in a strange mood.
Ahh.
What character are you
playing now?
Delilah.
Delilah-From the bible?
I don't see the parallel.
It's my own
interpretation.
If I'm going to be
destroyed anyway-
Is it going to be
that sort of an evening?
It's only Margaret.
Margaret. The woman
loves the telephone.
What would she have done
100 years ago?
Probably have sent
carrier pigeons. Hello?
The skies would have
been black with them.
Hello, David.
Oh, this is quite
a surprise.
Uh, you think
I ought to...
don't you dare leave.
You may wish
to speak privately.
Why, Philip,
you're not jealous?
That's not jealousy.
That's just
common courtesy.
You're beginning
to blush.
Huh? No, no.
I'm not alone.
Doris is here.
Doris is leaving.
She's just leaving.
I'm not interested
in Alfred's advice.
Oh, Margaret.
Then let Alfred
take a sleeping pill.
Good night.
You can come
back now, Doris!
You know, I think I
ought to point out to you
That I'm not jealous.
Oh, I'm glad.
I was so afraid when you
left the room just now
That you were displeased.
No-Well, yes, as a matter
of fact, I was displeased,
But that's not the same
as jealousy.
You see,
I'm a very honest man,
And I'll admit that I was
displeased at his calling you.
Yes, you are honest,
And I'm going
to match your honesty.
What do you mean?
I've been hiding this
from you.
Well, what is it?
A red rose.
Now, where
did you get it?
Where did it come from?
David?
I wasn't going to
let you know about it.
I didn't have
confidence in you.
I'm ashamed of myself.
Did he give it to you
this evening? Where?
Was he at the dance?
Was there a note with it?
Did he bring it over
himself?
A waiter
brought it over.
Oh, then he didn't
speak to you.
He did.
When? How? I danced
with you all evening.
I was with you
every minute.
When I went to the powder
room, he followed me.
He followed you
to the p-
Well! I will not
lower myself
To discussing
such behavior.
I will merely say that
he does not flatter you.
I pictured more
of a - a gentleman.
David is a gentleman.
Take my word for it.
Oh, come now!
You'd like him.
Yes, you would.
You'd get along
beautifully together.
Hardly. You know, I don't
consider myself a snob,
But I'm sure there's no
one among my acquaintances
Who follow women
to powder rooms.
Maybe I'm wrong. Maybe
he didn't follow me.
Maybe it was
just a coincidence.
No. He was
following you.
In any case, did I do the
right thing in telling you?
Certainly, you did.
And you're not upset?
Not the slightest.
I'm pleased.
Pleased?
Frankly, I was curious to
know what sort of a man he is.
I'm not anymore.
I'm glad. That's
the way to look at it.
What did he say to you
on the phone?
On the phone?
I'm sorry.
I wasn't asking,
But you were explaining
about him,
And I thought you
intended to tell me.
I was just trying to help
the conversation along.
I don't mind
telling you.
I'd rather not hear it.
I'd like to tell you.
It's of no interest
to me whatsoever.
He asked me
to go out with him.
And what did you say?
Here or at the dance?
He asked you
at both places?
Well, he asked me there,
and I said no,
And now
he asked me again.
And what did you say?
What do you think
I said?
Absolutely not.
Oh. Oh, well.
If you feel like it,
Why don't you
go out with him?
You're such old friends.
I like you better
when you're jealous.
No, I mean it. You'll
be lonely while I'm away.
I won't mind.
Oh, I couldn't.
I couldn't.
What I like about you
is you're so fair.
Yes, I think I am.
I try to be objective.
Sending a rose
to the table,
That's really adolescent,
isn't it?
Well.
He's not
very considerate,
Calling you
at this time of night.
He knows I don't go
to bed until later.
Oh, I'm sorry.
That was the wrong
thing to say, wasn't it?
Try to forget it.
Put it out of your mind.
For an evening
at started out well,
This has turned into one of
the most exasperating evenings
Of my whole life.
Your life
isn't over yet.
I think an ex-Suitor
who doesn't realize
He's an ex-Suitor
and doesn't stay ex'd
Is the most despicable
kind of human being-
I'd tell him so
to his face.
He's taller
than you are.
That's enough.
I'm leaving.
Good night, dear.
I'm terribly sorry,
darling.
Oh, that's all right.
Forgive me, please.
Mmm! Mmm.
What is it?
Oh, I have
a splitting headache.
Oh, don't be
irritated now.
It's only your vanity.
I'm not irritated.
Yes, you are.
Oh, don't be.
You're going to leave
so early in the morning,
And I won't
see you anymore.
I wish
I'd left yesterday.
Well, I can't help
the headache.
That's why I've been
acting so strangely.
I've been trying
to hide it.
I'm awfully sorry, dear. And I
haven't been behaving too well.
Yes, you have, considering
that you are worried
Whether I got
a splitting headache
Only after
the telephone call,
Aren't you?
No more.
Oh, darling.
Oh, good night, dear.
Good night.
Take care.
I will.
And write.
I'll phone.
Oh, here's your present,
darling.
Don't forget. At the
first stroke of midnight-
I'll raise my glass.
Yes, dear.
Goodbye.
I've seen plays with wonderful
goodbye lines in them.
I'm trying
to remember one.
I've heard them all.
Yes, I guess you have.
Well, goodbye, dear.
Very clever
and to the point.
Uh, don't forget.
Tomorrow at midnight.
I'm thinking about it
right now.
You think we've
overdone the flowers?
We've never had
this many before.
How many are there?
You told me
to get five dozen,
And Mr. Wilson sent two.
That's seven dozen
altogether.
It is a bit thick, and it
smells like a flower shop.
Shall I take
some of them out?
No. I want them
to be noticeable.
They have to stick out.
I want them to be seen
at first glance.
Yes, ma'am.
Grilled lobster,
And I've taken
the champagne
Out of the icebox
so it's cold.
Very good, Doris.
I cannot understand why
Mr. Wilson hasn't come yet.
What time is it?
20 minutes to 12:00.
Oh.
Mayfair 5-1-0-1.
Mr. Wilson, please.
David Wilson.
Oh, uh, could you tell me
how long ago he left?
Did he leave any message?
He didn't.
Well, thank you.
I don't know
what has happened.
Hello?
Yes.
Who?
Oh, no.
Oh.
Yes. Thank you, doctor.
Remember me to him.
Tell him
he has my sympathy.
Thank you.
Is anything the matter?
They carried Mr. Wilson off
the tennis court this afternoon
With acute appendicitis.
Oh, my!
He was on the operating
table 45 minutes.
The operation
was very successful.
Oh, I'm glad.
The first thing he said when
he came out of the ether was,
"Call miss Kalman
and apologize for me."
Wasn't that
considerate?
Considerate?
What the hell was he
doing playing tennis?
Would you like
some lobster?
No.
It will make you
feel better.
No, it won't.
You haven't
had anything to eat
Since before the show.
I'll give you a little.
I don't want a lobster.
I want a man!
I need a man tonight-
Here, right now.
A man? Do you want
to lift something?
Carl's outside.
Carl's not very big,
but he's very strong.
You'd be surprised.
Carl?
Shall I ask him
to come in?
Yes. We'll audition him.
Carl?
Carl, come in here.
You want me?
Come over here.
Stand there.
What do you
want him for?
Of course
he knows you. Still...
turn the lights off.
It will only be
for a few seconds.
Walk around, Carl.
Walk.
Where?
Over there.
Up and down.
Can't you just walk?
Does Carl have a nice dressing
gown or robe or something?
Yes, he has. The one you
gave him last Christmas.
Oh, yes.
Bring that.
You can stop
walking now, Carl.
Take your
glasses off.
Put them down.
Don't you see well
without your glasses?
Not small things,
miss Kalman.
Oh.
Give it to him.
Walk some more.
I'm thinking of playing a
practical joke on a friend of mine,
And I wonder if
you care to help.
Certainly, he will.
Practical joke?
Yes.
Will anybody be hurt?
Not physically.
It's none
of your business.
I only asked 'cause
I'm the one who-
What do you
want him to do?
Exactly at midnight, I
want him to open that door
And let Mr. Adams see
you just for one second,
Then jump back into the room
and close the door behind you.
Mr. Adams?
That's who we're
playing the joke on.
I wouldn't want
to spoil it for you.
I don't think
I could do it well.
But there's no danger,
if that's your concern.
I've seen many plays
in my time,
And jealous lovers
always have a knife or gun
Or the poker
from the fireplace.
Anyway, somebody's always
lying on the floor.
Carl, you're a coward.
That's true. All my life,
I've been a coward.
You ought to be
ashamed of yourself.
I am ashamed.
Mr. Adams
won't harm you.
You can lock the door behind you.
And hide
under the bed.
Why am I wasting
everybody's time?
Oh, thank you,
Carl.
But I'm going
to lock the door.
What did you
want me to do?
All you have to do is
to listen for the chimes
And come out
on the 12th chime.
Just step out. One step. That's enough.
Step back
and close the door.
And lock it.
The important thing
is to count the chimes
And come out
on the last one.
Maybe we ought
to have a rehearsal.
What's the matter with you?
Can't you count to 12?
I can count fine,
But this stepping out and
stepping back, it has to be right.
Yes, we need a rehearsal.
What time is it?
18 minutes to 12:00.
You get in there and
listen for the chimes.
Doris will be
the chimes
And come out
on the 12th one.
Right. The 12th one.
That'll be my cue.
My hero.
All right.
Ready, Doris?
Begin.
Bong.
Philip, what are you doing here?
He'll stand there
disappointed.
He'll take a moment.
To understand.
What he sees-
Supper for two,
the red roses.
Then he'll
look back at me.
I'll look at the door,
frightened.
I'll run to the door.
I'll stand in front of it,
speechless,
Hand to my mouth.
Ohh!
Bong.
What can I say?
Then I'll say I'm sorry
he had to find out.
I'm sorry it had
to end this way.
Then I'll
open the package,
And I'll say...
this is a beautiful
bracelet.
I hope
you can return it.
It is a beautiful
bracelet.
Oh, it is.
The one thing you
can't call him is cheap,
But you can call him
everything else.
Maybe he
won't take it back.
How was I?
You were fine, Carl.
You'll steal
all the notices.
What time is it? Put
the food on the plates.
Go back in the room and do
it just the way you did it.
I'm a little bit
nervous.
Oh, stop it, Carl.
Go on.
All right, Doris.
I'll be listening.
Philip, what
are you doing here?
What can I say?
I'm sorry.
Philip.
Happy birthday,
darling.
What are you
doing here?
Why aren't you
at the fireplace?
What can I say?
Don't say anything.
Just listen to me.
I have the most
astonishing news.
Darling,
we can be married!
I've just had word
from my wife.
She's willing to
give me a divorce.
She's fallen in love with a
ski instructor in Sun Valley.
Darling,
will you marry me?
Oh.
What is it, darling?
Uh...
what...
who is that?
No, no, no.
Wait a minute.
Calm down.
Now, who is that?
Oh, Philip.
Well, I knew you were
going to say that.
Who is that?
It's of
no importance now.
It's important to me.
Now, who is it?
That's Carl, dear.
Carl? In a bathrobe
in your bedroom?
That's David.
Oh, what am I
going to say?
I don't know.
I'd like to hear it.
What are you
going to say?
Well, I know what
I was going to say.
I was going to take
this bracelet and say,
"This is a beautiful bracelet.
I hope you can return it."
Don't you understand?
No, I don't understand.
And to think I actually
proposed marriage.
Marriage.
But, Philip...
but you don't
understand at all.
Oh, miss Kalman, it didn't
go very well, did it?
There was nothing
I could do. Nothing.
anybody could do.
How was I?
Oh, shut up, Carl.
Somebody tell me.
Please, Carl.
Miss Kalman, maybe if
you told him truth...
I did tell him the truth,
and he wouldn't believe me.
Oh, it is all over.
Did I spoil something?
No, not you, Carl.
I did...
with my little hatchet.
I can go to him and
explain the whole thing.
Maybe he'll
believe me.
Did something go wrong?
Nothing much.
A small thing-
My life,
that's all.
I don't want
this bracelet.
It's yours.
This wasn't a gift.
Consider it
as payment.
And while
you are there,
Will you please give
a message to my rival.
Tell him
I'm indebted to him.
I can think of no man to
whom I'm more indebted.
Wait a minute. You
can tell him yourself.
Come out.
It's all right.
Why, it's Carl.
I didn't do anything.
They made me do it.
Well, that was a cheap
and shoddy thing to do.
I didn't start being
cheap and shoddy.
It didn't become you. It
didn't become our relationship.
What was our relationship, may I ask?
Something fine
and spiritual.
On whose part?
On my part!
I contributed to the fine and spiritual.
You lied
and cheated.
You're not married.
You're dishonest.
I was honorable.
I stuck to the rules.
You're not going to
bring up the rules again.
What can man go by
but rules?
When you found out
I wasn't married,
You shouldn't have
done anything about it.
That's what a clever woman
would've done.
I'd had come around
to marrying you.
You notice I did.
You wouldn't have if I
hadn't made you jealous,
Not in
a thousand years.
I might've proposed a little
later, but it was inevitable.
No, it's not true.
What's inevitable is that we
are fated not to be married.
We had the chance for a
moment, and we lost it.
It's too bad, too, because
I love you very much,
And we could've
been very happy.
We can still be happy.
I wonder.
Well, I suppose
any happiness
Is difficult
enough to find.
It's not too becoming
from a woman, but...
we are hardly strangers,
And knowing
your passion for rules,
I'll make
the proposition.
If you're willing,
I'm willing.
The last two days
never happened.
What do you mean?
I mean we'll go on
as before.
And not be married?
That's right.
That's the most improper
thing I've ever heard.
What?
I can hardly
believe my ears.
What are you
so shocked about?
I didn't think
you were capable of it.
Well, what is different?
We're not married.
We weren't before.
But you didn't know
I wasn't married.
You knew.
I knew you didn't know.
What's the matter
with you?
How could you ask me
to do such a thing?
Haven't you been following
what I've been saying?
Oh, I tell you, women
are not the sensitive sex.
That's one of the great
delusions of literature.
Men are
the true romanticists.
I'd-
What are you
crying about?
Oh, shut up, Philip.
Don't cry, Anna.
I love you.
Everything
will be all right.
You'll like
being married.
You will.
You'll see.
Yes.