[Wind Blowing]
[Starter Grinding]
[Grinding Continues]
[Engine Backfires]
[Starter Grinding]
[Grinding, Backfire]
[Engine Sputtering]
[Backfires]
- [Grinding] - [Man On Radio: Country] # Why
don't you love me like you used to do #
- [Engine Stalls] # How come you
treat me like a worn-out shoe #
# My hair's still curly
and my eyes are still blue #
# Why don't you love me
like you used to do #
# Ain't had no lovin'
like a-huggin' and a-kissin' #
- # In a long, long while #
- [Starter Grinding]
- # We don't get nearer or further#
- [Backfires]
# Or closer than a country mile #
# Why don't you spark me
like you used to do #
# And say sweet nothings
like you used to coo #
# I can...#
[Horn Honking]
## [Continues]
# Well, why don't you be
just like you used to be #
[Engine Backfires]
# Why don't you love me
like you used to do #
- [Backfires]
- # Ain't had...##
[Wind Blowing]
[Screen Door Bangs]
Whew.
[Man Coughing]
- [Coughing Continues]
- [Radio Humming]
[Man On Radio] And President
Truman will be here tomorrow...
so all you folks in Dallas
turn out, you hear?
This is Cowboy Rhythms
on KTRN, Wichita Falls...
and here's Hank Williams's
big hit tune, "Cold, Cold Heart."
## [Country]
# I try so hard, my dear, to show #
You ain't ever gonna amount to nothin'.
Already spent a dime this morning
and ain't even had a decent breakfast.
Give me the chalk.
- # It's just some evil scheme #
- [Clears Throat]
Why don't you comb your hair, Sonny?
It sticks up. Look like you smelled a wolf.
# So far apart #
# Why can't I free your doubtful mind #
# And melt your cold, cold heart #
I'm surprised you had the
nerve to show up this
mornin' after that stompin'
y'all took last night.
- Well, it could've been worse.
- What'd you say?
- Could've been worse.
- Yeah.
You could say that
about nearly everything, I guess.
[Engine Rumbling]
A few football teams
have had some luck with tackling.
Keeps the other team
from scoring quite so often.
Sounds too rough for me.
# That make the teardrops fall #
- # Why can't I free your doubtful mind #
- You don't even care if it was your last game.
You ain't ever gonna get stomped
for your own high school ball team again.
- Where's your school spirit?
- Don't know.
# You'll never know how much it hurts #
- You workin' today?
- [Man] No, the truck's being greased.
- Mmm.
- # To see you sit and cry #
# You know you need and want my love #
# Yet you're afraid to try #
# Why do you run and hide from life #
- # To try, it just ain't smart #
- Oh.
# Why can't I free your doubtful mind #
Now, you see, this is what I get
for bettin' on my hometown ball team.
I ought to have better sense.
Wouldn't hurt
if you had a better hometown.
Do you mind pointing that at the floor
till I get by?
I don't want my eye poked out.
# But now I know your heart is shackled #
- Don't let Billy get too far away, will you, son?
- # To a memory #
You're a damn sight more dangerous in a
pool hall than you are on a football field.
- # The more we drift apart #
- Hey.
You ever heard of tackling?
# Why can't I free your doubtful mind #
- # And melt your cold, cold heart ##
- [Door Opens]
- [Brakes Squealing]
- [Sonny] Hey, Duane.
Boy, I froze my ass last night.
Hey! Why the hell can't you kids
learn to tackle?
Hey, how about taking Genevieve some
change, being as you're goin' that way?
[Vehicle Approaching]
[Horn Honks]
[Duane]
Hike me one!
Here comes the bomb, Crawford!
- Look at that, Larry. They can catch.
- Feisty sons of bitches, ain't they?
- Wish they could tackle.
- Or do something useful.
Team wasn't worth a kiss-my-ass this year.
- Hey, hup!
- Hup!
- [Door Bells Jingling]
- Straight out, Crawford, one more time. Whoo-ee!
[Bells Jingling]
All right, you boys. Cut it out.
I got enough problems
without you playing that game over again.
- We could have run off to Mexico with this, you know.
- Mmm.
[Jukebox: Man Singing, Country]
# As the door of love between us closes #
- Hey, play that new one we heard.
- Which one?
Down payment on breakfast.
Let somebody prosperous play the jukebox.
- Nobody prosperous would eat here.
- [Laughing]
- Well, I ain't very hungry.
- Well, I am.
- Say, you want the pickup first tonight?
- Nah.
I oughtn't get it first every Saturday night.
It's half yours, you know.
- Go ahead.
- You sure?
Sure, I'm sure.
Anyways, I got lots of deliveries to
make, and I have to go clear
to Ranger this afternoon.
- Okay.
- I'll be lucky to get back for the second show.
# One for every time #
# You broke my heart #
[Clicks Tongue]
[Man] Give me that coffee, hon?
I need another cup.
[Radio: Man Singing, Country] # So if you
want to have fun, come along with me #
# Say, hey, good-lookin' #
# What ya got cookin' #
# How's about cookin'
something up with...##
[Crickets Chirping]
- [Woman On Film, Chattering]
- My goodness, Sonny.
Frank hadn't ought to
work you so late on weekends.
That's what I keep telling him.
You ain't got in in time
to see the comedy in three weeks.
Hope you don't want no popcorn,
'cause there ain't none.
- [Man On Film, Chattering]
- And you missed the newsreel too.
And the main show's done started,
so I'll just charge you 30 cents.
Thanks, Miss Mosey.
[Spencer Tracy] I was
wondering if my daughter
had deserted us, too,
when I heard her voice.
[Elizabeth Taylor]
Pa! Pa!
- Hi, Pa.
- [Tracy Narrating] Kay was our only daughter.
I know a father's not supposed
to have favorites...
but when it's Kay...
- [Tracy] Mmm, you smell good.
- [Taylor] You like it?
[Tracy]
Mm-hmm.
- [Tracy] What's that?
- An atomizer.
- Where'd you get it? A present?
- Mm-hmm.
- Who from?
- Oh, somebody.
I decided you had a wreck.
[Man Coughing]
[Tracy]
What's happened to you? You look different.
- [Taylor] I do?
- Yeah.
- You look all lit up inside.
- [Taylor Chuckles]
You're not wearing
your usual deadpan look...
that "how did I ever get
into this family" look.
[Chuckling]
Oh, Father.
[Tracy] Oh, I know. You've been taking
those vitamins that Dr. Gray sent you, huh?
[Taylor]
That's right.
[Tracy]
I guess I'll get me some of those vitamins.
- [Phone Rings]
- [Taylor] I'll get it, Delilah.
- [Taylor] What's the matter with her?
She looks kind of queer.
Guess what.
What?
It's our anniversary.
We've been going steady a year tonight.
Yeah?
Seems like a lot longer.
[Girl] You should have got me
some anniversary present.
[Sonny] You can have another stick of gum.
That's all I got on me.
You can give me a dollar too.
That's how much it cost me and Marlene
for the show.
Hi. What y'all doing
back here in the dark?
- [Taylor] He's coming for me in a few minutes.
- [Maid] I'll get your coffee.
[Bell Rings]
[Tracy]
Where'd the boys go?
[Joan Bennett] Ben had some date,
and Tommy went to basketball practice.
- Oh, Delilah, will you bring the coffee, please?
- Yes, Mrs. Banks.
I don't see why they should get
the pickup first all the time.
All they ever want to do is neck anyway.
[Man Coughing]
[Taylor] Buckley says I'm not too young
for a man to marry.
- [Tracy] I didn't marry your mother till I was 25.
- Oh, I know, Pop...
[Wind Blowing]
[Dog Barking]
- Need some help, Jessie?
- Yeah, I sure do.
- Hey, so long, Sam.
- Bye, Sam. Come on!
- Good night.
- Good night, Sam. Sure did like the picture.
- Well, good. - [Sonny] Good night.
- [Sighs] Good night.
[Dog Barking In Distance]
[Radio: Man Singing, Pop]
# Rose, Rose, I love you #
# With your almond eyes #
# Fragrant and slender#
## [Fades]
## [Radio: Country]
[Dog Barking]
[Radio: Man Singing, Pop]
# When you see the time's a-wastin' #
- # You're a slow poke, dear #
- [Parking Brake Sets]
# Why should I keep tryin' #
Crack your window.
Leave the motor running.
It's just too cold in here.
# I guess I'll have to learn
to be a slow poke too ##
- ## [Ends]
- [Deejay] Pee Wee King's "Slow Poke."
Number two on the national chart.
- Now here's a brand-new...
- [Gasps] Your hands are like ice.
- I could put on my gloves.
- ## [Country]
[Man]
# Send me your spoon and your napkin #
# Send me your coffee cup too #
What's the matter with you?
You act plain bored.
Quit! Quit!
- # Anything that's part of you #
- You said this was our anniversary.
Let's do something different.
Well, I like that. You cheapskate.
Didn't even get me an anniversary present,
and now you wanna go and get me pregnant.
Oh, my God, Charlene.
It was just my hand.
Yeah. One thing leads to another.
My mama told me how that old stuff goes.
We'll have plenty of time for that
when we get married.
You wasn't no livelier than me.
That's 'cause you ain't good-lookin' enough.
You ain't even got a ducktail.
Well, anyway, I'm done late.
Let's go on home.
Some anniversary.
[Sighs]
If that's the way you feel about it,
I'd just as soon break up, Charlene.
- [Shouts] What?
- I don't want to spoil no more anniversaries for you.
That's the way nice girls
get treated in this town.
I might have known you wasn't dependable.
- You wasn't even in the backfield either.
- Now, what's that got to do with it?
This jacket's got a hole in the pocket, but
you needn't ask me to sew it up for you.
And you give me back my pictures too.
I don't want you showing them to all the
other boys and telling 'em how hot I am.
- You wasn't very hot.
- [Engine Starts]
- [Crickets Chirping]
- ## [Jukebox: Country]
## [Continues]
I hope you ain't down in the mouth
about Charlene.
- I ain't blue about her.
- She don't even have a good disposition.
What are you blue about then?
There ain't nobody to go with in this town.
Jacy's the only pretty girl in school,
and Duane's got her.
I call that his tough luck.
You don't have to eat so fast.
You ain't in a race.
Jacy will bring him more misery
than she'll ever be worth.
Did your dad give you this?
- He needs all he's got.
- [Register Bell Dings]
It wouldn't hurt you to take a little
something from him once in a while.
I don't know.
You and Duane both in a boardin' house.
Him with a mother and you with a father.
It don't seem right.
And your dad's taking too many pills,
you know.
Yeah.
Then I'm no one to talk.
I never did get on with Mama. Still don't.
- Say, I hear Dan's goin' back to work soon.
- # Say, hey, good-lookin' #
I guess you'll be quittin' before long.
Honey, we got $4,000 worth
of doctor bills to pay.
I will probably be making cheeseburgers
for your grandkids.
- [School Bell Ringing]
- [Kids Chattering]
Look at the little ducktail over here!
[Boy]
Oh, go to hell.
What's wrong with you, you duck ass?
[Whistles]
Well...
I wonder what my chances are
this morning...
of interesting you kids in John Keats.
- None at all.
- [Kids Laughing]
Joe Bob.
Well, I read that poem of his
about the nightingale...
and I didn't think it was so good.
Sounded like he wanted
to be a nightingale.
Right. I-I don't think he wanted
to be a nightingale, Joe Bob.
Maybe he just wanted to be immortal.
[Joe Bob] All you have to do to be immortal
is lead a good Christian life.
Anyone can do it if they love the Lord.
[Teacher]
Well, maybe so, Joe Bob. Maybe so.
Here now. Let me... Let me read you this.
"When old age
shall this generation waste...
"thou shalt remain...
"in midst of other woe than ours...
"a friend to man...
"to whom thou sayest...
"beauty is truth; truth, beauty.
"That is all ye know on earth...
and all ye need to know."
Run, you little pissants! Run!
Tough it out! Tough it out!
You gotta be men like the rest of us.
Ain't none of you pretty enough
to be women.
Here, Joe Bob, quit flapping your arms.
You look like a goddamned goose.
Even for a preacher's boy,
you ought to be in better shape.
What kind of female you ever gonna get?
Tough it out! Tough it out.
Run, you little pissants.
All right, off the court.
If y'all didn't jack off so damn much,
maybe you could stay in shape.
Come here a minute, Sonny.
Now, you do me a favor,
and I'll do you one.
Sure, Coach.
Now, my old lady's got to go over
to the doctor in Olney tomorrow.
You know women.
There's always something wrong with them.
Yeah, I guess.
Well... [Spits]
Take it from me.
Anyway, I haven't got time to drive her.
Now, if you'll do this for me...
I'll get you out of civic class.
I'll be glad to.
That's the best offer I've had all day.
You tell her you got to get back
in time for practice...
so she won't stay in there too long.
I've got enough bills to pay already.
[Tires Screeching]
Hey, you know what's the trouble
with you little pissants?
You ain't got no school spirit!
[Spits]
Ding! Ow!
# Anarene High School
we love you #
# Love you ever so grand #
# We will always be so loyal #
# Loyal to the man #
# Whether in defeat or victory #
# We will always be true #
# Anarene High School
we love you #
# And we'll fight for you ##
- [Jacy] Whoo!
- [Duane] Whoo!
[Barking]
## [Radio: Country]
[Man]
# Pardon me if I'm sentimental #
You need a haircut.
# When we say good-bye #
# Don't be angry #
[Boy] Hey, come on, Jimmie Sue.
We're hungry over here too.
- I'm comin'! I'm comin'! Hold your horses.
- It's been a half hour.
# When you're gone
yet I'll dream a little #
Uh-oh. Better watch it.
Here comes your mama.
# Now and then #
# There's a fool such as I #
Jacy, we're havin' supper at home tonight.
I expect you there in 15 minutes, you hear?
Okay, Mama.
I was just giving the boys a ride.
Mmm.
- [Man] Hey, Abilene.
- # And now you say #
# That we are through #
# I'm a fool, but I'll love you, dear #
# Until the day I die #
# Now and then #
# There's a fool such as I ##
Now, here's a tune that's been, uh,
on the pop hit list for a number of weeks.
- You listen and tell us the name of this one.
- ## [Pop]
[Host] # ...are a-comin',
their sails are in sight #
- What is it?
- ## [Continues]
- What is it, huh? Hear it again.
- [Boy] "Shrimp Boats."
[Host]
"Shrimp Boats." You got it. Very good!
- [Audience Applauding]
- ## [Organ: Flourish]
Very good, Carlos.
You were in on that too.
All right. There's a hundred twenty dollars.
We're goin' along fine.
Now we come to City Limits.
This is geographic.
[Radio: Man Singing, Pop Ballad]
# Keeps us so far apart #
[Knocking]
# Why can't I free your doubtful mind #
[Meows]
# And melt your cold, cold heart #
Guess you hate me tonight, huh?
Oh, Mama, you know I love you.
But I love Duane, too, even if you don't like it.
I don't care. I'd just hate to
see you marry him. That's all.
You wouldn't be rich any more,
and in about two months...
- I don't care about money. Not at all.
- he'd stop flattering you.
Well, you're pretty stupid then.
Well, you married Daddy when he was poor,
and he got rich, didn't he?
Scared your daddy
into getting rich, beautiful.
Well, if daddy could do it,
Duane could too.
Not married to you.
You're not scary enough.
Well, you're rich and you're miserable.
I sure don't want to be like you.
Not much danger of that.
- You slept with him?
- Mama!
We'll go to the doctor sometime
and arrange something...
so that you don't have to worry
about babies.
- You do have to be careful of that, you know.
- But, Mama, it's a sin, isn't it?
Unless you're married?
You know I wouldn't do that.
Oh! Don't be so mealymouthed.
I thought, if you slept
with him a few times...
you might find out that there
isn't anything magic about him.
Then we can send you away to a good
school and you can marry some wealthy boy.
But I don't want to leave.
Why can't I just stay here
and go to college in Wichita Falls?
Because everything is flat and empty here.
Ain't nothin' to do.
- Can I have some of that?
- Help yourself. Don't you have any?
Well, yeah, but I feel like
smelling good right now.
Don't you ever feel like
doing anything right now?
You ought to leave your
face just like that.
All you really need now is
a little eyebrow pencil.
- # Why can't I free your doubtful mind #
- [Exhales]
- # And melt your cold, cold #
- Okay. Good night.
# Heart ##
Just remember, beautiful...
everything gets old
if you do it often enough.
So if you want to find out
about monotony real quick...
marry Duane.
[Deejay] Number one hit
in the country right here on KTRN...
- your Mutual station in Wichita Falls.
- [Yowls]
Our old friend Hank Williams wrote that,
you know.
- [TV: Audience Applauding]
- ## [Organ, Upbeat]
[Male Announcer]
You're with us on Strike It Rich...
and the audience with a heart.
Say, if you like being
with our audience with a heart...
I'd like to remind you
that we're on television every day.
That's right, every day, Monday through
Friday at 11:30 a.m., New York time.
Also every morning Monday through Friday,
we're on radio on another network.
Just look at your paper
for time and stations.
And every Wednesday night at 9:00
right back here on television again.
Now, the Colgate-Palmolive-Peet Company
invites you to write us for tickets.
All's you have to do is write to: Strike It
Rich, Box 500, Grand Central Annex...
- Hello.
- Abilene, you... you asleep?
- No.
- Feel like company?
- Now again, here's Warren Hull!
- [Audience Applauding]
Well, I thought I'd drive out,
see how my well is coming.
Drill hard.
You're better at oil wells anyway.
[Hull] Before we continue Strike It Rich,
I want to remind you...
to look for one
of your favorite programs.
I know it's one of mine.
The whole family always watches
The Colgate Comedy Hour Sunday night.
[Radio: Man Singing, Country] # I got a
hot rod Ford and a two-dollar bill #
- # And I know a spot right over the hill...##
- [Engine Stops]
[Knocking]
- ## [Radio: Organ]
- Oh, hello, Sonny. What you want?
Uh, Coach said you needed a driver.
- [Man On Radio] For a wash that's
white without bleaching... - Oh.
- Use Oxydol.
- Didn't he tell you I was coming?
No, he didn't mention it.
I thought he was gonna drive me himself.
- I guess he just couldn't get off.
- ## [Radio: Organ]
Let me just get the radio.
[Man On Radio]
This after...
[Radio: Man Singing, Pop] # Eight
o'clock, nine o'clock, quarter to ten #
# Why should I linger
every time you snap your finger#
- # Little slow poke...##
- [Engine Stops]
Is it something bad?
No.
Just something... dreary.
- [Engine Stops]
- [Horn Honks]
Thank you.
Here's the keys.
Uh, I guess I'd better be getting
back to the school.
It was nice of you to drive me.
Well, it beats sitting
through civics, ma'am.
[Wind Blowing]
Wouldn't you like to come in
and have a soda...
if you can stand me
for a few more minutes?
Oh.
Okay.
I hate these northers.
Ah.
Would you prefer milk?
Just sit at the table.
Or you can go right now if you want.
I... I was just scared to be alone for a minute.
I'm sorry I made you come in.
I'll take a Dr. Pepper.
Ahh.
[Clock Ticking]
[Sobbing]
[Crying]
[Swallows]
[Coughs]
Oh.
[Gasps, Sobs]
You'll never forgive me, I know.
[Sniffles]
Go on. You don't have to stay
any... any longer.
- [Sniffles]
- Thank you for the Dr. Pepper.
I guess you'll be glad
when basketball season's over.
[Sniffles]
Why?
Well, Coach probably
don't get to stay home much...
during football and basketball season.
My God, you don't know a thing
about it, do you?
[Chuckles]
[Exhales]
You better go on to basketball practice.
Thanks for the Dr. Pepper.
[Door Opens, Closes]
[Muffled]
## [Country Band: "Jingle Bells"]
[People Chattering]
[Radio: Man Singing, Ballad]
# All my life #
- [Parking Brake Sets]
- # I shall remem...##
- Hi, Jacy!
- Oh, hi.
- Duane coming?
- Mm-hmm.
- Say, you know Bobby Sheen, don't
you, over to Wichita Falls? - Sure.
I met him at the country club.
Well, he's gonna have
this midnight swimming party tonight.
- You want to run over there with me later?
- I can't.
I guess you heard about the last one.
His folks were gone to Miami,
and everybody swam naked.
- Yeah? - His folks are gone again,
so it will probably be pretty wild.
Sure wish you could come.
Bobby has great parties.
- A lot of kids from the club gonna be there.
- [Vehicle Approaching]
[Horn Honking]
Gee, Lester, I'd like to go.
I'm gonna have a big problem
with Duane though.
Well, don't go off without me.
Maybe I can.
## [Ends]
[Crowd Applauding]
- Hi, Duane.
- What did Lester want?
Hmm? Oh, Lester, he's such a bore.
## [Band: "Red River Valley"]
## [Continues]
- [Man] Hey, Abilene.
- What do you say, buddy?
Hey there. Hi.
- Merry Christmas.
- Uh, this here's Jackie Lee French.
Jackie Lee, this is Lois
Farrow, my boss's wife.
- Hi, Jackie.
- What do you mean kissing her like that?
I ought to slap your face.
Oh, why don't you just kiss my ass?
I never come here to referee no fight.
Well, good.
Then come and dance with me.
Uh, uh... You get yourself a drink, honey.
I'll be back.
## [Lois Humming]
[Laughing]
Hi, Ruth.
[Chattering]
## [Ends]
[Crowd Applauding]
## [Band: "Oh, Dem Golden Slippers"]
[Mouthing Words]
- ## [Ends]
- [Applauding]
## [Waltz]
A thousand barrels...
A thousand barrels of oil a day.
Lousy field.
It's too hot in here.
Let's go outside.
I don't want a lot of drunk hillbillies
trompin' on my feet.
I got something to give you anyway.
- Hey, Sonny.
[Sonny]
Hi.
- Hi, Sonny.
- Hi, Dad.
How you doing?
Okay.
Well, that's good.
See you.
Sure.
- My Christmas present.
- Yeah.
Oh, goodness.
I haven't had time to get you anything yet.
- Well, that's okay.
- I just couldn't get loose a minute to shop.
I hope you like it.
I saved up for six months to get it.
Oh, it's just beautiful.
It's just what I've been wantin'.
You're so sweet,
spendin' all that money on me.
Oh, you're so sexy, Duane.
I just wish I didn't have
to leave you tonight.
- Well, you don't.
- Oh, I do too.
- I could just kill my mother.
- What do you mean?
She made me promise to go to a swim party in
Wichita with what's-his-name... Lester Marlow.
- Well, goddamn. What kind of thing is that?
- 'Cause his folks are so rich.
- Don't be mad at me, Duane.
- I ain't mad at you, but goddamn it!
It's all Lester's fault.
He keeps asking Mama.
- Well, goddamn!
- All I wanna do is stay with the man I love.
Goddamn!
- ## [Ends]
- [Applauding]
## [Band: Upbeat]
No, no, Duane.
I gotta go. I gotta go.
- ## [Ends]
- [Applauding]
## [Band: Waltz]
What do you think you're doing,
asking my girl for a date?
- You turn me loose!
- I'll turn you loose anytime you're ready to fight.
Come on. Let's have it out.
Come on, Marlow!
Here, knock off that shit, boys.
This is the Christmas season.
Run along here, Wichita. I can't stand here
all night protecting your shoeshine.
I just don't know
what I'm gonna do about him.
He's so crazy about me,
he doesn't have good sense.
Well, I'm not saying anything against
Duane, but that's a roughneck for you.
They never are very sophisticated
about these things.
- [Horn Honks]
- Well, merry Christmas!
Come in and let's have some punch, boys.
Hi, Sonny.
- Oh, hi.
- Want to help me?
Okay.
You're not dancing.
Don't you have a girlfriend?
Well, I did have.
We broke up a couple months ago.
Oh? Why?
Do you mind my asking?
I was goin' with Charlene Duggs.
She thought I got fresh with her.
I never did really.
I guess we broke up because we didn't
like each other much to begin with.
I hope you're not sad about it.
I don't think Charlene's
near nice enough for you.
Didn't see you dancing.
No, I don't dance much.
[Dog Barking In Distance]
Will you drive me to the clinic
again next week?
Oh, you bet.
[Vehicle Approaching]
We better not dawdle here.
[Can Clatters]
- [Man] # Oh, get out of here with that... #
- [Stomping]
# And don't come back no more #
- # Oh, get out of here with that... #
- [Stomping]
- # And don't come back no more #
- Bobby.
Hey, look! New victims!
[Girl Squealing]
Hi, Jacy.
- Hi.
- Glad you could make it.
- We're dressed informally, as you can see.
- Hi, Jacy.
- You know Annie Annie.
- Want to join the club?
Sure.
Well, you gotta get undressed
out there on the diving board.
- [Bobby] So everybody gets to watch.
- [Cheering, Wolf Whistle]
- We all do it the first time.
- That's the rule.
Yeah. I did it last Easter.
- [Annie Annie] Okay?
- Okay.
- Everybody out for the strip show.
- [Cheering]
- # So would you get out of here with that... #
- [Stomping]
# And take it down below #
- # Oh, get out of here with that... #
- [Stomping]
- # Take it down below #
- [Kids] Yeah!
# The moral of the story
is if you're out on the beach #
# And you should see a great big box
and it's within your reach #
# Don't ever stop and open it up #
# That's my advice to you #
# 'Cause you'll never get rid of the... #
Don't pay any attention to Sandy.
He's my little brother.
If he gooses you or anything,
I'll make him go to bed.
- [Laughter]
- ## [Ends]
Goodness.
Hope I don't fall off this thing.
Sandy can fish you out if you do.
[Laughter, Whooping]
[Laughter]
[Laughter, Cheering]
## [Background: Pop]
[Man]
# Rose, Rose, I love you #
# With an aching heart #
# Lonely is your future #
# Now we have to part #
# Standing on the jetty
as the steamer moves away #
# Flower of Malaya #
# I cannot stay ##
## [Band: "Silent Night"]
Duane, been lookin' for you.
Where's Jacy?
Aw, don't remind him.
We just got him quiet. You want a drink?
- Okay. Where'd you get it?
- Found it in a guy's car.
- When he weren't looking.
- Let's all go do something!
Good idea! Why don't we try
and hunt up some pussy?
Aw, you wouldn't know
what to do with it if we found some.
Hey. What happened, Duane?
Lester took his girl to a swimming party.
Let's all go out and get a fuck.
Hey, I know where there's a heifer.
It belongs to my Uncle Hank.
Yeah. Why the hell not?
- I say a heifer beats nothin'.
- Pussy's pussy.
I don't want no heifer.
Hell, what we ought to do
is buy Billy here a piece of ass.
- Yeah, we oughtn't let him die a virgin.
- Yeah.
Mama says idiot kids
don't live long anyway.
He ain't no idiot kid.
He just don't talk.
I bet he's still a virgin though.
Hey, we oughta fix him up
with Jimmie Sue.
- Ew!
- It wouldn't make no difference to Billy.
Look, I don't think
we should try anything like that.
Why not? It wouldn't cost us
more than a dollar and a half.
Hell, if that's all she costs,
we ought to get her ourselves.
Shit! Heifer's better than Jimmie Sue.
Get the stupid little thing in here.
I ain't got all night.
- [Boys Chattering]
- Come on. Let's get those pants off, boys.
Whoo!
You ain't gonna be a virgin much longer.
- [Duane] Come on, Billy. We're gonna get you laid.
- [Bottle Shatters]
- [Laughing]
- [Duane] Whoo!
Strap her on, Billy. Now come on.
- Do the job, Billy.
- Get her, Billy boy.
[Jimmie Sue]
Why, this is the dumbest thing I ever seen!
- He don't even know what to do.
- [Boy] Come on, Billy!
Damn it. Put it to her, boy.
- Get her, Billy.
- Come on, Billy. Screw it to her, boy!
You kids stop that yelling out there.
Got a hold of this thing. It ain't even in!
Goddamn... What you...
Goddamn, you stupid little thing!
- [Slaps Face]
- Couldn't even wait. Look at this mess!
- You okay, Billy?
- You all right?
Well, now I know.
Idiot's as bad as Mexicans.
Don't bother me no more
for that crazy thing.
Wouldn't mess with him again
for less than three and a half.
## [Car Radio: Country]
## [Stops]
Which one of you bloodied his nose?
I've told y'all not to fight with Billy
'cause he don't understand about fightin'.
- What happened, Sonny?
- It weren't none of us, Sam.
Nah. It was Jimmie Sue.
Jimmie Sue?
How'd he get messed up with her?
We all chipped in
and bought him a piece of ass.
Thought he was getting tired
of being a virgin.
She got mad about somethin'
and bloodied his nose.
[Vehicle Passing]
Now, you boys can get on out of here.
I don't want to have no more to do with you.
Scaring a poor,
unfortunate creature like Billy...
just so's you could have a few laughs.
I've been around
that trashy behavior all my life.
I'm getting tired of putting up with it.
Now, you can stay out of this pool hall...
out of my caf
and my picture show too.
I don't want no more of your business.
We didn't mean for anything bad
to happen, Sam. We...
You didn't even have the decency
to wash his face.
[Screen Door Squeaks, Closes]
We're his best customers.
He can't run us off.
Can he?
Lucky I fell asleep.
I'd hate not to be able to shoot no pool.
[Door Opens]
You're sure he won't come?
You know he won't.
He's just startin' basketball practice.
[Groans]
[Grunting]
[Gasps]
[Bed Springs Squeaking]
It's all right.
[Grunts]
[Squeaking Continues]
[Gasping]
[Quiet Sobbing]
[Crying]
[Gasps]
[Sonny Exhales]
[Quiet Sobbing]
[Ruth Grunts]
I'm sorry I cried.
Just a-scared, I guess.
Oh, he ain't gonna come.
They're probably running plays
right now, I bet.
No, not scared of that.
Scared I could never do this, I guess.
Can't seem to do anything
without crying about it.
How could you like me?
Oh, I like you.
I'm glad.
[Radio: Man Singing, Country]
# But she just wouldn't stay #
[Billiard Balls Clattering]
# So now that she is a-leavin' #
# This is all I can say #
# I got a feeling called the blues #
# Oh, Lawd, since my baby said good-bye #
# Lawd, I don't know what I'll do #
# All I do is sit and cry #
# Oh, Lawd, that last long day #
# She said good-bye #
# Well, Lawd, I thought I would cry#
# She'll do me, she'll do you
She's got that kind of lovin' #
# Lawd, I love to hear her
when she calls me Sweet Daddy ##
[Radio: Man Singing, Country]
# So I wrote it in the words #
# Of this song #
# I didn't know #
# God made honky-tonk angels #
# I might have known
you'd never make a wife #
# You gave up the only one #
# That ever loved you #
# And went back
to the wild side of life ##
[Bell Jingling]
Well, come on in.
I ain't gonna throw bottles at you.
Hi.
What have you been doing?
You lost weight.
Ain't had any of your cheeseburgers
in weeks.
Well, come on. I'll fix you one...
even though that wasn't
a very nice thing y'all done to Billy.
Can't blame Sam.
- Was that your idea?
- No.
- Duane's?
- Huh?
He was there, wasn't he?
Just didn't have the decency
to own up to it.
Oh, don't worry.
I won't tell on him. I should though.
- [Sizzling]
- Sure smells good.
One thing I know for sure...
person can't sneeze in this town without
somebody offering him a handkerchief.
- What you mean?
- Nothin'.
Just an awful small town
for any kind of carrying-on.
Don't forget to put some onions on 'em.
And some people got a lot of guns.
[Chuckles]
All right.
You don't need my advice anyway.
Why don't you go play a record?
These will be done in a minute.
[Jukebox: Drum Beating]
- [Bells Jingling]
- [Coughing]
[Man] # Kaw-liga was a wooden Indian
standin' by the door#
# He fell in love with an Indian maid
over in the antique store #
# Kaw-liga #
# Just stood there
and never let it show #
I just came in
to say hello to Genevieve.
# Though she could never
answer yes or no #
Sonny?
Food's gettin' cold.
# The maiden wore her beads and braids
and hoped someday he'd talk #
# Kaw-liga #
# Too stubborn to ever show a sign #
What are you grinnin' about?
Chicken-fry me a steak,
and try to use meat this time.
# Poor old Kaw-liga
he never got a kiss #
# Poor old Kaw-liga #
I heard about the ball game last night.
121 to 14.
Must be pretty near a record.
# That poor old wooden head #
Sam, I'm sorry.
I reckon y'all need glasses.
## [Continues, Fades]
- [Ruth] Hold still.
- [Sonny Laughs]
- Want some more cookies?
[Sonny] Mm-mmm.
- More milk?
- I'm full.
## [Ruth Humming]
Hey, how come you've stayed
with the coach?
You don't like him much.
Oh, I weren't brought up
to leave a husband.
I guess that's why.
Maybe I was just scared to.
I never noticed how ugly this room is.
- What's your favorite color?
- Oh, I don't know. Blue.
- Maybe I'll repaper it.
- Well, why'd you marry him?
I don't know.
My mother didn't like him.
Maybe that was it.
[Chuckling]
But I was 20 years old.
I thought hairy-chested football coaches
were about it.
I'm gonna buy us a new quilt.
A blue one.
What do you think he'd do
if he found us?
Shoot us probably.
He's always glad to have an excuse
to use his deer rifle.
[Bird Calling]
I thought you boys wanted to fish.
Come on.
Keep an eye on them corks, Billy.
I don't think there's anything
in this tank 'cept turtles.
That's what I like about it,
tell you the truth.
- Want to try one?
- Sure.
I never liked to clean fish
or eat them either.
Spend half your time picking out bones.
Yeah, I just come out here
to get a little scenery.
Too pretty a day to spend in town.
You wouldn't believe
how this country's changed.
First time I seen it,
there wasn't a mesquite tree on it...
or a prickly pear neither.
I used to own this land, you know.
First time I watered a horse at this tank
was more than 40 years ago.
I reckon the reason
why I always drag you out here...
is probably I'm just as sentimental as the
next fella when it comes to old times.
Old times.
I brought a young lady
swimming out here once.
More than 20 years ago.
It was after my wife had lost her mind
and my boys was dead.
Me and this young lady
was pretty wild, I guess.
In pretty deep.
We used to come out here a-horseback
and go swimmin' without no bathin' suits.
[Chuckles]
One day, she wanted
to swim the horses across this tank.
Kind of a crazy thing to do,
but we done it anyway.
She bet me a silver dollar
she could beat me across.
She did.
This old horse I was a-ridin'
didn't want to take the water.
But she was always lookin'
for somethin' to do like that.
Somethin' wild.
I'll bet she's still got
that silver dollar.
- [Chuckles]
- Whatever happened to her?
Oh, she growed up.
She was just a girl then really.
Here, let me help you with that.
Why didn't you ever marry her
after your wife died?
She was already married.
Her and her husband was young
and miserable with one another...
like so many young married folks are.
I thought they'd change with some age, but...
didn't turn out that way.
[Sonny]
ls being married always so miserable?
No, not really.
About 80% of the time, I guess.
We ought to go
to a real fishing tank next year.
Nah, it don't do to think about
things like that too much.
If she was here, I'd probably be
just as crazy now as I was then...
in about five minutes.
Ain't that ridiculous?
No, it ain't really...
'cause being crazy about a woman like her
is always the right thing to do.
[Chuckles]
Being a decrepit old bag of bones...
that's what's ridiculous.
Gettin' old.
[Exhales]
## [Background: Ballad]
[Man]
# Talk to her, please #
# Mr. Sun #
# Speak to her #
# Mr. Rainbow #
# And take her under your branches #
# Mr. Tree #
# Whisper to her#
# Mr. Wind #
# Sing to her #
- # Mr. Robin #
- My God, I'm glad it wasn't on fire.
I would have burned to death
before you got one button undone.
I'm going to get a drink of water.
# Mr. Moonlight
put in a word for me ##
Hi.
I wondered where you went.
Annie Annie asleep?
Yeah.
[Exhales]
Nice. You a virgin?
Guess I am.
Too bad.
- I don't want to be though.
- I don't blame you.
Come see me when you're not.
[Jukebox: Man Singing, Country]
# Another love before my time #
# Made your heart sad and blue #
# And so my heart is paying now#
# For things I didn't do #
- # In anger, unkind words are said #
- [Slurping]
Why don't we just take off and go someplace?
I'm sick and tired of this town.
- You're the only friend I got here.
- You mean go and stay gone?
Except Jacy. No, I don't know.
Hey, we could go to Mexico.
Be back sometime Monday.
- You reckon the pickup would make it?
- It might. How much money you got?
Oh, 30 bucks about.
Well, I got 40.
We could make a run with that. Come on!
Okay.
- You boys want... Hey, where you going?
- Mexico.
Where?
[Engine Revving]
[Radio: Man Singing, Country]
# ...more of your kisses #
- # I want more, more, more tender kisses #
- Better come with us, Sam.
We're headed for the valley.
- Going where, did you say?
- [Sonny] Mexico.
- I hear it's about the wildest.
- Yeah, all the way down.
You're going all the way to Mexico tonight
in this old heap of junk?
- [Duane Chuckling]
- My God.
Reckon the town
get along without us till Monday?
Oh, I reckon.
If I was young enough to bounce that far,
I'd go with you.
- Need any money?
- No, we got plenty.
Well, you'd better take some
for some insurance.
Take money below that border,
it sort of melts sometimes.
Well, thanks, Sam.
And try not to drink too much
of that buggy water.
Oh, we'll just drink beer and tequila.
Yeah. You catch the clap,
you'll wish you hadn't drunk nothin'.
[Sonny, Duane Laughing]
# I want more, more, more tender kisses #
# The neighbors all raise Cain
and I know that it's a shame #
# But I've got to have
another tender kiss ##
Oh, well. We'll see you.
- [Duane] Adios!
- So long!
[Radio: Man Singing, Country] # Well, I'm
in love, I'm in love with a beautiful gal #
# That's what's the matter with me #
# Well, I'm in love
I'm in love with a beautiful gal #
# But she don't care about me #
Duane. Hey, wake up.
We're back.
Oh, my stomach don't feel so good.
Got any more of those TUMS?
Aw, you ate 'em all
before we got to San Antone.
Well, Genevieve will have something.
My stomach, it don't feel so good.
[Sonny]
Closed.
Closed?
Yeah.
I never seen it closed before.
No, not even for Christmas.
Maybe Sam will have something.
'Cause I'm sick.
[Groans]
- ## [Stops]
- [Engine Stops]
[Sonny]
Oh, it ain't that early.
Must be some kind of holiday.
Sam don't close on holidays.
Maybe he had to go someplace.
- Well, let's go ask Andy, huh?
- Okay.
- Hey, Andy.
- It's a wonder somebody don't steal the town.
Hey, where is everybody?
Asleep, if everybody's got any sense.
Well, why'd Sam close the caf?
Oh, yeah, y'all been gone, ain't you?
Gone to Mexico.
- You don't know about it.
- About what?
Sam died yesterday morning.
- Died?
- Yep. Quite a blow.
Keeled over on one of the snooker tables.
Had a stroke.
Sam the Lion?
Yep. Sam's dead.
He was quite a feller.
He had his own way of doin' things.
That's for sure.
They found his will...
craziest thing you ever heard.
He left you the pool hall, Sonny.
What do you think about that?
He left Genevieve the caf.
That's the only thing he done
that made any sense.
Left the picture show to old Miss Mosey.
Hell, she's too far gone
to even run a popcorn machine.
And the craziest thing of all...
he left a thousand dollars to Joe
Bob Blanton, the preacher's boy.
Beats all I ever heard of.
He could just as easily left that to me...
'cause I deserve it least as much
as that ignorant little bastard.
Anyhow, it's done.
They're burying him tomorrow.
[Birds Chirping]
[Casket Clattering]
[Exhales, Sniffles]
[Clattering]
[Gasps, Sighs]
[Clattering Continues]
- [Boy] Duane's gonna get it, sure enough.
- ## [Radio: Country]
[Boys Continue Chattering]
[Man]
# If you love me #
# Half as much as I love you #
[Boy] Don't shit in your pants.
Everybody can't please everyone.
- [Chattering Continues]
- # You wouldn't worry me #
- # Half as much as you do #
- [Boys Laughing]
# You're nice to me #
- # When there's no one else around ##
- [Boy] You better get somethin'.
[Vehicles Passing]
[Jacy]
Come in.
[Radio: Man Singing, Ballad]
# They're not making the skies #
# As blue this year#
# Wish you were here #
# As blue as they used to
when you were near#
- I love you.
- I love you too.
# Wish you were here #
# And the mornings don't seem as new#
# Brand new as they did with you #
# Wish you were here #
# Someone's painting the leaves
all wrong this year#
# Wish you were here #
Oh, Duane, hurry.
# Why did the birds
change their song this year#
# Wish you were here #
- [Zipper Unzips]
- # They're not shining the stars as bright #
# They've stolen the joy from the night #
# Wish you were here #
## [Continues, Instrumental]
What's wrong, honey?
Um, I don't know.
That tickles.
You know I can't stand to be tickled.
What's the matter?
Aren't you gonna do it?
- I don't know what's wrong.
- What do you mean? How could anything be wrong?
Just go on and do it.
[Exhales]
Oh! What's the matter with you?
I don't know. I don't know.
Something's happened.
Well, get off a minute, for goodness sake.
You might fall and mash me.
I don't know what happened.
It was Mexico.
No telling what you got down there.
I just hate you!
I don't know why I ever went with you.
- I don't know what happened.
- [Exhales]
Put your clothes on. You think I wanna
sit around here and look at you naked?
I might have known you couldn't do it.
Now I'll never get to not be a virgin.
What'll we tell everybody?
The whole class knows.
I just wanna cry.
I think you're the meanest boy I ever saw.
My mother was dead right about you.
- I don't know what happened.
- Don't go out there!
We haven't had time to do it.
They'd know.
I don't want one soul to know.
You'd better not tell one soul.
You just pretend it was wonderful.
Hell, I'm sorry.
I don't know what happened.
Oh!
- If you say that one more time, I'll bite you!
- [Deejay] Now here's Tony Bennett.
# Lay out the cards
from left to right... #
[Engine idling]
## [Continues: Instrumental]
Oh, gee, tell us about it, Jacy.
What was it like?
I just can't describe it.
I just can't describe it in words.
## ["Texas, Our Texas"]
# Texas, our Texas #
# All hail the mighty state #
# So wonderful, so great #
# Largest and grandest #
# Withstanding every test #
# O Empire wide and glorious #
# You stand supremely blessed #
[Duane]
Jacy?
- Jacy?
- # God bless you, Texas #
I can do it now.
I know I can.
- # And keep you brave and strong #
- Jacy?
# That you may grow
in power and worth #
# Throughout the ages long ##
Oh, quit prissin'.
I don't think you did it right anyway.
[Laughs]
Come on.
It's your graduation present.
Hope you like it.
I never seen one as nice.
[Chuckles]
[Ringing]
[Radio: Man Singing, Ballad] # Since
you're gone, I spend each moment... #
- Hello.
- Jacy?
What's on your feeble mind, Duane?
Same as it's been. I want a date.
Uh-huh. Why don't you
just go back to Mexico?
I guess girls are just
easier to please down there.
Just go out with me once more.
Just one more time.
- You can at least see me.
- Uh-uh. You find somebody else to pester.
I've got a new boyfriend now,
and I can't be talkin' to you.
- What new boyfriend? Who?
- Bobby Sheen, of course.
Bobby Sheen?
- You crazy?
- I certainly am not.
I guess I've just been wanting to go with
him all along and never realized it.
Maybe we'll see you
in Wichita sometime.
## [Radio: Country]
[Man] # Now all the neighbors in her block
have altered things, you see #
- # They'll even pay the wedding...#
- Goddamn it!
Goddamn it to hell!
# More, more, more of your kisses #
# I cry for more, more,
more tender kisses ##
[Engine idling]
Well, I hate to see you go, Duane.
I don't have
a goddamn thing to stay for.
The roughnecks say you can
get a job out in Odessa anytime.
Come on back if you don't.
Hey, listen.
You hear they busted up, let me know.
[Duane Shouts]
[Audience Laughing]
[TV Continues]
[Sighs]
[Woman On TV]
Why don't we watch the movie?
[Laughter]
[Footsteps]
- Hi. I didn't hear you.
- Gene home?
No. He and Mama went to the club.
What are you doing home
on a Saturday night?
Bobby Sheen ran off and got married.
Oh.
Annie Annie Martin.
Want me to turn the TV off?
No. I'm gonna go play some pool.
Just tell your daddy
that well came in okay.
[Sighs]
I wish I could go to the pool hall.
I've always wanted to.
It's terrible
the things girls aren't allowed to do.
Well, hell, come on.
I'll show you the pool hall.
- Aren't there people there?
- If there are, they'll be in back asleep now.
Won't bother us.
Got my own key.
Okay, I will then.
[Laughter Continues]
[Key Turning In Lock]
Goodness, it sure is dark in here.
[Blows]
[Train Whistle Blowing In Distance]
[Gasps]
[Moaning]
[Engine idling]
What a night. I never thought
somethin' like this would happen.
How about hoppin' out?
[Engine Revving]
- [Engine Revving]
- [Man On Radio] ...and in Chicago today...
Governor Adlai E. Stevenson accepted
the Democratic presidential nomination...
and picked Senator John Sparkman of Alabama
to be his running mate.
In Dallas County, General Dwight D.
Eisenhower scored a second landslide victory...
- over old guard Republican forces...
- [Sighs]
- [Sobs]
- [Radio Continues, Indistinct]
- [Crying]
- [Clicks Tongue]
Oh, he's just awful, Mama!
Why do you fool with him?
Daddy's a nicer man than him, isn't he?
Oh, he sure is, beautiful.
Your daddy's a very nice man.
I oughta have been givin' Abilene hell
instead of him.
I don't know what I'm gonna do.
Bobby was the last one.
- No.
- I'm just gonna be an old maid.
Honey, that's just the way
it goes sometimes, you know?
- You win a few, you lose a few.
- What do you do?
Nothing's ever the way
it's supposed to be at all.
You're right. Come on.
I want to tell you something.
What I've done has not
worked out too well.
I think maybe we better think
of something else for you, huh?
- [Exhales]
- [Sighs]
Right now, I guess Ruth Popper's
got about as good a setup as anyone.
- Ruth Popper?
- I think Sonny's reasonably good-looking...
- Sonny? Sonny Crawford?
- Oh, don't you know about that?
It's been going on about six months now.
I thought you kids knew everything.
It's the silliest thing I ever heard of.
She's 40 years old.
So am I, honey.
It's kind of an itchy age.
- You want an orange?
- I don't believe it.
Sonny's always wanted to go with me.
[Man On Radio]
...and lows in the 80s.
[Radio: Man Singing, Country]
# if you loved me #
- # Half as much as I love you #
- [Man] Pretty easy shot, Sheriff.
# You wouldn't worry me #
# Half as much as you do #
Sheriff, we got some trouble.
Goddamn you, Monroe!
You made me scratch.
Sorry, Sheriff. Didn't mean to, but...
Well, Johnny Clarg's little girl's
kinda been kidnapped.
They said they saw the
preacher's boy put her in
his car about two hours ago
over at the drugstore.
Well, what the hell?
Maybe Joe Bob just give her a ride home.
Be doin' her a favor in this hot weather.
Who would want to kidnap Molly Clarg?
Don't ask me.
I just know she's not home.
They was seen
headed out of town toward Olney...
and, well, Miz Clarg's kind of afraid
that Joe Bob might be...
gonna molest her or somethin'.
Sonny, you and some of these boys
come with us.
If that's the way it is,
no telling what we'll find.
Molly! Molly!
Get him! Ain't you goin' to?
Here's my little girl.
He's the one that done it.
Why don't you get him?
If my husband was here, he'd kill him dead!
What'd you do to that child?
We know you done something.
Come on.
Filthy! Filthy, filthy!
Here now. Grab her.
None of this goddamn frenzy.
Filthy, filthy, filthy!
It's the Lord's justice, Son.
You'll have to suffer with the murderer and the thief.
- The Lord will help you now.
- Sonny, you drive that Plymouth to town.
We gotta get this man to jail.
[Engine Starts]
- Doctor said he didn't do nothin'.
- Never had the guts. Preacher's boy.
Sheriff figured he'd done somethin'.
- [Man] Yeah, stands to reason.
- [Horn Honking]
- ## [Radio: Woman Singing, Country]
- Isn't it terrible, Sonny?
Were you there? Did you see anything?
Oh, weren't nothing to
see except Miz Clarg.
And if she had a gun,
she might've killed us all.
And Joe Bob didn't do nothin'.
Oh, you know he must've done somethin'.
Scares me to death.
You just never can tell when somethin'
terrible's gonna happen.
It's okay. They got him now.
I called you before.
You did?
Mm-hmm. I felt lonesome.
Thought you might wanna
drive around a while.
Well, I'm supposed to be someplace.
I'm still a little scared.
Please take me riding.
Well, where will we drive?
- ## [Radio: Orchestra, Romantic]
- [Sighs]
- You ever hear from Duane?
- Had a postcard.
I really feel sad about that.
He's, uh... Makes 320 a month.
Said he bought a car.
Guess I'll always be
a little bit in love with Duane.
We just had too much against us.
It wasn't easy
being the one to break up.
[Radio: Man Singing, Ballad]
# She wore blue velvet #
# Bluer than velvet was the night #
# Softer than satin was the light #
# From the stars #
- Sonny?
- What?
# She wore blue velvet #
# Bluer than velvet were her eyes #
# Warmer than May her tender sighs #
# Love was ours ##
[Radio: Woman Singing, Ballad]
# See the marketplace in old Algiers #
# Send me photographs and souvenirs #
# Just remember, when a dream appears #
# You belong to me #
Not here.
I'm too old for screwin' in cars.
I don't like to hurry.
Why don't we go to Wichita
and get a motel room?
I'm afraid to right now.
I think my folks are watching me.
They know I don't want to go to college.
They might think
we're gonna run off and get married.
We'll do it when it's safe.
We got all summer.
[Radio: Man Singing, Country]
# Poor old Kaw-liga, he never got a kiss #
# Poor old Kaw-liga
He don't know what he missed #
# Is it any wonder that his face is red #
# Kaw-liga, that poor old wooden head ##
- Hey, Duane.
- Hey, buddy.
I didn't know you
turned roughneck.
Gotta make a livin' somehow so's
I can afford to keep the pool hall open.
- When'd you get in?
- Oh, about 2:00.
Thought I'd surprise you.
- This yours?
- Yeah. How about that?
38,000 miles on her.
She runs like new.
- Say, you want a beer?
- Not me.
It's about all I eat
for breakfast any more.
Hey, sure is a nice car.
Yeah, I like to drive it so much I thought
I'd just drop home for the weekend.
Yeah, you can't take too good care
of a car like this.
- I wash her every week.
- Oh, it looks great.
- Hear about Joe Bob?
- Yeah, I always knew he was crazy.
He didn't do nothing...
except get her to take her underpants off.
- He's out of jail now.
- Yeah.
Are you still screwing that old lady?
No. Yeah. I been kind of busy.
I seen old Leroy last week.
He said he thought you and Jacy
had been going together a little.
Yeah. We have a little.
She's been kinda bored, so once in a while
we go out, eat Mexican food or something.
The way I hear it,
that ain't all you been eating.
Well, whoever told you that
don't know what he's talkin' about.
Sure, I been goin' with her. Why not?
Never said I blamed you for it.
I don't blame you much.
Just never thought you'd do me that way.
I thought we were still best friends.
We are. What you so mad for?
I never done nothin' to you.
- I guess screwin' my girl ain't nothin' to you.
- I ain't screwing her.
- Hell you ain't!
- Well, I ain't.
- She's not your girl any more anyhow.
- She is my girl. I don't care if we did break up.
- Hell, you don't live here any more.
- That don't make no difference.
I'll always live here. I'm gettin' her back.
I'm tellin' you right now.
She's gonna marry me one of these days
when I get a little bit more money.
- She won't marry you.
- Sure, she will.
- We always meant to get married.
- She's going off to college soon.
I doubt I'll ever get to go with her
again myself once she gets off.
I never saw what it could hurt
to go with her this summer though.
- She's never gonna marry you.
- She is, by God! Don't you tell me she won't!
She'd never let you screw her.
That's for sure.
Hell, I was just seein'
how honest you was.
Jacy would never let you screw her.
You ain't that good a cocksman.
You never even screwed Charlene Duggs
all that time you went with her.
Course I didn't. You know why?
'Cause you had the pickup
all time Saturday night! That's why.
Nobody could have screwed her
in the time I had left.
I could have screwed her in five minutes.
I wouldn't even need no pickup.
Oh, yeah? Well, the only reason
she went with you as long as she did...
was 'cause you was in the backfield
and I was in the goddamn line.
What you talkin' about?
Me and her was in love.
Oh, you was. She likes me
just as much as she ever liked you.
- That's a lie.
- I'll stay with her all night one of these nights too.
- She done promised.
- You won't either.
Yes, I will. Why shouldn't I?
She done told me you
couldn't even do it that
time in Wichita Falls!
What about that?
[Groaning]
What happened?
Sonny?
[Man On Radio] This is your
Turntable Matinee here on KTRN...
where you can hear Fulton Lewis, Jr.
every Monday through Friday at 6:00 p.m.
- ## [Band: Country]
- Now here's Hank Williams...
"My Son Calls
Another Man Daddy."
There's a lady in the waiting room.
She sent you this.
# Tonight
my head is bowed in sorrow #
# I can't keep the tears
from my eyes #
Could you tell her I'm asleep? Please.
All right.
# The right to his love
I've been denied ##
[Bell Tolling]
[Radio: Man Singing, Country]
# Today, I passed you on the street #
- That too cold?
- Nah, it's great.
Say, I hear Duane joined the army.
Good place for him too.
Aw, he was just holding that bottle.
Didn't mean to hit me with it.
That boy's always had meanness in him.
Of course, Jacy's just the kind of girl
that brings out the meanness in a man.
She's just like her grandmother.
I hadn't ought to talk about 'em anyhow.
We was all good friends once.
Dan roughnecked with Gene Farrow.
He and Lois, they used to live in this little
one-room place over the newspaper office.
Hell, Lois couldn't afford a flour sack,
much less a mink.
I've always had a soft spot for her though.
[Chuckles]
Yeah, I wondered a lot of times, you know,
what would have happened...
if my Dan had made the strikes
that Gene made.
They offered that rig to him first.
Yep.
Dan Morgan never took a chance in his life.
Do you wish y'all had made it?
Oh, sure, I wish we'd made it.
Guess the army won't take me
now I just got one good eye.
You want to go over to Korea
and get yourself killed, huh?
You ain't got your senses back yet...
what few you ever had.
Well, caf won't run itself.
You rest up now.
Oh, here's for the cheeseburger.
Okay, I'll bring your change
when I bring your supper.
Thanks.
## [Continues, Indistinct]
# And holds you
just the way I used to do #
# Oh, heaven only knows
how much I miss you #
# I can't help it #
# If I'm still in love with you ##
- Sonny?
- Come on in.
[Deejay] "I Can't Help It"...
Hank Williams's big sound from last year.
Now here's a brand-new one
just came in from my old pal Webb Pierce.
Gonna hear it a lot, I bet.
"Back Street Affair."
Oh, I was so worried.
I just had to see you.
Oh, I been missing you.
And I'm a lot better than I was.
Here, sit down.
You just can't believe
how famous we are.
- We're all anybody talks about in this town now.
- Yeah, I guess so.
- I want us to get married.
- What?
- I really do.
- Get married?
Just as soon as you want to.
Don't you want to?
Oh, yeah.
I bet the whole town will be knocked for a
loop if we do. They'll never forget it.
- Ain't you goin' to college?
- Oh, I don't care about that.
I love you, and that's more important.
You were so dear to fight for me.
My folks won't like it,
but we can run off.
- They'll kill us.
- No, they won't.
- Kill me anyhow.
- They'll get over it.
You're working for Daddy now anyway.
Pretty soon, they'll love you
just as much as I do.
Can we?
Sure.
I just hope I can see to drive.
Don't you worry. I can drive.
[Slurping]
## [Radio: Country]
Don't do that, Sonny.
Why not? We're man and wife now.
We can do anything.
Not while I'm driving.
I might have a wreck.
Goodness. Wouldn't it be just awful
if Mama and Daddy got the police after us?
Oh, they don't even know where we are.
Well, I had to leave 'em a note, you know, so
they wouldn't be worried out of their minds.
You shouldn't have done that.
I had to.
I figured they'd have to know sometime.
Well, what could they get us for?
We got a right to get married,
ain't we?
I guess so.
I wish you didn't have that stupid eye patch.
It's really creepy.
I can take it off pretty soon.
'Bout two hours,
we'll be in Lake Texoma...
and have a room to ourself, hmm?
My goodness, you're sitting so close
I can barely drive.
[Radio: Man Singing, Country]
# Good-bye, Joe, me got to go #
# Me-oh, my-oh #
# Me got to go pole the pirogue
down the bayou #
# My Yvonne, the sweetest one
me-oh, my-oh #
# Son of a gun
we'll have big fun on the bayou #
Oh, goodness.
# Jambalaya and a-crawfish pie
and a fillet gumbo #
# 'Cause tonight
I'm gonna see my ma cher amio #
[Police Radio Chatter]
# Son of a gun
we'll have big fun on the bayou #
Howdy. What part of Texas y'all from?
- Anarene.
- Newlyweds, ain't you?
Well, y'all better follow me on in.
I think somebody's lookin' for you.
We ain't done nothin' wrong.
Ain't we got a right to get married?
- How can you arrest us just like that?
- I ain't arresting you.
I just want you to come with me
till we find out somethin'.
I don't know what your rights are.
I guess we better follow him, honey.
I'll just be heartbroken
if my folks have done this.
## [Continues, Indistinct]
You think I worked like a dog all my life
so my daughter can end up in a pool hall?
We was gonna get another apartment.
I'll bet you was.
Where are your car keys, hon?
It's a hell of a note. A hell of a note.
Just a hell of a note!
- Oh, shut up and take her home.
- You bet I will!
- I'm tired of this.
- You take her car.
As far as I'm concerned,
he can walk!
- [Car Door Slams]
- [Engine Starts]
[Engine Revs]
Not much of a wedding night, huh?
Nope, not much of one.
Here, have a little drink of bourbon.
It'll pick you up.
Take all of it. I'm gonna drive.
You won't believe this, Sonny, but you're lucky
we got you clear of her quick as we did.
You'd have been a lot better off
staying with Ruth Popper.
Does everybody know about that?
[Chuckles]
Of course.
Sounded like a good deal to me, kiddo.
You shouldn't have let
Jacy turn your head.
Well, she's prettier.
I guess I shouldn't have though.
- I guess I treated her terrible.
- Guess you did.
- [Dogs Barking In Distance]
- ## [Radio: Country]
## [Stops]
Sure weren't out of Texas very long.
Well, Oklahoma's not much
of an improvement.
It's not the same now.
Nothing's really been right
since Sam the Lion died.
No.
No, it hasn't.
Oh, God.
I get sad if I think of Sam for long.
Did you know he had beautiful hands?
I guess you liked him, didn't you?
I guess everybody did.
Well, I'll tell you.
It was different with me, Sonny.
I loved him.
He loved me too.
Are you... [Chuckles]
Are you the one he used
to take swimmin' out in the tank?
He told you about that, huh?
Yeah, I was the one.
[Exhales]
I guess if it wasn't for Sam, I'd...
[Sniffles] just about have missed it...
whatever it is.
I'd have been one of them Amity types
that thinks that...
playin' bridge is about
the best thing that life has to offer.
[Chuckles]
[Sighs]
Old Sam the Lion.
"Sam the Lion." You know,
nobody knows where he got that name.
I gave it to him.
One night, oh, it just came to me.
He... He was so pleased.
I was 22 years old then.
Can you imagine?
[Laughs]
I'll tell you, Sonny...
it's terrible to only meet one man in your
whole life who knows what you're worth.
Just terrible.
I've looked too.
You wouldn't believe
how I've looked.
- Well, now I know why Sam liked you.
- Loved me!
Loved you, I mean.
Do you?
Well, I can kind of see
what he saw in you too.
Nope, I'll just go on home.
- Go on, get out.
- [Engine Starts]
# I got a feeling called the blues
Oh, Lawd #
Think I could...
think I could learn to drink?
# Lawd, I don't know what I'll do #
[Laughing]
You might.
You better keep on practicing.
## [Continues, Indistinct]
## [March]
That Logan boy's
a quarterback now, ain't he?
Boy, we finally got us a team.
Didn't back in your day,
did they, Sonny?
Nah, we wasn't much good.
Well, you just never learned
the fundamentals...
you know, blocking and tackling...
not like this team.
- When was it you graduated?
- Last year.
You don't mean it?
Seems like longer than that
since you and old Duane played ball.
I seen old Duane a while ago.
He's home on leave.
- Wearin' his uniform.
- I ain't seen him yet.
- ## [Continues]
- [Cheering]
- ## [Ends]
- [Cheerleaders Yelling, Indistinct]
- How are you, Chuck?
- Fine, Coach.
Now, listen, see if we can't stretch
that goddamn thing a little.
You know a man never ought to cheat...
unless'n it's for a good cause.
He's a good old boy, ain't he?
## [Marching Band]
# Anarene High School
we love you #
# Love you, oh, so grand #
# We will always be so loyal #
# Loyal to the end #
# Whether in defeat or victory #
# We will e'er be true ##
Hi, Miz Jackson. Duane here?
That's his car out there, ain't it?
He's here if he ain't walked off.
[Door Opens]
- Hi. How you been?
- Oh, pretty good.
Yeah, I been thinking all week
that, you know, I'd run into you.
Yeah.
I heard you was going off to Korea.
I thought I'd better get over here
and see you before you got off.
Glad you did.
I'm taking the bus out
early in the morning.
Oh.
Thought you might want to go
to the picture show.
Miss Mosey's having to close it.
Tonight's the last night.
Yeah, might as well go.
Hate to miss the last night.
Take the Mercury. Be the last chance
I'll have to drive it for a while.
## [Movie Soundtrack: Dramatic]
- [John Wayne] Ready, Matthew?
- [Montgomery Clift] All ready.
[Projector Whirring]
[Cattle Mooing]
Take 'em to Missouri, Matt.
Yee-hah!
Yah-hah!
Yee-hoo!
- Yah-hah!
- Yee-hah!
- Yippee!
- Yah-hah!
- Hyah!
- Yee-hee!
- Heee!
- Yah-hah!
- Yee-hah!
- Ee-yah!
- Eee-hah!
- Yah-hah!
## [Chorus Singing, Indistinct]
[Cowboys Whooping, Shouting]
## [Soundtrack]
- ## [Ends]
- [Projector Whirs To Stop]
- That was a good movie.
- Yeah, I seen it here before once.
Why don't we run over to Wichita
and drink a little beer, huh?
Okay. I got lots of time till morning.
Sure.
- [Sonny] Well, so long, Miss Mosey.
- Sorry you're closing the show.
Nobody wants to come
to shows no more.
Kid baseball in the summer...
television all the time.
If Sam had lived, I...
l believe we could have kept it goin'.
But I just didn't have the know-how.
Won't be much to do in town
with the picture show closed.
Yeah.
Well, so long.
Duane.
You watch out now overseas.
[Radio: Man Singing, Country]
# Each night I laid there in prison #
# I pictured a future so bright #
Sure weren't no women around.
I guess the next piece of ass I get
will be yellow.
Wished I was going with you.
Hey, why don't you take care
of the car for me?
What, your ma don't need it?
I wouldn't want her driving it,
no better than she can drive.
You might help her take the groceries home,
you got the time.
Okay.
[Bus Brakes Squeal]
[Bus Engine Idling]
[Car Door Closes]
[Shivers]
You ever, uh... You ever hear from Jacy?
No, not a thing.
She don't get home much.
Ain't been back to town since August.
I guess she just stays
in Dallas all the time.
Yeah, probably does.
I guess there's lots to do down in Dallas.
I ain't over her yet, you know.
I ain't over her yet.
It's the damndest thing.
That's the only reason, uh...
the only reason you and I
got into it that time, you know.
Reckon she likes it down in Dallas?
It's hard to say.
Maybe she does.
[Deep Breath]
You reckon you and her would have got it all
straighted out if I hadn't have butted in?
Oh, no.
No.
[Sighs]
No. They'd have annulled me, too,
even if we had.
Y'all, uh... Y'all never even
got into the motel?
No.
Well.
Better get on before we both freeze.
Here are the keys.
- So long, buddy.
- So long, Duane.
Be careful.
I'll take care of the Mercury for you.
I'll see you in a year or two
if I don't get shot.
[Wind Blowing Outside]
[Horn Honks, Brakes Squeal]
[Wind Blowing]
[Cattle Mooing, Hooves Clattering]
[Men Chattering]
[Man]
He run right out in front of that station.
Christ, he didn't...
Trucker didn't have a chance.
[Man #2] Yeah, he's out here
all the time doin' something.
- [Cattle Mooing, Hooves Clattering]
- [Sheriff] I could see it wasn't your fault.
[Man #1] You can call the kid retarded.
You couldn't help it.
- [Driver] Sand was blowin'. I never noticed him.
- Yeah. Hard to see.
Never figured
nobody would be in the street.
What was he doin' out there, anyway,
carrying that broom?
Aw, he weren't doin' nothin'.
He's just an old simple-minded kid.
- Never had no sense.
- [Man] Sorta retarded. Wasn't your fault.
[Sheriff]
Hell, no, mister. I can see that.
He was just a dumb old kid.
Never was good for nothin'.
Didn't know enough to keep
his ass out of the cold, mornin' like this.
Let's go to the caf.
I ain't had no breakfast.
I'd still like to know what was he doin'
lugging that broom around this time of day.
He was sweepin', you sons of bitches!
He was sweepin'!
[Sniffles]
[Crying]
Y'all got some crazy kids
in this town, if you ask me.
[Door Banging]
- [Wind Blowing]
- [Door Banging]
[Engine Decelerating]
[Gears Grind]
[Engine Stops]
[Knocking]
[Radio: Audience Laughing]
Hi.
[Man On Radio, Indistinct]
Could I have a cup of coffee with you?
- I guess.
- [Man On Radio] Leave them alone.
Leave them alone.
- It's in the book!
- [Laughter]
I'm sorry I'm still in my bathrobe.
Leave them alone.
And they... they being the sheep...
they will come.
- Oh, yes, they'll come.
- [Rattling]
Oh, there'll be a brighter day tomorrow.
They will come.
- [Cup, Saucer Rattling]
- It's in the book.
What am I doing apologizing to you?
Why am I always apologizing to you?
You little bastard!
[Crockery Shattering]
Three months I've been apologizing to you
without you even being here!
I haven't done anything wrong.
Why can't I quit apologizin'?
You're the one ought to be sorry.
I wouldn't still be in my bathrobe
if it hadn't have been for you.
I'd have had my clothes on hours ago.
You're the one made me quit caring
if I got dressed or not.
I guess just because
your friend got killed...
you want me to forget what you did
and make it all right.
I'm not sorry for you.
You'd have left Billy, too,
just like you left me.
I'll bet you left him plenty of nights
whenever Jacy whistled.
I wouldn't treat a dog that way.
I guess you thought
I was so old and ugly...
you didn't owe me any explanation,
you didn't need to be careful of me.
There weren't anything I could do
about you and her.
Why should you be careful of me?
You didn't love me.
Look at me.
Can't you even look at me?
[Radio Continues, Indistinct]
See?
You shouldn't have come here.
I'm around that corner now.
You've ruined it.
It's lost completely.
Just your needing me
won't make it come back.
# Grandma's lye soap #
# Good for everything in the home #
# And the secret was in the scrubbing #
# It wouldn't suds and couldn't foam #
# Then let us all sing right out of grandma's...
of grandma's lye soap #
## [Audience Clapping In Rhythm]
# Used for everything
everything on the place #
# For pots and kettles #
# The dirty dishes #
# And for your hands #
# And for your face #
Shall we now sing the second verse?
Let's hit it with a great exuberance.
Let's live it up.
It's not raining inside tonight.
Everyone.
Let's have a happy time.
Are we ready?
All together.
# Little Herman and Brother Thurman #
# Had an aversion to washing their ears #
# Grandma scrubbed them
with the lye soap #
# And they haven't heard a word in years #
# Then let us all sing right out
of grandma's... of grandma's lye soap #
It...
- # Sing all out, all over the place #
- It...
# The pots and kettles #
# The dirty dishes #
# And also hands and all the...#
## [Clapping Ends]
Well, let's sing what's left
of the last verse.
Let's have a happy time, everyone.
The last verse all together.
Everyone.
Thank you kindly.
# Mrs. O'Malley out in the valley #
# Suffered from ulcers, I understand #
Never you mind, honey.
Never you mind.
# ...the cleanest ulcers in the land #
# Then let us all sing right out of grandma's...
of grandma's lye soap #
## [Audience Clapping In Rhythm]
# Sing right out, all over the place #
# The pots and... the pots and pans #
# Oh... Oh, dirty dishes #
# And the hands ##
[Wind Blowing]
[Leaves Rustling]
## [Band: Country]
[Man] # Well, why don't you love me
like you used to do #
# How come you treat me
like a worn-out shoe #
# My hair's still curly
and my eyes are still blue #
# Why don't you love me
like you used to do #
# Ain't had no lovin'
like a-huggin' and a-kissin' #
# In a long, long while #
# We don't get nearer or further
or closer than a country mile #
# Why don't you spark me
like you used to do #
# And say sweet nothings
like you used to coo #
# I'm the same old trouble
that you've always been through #
# So why don't you love me
like you used to do #
## [Continues, Instrumental]
# Well, why don't you be
just like you used to be #
# How come you find so
many faults with me #
# Somebody's changed, so
let me give you a clue #
# Why don't you love me
like you used to do #
# Ain't had no lovin'
like a-huggin' and a-kissin' #
# In a long, long while #
# We don't get nearer or further
or closer than a country mile #
# Why don't you say
the things you used to say#
# What makes you treat me
like a piece of clay #
# My hair's still curly
and my eyes are still blue #
# Why don't you love me
like you used to do ##