oh !
( laughing )
- ya-ha !
- ( laughing )
That's marvelous. Tomorrow you give me
lessons, and I give you your money back.
oh, I feel so good.
( Soft )
listen. listen to what
they're playing.
Yeah. ''Roslein. ''
De, da, dum
''Lief er schnell
es nah zu sehen ''
''Sah mit viele''
- ooh !
- Go on. I'm sorry. Go on. Please.
'' Oh, Roslein
Roslein rot ''
''Roslein auf ''
''Der heiden''
you know, as a rule, Americans
speak German with a very bad accent.
But your accent is
really horrible.
oh, Christian.
- This has been so wonderful.
- yes.
I wanna thank you.
you've been more than
generous with your time.
Well, that's only because
I've had the very worst of intentions.
( laughing )
Thank you.
oh, I hate to leave.
I hate to say good-bye now.
Why-- Why don't you
say good-bye in the morning ?
No. No, I can't.
I've got to leave too early.
Now, look,
it is New y ear's eve.
you go back to America,
I never see you again.
- And please, I want you
to spend the evening with me.
- No.
Too bad.
Do I have a rival ?
- Michael.
- Who ?
Michael.
But I think Michael
would not mind if I just...
stole one tiny
little Bavarian evening.
Are you kidding ?
I don't think it would even occur
to Michael that anybody would ask me.
- All right. All right,
Christian, I'd love to.
- Wonderful.
(''The Blue Danube'')
- oh, you look lovely.
- Thank you.
- you look really-- I want
to present my sister Freda.
- Charmed.
I'm so happy
that you came tonight...
because I composed a little
piece of music for you.
And, uh, it's-- Well,
would you like to hear it ?
- I'd love to.
- Really ?
( Trumpeting )
- Do you like it ?
- yes.
- Isn't it nice ? Come on.
- It's wonderful.
( Cuckooing )
- Prosit NeuJahr!
- ( All Cheering )
Happy New y ear, Margaret.
Prosit NeuJahr,
Christian.
Ich bringe einen toast.
Bitte.
Gott beschutze unsern
Fuhrer Adolph Hitler.
- Heil!
- ( All ) Heil!
( Applause )
''Die Horst Wessel Lied. ''
(''Die Horst Wessel Lied'')
( All )
'Die fahne hoch '
'Die Reihen
dicht geschlossen'
'S.A. Marschiert'
'Mit ruhig festem schritt'
'Kamaraden, die rot-front
und reaktion erschossen'
Are you all right ?
What's the matter ?
oh, you know,
I was just in Berlin, and I--
I saw some
Nazi demonstrations.
But I didn't realize
it had gone this far.
Not-not here...
in this little town.
It's a little frightening.
Well, do you think that being
a Nazi is such a terrible thing ?
Christian--
Christian, are you a Nazi ?
No, I am not a Nazi.
I'm not political at all.
But I think that they stand
for something hopeful in Germany.
Christian, you don't
really believe that.
yes, I believe this.
But why ? Why ?
What can you possibly find
to justify Hitler ?
I think that--
that Hitler will bring us
a better life.
Is the life you have now
so terrible ?
No, but, uh--
My life is not so terrible,
but I don't wish to spend the rest
of it wearing fancy sweaters...
and teaching fat little
children how to ski...
and being charming
and picturesque.
I can understand
your wanting more than that.
I think, perhaps, you cannot
understand what it means...
to live on tips from foreigners
in your own country.
you know what I really am ?
I'm not a ski instructor even.
I do this for two
or three months in the year.
When the season is over,
I go to work in a little shop...
as an assistant to my father,
and I'm a shoemaker.
- And you don't want
to be a shoemaker ?
- No, I don't.
- I want to be something else.
- Then you don't have to remain one.
oh, this is
not the united States.
It's so hard
to explain to you.
But you see,
it's very difficult...
for people to rise above
their class in Europe.
I tell you something.
At one time, I wanted
very much to be a doctor.
And I worked
very hard for this.
And when there was no longer any money,
I was forced to give it up...
because we have
no free university here.
And I think this is--
this is where Hitler can help us.
I think that he-- he has promised
to change all this.
Christian, Hitler promises
to conquer the whole world.
Ja. But this is
a direct result...
of a handful of completely
insane fanatics--
- oh.
- yeah.
It was, and this will pass.
It will not pass !
It's going to get worse
and worse and worse.
And I think it's
going to end in war.
I think that we should
not discuss this...
because I don't know
all the answers.
I know you don't know
And with political discussions
we go round and round,
and nothing is ever settled.
let's go back in
and have a nice time.
- Come on.
-;';'(''Deutschland Uber Alles'')
No.
Good night, Christian.
I'll say good-bye
in the morning.
( Male Announcer )
This is the B.B.C., London.
Today,June 2 4, 1 940,
at 7.'1 5 p.m.,
France surrendered to Germany.
The events of the past 45 days,
beginning with the German invasion...
of the low countries on May 1 0,
have thus come to a tragic climax.
England, now fighting
virtually alone,
faces the German military power
whose aim to conquer...
or destroy the entire
civilized world...
can no longer be questioned.
In the words of
Mr. Winston Churchill,
''What General Vegar has called
the Battle of France is over.
The Battle of Britain
is about to begin. ''
Leutnant, I do wish you'd
order your driver to slow down.
I am reluctantly willing
to die for the fatherland,
but not in a traffic accident.
We're late, Brandt.
Go a little faster, Basserman.
But we almost hit a cow
back there.
The only living thing
we have seen all afternoon.
Where is everybody?
( Brandt )
Making love, drinking absinthe.
- you know the French.
Don't you read our papers ?
- Where are they ?
When I was a little boy, I promised
my father I'd kill a Frenchman for him.
They shot off his leg
in Verdun,ja, in 1 91 6.
So I promised him--
on Christmas eve it was--
I promised I'd shoot
a Frenchman for him.
Have you ever
been to Paris ?
No, I have not been there.
oh, what a city.
What a wonderful city that is.
I'll show you
a good time there.
you won't keep those people
indoors forever, not those Parisians.
Ah, what wonderful girls.
When I was a correspondent
there last year, we practically
lived in the streets.
Simone and I-- We will show
you Paris the way it always was,
the way it always will be.
( Gunfire )
( Gunshots Continue )
Basserman, go up to the wall
and keep firing on them...
in case they try to come
to the front, ja.
-Ja.
-( Gunfire Continues )
Go !
( Speaking French )
Come on.
Maeschen, stay behind
this tree here.
- I go over behind the tree
over there.
-Jawohl.
I got him.
( Christian )
Maeschen, stay down!
( Gunshot )
( Speaking French )
Streicher, hold your fire.
- Streicher.
-( Gunfire Continues )
Brandt.
Streicher, come on.
Tell him to go back and
tell the others to surrender...
because we now have them
in a cross fire.
Go. Allez.
Ecoutez moi.
- Maeschen is dead ?
- What ? What ?
Maeschen is dead ?
yeah.
I'm sure his father
is very happy now, eh ?
Allez! Allez!
Vite!
( Speaking French )
Arretez!
Nous sommes fini!
- Captain Hardenburg.
- Ah, Diestl. Nice to see you.
- I understand you have had
a little difficulty on the road.
- yes, sir.
- At ease.
- Thank you, sir.
There were young conscripts,
sir, making a token gesture.
There was a roadblock,
and it was quite unavoidable.
There is no need to be apologetic.
It makes for excellent training.
- I want to commend you
for the way you have handled it.
- Thank you, sir.
We had one casualty, you know, sir.
Private Maeschen was killed.
oh, yes.
uh, Private Maeschen.
Did he perform his duty ?
yes, sir. He killed one of
the enemy with his first shot...
and then became excited
and failed to take cover.
Too bad.
I'm sure he fought bravely.
That's wonderful,
isn't it ?
yes, sir.
Sir, with your permission, I would like
to write a letter to his family.
Never mind, Diestl.
I will do it. Leutnant!
Since you are attached to us,
I wonder if you would mind
taking a photograph for my wife.
We had always
planned to come here.
- It would be a pleasure, Captain.
- Come on, Diestl.
- I'm sure your wife
is not interested to see me.
- oh, yes, yes, yes.
I've written her about you and many of
the men. I'm sure she's most interested.
Just a moment.
We will stand on the steps.
Come on, Diestl.
With the church
in the background.
( Bell Tolling )
A great day.
A day of historic importance.
In years to come, we will
look back on this and say...
we were there at the dawn
of the new era.
Ay ! Ja. Now, Captain,
this is the one.
( Speaks German )
- ( Indistinct Chattering )
- All right, settle down.
Settle down !
This is New y ork City property.
Stop spitting and throwing butts
on the floor and stop shoving.
Nobody's gonna be left behind. The
army's got plenty of room for everybody.
- What's wrong ?
- It's cold.
Now cough.
Turn your head and cough.
All right, breathe in.
Breathe out.
Now breathe in.
out.
All right, bend over.
- Bend over and touch your toes.
- oh.
okay.
For a man your age in your profession,
you're in excellent health.
- How do you manage it ?
- Clean liquor.
Give this to the board.
Next man.
you didn't register
in California ?
yes, I did. But I came east before
I got my classification.
- you came to New y ork
to get a defense job ?
- To get any job.
Michael Whiteacre.
Sit down over here,
Mr. Whiteacre.
you must be very busy,
I'm told we had a special call
from Selective Service headquarters...
asking us not to waste
any of your valuable time.
Well, I'm rehearsing a show
against a deadline.
Well, we'll try
to rush you through quickly.
How long will this show run,
do you think ?
I don't know.
No one ever does.
Well, this is March.
If it runs very long
your understudy will get a break.
We're booking you
for uncle Sam as ofJune 1 5.
- I don't think that's quite fair.
- you can file an appeal, if you like.
oh, I'll appeal.
- Is there anything else
you'd like to discuss ?
- No, I'll just appeal.
Just see the secretary outside.
Ackerman.
Sit down over here,
Mr. Ackerman.
Mr. Ackerman, you don't seem to have
any dependent relatives...
or any occupation essential
to national defense.
Can you think of any reason
why you should not be classified 1 -A ?
No, sir, I can't.
I see you work for Macy's.
you'll stay for the Easter rush,
and you will reportJune 1 5.
I think that'll be all.
Thank you very much.
Just a moment.
May I have your form, please ?
Ralph Benton.
Anybody got a cigarette ?
- Need a cigarette ?
- oh, thanks.
Here.
How do you spell
''extenuating'' ?
- Hmm ?
- Extenuating.
uh, I don't know.
E-x-t-e-- No. E-x-t--
Illiteracy, that'll do it.
I heard you sing
a lot of times.
oh, you have ?
At the club ?
- on the radio.
- oh.
- Are you singing at a club ?
- No, rehearsing a show.
- on Broadway ?
- Mm-hmm.
What's the name of it ?
Soft Shoes.
I gotta remember that.
let's have a drink.
Don't frustrate me.
Anybody that can't spell
extenuating is a friend of mine.
Come on.
you know, sometimes I think
I give off a scent or something.
- you know, rouses the female.
- Hmm ?
- Those girls.
- Where ?
oh, wait a minute. you mean
to tell me that you didn't--
- oh, your antenna's turned off.
- No, I didn't notice.
oh, you're sick.
- Have you ever had a girl ?
- Have I ever had a girl ?
That's what I thought.
listen, Ackerman, tonight I'm giving
a party. Girls, females, broads.
you will attend. you will capture
one and carry her off to your cave.
- you will attend ?
- Sure. yeah.
Good. let us not discuss
this sort of topic any longer.
let us discuss alcohol.
* I like New y ork in June *
* How about you *
* I like a Gershwin tune *
* I like a fireside
when a storm is due *
* I like potato chips
moonlight and motor trips *
* How about you *
* I'm mad about good books *
* Can't get my fill *
* And James Durante's looks
give me a thrill *
-;';'( Continues )
- May I refresh your drink ?
Thank you, no.
I'm fine.
Have you met everyone ?
That's all right.
I was listening to the music.
Michael's told me
all about you.
- He has ?
- y-yes.
No, I meant, I only met him
this morning at the draft board.
- you met Michael at the draft board ?
- yes.
And he was 1 -A ?
We're both 1 -A.
- Excuse me, would you ?
- yes.
* you saw me standing alone *
- * Without a dream in my heart *
- I wanna talk to you.
- Good evening. How are you tonight ?
- Fine, thanks, and you ?
- Hi, Hope.
- Hi, Mike. How are you ?
- Fine. How are you ?
I want you to meet somebody.
- Good.
- oh ? Friend of yours ?
- yes.
Noah, this is Hope Plowman.
Noah Ackerman.
- Hello.
- How do you do ?
See if you can cheer him up.
I don't think he likes my music.
Actually, I have been listening.
oh, my, what a lovely view.
Isn't it ?
( Michael )
Yes, Margaret ?
I hear you're being drafted.
- I'm not being drafted.
- Mr. Ackerman says you are.
Mr. Ackerman doesn't know
what rabbits can be pulled out
of a hat in Washington.
look, I'm not a hero,
and I'm not a pigeon.
The pigeons can do
my fighting for me.
oh, Michael,
what's the matter with you ?
you think I hate you
for trying to get out of it ?
I don't.
Really, I don't.
Anything you do is okay with me,
but you start to feel guilty about it,
- then we start having fights,
and you take it out on me.
- I don't feel guilty !
It's just that I'm against war
and this whole drummed-up,
superpatriotic atmosphere.
you just don't want to get shot.
Nobody wants to get shot.
So stop trying
to convince yourself.
Forget it.
- I got a sick show on my hands !
- yes, yes, yes, yes.
look, Michael,
this is me, Margaret.
I understand you.
you're a heel, but you're
not that big a heel.
And then, too,
they fish for fish
in the river.
I was told that.
- I like your tie.
- you do ?
I just saw it,
and I bought it.
Do you think
it's gonna rain ?
- I like to walk in the rain.
- I do to.
- you do ?
- Mm-hmm.
- you wanna walk ?
- All right.
- let's walk.
- okay.
- What are you gonna tell him ?
- Who ?
- Michael.
- Nothing.
oh.
Well, maybe so.
New y ork City must be quite frightening
to a girl from the country.
oh, no, it isn't.
The truth is it puts on
an act of sophistication,
but at heart
it's strictly provincial.
I don't think
it's provincial.
Anyway, not after Vermont.
- Vermont ?
- Mm-hmm.
New y ork City-- I must say--
does have some beautiful women.
Flashy, some of them.
you know,
I'm told European women...
are more mature emotionally.
- They are ?
- oh.
As a matter of fact,
friends of mine have told me--
- Well, anyway.
- What time is it ?
- It's late. We better be getting back.
- No. I'd like to go home.
- oh. Well, I'll take you home.
- Thank you.
- Where do you live ?
- Brooklyn.
- Mm-hmm.
Well, at last.
- Now we take the bus.
- Now we take the bus ?
- Now what ?
- Now we walk.
- Margaret.
- yeah ?
- Don't.
- Don't what ?
- Don't be angry with me.
- Why not ?
you have been very charming.
you have not been understanding.
In fact, you haven't even been
conversational all evening long.
I'm sorry, Margaret.
Really, I am.
But lately it seems
we can't talk without arguing.
you haven't the faintest idea
what's bothering me.
Honey, I'd flip without you.
- you sure would.
- Well, that's the truth.
you're so right about me.
I sure am.
- look, why don't we just sit
and be quiet ?
- And then what ?
Then you kiss me.
Then I kiss you.
oh, Michael,
I love you so.
Are we getting warmer ?
you'll be happy to know
that we're here.
Good night.
I wanna say I'm pleased--
very pleased, I mean,
to have brought you home.
Thank you.
I mean,
I'm really pleased.
you do that with
your other girls, not with me.
yes. No !
No, I don't.
oh, only with me ?
you don't understand
what I mean.
I suppose you think that you're
such an attractive young man...
that any girl would fall all over
herself to let you kiss her.
- oh, God.
- Never, in all my days,
have I met such an opinionated,
self-centered young man.
- Good night, Mr. Ackerman.
- No, don't. I--
- Hope.
-( Door Closes )
( Tapping )
Stop that.
you'll wake everyone.
How do I get back
to the city ?
you're lost ?
No one will find me
again, ever.
you're a terrible fool,
aren't you ?
Well, you walk two blocks
to your left,
and you wait for the bus--
the one that comes from your left--
and you take it
to Eastern Parkway.
Noah, are you listening to me ?
I wanna say
something to you.
I am not opinionated.
I don't think I have a single opinion
in the whole world.
I don't know why I kissed you.
I just couldn't help it.
I guess-- I guess
I wanted to impress you.
I was afraid
that if I was myself...
you wouldn't
look at me twice.
It's been a very confusing night.
I don't think I've ever been through
anything so confusing.
you tell me tomorrow.
The bus to Eastern Parkway.
Don't get lost
on the way home.
uh, the bus
to Eastern Parkway,
and then--
I love you.
Good night.
Thanks for taking me home.
- This is really boring here.
- Don't be so impatient, Christian.
Wait till you see her. A more delicious
little strudel you have never seen.
Really superb,
typically French, and very--
( Chuckles )
Well, I could use
a little strudel, Brandt,
but we have been here--
yeah, two hours.
- To be French is to be late.
- Two hours.
It's part of their charm.
I only hope they get here before
I'm too blind drunk to recognize them.
Francoise, please. of course the men are
Germans, but not all Germans are swine.
- No ?
- oh, I promise you, one drink.
-Just one drink, then we'll go.
- I don't want to be seen
fraternizing with the enemy.
- I don't want to be beaten
by my neighbors.
- Please.
I would not look good
with a shaved head.
- Francoise, please. Please !
- oh !
All right, I'll go.
But not because of your arguments,
because I'm curious.
I'd like to observe
one of these supermen.
I'm a city girl. I've never seen
a pig up close. Come on.
Here they are.
Ah, at last you are here.
If you didn't look so pretty,
I'd give you a good spank
in a very important place.
- Perhaps I'd like it.
- yes, we can talk about that later.
How nice of you to come,
Francoise.
May I present Herr Leutnant Diestl.
This is Francoise.
Enchante de faire
votre connaissance.
- I'm sorry, but that's
all the French I know.
- oh, that's all right.
you are all the German I know,
and perhaps, all I care to know.
( Nervous Chuckle )
And this is my little Simone.
It's a pleasure, Leutnant.
I'm sorry that we're a little late.
you see, didn't I tell you
they were worth waiting for ?
Would you care to sit ?
oh, really gallant you are.
Are you always as dashing
as that with the ladies ?
yes, always,
if they are ladies.
I must warn you not to be
deceived by this Aryan charm.
- He is the most famous
lady-killer in the Alps.
- oh, la, la.
Tell me, lieutenant. How many
French ladies have you killed ?
Well, I think that I'm not
clever enough to do that.
But perhaps if I serve in France
for a little while,
I could learn how
with your very kind help.
But I'm confused. I thought you
came here to teach us something--
how to be tall and blond
and clean and efficient.
Perhaps if you were not French
and I was not German,
but we were just simply Europeans,
we could learn from each other.
Don't you think ?
united Europe, of course.
How stupid of me.
you Germans have charmed me so that
I forgot that you were all idealists.
oh, now, look, doesn't somebody
know a good, dirty joke ?
Ferien, Francoise,
tu nous auras gache un soirre.
( French Continues,
Indistinct )
How many of us do you plan to murder in
the name of that golden plan of yours ?
If there is no unification, we will all
go on murdering each other anyhow.
I know a nice little restaurant in
Montmartre. It has a beautiful garden.
We can have it all to ourselves.
Shall we go ?
yeah. We can answer
all historical questions there.
- And we don't even
need to get arrested.
- No, wait.
I would like to know...
how many French lives
you have personally contributed
to that Wagnerian dream.
- Now, look, this is no longer funny.
- let go of me !
I want an answer
from the boche.
Francoise !
How many Frenchmen
have you killed ?
I've killed no one.
No one.
But if I have to sacrifice
a few lives for peace,
I will do it.
Ja. Even if
one of them is my own.
Now I have seen
a pig up close.
Thank you for your wine.
Oh, folle.
- Laissez mois tranquille.
- Tu te rends compte de ce
que tu viene de faire.
( Speaking French )
Christian.
- Good night, Simone. Thank you.
- I am so sorry.
- oh.
- Really, I am.
Good night, Francoise.
lieutenant.
- I'm sorry. I should not
have made such a scene.
- No. No.
Please.
My husband was killed...
in 1 940 in Belgium.
And all this talk about sacrificing
lives in order to have peace...
just doesn't
make any sense to me.
The only way to peace is to stop
killing each other.
I think about this
1 ,000 times in a day.
And I wish it would seem
so simple to me.
Could I have
another glass of wine ?
yes, of course.
This is my house.
This is where I live.
I think that I will not...
try to tell you how lovely...
this evening was for me.
But I would like so much
to see you again.
you're still the conqueror,
a young, golden god of war.
Perhaps...
when the gold has worn off
a little.
Good night.
( Bell Tolling )
Well, that's one of the hazards you run
when you have a daughter.
one day she's going to come
to you and say, ''I love him.
I want to marry him.''
Mm-hmm. That's one
of the hazards.
But you haven't told me anything
about this man at all.
oh, he's-- he's gentle
and he's clever.
He's not just a man,
he's a boy.
And poor.
He writes me a letter a day,
even when we see each other
in New y ork every night.
And he's alone.
He's Jewish, Father.
Father, this is Noah.
- How do you do ?
- How do you do, sir ?
Well, seems to me Mr. Ackerman
and I might have a little talk.
Certainly, sir.
Why don't you finish
your coffee, Hope ?
We won't be very long.
That's Jack Marshall's.
I went to school with his father,
my father with his father.
Virgil Smith's law office.
one of his people did the legal work
when they incorporated this town.
1 7 50.
Well, looks like
it's gonna be a nice day.
;';'( Choir, Indistinct )
It's the family plot.
Seven generations of Plowmans there,
Hope's mother too.
There's the school.
Mr. Plowman, um,
I don't have a family plot.
I don't have a family.
I earn $3 5 a week,
and I'm 1 -A in the draft.
But I love Hope, and I shall
love her for all my life.
you're doing an awful thing,
putting a man to the test
of his principles.
I wish to heaven you'd
turn around and get on that bus
and never see Hope again.
But you won't do that,
will ya ?
Didn't think you would.
Anybody from town asked
to marry Hope, I'd say,
''Come on out to the house.
We got turkey for dinner.''
I never knew a Jew before.
you go along all your life
thinkin' a certain way,
someone jolts you, you have
to look inside yourself.
That's what you've made me do,
and I'm not fond of you for it.
I was just telling Mr. Ackerman
we've got turkey for dinner.
Thank you.
-( Knocking )
-( Doorknob Rattling )
If you don't open the door,
we are obliged to break it in.
Is this headquarter's idea of a friendly
little visit for me to photograph ?
Ja.
Well, we can't wait
any longer.
Kraus, Faber.
- Madame Brenner ?
- yes, that's me.
Where is Marcel Brenner ?
oh, monsieur,
I wish I knew.
The boy's 1 6 years old.
Half of the time we don't know
where he is. He don't come home at all.
Kraus, here. Faber.
Marcel !
( Screaming, Indistinct )
Stop ! Stop !
Take the boy downstairs.
- ( Screaming Continues )
- He'll be all right.
- ( Speaking French )
- He will not be hurt.
- oh, monsieur.
- I promise you. I give you
my word. He will not be hurt.
He simply must perform
his labor duties.
I am sorry.
( Knocking )
Come in.
I would like to apply
for a transfer, sir.
Why ?
I think I am not able
to do this work.
you don't believe
you are suited to this work ?
I don't believe
in arresting children, sir.
I spent four years
at Spandau,
two years at the war academy.
I should be in Russia,
but I am here.
And I will stay here
until I am ordered elsewhere.
And so will you.
What time does your train
leave for Berlin ?
Ja. uh, 1 2:30, sir.
Here are your furlough papers.
I wish you to do me a favor
while you are in Berlin.
( Man Screaming )
- What was that ?
- oh, I don't know. It is the Gestapo.
( Man Screams )
oberleutnant !
leutnant !
Close the door!
Do you know where you are ?
Do you know who you are ?
Answer me !
yes, sir.
Then stop being a child !
Don't you know that when you
became a soldier, you contracted
for killing in all its forms ?
I do not think it possible
to remake this world...
from the basement of
a dirty little police station.
It doesn't matter
what you believe.
under battle conditions, I could
shoot you for what you have just done.
And I would.
The German Army is invincible
because it is an army...
that obeys orders,
any order,
no matter how distasteful.
- I cannot believe--
- Be quiet.
It has no sentimentalists,
no moralists,
no individualists.
you will have no future in it
if you don't understand that.
you may have no future at all
if you oppose it.
I trouble to tell you this
because you have a fine record.
you will be
a creative soldier...
once you get all this
thinking knocked out of you.
Well, we will forget it
for the present.
Now, as I was saying,
I would like you to do me a favor.
I have secured
a piece of lace.
Very beautiful. Black.
For my wife.
I'd hoped to give it
to her in person,
but I'm too important here.
And since I can't, I would like you
to deliver it to her in Berlin.
yes, sir.
Give her my most tender regards.
you may say that
I think of her constantly.
The address is on the package.
Enjoy your leave !
-( Doorbell Buzzing )
-( Woman ) Coming.
-( Buzzing Continues )
- Coming.
uh, Mrs. Hardenburg, please.
- yes ?
- I am lieutenant Diestl
from your husband's company,
and this is a gift
from Captain Hardenburg.
Well, come in.
oh, yes, of course.
you're the serious one...
in the photograph
with the captain.
- oh, yes, in front of the church ?
- yes.
yes.
- How do you do ?
- It's a pleasure.
He wrote me
you were coming to Berlin.
If there was anything
I could do for you and so forth.
Well, that's very kind
of the captain.
Please, sit down.
Thank you.
Make yourself comfortable.
What would you like
to drink ?
Perhaps I am intruding here.
you were just going out, no ?
only with a general. I'll tell him
I kept him waiting for a lieutenant.
Well, in that case, I--
- Vodka ?
- Yes, wonderful.
I have some direct
from the ukraine.
And how is the captain ?
uh, he's fine. He asked me
to give you his tenderest regards,
and to tell you that
he thinks of you constantly.
That's very thoughtful of him.
Thank you.
And, uh, how is gay Paris ?
Well, gay Paris is not so gay.
oh, that's too bad.
-( Doorbell Buzzing )
- Where are you staying ?
As a matter of fact,
I have no accommodations. I was--
you'll find it impossible
to get a hotel room.
- Maybe I can do something
for you at the Adelon Hotel.
- oh, that would be wonderful.
- Thank you.
- Excuse me.
of course.
All right, Franz.
Tell him I'll be right down.
Are you in a hurry
to get someplace ?
uh, no.
Then stay.
I won't be too long.
And I want to talk to you
about the captain.
Will you ?
yes.
Wonderful.
Have another drink, lieutenant.
Take some caviar.
See how the home front suffers.
-Au revoir.
- Au revoir.
- I'm sorry.
- No, no. Don't disturb yourself
I hope you were not
too bored.
No. I wasn't
bored at all.
As a matter of fact,
I found a wonderful companion.
Aren't you going
to offer me a drink ?
oh, sure.
I offer you a drink.
oh, that's too much.
Enough.
It couldn't have been a very interesting
evening for a soldier on leave.
Well, I am, uh--
I'm not a soldier.
I'm a...
policeman.
And you don't
find this interesting ?
uh-uh.
Well, cheer up.
Things may be different.
I have a friend
on Rommel's staff.
Maybe he can be helpful.
Wait.
you-- you can do this ?
you can arrange
military transfers ?
With a small effort.
** ( Ends )
** ( Soft )
How are the girls in Paris ?
oh, French.
Very patriotic.
Welcome to Germany,
soldier.
Get me a cigarette, please.
- Hmm ?
- Oh the table.
- Good morning.
- Morning.
- I hear your show's going just great.
- It's a lulu.
- Brandy and soda.
-Si, signore.
Can you spare it ?
- What's the matter ?
- Nothing.
oh, come on, Michael. you can usually
fake an affectionate kiss at lunchtime.
Something fell through in Washington,
and I have to take basic training.
oh. Tsk, tsk, tsk.
I wasn't supposed to leave
until tomorrow, but I can go now.
- I'm sorry.
- Now that's better.
- Why don't you take the afternoon off?
- oh, I can't, Michael.
The office of War Information
can spare you on my last afternoon.
- We'll see each other tonight.
- Tell 'em you're involved
in a troop movement.
No, Michael.
I can't.
on the house.
This is the last of the cognac.
I bet they still have
plenty in Italy.
I came here in 1 92 4, sir.
I don't know anything
about Italy anymore.
- That was pretty unnecessary.
- Not the way I feel.
Margaret, what do
you want from me ?
I want you
to act like a man.
I want to be proud of you,
the way Hope is proud of Noah.
you want me to get shot.
look, I've read all the books.
I know that in ten years we'll be bosom
friends with the Germans and Japanese.
Then I'll be pretty annoyed
that I was killed.
look, Michael, I don't
want you to get shot !
I don't-- I don't even mind
your wanting to get out of the army.
I just want you to stop pretending
that you think it's all right.
- Is that all ?
- No.
I want us to go someplace
and get married.
- Now ?
- Mm-hmm.
look, honey, I love you,
but today ?
Now you've been seeing
too many war pictures.
- you mean no ?
- I could be in for years.
- last chance, Michael.
- oh, honey, that'd be foolish.
oh, I almost forgot.
The office is
sending me overseas.
I was gonna
tell you that tonight.
- oh, hello, Mrs. Ackerman,
Mr. Ackerman.
- Hello.
-Rather early this morning, aren't you ?
-yes, we are.
- Well, today's the day, eh ?
- yes, it is.
Here. Give you courage.
Calm the nerves.
Go ahead. Drink it.
It's full of cream.
Homogenized.
- Good, isn't it ?
- yes, it is.
I drink two quarts
a day myself. Keeps me young.
Well, I've got to be
on my way. Good luck.
Thank you.
oh, you taste good.
I love you.
- ( Whispering ) Are you ready ?
-Jawohl.
Kraus.
yeah.
They're all ready, sir.
All right, Leutnant.
- Now.
- May I suggest we wait, sir ?
Wait ? Why ?
over your shoulder, sir.
The sun will be up in a few moments.
And when the sun is up
and in their eyes,
their guns will be
completely useless.
A wonderful idea.
We will wait.
Morter.
Machine guns.
Fire. Quick !
- left ten !
- ( Gunfire )
( Explosions )
( Gunfire Continues )
Back ten !
Kraus, left !
All right.
Cease fire !
Kraus !
( Gunfire Stops )
I gave no order
to stop firing.
What are you doing,
oberleutnant ?
The machine guns will continue
to rake the area for 60 seconds.
- Fire!
-( Gunfire )
( Gunfire Continues )
Shoot all wounded.
leave no one alive here.
We cannot take prisoners.
our movements must
not be reported.
These wounded can
give information,
and their planes would be
on us before we got back.
Then all our reconnaissance,
useless.
Proceed.
( Firing )
( Gunfire Continues )
Shoot him.
Shoot him !
That's an order.
;';'(''Reveille'')
( Indistinct Chattering )
okay, fellas !
Attention !
At ease.
Prepare for inspection.
- Eighth general order.
- To give the alarm
in case of fire or disorder.
Wipe that smile
off your face, Whiteacre.
you're not
a Broadway big shot now.
you're a soldier in
the army of the united States.
Rip this man's bed.
This isn't the Astor Hotel,
Whiteacre.
The maid doesn't
come in here.
Two extra days fatigue duty.
let's see the inside
of that footlocker, soldier.
This isn't the New y ork
Public library, soldier.
I know this book.
It's a filthy, dirty book.
The army doesn't care
what you read, but I do.
Get rid of it.
Eyes front.
All right, soldier.
This window hasn't
been cleaned at all.
The whole barracks
is unmilitary.
Sergeant, these quarters aren't ready
for inspection. Get them ready.
yes, sir.
you men are going to learn if there's
one sloppy soldier in the outfit,
it's up to all of you
to teach him to be clean.
This platoon is restricted
to the post for the weekend.
- Sir, don't you think
punishing the entire platoon--
- No, lieutenant.
- I do not.
- yes, sir.
Rest.
( Indistinct Chattering )
All right, Ackerman,
you've finally
gone and done it.
Now I'm gonna have to take you
under my personal wing.
This ain't no crummy tenement
in the Bronx.
- Now wait a minute, Sergeant.
- Keep your mouth shut.
When I want you to talk,
I'll ask you a direct question.
you'll answer yes or no.
That's an order.
Now, lesson
number one begins.
Ackerman,
get yourself a bucket.
And you know what ?
you're gonna wash every window
in this barracks.
you're gonna wash 'em
until they're clean,
white-glove clean.
That's an order.
Now move.
- ( Chattering )
- uh, uh. Ace gets the devil.
There we go.
I'm workin' on sevens.
Jack. uh, oh !
And a queen. Check the pot.
Take care of it.
Give me a jack.
Not even a pair on the table.
( Man #1 )
Here comes mama's helper.
- Hi.
( Michael )
Did you have a ball?
- Hey, uh, Cowley.
- yeah ?
you know everything.
Who's our ambassador
to New y ork ?
We don't have one.
We don't recognize it.
oh,just relax.
They'll get bored.
- ( Man ) Isn't New y ork part
of the united States yet ?
- Nope.
- What language do they speak ?
- language ?
They talk with their hands.
- ( Man #2 ) Well, how come
Ackerman speaks English ?
- He's a spy.
( Man #3 ) Hey, wait a minute.
you guys ain't bein' fair.
- I feel sorry for him. Really, I do.
- ( All ) oh, sure !
look at the dough he could
be makin' sellin' black-market
tires and gasoline...
if he weren't in the service.
- oh, forget it.
- you're right.
Hey, uh, Ackerman !
How come you're
in the service anyway ?
( Man ) He had no influence with
the draft board. They were all Irish.
( All laughing )
( Man #2 ) Here. Cut.
All right. What are you bettin'?
What'd you hear from Hope ?
Hope ? She's fine
the last I--
What's the matter ?
oh, now I've done it.
I've done it.
Her birthday.
I got $20 stashed,
and I can't even get to a store.
Maybe you can get something
at the P.X.
Come on.
I'll go with you.
That's a good idea.
My bank.
( Coughs )
Whose play is it ?
-( Chattering )
- No.
I'll lend you the 20.
let's go.
you got a pen ?
Noah, forget it.
- If I were you--
- you're not.
( Indistinct Chattering )
Hey, aren't you
gonna eat ?
Read this.
Would you act as my second ?
- What second ?
- I want everything to be
absolutely correct.
And I-- I don't trust myself to
arrange it. I might lose my temper.
Are you out of your head ? These are
the four biggest guys in the company.
So ?
What do you weigh ?
Never mind what I weigh.
A hundred and thirty-five.
look, they're only needling you because
you had them confined to the post.
Will you arrange
the schedule ?
okay. you don't want
to help, don't help.
What schedule ?
you want me to fight
all four guys in one night ?
you're crazy.
I don't want to have anything
to do with this. Now take it.
Take it !
okay, Donnelly,
so you're a big man.
- Nice punch, Donnelly.
- Come on. I'll buy you a beer.
What do ya know ? The little punk
gave me a bloody nose.
- ( All laughing )
- Come on.
Well, you asked for it.
Teach him a little bit about boxing.
Nope. look out. look out.
Come on, Burnecker.
Finish 'im.
oh, oh, look.
- lay it into him, Burnie.
- okay, Burnie. Knock him on his back.
-Ah, don't kill 'im. oh, not yet anyway.
-Give him a one, two.
Fix it so he won't want to
fight anymore. Come on, Burnie !
Come on. Hold 'im up.
He's goin' down. Ah, look out now.
( Man #1 ) That'll teach you
to keep those windows clean.
( Man #2 )
Give him that one, two, Burnecker.
look, kid. look.
Fall down, kid. Fall down.
Come on. Finish 'im.
( Breathing Heavily )
yes, Whiteacre ?
I'm sure you're not aware of it,
Captain, but Private Ackerman
has been badly beaten...
in fights with the biggest men
in the company.
yes ?
He's been seriously hurt,
and I'm sure now that you know,
you'll want to stop it.
you're quite right,
Whiteacre.
If I knew, I would stop it.
I'd be obliged to stop it.
But then, I don't know.
you know now, sir.
What's the matter with you ?
Ackerman isn't one of
those rich Broadway producers
you have to suck around.
He's just a dogface.
Get some sense.
I think you'll have
to stop it, sir.
you know, the colonel had
a phone call about you out
of channels from Washington--
very much out of channels--
to transfer you
to special service in london.
It's up to me to approve it
or disapprove it.
I still think you'll have to
stop it, sir. I know the colonel would.
All right, Whiteacre.
I'll spell it out for you.
you go to the colonel
and you won't get your transfer.
you'll have to be fives times
more soldier than any man in
this outfit just to stay alive.
Now get out.
Rickett.
Get rid of'im... today.
- Send his papers through.
- yes, sir.
( Michael )
Well, I hope you're satisfied.
- This makes three beatings in a row.
- I almost had him though.
- How'd he look ? yeah.
- Who ? Cowley ?
Better than you do.
- What are you trying to prove ?
- Nothin'.
- Well, why are you tryin'
to kill yourself?
- I like to fight.
Well, I'm tired of watching
you get your brains beat out.
look, if you fight Brailsford,
you're on your own.
- ( Gasps )
- Sorry.
That's okay.
That's all right.
Michael,
I can lick Brailsford.
Well, I don't care.
It's important to me.
It's the last fight.
- you're crazy. This whole thing
has got you crazy.
- Maybe.
- oh, excuse me, men ?
- yes, lieutenant ?
- I'd like to speak with Ackerman.
- Certainly, sir.
you'll be around ?
Mm-hmm.
Cigarette ?
Thanks.
oh. Sorry.
Ackerman, I've been
watching the sick book.
In my opinion, you're the most
accident-prone soldier in the
entire united States Infantry.
I'm careless, sir.
Saturday nights in town
you're careless.
Every Saturday night.
on weekdays, you run the roughest
obstacle course on the post...
without stubbing your toe.
Now why don't
you level with me ?
I know you're fighting.
I think I know why.
This is something
for the colonel to handle.
Just give me the word.
Besides, you're getting licked.
you're no good to us punch-drunk.
( Exhales )
I appreciate it, lieutenant. Thank you.
But this is my business.
- Whiteacre ?
- yeah ?
I've been looking all over the post
for you. your orders just came through.
you've got 40 minutes
to make the train to Washington.
Thanks.
He's all yours, medic.
Don't fall ! Don't fall !
Don't fall !
Come on.
Now leave it alone.
you'll get dirt in it.
Ready ! Hut !
Attention roll call !
- Abbott ?
-( Abbott ) Here!
- Acaro ?
-( Acaro ) Here!
Ackerman ?
Ackerman!
Any of you men
seen Ackerman ?
Abbott, did Ackerman sleep
in his bunk last night ?
I don't know, sir.
I didn't notice.
Donnelly, did he ?
Eyes front, you.
Well, Donnelly ?
I don't know, sir. He's at
the opposite end of the barracks.
I warn you, men.
I want a straight answer
from the next solider. Cowley !
No, sir.
He didn't.
Nobody deserts this company !
When they find 'im,
I don't want him in a stockade.
I want him right back here.
- He's mine.
- yes, sir.
Gentlemen,
your attention please !
The briefing will begin.
Gentlemen.
I will come directly
and frankly to the point.
you have heard rumors that
our position is deteriorating.
It is.
An American invasion fleet
of tremendous strength...
is believed to be approaching Tunisia
to attack us from the rear.
The British are about to launch
a massive frontal offensive.
The resistance at Stalingrad...
has bled off fuel and ammunition
in unexpected quantities.
We must, therefore,
prepare for a breakthrough.
( Airplane Engine Droning )
For the present, this
information is for you only.
( Man )
Air attack!
Dismissed.
( Gunfire )
( Explosions )
;';'( Bagpipes )
( Gunfire )
- Damn you ! Keep awake !
- I am awake.
Well, you stay that way !
Talk to me !
See that you don't
fall asleep !
- What do you want me to say ?
- Anything. Anything.Just talk.
All right.
How far-- How far do
we have to go now ?
About 400 kilometers more.
Seven hours !
I think I must sleep.
If you sleep, you'll wake up
in a British prison camp.
Come on ! Talk !
I wish I was
in the mountains...
where it's so cool
and peaceful in the snow,
so wonderful to feel
the wind in your face,
clean and nice.
And I like the smell
of smoke in the winter...
coming from the wood...
in the fireplaces.
Talk about something else !
Talk about women !
Women ! Women !
I have a French girl, Francoise,
and I think I can love her.
- Was she beautiful ?
- yes, she was beautiful.
And I wish I was with her...
and not on this motorcycle...
because I am--
I am sick of Africa !
And I am sick of
the great German army.
doing my duty.
I should have shot you.
- What ?
- I said I should have shot you !
I ought to shoot you now !
you'd better learn
to drive this first.
you will destroy us !
Men like you
poison an army !
you let discipline slip
a little one day...
and a little more the next day
and soon you're nothing !
you are not able to fight at all !
I should have shot you !
- Why didn't you shoot me then ?
- Because I was an idiot !
yes ! you recognize it ! Ja.
you are still infected with
a little decent human feelings !
- oh, shut up ! Shut up !
- And you hate that in yourself,
don't you ?
- Shut up !
- you hate it in yourself--
( No Audio )
( Whispers )
What ?
Hello.
I want to kiss you.
Why didn't you tell me ?
I couldn't.
Besides, there is a law against
harboring deserters.
you're not a deserter.
The army knows you told me
you gave yourself up.
you all right ?
yes.
Noah,
you know what
they're asking me to do ?
Sure. Sure.
The lawyer says if you go back
to your own company,
you won't go to prison.
Mm-hmm.
I'm not trying to tell you what to do.
you do what you have to.
Hope, stand up.
Stand up.
Honey, how long is it ?
- What ?
- How long is it ?
- Five months.
- Five months !
Why didn't you tell me ?
I could've written you,
I guess.
I had to work
this out myself.
The doctor said I should stay
in bed for a while.
I did.
I guess that's why
I didn't write to you.
I wanted to make sure
it would be all right.
I don't want this to influence you
one way or the other.
Are you glad ?
It's wonderful.
Absolutely... wonderful.
Time's up.
Don't worry about me.
I'm going back home.
Don't worry at all.
I'm not worried.
Can you imagine ?
listen.
Go to the lawyer,
and tell him I'll go
anyplace they want to send me.
- All right, soldier.
- 'Kay ?
( Whispering )
I love you.
Not only are you a disgrace
to the army, Ackerman,
but your actions have caused a black
mark to be made against this company...
and against me personally.
I'm gonna see that
you erase that black mark.
I'm gonna make a soldier out of you
if I have to break you in half to do it.
yes, sir.
you'll get no passes.
you'll be on K.P.
every day for the next week.
Also you'll have the same cot
and the same men around you.
You're going to have to make
mighty sure any punishments
handed out to them...
-aren't caused by you.
- yes, sir.
Now get out of here. I don't want
to see you in this orderly room again.
yes, sir.
Thank you, sir.
( Door Closes )
- ( Man on Intercom ) Captain ?
- yes ?
This is Major Price. The colonel
requests that you report to his office.
I'll be right there, Major.
you wish to see me, sir.
There are many kinds of officers
that we get in a war,
men like Green, Emerson...
and a few officers like you.
Fortunately,
a very few like you.
Sometimes we find you out.
Occasionally we don't.
In your case,
we've been lucky.
I've just completed
an investigation...
of the reasons
for Private Ackerman's behavior.
- Sir, I can explain. you see--
- I hope you can.
I'll read you the charges
that'll be brought against you...
at your court-martial.
''That said officer willfully persecuted
Private Noah Ackerman...
''by ordering mass punishment
of his entire company
as a means of disciplining him,
''by willfully and knowingly
permitting savage beatings...
''to be inflicted upon him
by members of his company,
by attempting to blackmail
Private Michael Whiteacre
who interceded in his behalf.''
you want me to go on ?
I thought not.
I've proffered these charges
against you, and...
I officially serve you
with them now.
( Man ) Ah,just put your money in.
Never mind the--
How much ? Five bucks.
Hey ! Hey, you guys.
I think I just seen a ghost.
( Burnecker )
I don't see anything.
-( Cowley ) I think it's Ackerman.
-( Abbott ) You're crazy.
Ackerman's in New York
living it up.
( Cowley ) If it isn't Ackerman,
it's somebody who looks like Ackerman.
- ( Donnelly )
Nobody looks like Ackerman.
- ( Burnecker laughs )
( Donnelly ) All right. Don't just
sit there. Make room for one more.
I've just found a pigeon
with 20 bucks.
-( Man #1 )
Okay. Come on. Who's bettin'?
-( Man #2 ) King and queen.
Five. You're out of your mind.
- Good afternoon.
- Good afternoon, Captain.
May I help you ?
yes, uh, do you have
a Captain Hardenburg in this section ?
- yes, he's here.
- Would it be possible to see him ?
- Are you a friend of his ?
- Mmm. yes.
Very good. He's right in there.
Go right in.
Thank you.
Captain Hardenburg ?
- Is that you, Diestl ?
- Yes, sir.
I was just released
from my hospital this afternoon,
and I came to say good-bye.
That's very nice of you.
Well, are you feeling
any better, sir ?
- Ah, better each day.
- Good.
But they tell me
I will be here for six months.
Six months. Ah, well, I'm sorry
that it will be so long for you.
oh, why sorry ?
It gives me the opportunity
to think of the future.
- I plan to go into politics.
- oh, yes.
My face will be a reminder of what
I have given for the fatherland.
It will stand me
in good stead...
before audiences
at public meetings.
Well,
you know, sir, that...
they do remarkable things
nowadays with--
yes, remarkable.
Remarkable.
Glass eyes,
plastic noses,
reconstructed cheekbones.
I have written to Gretchen
in this kind of detail...
to prepare her for it.
And she has assured me
she is proud of me,
and it will
make no difference.
Gretchen is
the name of my wife.
yes, I know.
How do you know ?
Oh,yes. You delivered
a package for me.
She's quite handsome,
isn't she ?
yes, sir.
She's quite handsome.
She will be very useful
to my career.
What I would like
for you to do for me is...
visit her again...
to reassure her.
I know it's
a great deal to ask,
to speak for a man to his wife
under these circumstances,
but I want her to hear
from a third party that I am...
salvageable.
yes, I-I-I will be
glad to do that.
Thank you.
Thank you, Diestl.
Now, come closer.
yes, sir.
Are we alone ?
- yes, except for--
- yes, it's all right.
I have one more favor
to ask of you.
I want you to bring me
a bayonet.
- A bayonet ?
- yes, yes. A bayonet.
- Well, I think, uh--
- W-What is the matter with you ?
Not for me.
For him.
He has no hands left...
or anything left.
He wants to die.
I've promised him.
( Whispering )
He whispers to me... when we are alone.
And he can hear.
He's a watchmaker...
in Nuremberg.
He specializes
in stopwatches.
He has three children,
and he wants to die.
Where is my hand ?
Approximately over his heart.
Good.
That's where I will place
the bayonet.
We have practiced it
every night for a week.
Come back tonight
with the bayonet.
Diestl, will you bring me
the bayonet ?
yes, sir.
Good-bye, Diestl.
Good-bye, sir.
-( Gretchen ) Yes ?
- It's Christian Diestl.
Who ?
Christian Diestl.
- Hello ?
- oh, the lieutenant.
- yes.
- Come in.
How are you ?
I'm all right.
And you ?
Forgive me, lieutenant.
I must look awful,
but I haven't slept
for so many weeks.
- We've had so many air raids.
- Mmm.
Come in.
Excuse me.
They come over
two or three times a night.
you can't imagine
what it's like.
The soldiers at the front
would strike under such conditions.
I mean it.
There's no heat,
no light.
oh, yes.
I remember.
Sit down.
Thank you.
Did you bring any food
from Russia ?
- Africa.
- Of course.
- My husband's company.
- yeah.
All I have left
is some kummel.
No thanks.
Do you hear from
your husband ?
He killed himself.
- He what ?
- He killed himself with a bayonet.
I have the letter somewhere.
He asked me to come here
and speak to you for him.
Perhaps it's just as well.
He wanted to come back here.
Naturally,
I didn't encourage him.
I spent a whole night
composing a most tactful letter.
I told him, of course,
he would be better off in some
permanent veteran's hospital.
What are you doing now ?
For heaven's sake, Christian,
be a little realistic.
you people are getting
stranger and stranger.
Stay a little while.
Maybe I can find some vodka.
I make myself
pretty for you.
( Brandt )
Christian ?
Christian !
Brandt.
Christian, how wonderful
to see you again.
It's good to see you,
Brandt.
- ( Chuckles ) oh, no.
- I can't believe it.
( laughing )
oh, it was bad, huh ?
No. They moved us around
a little bit, but you know, it's--
listen now, uh,
what's the matter with you,
being so near the front ?
Well, you know me.
It was a mistake in the orders.
But you, what are you doing here ?
Are you stationed here ?
No, as a matter of fact,
I'm waiting for transportation.
I'm trying to get to Paris.
let's go someplace where
we can talk. I'll buy you
a drink for old-time's sake.
Brandt, I see you are
a captain from taking pictures.
It's an outrage.
I should be a major.
you have no idea
how glad I am to see you.
I'll take that.
Bring us some glasses.
I've been hanging around here
for two days waiting for
somebody to go to Paris.
- listen. What are you
doing in Paris, Brandt ?
- Well, my headquarters are there.
This is your headquarters with
the blond hair who likes goose liver ?
( laughing )
yeah, yeah. That's the one.
In other words,
you have no orders whatsoever.
- only a desire.
- yeah, yeah.
look, Christian, I have also managed to
acquire a little French car all my own.
- Well, this follows, naturally.
- yes, but look.
A poor, old photographer.
I wouldn't last an hour before
somebody requisitioned it.
But you have combat orders. With you,
there would be no questions asked.
you have this car here
with you ?
yeah,just near here
in a little stable.
- Why don't we go now ?
We'll take the car.
- All right. let's go.
Good. Good.
Why don't you have dinner
with Simone and me tonight, huh ?
Well, that would be very nice,
but I think I must report.
oh, report in the morning.
you need some rest.
Brandt, do you ever
see Francoise ?
Why, of course.
She is living with Simone now.
She is living
with Simone ?
yeah, sure. She has been
for more than a month.
Brandt, would you like to have dinner
with Francoise and me tonight ?
Very nice.
We'd be delighted.
Simone ?
Simone ! Wha--
Simone. Darling.
It's been forever, ja ?
- Forever, hmm ?
-( Simone Speaking French )
Hello, Francoise.
Hello.
Come in.
- ( Indistinct Chattering )
- ( laughter)
oh, my wonderful friends, I want
to thank you for this beautiful night.
I love you for it.
And now I'd like to make
a little toast, huh ?
Farewell, Captain Brandt
of the Army of the Third Reich.
you're drunk, darling.
- Say good night to everyone.
- No, no, no. Christian understands me.
Good night, Captain Brandt.
Tomorrow you'll awaken
to your new life--
Monsieur Brandt,
citizen of the world.
Isn't he funny ?
He has such ideas.
Sit down, Simone.
Sit down for a minute.
Christian, I-I know
you don't approve,
but listen to me
for a minute.
Tell me-- Are we
civilized human beings...
or are we wild beasts ?
A human being knows
when he has lost...
and he tries
to save himself.
When you are put into the army,
you are expected to risk your life.
But you are not expected
to just throw it away.
After all,
in any war, Christian,
after all the arms and the legs
have been blown off,
it doesn't really matter...
because nothing really changes.
Good night,
my dear friend.
Francoise,
be good to him,ja ?
Because he is the best
of the best.
- All right, all right.
-Ja.
Come on.
Christian.
you-- you won't report him.
Thank you.
you're not the same.
When you are--
When you are in a hole...
filled with your own excrement
for days on end,
and when you see the faces
and the bodies of the men you've killed,
you change.
And when you're
out there like that,
when you have to live
with death every day...
for so long,
you have to keep something
in front of you or you will go insane.
And there were hours...
I was always afraid that
I had just invented you.
But I'm real.
yeah.
Christian,
please stay.
There isn't anything
for you to fight for.
There never really was.
Christian,
you're not the
golden warrior anymore,
and soon...
you will be
just another refugee.
Don't throw this away.
Please.
( Whispering )
Don't throw this away.
I think--
I think I've come too far.
-( Air Raid Sirens Wailing )
-( Bombs Exploding )
* My mother makes
synthetic gin *
* My brother sells gas
without coupons *
- * oh, what a-- *
-( Bomb Explodes )
What are you staring at ?
-;';'( Continues, Indistinct )
- The faces of the generals,
I don't like 'em.
If there is one thing
I cannot stand...
it's enlisted men with their air
of injured moral superiority.
They don't look like they could lead
you up the walls of a German fortress.
( Chuckles )
Well, don't you worry, honey.
They're not gonna lead you anyplace
outside of a london bar.
- let's not start that again.
- All right--
( Bomb Explodes )
;';'( Stops )
Go on, dear.
oops. Here comes
another big man.
;'Bless the long
and the short and the tall ;'
( Bomb Explodes )
No, no, no. Sit down. Sit down, soldier.
How are you, Margaret ?
I'm all right, Sam,
so far.
( Sam )
They are a little early tonight.
oh. Private Whiteacre,
I'd like you to meet General Rockland.
Sam, huh ?
Nice to know you, sir.
Thank you. Come on over to the bar.
Bring your friend.
In a little while.
Thank you, Sam.
How long's this
been goin' on ?
- Wouldn't you like to know ?
- And a general too.
( Bomb Explodes )
Johnny one Note.
Always criticizing officers.
Always turning down promotions.
Why do you insist
on staying a private ?
Guilt, I guess.
Dr. Freud would say
I'm punishing myself...
because I'm staying
out of combat.
Because I'm letting Noah
Ackerman do my fighting for me,
if you wanna personalize it.
Well, then get into it.
Stop feeling so guilty.
It's getting a little sickening.
I'd rather be guilty
than dead.
( Bomb Explodes )
Go on. See Sam.
These things get any closer...
I'll probably chicken out
and make a spectacle of myself.
Go on ! See Sam.
Go on.
- you would, too, wouldn't you ?
- let me go.
( Bombs Exploding )
Stay here.
What are you trying to do ?
Get yourself killed ?
General, will you
do something for me ?
- ( Mouthing Words )
- Will you ?
I don't know.
What is it ?
- Can you send me back
to my old outfit ?
- Where are they ?
- They're fighting in Normandy.
- I suppose so.
- Why don't you just put in
a request through channels ?
- I don't wanna wait that long.
All right.
- Give me your name
and your serial number.
- yes, sir.
Thank you, General.
Thank you.
Well, now you've done it.
you're practically
in a foxhole right now.
- That's what you wanted, isn't it ?
- Michael, you big, stupid idiot.
That isn't what I wanted. you don't have
to get killed to keep me loving you.
I won't get killed. Believe me,
I'll have the deepest foxhole...
and the biggest helmet
in the whole infantry.
No, you won't.
I'll talk to him.
Don't. Margaret, please.
Come here.
Now let that be
a lesson to you.
Margaret,
I-I have to do this.
I know I'll chicken out afterwards,
but by that time it'll be too late.
I'm-- I'm scared.
- Don't be scared.
- I-- I--
I'll come back. I have to come back.
How else can I marry you ?
- Morning,John.
- Morning, Peter.
Here it is.
( Noah's Voice ) Also, the mail may
be slow, and I don't want you to worry.
I can't tell you where I am,
because the censors wouldn't like it.
If it's not too private,
could you read it to us ?
yeah.
''The photograph was wonderful.
''I'm delighted
with my little girl.
''I can see that she
is a fine child...
''straight of limb,
quick of mind.
''I promise to return
to both of you...
''with a whole body and a whole heart,
no matter what happens.
''I shall return to tell her
stories at bedtime,
''to feed her spinach...
''and to teach her how to
drink milk out of a glass,
''to take her out
in the park...
''and tell her the names
of the animals in the zoo,
''to explain to her why she
must not hit little boys...
and why she must love her mother
as much as her father does.''
( Noah's Voice )
Write me.
Darling, write me.
Write to me, please.
Write me. Love--
''Noah.''
( Gunfire )
They're gettin' close.
look, I want no firing no matter
what happens, till they move up.
oh, no. No shooting.
We're only artillery observers, ya know.
I can still hear the old man.
''you boys go on up ahead.
See what we have to clear out.
It's easy. like taking a walk
on a peaceful Sunday morning.''
What are they doin' out there
on a peaceful Sunday morning ?
- ( Sneezes )
- Bless you.
Mother. Mother.
Mother.
( All Shouting )
Here they come.
Put your guns on 'em
and make it count. Now !
Don't bunch up down there !
Grenade !
( Gunfire Stops )
There's no sense in putting it off.
We're french fried if we stay here.
Another few minutes before they
reorganize. Who wants to go first ?
We'll leave
by twos and threes.
We'll dissolve the detail
in twos and threes.
No need to tell you to be careful.
Who's goin' first ?
Look, when you get
through the Germans--
I wish I could tell you
where our lines are.
But don't expose yourself
till it's absolutely necessary.
- you don't want to get shot
by your own men.
-( Gunshots )
Somebody'd better go now.
- All right.
- yeah.
I'll go too.
( Gunfire Continues )
- ( Gasping )
- What's the matter ?
It's all right.
okay ?
( Gunfire Continues )
( Gunfire )
- What are you doin' ?
- What do you mean ?
Get your stuff off.
- oh, no, not me. I can't swim.
- Well, I can't swim either.
- It can't be too deep.
- There's krauts all around us !
Big deal. We'll sit
here and wait for 'em.
- Those are our guys across there.
- They're not gonna ask any questions.
The minute we hit that water, they're
gonna spray us like sittin' ducks.
- Get out of your gear !
- I'm takin' off nothin' !
I've had enough of this !
- Cowley, you can't--
- I've had enough of you.
I don't know what you're doin', but
I'm not doin' it with you. you're nuts !
- I can't swim ! you understand ?
- Shut up !
Get outta here.
I'm ready. let's go.
I'll go first.
( Grunts )
Wait a second. Wait a second.
Just dog paddle.
- ( Rapid Breathing )
- Take it easy. okay ?
Hold onto me.
Hold on.
( Coughs )
( Whispering )
Hey, not here. Not here.
Hey, hey. Here.
( Gunfire )
Is it bad ?
- No ?
- No.
Don't try to move.
- Hey !
-( Gunfire )
Hey, you guys !
Cut it out ! Cut it out !
( Gunfire Continues )
Hey ! Will ya
quit shootin' ?
We're Company C, Charlie Company.
There's only two of us.
And he's wounded.
Gimme a hand.
Gimme a hand, will ya ?
-( Man ) You got dog tags ?
- Sure, I got dog tags.
your name ?
Ackerman, 397 4287. okay ?
All right, keep your shirt on.
We're coming.
( Man ) Take it easy now.
Be careful. Easy, easy.
Easy.
( Gunfire Continues )
Thanks.
This here is Red Dog 4.
A couple of guys from C Company
just come up. Ackerman and, uh--
- Burnecker.
Burnecker's wounded.
Ackerman ain't got no clothes.
Better get some up here.
Ask him if lieutenant Green
showed up.
What about Green ?
uh-huh. yeah, I gotcha.
They're all okay.
They just barely made it.
How was it out there ?
They're sending up
some dry clothes for you.
I found some schnapps.
Get you warm.
( Gunfire Continues )
( Grunts )
Hmm ?
oh, Michael.
How'd you get here ?
I have a friend
that's a general.
I'm pretty big behind the lines.
Here, put these on.
( laughs )
What's the matter ?
There's still--
Hey, uh--
Could one of you, uh,
pass the word down the line...
to hold fire for, like,
1 0, 1 5 minutes ?
-( Man ) What gives ?
- There's a guy we left over there.
Vernon, you go down the line
and tell those trigger-happy joes...
if they see a derriere
in the canal, it's one of ours.
- Who's out there ?
- Cowley.
oh, Cowley. Good.
- yeah, except he can't swim.
- Even better.
look, you don't owe him
anything. Nothing.
No, I don't.
you've just been out there.
There are plenty other guys.
How about you, son ?
you look fat and sassy.
Wait a minute.
I just got here.
Besides, I'm a coward.
( Gunfire )
( Whispering )
Cowley ?
- Cowley ?
- What do you want ?
- Come on. let's go.
- Will you leave me alone ?
Cowley, it's not deep.
Damn you, it's not deep !
The guys are waiting
for us ! Now come on !
No. No, I'm not going.
- okay.
- Wait !
( Gasping )
- you all right, Noah ?
- yeah.
( Plane Engines Droning )
( Gunfire )
- I would like to speak with
your commandant, please.
-Ja, Kapitan.
Enter, Kapitan.
- yes ?
- I was wondering if
you had some food, sir.
We have no food. We've already been
cleaned out by deserters.
I'm not a deserter.
My company has defected, I am
without command and I have not
eaten anything in two days.
Forgive me, Captain. Sit down.
Pour yourself some coffee.
It's a relief to find someone who
still has some sense of discipline left.
How close
are the Americans ?
Well, I think they are-- I don't know--
five minutes or five hours.
- I'm sorry. That's all that's left.
- Thank you.
Everything is gone.
Colonels and generals passing by,
snatching the food out of my hands,
throwing away their uniforms.
unbelievable.
My men are running too.
This organization is falling
apart in front of my eyes.
I'm sorry.
- Are you hurt ?
- No.
I can see you had
a bad time.
Well, so did I.
I have my wounds, too,
even if you don't see them.
Running a concentration camp
is not a picnic, believe me,
with all the gas chambers, target
ranges, doctors with their experiments.
I had an extermination quota
of 1 ,500 people a day--
Jews, Poles, Russians, French,
political prisoners.
And I had only 260 men to do it.
Still I managed it.
Then they sent memorandums from Berlin,
inspectors running, shouting,
''In Auschwitz they kill
20,000 a day. ''
( Phone Ringing )
I know who it is.
It's Berlin again...
for the fourth time today.
yes ?
yes.
Very near. A few miles.
I told you.
All right, I didn't tell you.
I told whoever
it was that called.
I have ten men left. How can
I kill everybody in the camp ?
Don't you understand ?
The equipment is not working.
Nothing is working.
I don't care what
they did in Buchenwald.
I'm here alone, and I have
no personnel left !
you know what this is,
this phone call ?
They want me to kill every man,
woman and child in the camp
before the Americans get here.
Six thousand people.
And the man who asked me
to do this-- this same man--
will walk the streets free.
And they will come to him,
the Americans, the Russians,
and he will say, ''I've never
heard of concentration camps. ''
He will say there never was a national
policy to kill 1 2 million people.
The S.S. invented it.
Nobody in the government
ever heard of it.
And I'll be here trying to
explain to the Americans.
Do you know, the Americans may not
understand what they see here.
They may not know that the
German officer-- our kind of officer--
does what he's ordered to do.
Well, we at least know...
what is important--
the courage to stay
and face the enemy...
and the honor to be able to say, ''I have
done my duty for the fatherland.''
What's the matter ?
My God.
( Man ) Captain, this is
the mayor of the town we just
came through on our way up here.
He says he can send a gang
of civilians in to help us.
As I was telling
the sergeant, Captain,
we have heard some of your most
important generals and newspaper
men are on their way up here.
I can provide you with a
number of my townspeople...
- who will help you to
clean up this place--
- yes ?
Excuse me.
My name is Joseph Silverson.
I am a rabbi.
yes.
I do not wish to annoy the officer,
but I have a request to make.
yes, what is it ?
Thousands have died here.
More will die tonight, tomorrow.
Sorry, Rabbi.
We're doing all we can.
of course. I know that.
But there's nothing
to be done for them.
Nothing material.
We understand that.
All efforts must be
for the living.
What I am asking for
is a luxury.
yes ?
I ask to be permitted
to collect all of us,
the living
and those without hope,
and hold a religious service--
a service for the dead
who have come to their end here.
There has never been a religious
service for us in this place.
Permit me, Captain.
I don't like to intrude.
I understand why the rabbi
has made this request,
but this is
not the time for it.
I'm a European. I understand things
perhaps the captain doesn't understand.
If you allow this gentleman to hold
the services, I'm obliged to warn you.
There will be riots. The other prisoners
will not stand for it, and...
the generals who are coming
will not like what they see.
The, uh, other prisoners
will not stand for it and
the generals will not like it ?
That's a fact.
I guarantee it.
I'm gonna guarantee
something myself.
I'm gonna guarantee that you--
you'll hold your services.
I'm also gonna guarantee that
machine guns will be set up...
on the roofs of the buildings.
And further, I will guarantee
that anyone who attempts to
interfere with those services...
will be fired upon
by those machine guns.
And further, I guarantee that if you
ever try to come into this place again,
I will personally break
your neck.
That is all.
Thank you very much, sir.
Ackerman, you're not needed around here.
Go take a walk outside the camp.
Thank you, sir.
Whiteacre.
How do you feel ?
Fine, fine.
I never-- Did you ever imagine
it could be like that ?
Nope.
My father's brother
died in one of those.
- Did you see them ?
- The ovens ?
yeah, yeah.
- Did I ever tell you about my father ?
- No.
When that guy started
to talk to Green...
- I could've gone outside
and blown my brains out.
- I felt the same way.
And then Green said,
''I guarantee. I guarantee.''
I don't know. I got a lot
of hope for Captain Green.
you know what ?
When this war's over,
Green is gonna be
running the world.
There are millions of him.
Millions ! They're human beings.
There are millions, millions of them !
They're gonna run the world !
( Vehicle Approaching )
( Grunts )
( Banging Continues )
( Screams )
Kraut !
- ( Horn Honks )
- Hey !
( Horn Honks )