My name is Gladys Aylward.
I've written to
the head of the missionary society.
His reply stated that he'd see me
if I ever came to London.
-If he's busy, I can wait.
-Just one moment, please.
Sit down, won't you?
Dr. Robinson will see you now,
Miss Aylward.
-How nice of you to drop in so soon.
-Thank you.
I decided to come
after I'd received your letter.
I couldn't wait any longer.
You've severed
your connections in Liverpool?
There wasn't much to sever.
I brought everything I own with me.
I see.
Well, sit down, please.
Well, you are going to use me. Aren't you?
You are going to send me to China.
It's quite impossible.
Why?
Look, I'm terribly sorry about this.
I blame myself for not having
been more clear in my letter, but...
But why can't you use me?
To be a missionary in China today
is frightfully difficult.
I'm not speaking from hearsay.
I spend three years there
for every year I spend here at home.
You don't know what you'd be facing.
The... The filth, the squalor,
the hardships in the remote areas.
That doesn't frighten me. I'm strong.
I'm used to hard work.
My dear girl, don't you understand?
You're just not qualified.
We send to China only those of our people
who have very special
education and experience.
I know. I've had a very ordinary schooling.
And since then I've been a servant, but...
But I've read. I've studied by myself.
I've worked at
the Liverpool Mission on my days off.
I understood that from your letters.
And I do understand
the strong call you feel for China, but...
But it isn't enough?
Thank you anyway.
Have you any plans?
N... No.
Well, forgive me
but are you all right for money?
Oh, I'll get a job.
That may be difficult.
There's so much unemployment now.
I'll manage.
No, wait, please.
I may be able to help you.
People sometimes contact us
when they have positions.
Old China hands, clergymen, and so on.
I suppose they feel confidence
in anyone we recommend.
Yes, here's one.
Sir Francis Jameson, the explorer
and a good friend to China missions.
I'd be very happy to approach him for you.
That is, if you've had
experience as a second maid.
Yes. Yes, I have.
For that, I'm qualified.
Good morning.
What is the fare to China, please?
China? But where in China, miss?
Well, wherever I can get to the quickest.
Exactly £90 by boat.
Is that the cheapest way?
No, that's not the cheapest way.
The cheapest way is overland,
the Trans-Siberian Railroad.
That is only £41.
It's a lot, but it's better.
Unfortunately, it's quite impossible.
Look, uh, will you come over here?
I'll explain.
Look. This is the route.
You go from England to Holland
across Germany, Poland,
Russia, Siberia, China.
At best, it's a very long,
dangerous, and difficult trip.
But over and above that, at the moment
there's a situation on
the Russian-Chinese border
to which both parties have sent troops.
There's been considerable disturbance.
Oh, that doesn't matter.
But, miss, there's been shooting.
This may turn into a war.
Why would anyone bother me?
Miss, Milfields undertakes to deliver
its clients to their destinations,
usually in good health, but always alive.
We cannot guarantee your deliverance
to China alive,
not by the overland route.
I'm on my way to Chelsea, a mile away.
Who can guarantee I'll get there alive?
Will you book me a passage, please?
Very well then. For what date?
I don't know yet. I haven't got £41.
But I'll pay something on account
and come back every week and add to it.
I'm very reliable.
I don't doubt it.
But we don't sell tickets that way.
Look. Couldn't you save it up
and then bring it in?
I might get discouraged.
If I know I own a small part of a ticket
it'll be easier.
I'll take the pennies and leave you the rest.
There is £1 and 5 shillings.
Is that all you have?
Isn't it enough for the first payment?
You can't leave yourself
with just four pennies.
I'm on my way to a new job.
But supposing you don't like the new job
or it just doesn't work?
I'll make it work.
Will you spell your name for me please?
Last name first.
Well, the mission don't send
flighty ones, and that's a blessing.
Come in.
You're Gladys Aylward?
I'm Miss Thompson, the housekeeper.
I expected you an hour ago.
-Oh, I...
-No excuses, please.
Are you an experienced second maid?
Yes, Miss Thompson. I've worked for...
We'll soon see.
The wages are 19 shillings a week.
Thursday and every second Sunday off
from 10:00 till 10:00.
-That'll be fine. Thank you.
-I should think so.
Remember, there are 50 girls
for every job in London.
I'll take you to your room.
Short of breath, are you?
Oh, it's just the suitcase.
The room's small, but it's clean.
Oh, it's fine. Thank you.
Good.
Now, Gladys, stop it.
Why make work for yourself
on your day off?
It was streaked.
With people coming in for tea
you would have bitten my head off.
Good morning, Sir Francis.
Good morning.
Was he annoyed at your being there?
No, I don't think so.
He said what he always says,
"Good morning."
I daresay you want your money.
And I daresay it will be spent by tonight.
Every penny. Every single penny.
With that,
I make the grand total
£24, 9 shillings.
That's more than half your ticket.
At this moment, I'm entering
the western end of Siberia.
Well, not quite. Tomorrow, perhaps.
Tomorrow I'll be halfway through it.
I'm cleaning a lazy woman's kitchen
this afternoon
and serving at a birthday party
this evening.
That's at least another 10 shillings.
And much too much work.
You haven't had a holiday for three months.
I don't need one.
You'll be exhausted
by the time you get there.
No, I'll have lots of energy left.
Lots left to use. Good-bye.
Birthday cake, Bessie,
with half a yellow rose.
Oh, Glad, whatever have you done?
What is it?
Take off your coat and put on your apron.
Sir Francis is waiting in the library.
Those gentlemen came to tea.
There was an argument about a book.
Walled Cities of China.
Sir Francis went to the shelf,
and it was gone.
He rang for me.
"Perhaps it's been borrowed," I said.
"I didn't lend it," he shouted.
"Search the house!"
There it was under your pillow,
a book worth £50.
I'm afraid this is the end, Gladys.
SIR FRANCIS: Come in.
Since you were recommended
by the missionary society
I assume you know the difference
between right and wrong.
What have you to say for yourself?
I... I'm... I'm sorry that you were worried
but I didn't damage the book.
I've been very careful with all of them.
All of them? You've done this before?
Yes, sir.
I... I have read a whole shelf on China
and I'm in the middle of another.
Did it ever occur to you
that you might ask
if you could borrow the books?
I was afraid you'd say no.
I had to read them. I'm going to China.
I have to learn all I can about it.
Oh, Sir Francis,
only half of my ticket is paid for.
If I can keep this job a little longer...
Stop fussing, girl. Sit down.
Now, what's all this
about your going to China?
Is the mission sending you?
No. No, no,
they don't think I'd be any good.
I'm going on my own.
You can't just wander
into China without a job,
without a destination, without money.
I'll have at least £5 over and above my fare.
-£5?
-Mmm-hmm.
Why? Why must it be China?
You... You feel where you belong
as if you were told.
For me, it's China.
Give up this ridiculous adolescent idea.
But I can help out there.
Help? How can you help?
You're not a trained nurse
or a welfare worker.
I want to be a missionary.
A missionary? You?
Take my advice. Stay here, my girl
and go on polishing the furniture.
You'll do far more good.
No, I won't.
It doesn't matter
why I feel God wants me to go to China.
The important thing is that I feel it.
Because I do, I'll go
no matter what you or anyone else can say.
If I can't stay here and earn the money
then I'll go somewhere else.
Oh, I see.
You may keep your job.
Thank you.
You're a foolish, stubborn girl
unquestionably heading for trouble.
However, I shall worry less
if some of the more obvious idiocy
is removed from your plans.
I've outlived all my missionary
friends in China, except one.
Jeannie Lawson,
worth any ten women I've ever known.
Mind you, I don't promise anything
but I'll drop her a line
when I have a moment.
She must be getting on.
It's possible she could do
with a strong, young helper.
Ah, here it is. Her last address.
Hmm?
Did you pin your passport
into your underthings?
If anyone wants to see it
they must just wait
while you go to the ladies and get it.
-After all, you're a British subject.
-Why, there's Mr. Murfin.
How kind of you to come.
Well, I'm interested, naturally.
Some shortbread. Mrs. Murfin made it.
Is this the Aylward expedition?
-Sir Francis.
-I forgot to give you this at the house.
It's been with me on quite a few treks.
You'll find it useful on cold nights.
Thank you, Sir Francis.
Miss Thompson gave me a camera
and Mr. Murfin some shortbread.
Sir Francis, Mr. Murfin
from the travel agency.
I'd better be putting
your luggage in, Gladys. It's time.
What are you planning to do,
trade with the natives?
I thought I was going to make
my own tea and save money.
Boil everything, I told her,
foreigners being what they are.
Very sensible, very English.
Now, remember
the mission at Tientsin
will get you in touch
with Mrs. Lawson at Yang Cheng.
At least you have a destination.
That's something.
It's more than enough.
I might not be leaving today
if it wasn't for you.
That is a thought that
gives me no peace of mind.
Well, off you go.
Are you afraid, Gladys?
It's not too late to back out.
I would, honestly.
Good-bye.
Good-bye, dear friends.
Yurga! Yurga!
Yurga!
Conductor.
Can't you tell me what is happening?
Yurga... What is Yurga?
Ah, angliyskyi.
Angliyska.
English spoken.
Oh, good. Can you tell me
what is happening?
We arrive to the village Yurga.
You must disbark.
No, I have a ticket to Harbin.
Nyet, Harbin. Yurga.
Harbin across border of China.
There is argument.
I'll go as far as I can.
Thank you just the same.
Ha! Angliyska.
English spoken with excellence, yes?
Yes, very.
Stop shouting at me.
I can't understand a word you're saying.
Didn't you hear
the conductor say I'm English?
-Angliyskyi... ska.
-Tovarisch commissar.
Oh, Tovarisch commissar.
You cannot stay here. You woman alone.
Soldier men not moral.
Your passport, please.
Passport.
Passport!
I'm on my way to China
but I was supposed to stop...
Nyet, nyet, nyet. Next station, you go out.
You are by profession machinery?
But China no machinery.
Why go there?
Here in U.S.S.R., machinery good.
Tractors, combine, conveyors.
You stay here.
Machinery China, pfeu!
I'm not that kind of machinery.
I'm a missionary.
I'm going to China
as a missionary, with a Bible.
Onward
Christian soldiers
Marching as to war
Yes. Yes, that's it.
That's it.
-Yes.
Good-bye.
Oh, wait a minute!
Come on.
Yang Cheng.
Ohh.
This place, Mrs. Lawson's
Are you Mrs. Lawson?
Yes.
You're Gladys Aylward.
Good for you.
I didn't think you'd make it.
Get down, girl.
You're home.
Ha ha!
Come in and see our grubby palace.
Oh, don't get too discouraged.
We'll fix it up.
Isn't it very big?
That's why I bought it.
It's an old inn.
We're going to reopen it.
You and I and Yang, my cook.
That gave you a toot, didn't it?
You didn't come out here
to be an innkeeper.
You came to be a missionary
and teach the word.
Well, didn't you?
Gladys, I've never been
this far north in China before.
Very few missionaries have.
There are a few in Tsechow, Tientsin,
the big cities.
But there's never been one
in Yang Cheng before
nor any white person, chances are.
Thank you.
Good-bye.
Good-bye and thank you.
Now, people here
call men in the next village foreigners
and suspect them
so why should they listen to us?
Then how do you hope to reach them?
We're after something bigger.
The mule trains pass through here.
They stay the night at the inns,
then go on their way.
These muleteers
are the newspapers of north China.
If we can make one of them
listen to us and believe
we've reached more people
than there are in Yang Cheng.
Come on in.
It's even worse inside.
Why would they stay at our inn?
Because we're going to charge them
what the others do
for food and lodging
and offer something the others don't.
First, no bugs.
Second, stories, which the Chinese love
free with their dinner.
I've got a good one
for them to listen to and repeat.
Once upon a time, in a little town
called Bethlehem
a baby was born.
Oh, it's a wonderful idea.
Well, the mission center at Shencheng
put up the money
but they weren't that enthusiastic.
Come along in here.
Now there's Yang, my cook.
Yang, this is Miss Gladys
who's going to be our new helper.
Yang's been with me 20 years
and in case you should think
our work's easy
he still isn't a Christian.
He stays with me
because he thinks foreigners are funny.
Now come and see the rest.
Oh, why is it built this way?
Oh, it's a k'ang.
It's heated from underneath
like an oven.
A k'ang?
What is a k'ang for?
A community bed.
You'll find them in every inn in north China.
We've got lots of rooms,
but when winter comes
this is the bed everybody'll be in.
You mean together?
30, 40, 50 at a time
all fully clothed and ignoring each other.
It gets cold here. You'll find out.
Miss Lawson, I go shop now.
Why not go with him?
See what you've let yourself in for.
She go like that?
I'll get her some proper things.
I wait for you outside. Courtyard.
The merchants will start raising their prices
if they see you in those clothes.
They'll take you for a rich foreigner.
Rich? Ha ha! In these?
For people as poor as they are, yes.
My dear girl, you're in China now.
Yes.
Yes, I know.
Oh, my.
You look like a Chinese woman.
We go now.
Miss Jeannie like you.
You stay when she die?
Oh, Yang.
She's very old. Cannot live long.
It isn't nice talking about people dying.
You funny. Just like her.
Good. You stay in China.
I stay with you.
Yang, I've tried to learn
Chinese from a book.
Book don't know. I teach.
We point things, then I tell you.
Oh.
Hsien Chang.
Foreigner call him Mandarin.
He like judge.
Very important.
He say die. You die.
This is house where he lives.
Chinese call Hsien-Cheng-Fu.
Hsien-Cheng-Fu.
Are all those girls his daughters?
Not exactly daughters. More like wives.
But not exactly wives.
I go shop here.
Are you going to stay long?
Oh, yes. Plenty.
First, gossip.
Then he tell me how much
what I want cost.
I say no. I go.
He call me back. More argue
plenty long time.
I'll walk around a little by myself.
I'll find the way back.
Yes, but don't forget.
You foreign devil here.
Ooh. Ohh.
But I'm sorry. I... I didn't mean any harm.
Aah!
The man was a murderer.
He was tried before the Mandarin
proved guilty, and executed.
That's their law.
But to chop off his head...
I don't suppose hanging's a pretty sight
but that's what we do in England.
That's our law.
But it's different.
This is so horrible, so bloodthirsty.
And the way people act...
Those women were frightened.
But what about the men
in that dragon place
yelling and screaming at me for no reason?
They had a reason.
That dragon place, as you call it
was for men only.
There's much that is horrible in China
as in any country.
Babies left to die in ditches,
the poor preying on the poor.
Many things, but they'll change.
One thing at a time,
with the help of the Lord
and that's what we're here for
in this dirty room,
to try to help.
It's a hard life for a young woman
but it won't seem hard, I promise you.
When you're my age and look back
it'll only seem beautiful.
"The Inn of the Sixth Happiness."
Ah, it sounds quite Oriental, doesn't it?
Yes.
Yes, but Yang...
Yang says that everybody in China
wishes you the five happinesses.
Wealth, longevity, good health,
uh, virtue, and a...
And a peaceful death in old age.
Yes, but he didn't mention any more.
What is the sixth happiness?
That you must find out for yourself.
Each person decides in his own heart
what the sixth happiness is.
Come on.
Oh, so much still to be done.
The windows, the balcony, the roof...
Do you think we should've
waited longer to open?
Can't afford to.
I've used up all the year's
allowance from the center
doing what fixing we have done.
Can't do any more
until we make some money
but don't worry. We will.
Mule trains are passing through every day.
I only hope some stop here.
That's your job. You've got to stand outside
like a regular Chinese innkeeper
and shout to them to come in.
With my 20 words of Chinese.
Ask Yang what to shout.
All right.
Oh, Mrs. Lawson,
what are you doing?
Binding it up so the mules won't...
But these bales are heavy.
Let me do it.
Oh, don't bury me before I'm ready.
I have to holler to the mule drivers.
What shall I say to them?
Oh, I tell you.
We have no bugs. We have no fleas.
We do have stories.
Good. Come.
Now start.
That's the second one that passed by.
What shall I do now?
Well, get the lead mule in.
The rest will follow.
Once they start on the fodder
nothing will get them out.
But I can't drag them in, can I?
Whoa!
I've got mules, plenty of mules,
but no men.
Yang!
Yang, what does yong gwee tso mean?
MAN: Yong gwee tze.
That means foreign devil.
I'm delighted that you have no fleas.
Oh, you speak English. That's wonderful.
Wonderful? To an Englishman, perhaps.
Where is the Hsien-Cheng-Fu, please?
Oh, it's down the road,
but could you tell me
why the men ran away?
They've probably never seen
a white person before
especially one bent on
capturing their mules.
Could you tell them
there's nothing to be afraid of?
-Only if it's true.
-Of course it is.
Mrs. Lawson who owns
the inn is a missionary.
The most frightening kind of foreign devil.
I welcome you to Yang Cheng,
Captain Lin Nan.
As a government representative,
you honor us with a visit.
In the future, you will be honored
by other representatives, Hsien Chang.
China is going to be one country,
not a group of weak provinces
left to their own devices.
You're an intelligence officer, Captain,
according to your credentials.
May one ask have you come
to impart intelligence
or to obtain it?
Both.
Primarily, I'm here to observe.
The government wishes to know more
about this isolated region,
its terrain, its population, its problems.
The terrain is mountainous.
The population is peasant.
And the problem, as always,
is to stay alive.
Continue.
I'm instructed to tell you
that in some remote areas of China
the laws concerning taxes,
the registration of birth and death
and the prohibition against
the foot-binding of women
are not being properly enforced.
But foot-binding is a very old custom.
Some of the people will
never obey this law.
You must appoint a foot inspector
who will see they do.
This is part of a program
aimed at the equality of women.
The equality of women?
That is amusing.
The government is interested in the opinion
of the local officials,
their functions, their efficiency,
how they run their prisons,
their modes of execution
and their corruption or...
Or lack of corruption.
The elimination of concubines,
the management of government funds,
even their manner of dress.
Now, shall I make a formal protest
about the foot-binding law in your name?
I think not, Captain.
It is better to bend with the wind
when it blows.
We will have tea.
Mine will not be a long visit.
However long, it will be too short.
I fear you will find us very backward.
Our district is isolated from this world.
Not so isolated that the missionaries
haven't found you.
My mule train was waylaid
at an inn they run.
So you don't object
to foreigners in your city.
What is a foreigner, Captain?
How would you describe yourself?
My heart and my mind are Chinese.
Only my blood is mixed.
If I have offended a guest in my house
I shall not forgive myself.
It's my own mixed blood which offends me
since I believe China
should be for the Chinese.
I cannot speak for all China,
just for this one district.
Poor and weak as it is,
I'm confident it can survive many things.
New laws, no concubines,
even two eccentric Englishwomen.
Oh, Mrs. Lawson.
Oh, really.
All right. I lifted a pot.
And a bale of hay this afternoon.
And tomorrow I may move all the furniture
or start on the balconies
and you're my helper, not my nurse.
But I can't help with the real work.
I can't go in there
and tell stories in Chinese.
But I can free you for what is important.
And if you won't let me,
I don't know why I'm here.
You're here because I need you.
Oh, and I'm a dreadful old woman.
It isn't every day of the week I'd admit it.
They eat like starved.
Must like food.
Now all they've got to do is like the stories.
Pray. That's an order.
Tsai Bethlehem Jesus...
Are they listening? I can't tell.
Mandarin servant from Hsien-Cheng-Fu.
What do you think he wants?
Maybe he make us close down.
Maybe this last supper like Bible say.
Not to worry.
He want chief mule driver
get baggage for important person.
Guest at Hsien-Cheng-Fu.
He say let important person wait.
He want to hear end of story.
He does? Oh, Yang,
then they all have been listening.
Shh!
Aah!
Oh!
Mrs. Lawson!
Get a doctor, quickly!
They will stone anyone who goes
into the mountain villages
and orders the women's feet unbound.
No one wants the position
of foot inspector.
I have approached every likely candidate.
It's my impression that in other matters
you command rather than approach.
-In your own interest, I would like you...
Hsien Chang, are you well?
Yes, I am well.
Who are you?
I am the servant of the foreign women.
The old one has fallen from a great height.
Hsien Chang, please, your doctor...
My doctor?
Would you like me to go with him
because of the language problem?
Ahh, perhaps it would be better.
Two women in a strange land.
Get the doctor.
Yea, though I walk
through the valley
of the shadow of death.
I shall fear no evil, for Thou art with me.
Thy rod and Thy staff, they comfort me.
Thou preparest a table before me.
Good. In one week you learn much.
Oh, it's not enough.
It'll be ages before
I can really tell the Bible stories.
Not to worry.
Until you can, I tell.
Oh, yeah, and you don't believe them.
Don't have to. Good stories anyway.
You want to worry?
Worry about food.
Two days more, no more.
I knew you wanted it the moment it came.
Thank you. Please don't go.
They don't believe in the inn.
They only agreed to it reluctantly
"out of respect for Mrs. Lawson's
vast experience in China.
"Without her or a person
equally qua... Qualified,
"the project is hopeless.
"Our advice is to abandon it
"and come to Shencheng.
"In gratitude for your help
to our dear colleague,
"we will arrange
for your return fare to England."
With that money, I could open the inn.
Why don't they give it to me?
They gave their reasons.
Yes.
One reason. Always the same one.
I'm not qualified.
I was a servant in England.
That's what they mean,
but I came here when they said I couldn't
and I'll stay here
though they say I can't.
I'm going back
to Shencheng in the morning.
I'll be glad to see that you get there safely.
I'm not going to leave.
You are angry and disappointed.
That's understandable.
But you must be realistic.
You cannot stay.
I'll go to the food merchants. I'll beg them.
They will not give you credit.
You will not be able to open the inn.
You have no friends, no money.
You don't know the language.
We're in the most isolated
part of the country
entering a period of violent conflicts
from within and without.
It isn't your country.
It isn't your problem.
You're white.
You shouldn't be in China at all.
How can you say that
when you're part white?
I'm half white.
In your world, I can only
be a second-class citizen.
I chose China
because here I'm allowed to be of value.
That's why I came here. To be of value.
How?
By trying to make people believe
what you believe?
By saving souls
who don't want to be saved?
Who will agree to anything
for an extra bowl of rice
and laugh at you once it is eaten?
To argue about such things
is to argue about shadows.
The dangers that confront you,
those are real.
Leave now while you still can.
Go back to England where you belong.
If I feel that God wants me in China,
then this is where I belong.
In that case,
I'll leave you in His hands.
Obviously, you don't need my help.
Captain Lin, I...
I know you think I'm stubborn,
but I'm not ungrateful.
For you to be concerned, to bother,
it is very kind.
If I were really kind,
I'd have you ordered out of Yang Cheng,
but since I'm not obsessed
with saving souls or lives,
I wish you well.
A pleasant journey, a swift return.
You honor me, Hsien Chang.
I am told that you are not able
to persuade the foreign woman to leave.
She's a very foolish young woman.
Clearly, if she closed
her ears to your advice.
When she goes,
it would be an act of charity
to help her, Hsien Chang.
If that is your wish.
It seems possible, however,
that she will not go.
She'll go. They all go,
the outsiders, the do-gooders in time.
How I envy the young men of China.
How I regret I was born too soon
to be so sure of everything.
And how I regret
I cannot report to my superiors
that the law against foot-binding
is being fully enforced
in the district of Yang Cheng.
It is being enforced.
In the city itself, perhaps,
but not in the outlying villages,
Hsien Chang.
Nor can it be.
That is my first foot inspector.
Numbers two and three
are not yet able to leave their beds.
My superiors will probably
understand your difficulties,
but since they will certainly
reduce your income
till their orders are obeyed,
I would appoint number four if I were you,
and if necessary, five and six and so on.
Whom shall I appoint?
Those men who are not
frightened of the job
are disgusted by it.
They say it's not men's work
to inspect the feet of women.
Then appoint a woman.
It's an interesting problem, Hsien Chang.
I shall be happy to hear you have solved it.
Then be happy, Captain.
I've just solved it.
I'm delighted.
How kind of you to rejoice for me.
Mandarin say,
Captain Lin ask him to help you
so he offer you job on his staff.
Foot inspector.
-Foot inspector?
Foot inspector will tour district.
See people no more bind feet
of female children
to make small.
If female under 30, unbind.
Well, I certainly approve of that,
yet I suppose you can go with me
until I can speak more Chinese.
But will the people listen to us?
He send soldiers, make listen.
Ask him how much I'll get for it.
What did he say?
Well, he said
maybe you worth something, maybe not.
When you come back
from first village and report
Mandarin tell you.
-
-Decide fast, he said.
He does not need you.
He make this offer to be kind.
It is kind of him and the captain.
Yes, it is, Yang.
And if it pays enough to start the inn
I have to take it.
Tell him yes and thank him.
Tell them it is not a bad law.
It is a good law.
Tell the women I am speaking to them.
This law is for them and their children.
It is wrong for them
to hobble on crippled feet.
If the Mandarin knew that
the people felt this way about the law,
why didn't he warn me?
He need foot inspector.
If anything happens to you,
what does he lose?
Is there not one mother...
Is there not one mother in Peh-Chu
that loves her little girl enough
to let me unbind her feet?
Old person say unbind her feet.
No! No! The pain would kill her.
She couldn't walk.
Her feet have been bound too long.
Tell her the law is for
the children and young women.
She says, unbind her feet.
Let the young women see
that she cares more
for their children than they do.
Do it or she will do it herself.
No, I can't. I can't do it.
Oh.
She say, unbind her child's feet.
There. That is good.
Don't be frightened. It won't take long.
If God wanted girls to have
stubby, horrid feet,
He would've made them that way.
What use? The father will
order them bound again.
Look at her feet!
Look at them.
Take these.
If you want her feet bound again,
you bind them.
You listen to her scream.
Not a woman, you.
Yang, what is happening? What is it?
I don't know.
Maybe the women have their feet unbound.
Mandarin is pleased with his new servant.
She has done well.
As reward, he make you
official foot inspector.
You will also carry messages for him
to the far villages
and stop foot-binding everywhere.
Besides all this honor,
he give you a horse for your journeys
and one yuan a month pay.
I'm not staying in Yang Cheng
to be his foot inspector.
I've got to run the inn.
I want credit arranged
with the food merchants.
And when I take
his messages to the people,
I am also going to tell them
of my own beliefs.
It's only with honesty
that I can take this job,
though it was not with honesty or kindness
-that he offered it to me.
-
Mandarin agree to what you ask
and forgive you
for the way you speak to him this time.
In a world full of frightened people,
he likes courage wherever he find it,
even in a rude and angry woman.
I am the Mandarin's servant.
These were the years
of endless work and contentment.
Soon every muleteer
who traveled the old trade routes
knew of the Inn of the Sixth Happiness,
but my happinesses
were too many to count.
The happiness of being one of them,
of being called by my new name.
Jen-ai: the one who loves people.
Eu Eu.
Of learning to speak their language,
of being able to talk to the people
in the marketplace,
to my neighbors in the fields
and my friends in every village
in the mountains,
the happiness of watching the seasons
turn and change,
from autumn to winter,
from winter to spring,
the happiness of beginning new things
that every year brought a harvest
of inner happiness
from teaching the children
God had let me borrow.
Now...
Now we learn a song
that I knew when I was a little girl.
It goes like this.
This old man
He played one
-This old man
-He played one
He played knick-knack on my drum
MAN: Good morning, Jen-ai.
Good morning, Jen-ai.
Are you well, Hsien Chang?
I am well enough, Jen-ai.
Good morning, Jen-ai.
-Good morning.
How beautifully you paint, Hsien Chang.
It requires patience,
a virtue of which I have great need.
Have the recent emissaries
from the government annoyed you?
Government emissaries
I am used to these days.
They even want me
to wear some kind of uniform.
But, no, Jen-ai,
the source of my annoyance
is closer to home.
It is you.
You have attained importance
throughout the district,
and with good reason.
Your name is as well-known as my own.
You are loved by the people
even more than I am,
and with that I am content.
Hsien Chang should be feared and obeyed,
not loved.
But you are all these things.
Do not compliment me.
Do not manage me.
Do not be so... So Chinese, Jen-ai.
I am sorry, but I meant it.
You are loved by the people, I said,
but my officials, they do not love you.
Every day there is
another complaint about you.
The official in charge of road building
complains that you urge his coolies
to demand more money.
The prison warden complains
that you badger him with questions
about the welfare of the convicts.
In short, they tell me
that you are an interfering woman.
I probably am, Hsien Chang,
but you have to interfere
with what is wrong
if you hope to make it right.
That is what I tell them.
Of what are you guilty, I ask,
that you object to her interfering?
Then you don't object?
Certainly not.
Bother the officials all you wish.
Embarrass them,
ask them questions, badger them,
but leave the women
of my household alone.
Oh.
Exactly.
Did you not tell them
that no human being should be subject
to the will of another?
And did you not tell them
that to obey any man unquestioningly
was old-fashioned?
And have you not been
teaching them to read?
Where will it end?
With your converting them?
With hymns being sung
in my Hsien-Cheng-Fu?
I have not tried to convert them.
Why not? Why stop at that?
I'm surprised that you've never
attempted to convert me.
I may be an interfering woman,
Hsien Chang,
but I am not a completely foolish one.
I know when I have met my master.
Hsien Chang!
The chief guard of the prison
has just arrived.
There is trouble.
Chief guard, where is the prison warden?
He's nowhere to be found in Yang Cheng.
What's the trouble?
The convicts are rioting.
They are like madmen.
Do I have your approval to shoot
them from the walls?
It would be better to leave them there.
They'll hunger in time and listen to reason.
Of course, they may wreck the prison.
Before the prison warden left,
he gave orders to shoot them.
The convicts are under
the prison warden's charge
to be cared for, not be murdered.
Can't this man reason with them,
or is he afraid?
It is unfair to goad him into danger.
I would not order him
in there to die, Jen-ai.
In this mood, the convicts
would kill anyone
who tried to reason with them.
But it is his duty to restore order,
not to slaughter people.
Let others go in. I will not.
This riot is not of my making.
I am not responsible.
You're responsible for order in the prison.
I've heard that you say everywhere
that you have a god who
protects you from harm.
Even in prison, we have heard it.
Well, I have no such god.
You go in.
Surely, you cannot be killed.
It is the safety of the soul
that my faith promises, not of the body.
With your permission, Hsien Chang,
I'll go to the prison. I'll try.
I have many convicts
but only one foot inspector.
Shall I lose your services
so that you may save the face
of your religion?
If my religion loses face,
how will my service be of value?
Do not go in, Jen-ai.
Admit you are afraid.
Yes. I am afraid.
Open the gate.
My name is Jen-ai.
I want to speak to you.
It is Jen-ai.
The one who tries to help the people.
Jen-ai.
Give me that ax.
Go and sit against the wall
and rest.
You are tired.
Bring the wounded...
Bring the wounded into the shade.
Choose the man to speak for you.
-Li.
Form into a line right there.
They have chosen me.
Who are you?
My name is Li.
I have been inside these walls
for eight years now.
And before that?
I was a teacher.
How did the riots start?
Because of hunger.
Aren't you fed enough?
Not ever enough.
The warden steals our ration and sells it.
-What do you do here all day?
We sit or we pace
or we fight.
Men should have work,
but to the warden, we are no longer men.
Tell the men it will change.
I will speak to the Hsien Chang.
I promise you it will change.
It has been a long time
since we have tasted tea together
in my humble abode.
You honor me, Hsien Chang.
Hsien Chang!
We were not to be disturbed.
I told Jen-ai you were not to be disturbed.
Jen-ai has returned? Unharmed?
Yes, Hsien Chang, but angry, very angry.
My foot inspector.
You'll forgive an interruption?
Send Jen-ai in.
An exceptional name, Jen-ai,
the one who loves people.
In Yang Cheng, even the foot
inspector is exceptional.
Hsien Chang,
what I found in that prison
is a disgrace to...
Yes, she is still here.
And if I am, it's thanks to you.
Well, don't you remember?
When you left, you asked
Hsien Chang to help me.
To help her leave, wasn't it?
To help me leave?
Ah, perhaps I misunderstood.
Perhaps I misunderstood a moment ago.
You said there were
no foreigners in Yang Cheng.
Nor are there.
I'm a Chinese citizen.
You gave up British citizenship?
I once told you that I belonged here.
The government must've thought so, too,
or they wouldn't have accepted me.
So you see, Captain, you were wrong.
Our friend is a colonel now,
though equally wrong, of course.
May I speak about the prison now?
Sit down, Jen-ai.
I regret to say there's been a riot.
The riot is over,
but not the misery that caused it.
First, the convicts have been starved.
The warden was stealing
their food allotments.
He will be found and severely punished.
A new warden will be appointed at once
but perhaps,
as the government representative,
you would prefer to rule on this case?
There's no need.
You are doing as
the government would wish.
Hsien...
Hsien Chang, just as important
as the men's need for food
is their need for work.
When I left the prison,
I went to a farmer nearby.
If the convicts are allowed
to work in his fields,
he'll pay them with food.
This would keep them active
and add to their food allotment.
Permission is given.
One more thing, during the riot,
the prison was badly damaged.
It should be repaired.
The year's funds for prison repairs
has already been used.
Can more be obtained?
Not at this time. Our money must go
to more important things.
Well, what could be more important?
A war.
We're expecting a Japanese attack.
A war?
But if this should happen,
why should they attack this region?
We're so poor, so isolated.
An innkeeper, foot inspector,
prison reformer,
and now, a military expert.
Careful, Colonel. No one is more trusted
by the mountain people than Jen-ai.
You need her to send your orders to them.
There are new taxes,
new quotas for the army.
Yes, and there's a message to them.
When the invaders come,
they're not to be met
peacefully as in the past.
They're to be fought.
Each man must fight.
Each man must kill.
I cannot take that message.
To me, killing is a mortal sin.
You are a citizen of China.
You will obey its laws.
When the laws of China
conflict with the laws of my faith,
I know which one to obey.
Now, on the night the baby Lord Jesus
was born in that stable in Bethlehem,
several came to bow down to Him
and His mother, the Lady Mary.
There were three powerful warlords
known as the magi
who brought many fine gifts.
And still another wonderful man,
a sea captain named Noah
came to visit Jesus.
His ship was called Noah's ark.
The Lord Jesus liked this Noah
for he was a wise man...
Ahem.
Especially in the ways of animals
whom he often took sailing in his ark.
Ahem.
This man Noah...
Yang.
This man Noah was born
long before the Lord Jesus,
but men in those days lived to be very old
so no one can be sure,
no one at all,
that Noah did not visit Jesus in that stable
in Bethlehem.
Ahh!
May I speak with you a moment?
Since you won't take the new
orders around the district,
I must.
Do you object to my traveling with you
on your next tour?
No.
And to introduce me to the village elders?
I'm leaving tomorrow morning
as soon as it's light,
but I have to stop at the prison first
if that is convenient.
Perfectly. I'll meet you here.
I... I remembered you as a friend.
I know we think differently
about things, but...
But I can't understand
why you were so hostile
at the Hsien-Cheng-Fu.
I'm not hostile to you personally.
I have few personal feelings.
With the Hsien Chang's approval,
your new prison warden gives you leave
to plant the little field outside the wall
for your own use.
It isn't much, but it is a beginning.
We thank you, Jen-ai.
We are grateful.
Surely that was a great opportunity
for making converts.
Aren't you neglecting
your missionary work?
Is that what you think it is?
Collecting converts,
the way a child collects pretty stones?
Is it anything else?
To me, it's making each man
know that he counts
whether he believes in Christ or Buddha
or nothing, Colonel, like you.
I believe in China as it can be.
I love China the way it is.
Filthy, ignorant, backwards?
No, but if your house is dirty,
you can clean it.
One can make improvements
even in small corners, like this prison.
If enemies plan to burn your house,
is it time to clean or to fight?
The village elder tells me
that except for those citizens
under five years old,
you all know every word in the first reader
so here's the second one
and it's much harder.
And I'll tell the Hsien Chang
that in Peh-Chu all the toes can wiggle
and everyone can read.
Now, that finishes my business.
Colonel Lin, an officer in our army
will now talk to you.
I bring bad news
and orders that mean hardship.
The government believes that our country
will soon be attacked by the Japanese.
Because this may well start here
in the north, this concerns you.
They will not bother us.
This is a small, poor village.
This is a small, poor finger.
It must do its part if I'm attacked
or it will become a small, dead finger.
A large army is being trained to defend you.
To maintain it,
you must give half your grain and livestock.
All men must register for the army.
Many will be taken,
but those at home must fight, too.
They will kill the enemy if they can.
Burn the crops that might feed him.
And plant again when he's gone.
Read the orders.
Jen-ai, must we obey this man?
It's not for me to tell you
what you should obey or not obey
but you must listen.
The colonel speaks for the government.
You mustn't mind.
They are just terribly suspicious
of foreigners.
At the four villages we visited,
has anyone listened to me?
They've listened.
They'll fight.
People are always ready to fight.
I appreciate your not trying
to influence them differently.
My conscience is my own affair
and theirs is theirs
and yours is yours.
Hoka! Hoka!
Three days we wait for you, Jen-ai.
A fine greeting.
And now look what you bring. Let him go.
Why not the police, huh?
Come on.
Those bandits are obviously your friends.
Are there more of them?
About 20. It's a small band.
They're poor, ignorant men who need help.
One has been hurt.
I want to see what I can do.
Hoka says you can wait here without harm.
If you give me your word
you'll forget you ever saw them.
I promise. On one condition.
That I can go with you and talk to them.
20 bandits used to these mountains.
They'll make excellent scouts for us.
You never miss an opportunity, do you?
You do your work. I do mine.
Jen-ai!
I'll speak to him.
Hoka!
He promises, but only if he can talk to you.
All right!
It's all right, Colonel!
Hello, Jen-ai.
The government believes
that our country
will soon be attacked by the Japanese.
When it comes,
you can perform an important service
by scouting the enemy.
If you will help,
you will be pardoned for all your crimes
and become honored citizens again.
You will not have to hide in the mountains
like thieves.
Think about it.
You can be of valuable help in the north
if it starts here.
That's all I have to say.
Your friend makes a fine speech.
He says we're all going to be heroes.
If the Japanese come,
we'll all be honored dead, I think.
Thieves and citizens alike.
Is he going to be all right, Jen-ai?
I don't know enough to be sure
but at least I got the wound clean.
Well, use your medicine to make him well.
He's a good man.
He's a bad man, Hoka, just like you.
But I will use the medicine
if your men don't rob
or kill for eight weeks.
Four weeks.
-I can kill you and take the medicine.
-Go ahead.
No killing or robbery for eight weeks
or I'll let this man rot.
All right.
But you can be very hard, Jen-ai.
Like a man.
If Dr. Robinson could see me now,
with my convicts, my bandits, and you.
Still I wonder if in England
you wouldn't have had a more normal life.
Marriage, children, and all that.
For some people, that never happens,
no matter where they are.
I have always felt that I was one of those.
Maybe Hoka is right.
I am like a man.
It's a warm night.
Why don't you come for a swim with me?
Hoka was wrong, Jen-ai.
You're not like a man at all.
This village we are coming to
will be our last visit.
We head back for Yang Cheng
in the morning.
The baby should be covered.
Do you want it to die?
If it dies, I'll get another.
It is easy to get babies. Ask your man.
Be quiet. Did you steal this child?
No! No!
It's a girl child, worthless.
A beggar gave it to me.
I hope to find a woman with pity
who would take it.
I'll take it from you. I'll adopt it.
But I need money.
How much?
Jen-ai.
10 yuan.
Jen-ai, you can't be serious.
All I have is this lucky piece from England.
Could you lend me some money?
Not for this idiocy, no.
Sixpence. English money.
-No.
-Take it.
If you don't, the child will die,
and you'll have nothing.
Don't you see how stupid
and pointless this is?
You can't adopt
every abandoned baby in China.
No, just the ones I'm offered.
What are you going to do with her?
Call her Sixpence. Do you like it?
I said what are you going you do with her?
What do you know about babies?
What is there to know?
When they're dirty, wash them.
When they're hungry, feed them.
We'll find an inn and do both.
I will feed the baby, Jen-ai.
I spoke to my husband about it.
Why don't you let us keep her?
We have no girls.
No.
Aren't you being a little selfish?
It's right for her to be with them.
I like her. I don't want to give her up.
WOMAN: Where will you eat,
you and your friend?
Jen-ai and her friend will eat outside
so that they may quarrel
in peace like true friends.
Why do you think it's more right
for Sixpence to stay with them?
'Cause you think she'll mind one day
having a white mother?
'Cause you may mind one day
having a Chinese child.
But how can you say that?
Because I know.
My mother was Chinese,
my father Dutch.
He took us to his country
after China made him rich.
It was a great novelty
having a beautiful Chinese wife.
Till the embarrassment started coming
and the insults.
Then he divorced her and sent her back.
She was a gentle little woman.
She never recovered from it.
He kept me with him.
An empty man needs sons.
I didn't look very Chinese as a child.
Then the day came
I wasn't a child anymore.
And I don't want Sixpence ever to tell you
what I told him the day I left him.
But you were hurt, Lin Nan.
Oh, do you think I would ever hurt a child?
No,
you wouldn't.
But what if you marry?
Oh, that won't happen.
You said it before.
How can you be so sure?
You've never met anyone you loved?
Nor anyone who loved me.
Ohh.
I'm not attractive in that way.
But
don't you know you're beautiful?
Once in her life,
every woman should have that said to her.
I thank you for being the one
who said it to me.
Oh, it's late. I...
I better go in.
May I have the baby?
Yang! Yang! She's coming! She's coming!
I can't wait to see the Hsien Chang's face
when he hears his foot inspector
has a baby now.
He'll take it calmly.
They always light firecrackers
when I come home.
-Hello, children.
No scolding! They were good!
We were wonderful.
The noise scared her.
Ahh.
These are my children.
This is my big daughter, Sui-Lan,
and my little girl, Mai-Da,
and my big son
and my little son, Bao Bao.
Children, this is Colonel Lin.
Mother, you forgot to say my name.
It's the same as yours. Lin.
Lin?
Yes, yes, we call him Lin.
Children, this little baby's your new sister.
Her name is Sixpence.
Yang, we can handle one more, can't we?
Can five be more trouble than four?
I... I found Lin soon after you left
and I felt you were my first friend in China,
so naturally, I named him after you.
I hope you don't mind.
No, I don't mind.
And so you lectured her
on the difficulties of raising children.
Ha! She thrives on difficulties.
She's a very forceful woman.
Yes. Yes, she is,
but she's also gentle and trusting.
She walks through a world full of evil
and sees only children,
not complicated or cruel,
just untidy ones
needing to be washed and fed and loved.
I see this trip has been eventful for you.
And for Jen-ai?
I don't know.
In any case, I shall be leaving soon.
And returning?
No.
Are you troubled, Colonel?
Confused.
A sign of growth.
When first we met,
you were not capable of confusion.
You were sure of everything.
That's the way I must be.
My life is planned.
A life that is planned
is a closed life, my friend.
It can be endured, perhaps.
It cannot be lived.
Excuse me, Hsien Chang.
Write a letter to Jen-ai.
Write and tell her
the colonel sings the praises
of my foot inspector
which honors me
and ask her to dine with us this evening.
Also tell her I am sending her
something which was intended
as a gift for her name day.
I think this is a more appropriate occasion.
MAN: The honorable tax collector!
Hsien Chang, are you well?
I am well, tax collector.
This is our guest, Colonel Lin.
Our city is honored, Colonel.
MAN: The honorable foot inspector!
I thought it would give you pleasure
if she joined us.
Look at the elders. They're stunned.
They've never dined here
with a lone woman before.
Officially, that is.
Are you well, Hsien Chang?
I am well, Jen-ai,
and well-pleased
my foot inspector is beautiful.
So you see, Jen-ai,
more than one man has told you that.
It's the Hsien Chang's gift that is beautiful.
Yes, that, too.
I am also well-pleased
with my own judgment.
No disrespect to Hsien Chang's gift.
It is his foot inspector who is beautiful.
You're confusing me.
Many people are confused these days.
Let us have dinner and wine and music
and discuss it further.
We will dine!
When you left me at the inn
I thought you were angry.
You were wrong, Jen-ai.
Colonel.
Jen-ai.
Colonel, I'm afraid it is the old China
which impresses Jen-ai.
No. I like all of it.
I know there are beautiful things
in other places,
but I couldn't see until I came here.
Sometimes, I think my life
really started in China.
Colonel Lin?
Yes?
I'll be just a few minutes.
Well, it seems to be starting.
Enemy troops are massing at
several points along our borders.
Is my city in danger?
Not yet, certainly.
Though you never know
where they'll strike
or when or if.
Hsien Chang, I must go now.
May I ask a favor?
A moment alone with Jen-ai.
Go into the garden.
I told you once that I have
few personal feelings.
You were trying to be unkind.
Perhaps I'm being even more unkind now.
I've many personal feelings,
for you, all of them.
What I wanted to say to you,
I... I tried not to say,
I was afraid to say,
but I cannot leave
with the words unsaid.
There's nothing you can't say to me.
Would it offend you to be loved
by a man of another race?
It would honor me.
That makes me very happy.
So let's leave it this way, Jen-ai,
till I come back.
Look, Mother.
Children, come down from there.
Oh, children. Here. Wait here
until I get back for you.
There is food in the basket.
Sui-Lan, watch out for them. Be brave.
Jen-ai! Jen-ai!
What is to become of us?
Tell me what to do!
Take the children whose parents
are gone to my inn!
Are you hurt?
No.
Yang! Yang!
Yang!
To the square, everybody!
Everybody go to the square!
Have you seen Yang?
I don't know. Go to the square.
The Hsien Chang wants everyone!
Citizens of Yang Cheng,
Japanese soldiers are close to us
less than a day's march away.
We will take refuge in the mountains,
on the farms in the small villages.
The officials and I will
stay close to Yang Cheng
to keep watch and to send word to you
when it is safe to return.
Go now and work for your city
and your brothers.
Go to the west gate. It is time now.
To the west gate! It is time!
To the west gate, everyone.
To the west gate.
Jen-ai!
Li, what are you doing here?
The prison has been destroyed.
Many were killed.
The few who survived have been set free.
I have come to help.
Jen-ai, we found Yang.
Where is he?
He's behind the marketplace.
-Is he hurt?
-Badly.
I'll come!
Li, you go on with the children.
Follow the Hsien Chang.
I'll see you in Peh-Chu.
You're staying here alone?
I must say good-bye to an old friend.
Very tired.
I die soon.
Not so bad to die.
Not good, but not so bad.
Not to worry, Miss Gladys, not to worry.
No sign of the enemy, sir, or anyone else.
The others are still searching,
but the city seems abandoned.
Possibly, a week.
All right, we go in.
Groups of six, five minutes apart.
Tell the men.
-Lieutenant Wong?
-Yes, sir.
You come with me.
Sergeant Wu, Sergeant Ching,
Sergeant Fong.
Lin Nan!
Oh!
You are alive.
So many things to tell
and so many things to ask.
All I can think of is
can Sixpence walk now?
Yes.
Yes, and she said her first word last week.
What was it?
She said no.
What is it?
It's the elders celebrating their return.
We were close by in the hills
with the Hsien Chang
and we saw you ride in.
Jen-ai, is the Hsien Chang
in the Hsien-Cheng-Fu?
Yes.
I have to talk to him
and to you.
Hsien Chang!
Ah, you have found each other.
This is a happy night for many reasons.
They will be glad to see the last of us
at Peh-Chu, thanks to this young woman.
You should see the orphans
she has collected there.
10, 15, I've lost count.
Captain, start on with the men. I'll follow.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I thought there would be a little time.
Soon there will be all the time in the world.
Our troops are advancing.
The enemy has been pushed back.
No, Hsien Chang.
They've been withdrawn
to join a powerful army
which has just crossed our border.
We'll bring up everything
we have to meet it.
The war is just beginning.
They will have to put up with us
a little longer at Peh-Chu.
No, Hsien Chang.
You must leave tonight with the elders
for the town of Lao.
But Lao is in another province.
Exactly.
If you were captured here,
the enemy could use you
as a puppet governor,
issue orders through you,
which the people would obey.
You speak as if we were defeated!
The battle has not yet been fought!
We will be defeated.
We'll hold them up as long as we can,
but they'll push us back, mile by mile
till they suddenly burst through
and pour across the north like a river.
I must tell the elders.
They are at the temple
offering thanks for their homecoming,
but we will sit down
together, one last time.
You could go with him,
but Shencheng is better.
It's army headquarters.
I'll be sure of finding you there.
You'll find me right here
or in the hills nearby, where I belong.
All missionaries and foreigners
are being ordered out of this area.
If it is true, that doesn't apply to me.
I'm not an accredited missionary
and I'm a Chinese citizen, not a foreigner.
But it isn't true, is it?
You don't lie very well.
I want you to promise me you will go.
I want you out of it.
Don't wish me out of this
or in any way seek to get me out
for I will not be got out.
These are my people
and I will live and die with them.
I want you to be safe.
I'm afraid for you.
Oh, I'm afraid for you, too.
So many men will die,
but I don't love you any less for leaving.
Do you think I love you less for staying?
Jen-ai, life was good to bring us together.
Two people who thought that
they had to live without love.
And tonight again, when everything
seemed against it,
we found each other.
But isn't it asking too much,
even of God, if there is a God,
to hope that we will meet again
if you stay here?
Whatever you decide, let Hoka know.
I'll get in touch with him.
Whatever you decide,
I love you.
As long as I'm alive,
I will love you.
These robes, in farewell to the past,
mine and China's.
In a little while, we must leave our city
perhaps for years, perhaps forever.
For those of us who are old,
certainly forever.
Elders of Yang Cheng,
I thank you for your help
in this time of trouble,
but we were born to our trouble.
There is one who has taken it upon herself
not from necessity but from love.
Jen-ai,
we thank you for those who are not here,
for the dead, whose children
you have taken as your own,
for the poor and the sick and the afflicted,
for all the people of Yang Cheng,
for the past and for the future.
I honor you for your strength.
I wish to share with you
the faith from which it comes.
City recorder,
close the books of Yang Cheng
with this entry.
As a sign of respect
for the honored foot inspector
of this city,
the Hsien Chang of Yang Cheng
has become a Christian.
Oh, I...
I thank you for this... For this great gift.
I can't... I can't...
Jen-ai,
accept my gift.
It is offered with love.
It is time to go, old friends.
Stay here in the Hsien-Cheng-Fu for a little.
It will comfort me as I leave to know it.
We shall not see each other again, I think.
Farewell,
Jen-ai.
How many more can we lose?
When the Japanese have gone,
if any of our men are still alive, help them.
This is all the food I can spare.
I wish I could keep you here longer
but it isn't safe.
Be careful and good luck.
If you'd gone when the colonel told you,
you wouldn't have so many children.
Have you any news of Colonel Lin?
No. Many soldiers are trapped in Tsechow.
-He might be there.
-She hit me.
I want to speak to you.
Go. Go and play.
There, the Japanese are. Here we are
with only Tsechow in between.
There's only one thing to do...
Get out while you have the chance.
That's what I'd planned
if they came that close,
but that was before I had 50 children.
There's no place for them.
There's no room in Peh-Chu.
I thought of the mountain caves,
but it's getting too cold.
We have to stay here.
That's foolishness. Get out
while you have the chance.
I would if I knew where l
could get food for the children,
medical care, schooling, all that they need.
At least the inn is on neutral ground.
It's owned by the mission.
I don't think anyone would hurt them.
You think the Japanese will feed them?
They're human beings. They might.
Oh, I don't know.
You've been awake all night.
I don't know what to do.
I've thought. I've prayed. I...
It's no use. I can't find an answer.
I've started the stove.
I'll bring you some good hot tea.
-And then...
Wait! Wait!
Your friend ran after
the men who brought us.
They were afraid.
All the way from Tsechow,
they were afraid.
I thought Tsechow was taken.
It was, but our missionary got us out.
We're from the mission orphanage.
I see.
Where were the men
supposed to take you?
Do you know?
To you, if your name is Jen-ai.
I've a letter for you from our missionary.
My name is Timothy.
I couldn't catch the men.
There must be 50 of them.
Oh, Li, the answer came.
It's from the missionary in Tsechow.
He wouldn't leave his hospital,
but there's a home
for the children in the interior
with a school and everything
and they'll take ours.
We have to get them to the mission
at Sian by November 12th.
The army trucks which will take them
must leave on that date.
But that is three weeks away!
And it'll only take one week
on the Honan Road.
Oh! "These children will be met in Sian
"and taken the rest of the way
"by the head of the mission center,
Dr. Robinson."
Dr. Robinson.
Oh, children!
Oh!
Hurry up, men!
Get out of your uniforms quickly.
He's coming, Colonel!
She wasn't there.
There's no one in Yang Cheng
but a few old people.
Where did she go?
Sian, with the children and Li,
by way of the Honan Road.
Honan Road.
The Japanese have a roadblock
on the Honan Road
30 miles south of Yang Cheng.
When did she leave?
Yesterday afternoon. On foot.
On foot
with 20 children to slow her down.
With 100 children to slow her down.
100 children.
Jen-ai.
Jen-ai!
Lin Nan.
I didn't think I'd reach you in time.
You're walking into an enemy roadblock.
Oh. Oh! I have to get
these children to Sian.
I can't go back. Not a handful
would survive the winter.
But the roadblock...
I can get them across the mountains.
But it's twice as long, terribly dangerous
and impossible for you alone
on foot with 100 children.
I can't go with you.
My orders are to start the resistance here
with the people and soldiers left.
You'd only put us in danger,
you or any soldier.
This way, if we're caught,
I can explain who we are...
If you're given the chance to explain.
If the journey doesn't kill you.
No. No. I think this journey
was meant for me.
Lin Nan, I think this is why God
wanted me to come to China,
to get these children out.
Remember to avoid the traveled roads
and look for the hidden ones.
I've marked the distance
you should cover each day
to reach Sian in time.
When you get there,
go to army headquarters.
They will try to get
a message through to me.
Then you're not going to
ask me to stay in Sian
or to go to safety in the interior
with the children?
I know you too well for that now
and I love you too much.
I know you'll come back if you can.
I'll give it to our oldest son one day.
You must go while there's still light.
A safe journey,
a happy return.
Timothy, take Sixpence a while.
I thought the big boys
were carrying the pot.
They're playing a game.
It is good that they're in high spirits.
I'd like to keep them that way
as long as we can.
Three more days and our food is gone.
But here is the village.
I know the people will help us.
We should be there in about two days.
Should we stop and let them rest?
Let us go on a little longer while it is light.
Up.
Come on, children.
Some rice.
There. Now you two share that bowl.
Give me that.
You two share it.
There.
Now you share it with her.
Go over there.
There's so little food in this soup.
It's hot. It'll fill their stomachs
until they fall asleep.
And when they wake?
I could have 10 more bowls full.
Big talk. Big stomach.
Children, run down the road.
Keep going.
Come on, children.
Hurry up.
We'll try and find a crossing upstream.
Children, come down here. Be very careful.
Children, come down this way.
Careful.
It's too deep.
It's over my head.
Too dangerous.
And cold. Very cold.
But we can't stop now.
If we had a rope,
we could tie one end to a tree
and one of us could get across
with the other end.
And then we could make a big fire.
Jen-ai, we have some rope and blankets.
Children, you know what
the coldest sound in the world is?
Well, it's teeth chattering.
And that is all I can hear.
Do you know what we are going to do?
We're going to sing a song
and drown it out.
Take your jacket off.
We're going to sing... You know this one.
Hold it up. There.
We're going to sing, you know.
This old man
He played one
He played knick-knack on my drum
Knick-knack paddywack
Give the dog a bone
This old man came
Rolling home
Come on.
This old man
He played one
He played knick-knack on my drum
With a knick-knack paddywack
Give a dog a bone
This old man came rolling home
This old man
He played two
He played knick-knack on my shoe
With a knick-knack paddywack
Give a dog a bone
This old man came rolling home
This old man
He played three
He played knick-knack on my knee
It's quiet. Too quiet.
So are the children.
Children!
Run! Come on!
Under the trees!
Come on!
Get up.
Come.
Children, get up.
Get up, children.
Come on, children.
Come.
Oh! They are ours! They are Chinese.
Woman, where you taking those children?
I'm trying to get them to Sian.
We've been walking for days.
The children are starving.
Men, feed the children.
Thank you. Do you think
the airplane will come back?
I don't know. They were
reconnaissance, I think.
We had to hide too.
Yesterday we saw some Japanese soldiers
in the forest you're coming to.
It's very dangerous. There may be more.
We have no other way to go.
I wish we could help you
but our orders take us north.
Anywhere near Yang Cheng?
I don't know.
If you should get near Yang Cheng
and you run into a man
called Lin, Colonel Lin...
Would you give him a message?
Tell him you met a woman
with 100 children
only six days from the Yellow River.
And tell him to stay alive.
Just to stay alive.
How good it was to see them eat.
It would be good to see you eat.
Drink this. One of the soldiers
gave me a pinch of tea.
This forest... This is where
we're going to lose time.
No path, the children running off.
I got this chalk from one of the soldiers.
What do you want that for?
I want to leave ahead of you and scout.
But if there's danger ahead.
I could mark the trees
with this chalk as a guide.
The children could make a game
of looking for the marks.
It would hurry them too.
We'd better stay together.
I don't want you to go alone.
Alone or together,
we'll meet what we're meant to,
danger or safety.
I'll wait for you at the end of the forest.
Mother,
you are worried, aren't you?
I'm just tired.
We must all sleep.
Mother,
do you think we'll be in time
for the trucks on the 12th?
Of course, Sui-Lan. We'll be in time.
We must be in time.
Mother,
when you take us to Sian
you're going back, aren't you?
To Yang Cheng.
Oh, Mother, will I ever see you again?
-Oh, Sui-Lan.
-Oh, Mother.
Sui-Lan.
You and Lin and the three little ones,
you're mine. You're my family.
We'll keep together. I promise you.
I'll just be gone for a little while.
You'll go to school,
and I'll be so proud of you.
And when the war is over
we'll all go home.
We'll all go home.
Yes.
I'll look after the little ones.
Until you come back to us.
Oh, my mother, you come back to us.
You come back for us.
Come back for us.
Oh, Sui-Lan.
I found one!
I found another one.
I found one.
I see another.
Sit down, children,
wherever you are. Sit down.
Don't move until I get back.
Be very quiet. Sui-Lan, watch them.
Timothy. Timothy, come with me.
"If you keep My commandments
"you shall abide in My love
"even as I have kept
My Father's commandments
"and abide in His love.
"These things I have spoken unto you
"that My joy might remain in you
"and that your joy might be full."
This is My commandment...
That ye love one another
as I have loved you.
Greater love hath no man than this
that a man lay down his life
for his friends.
How far have we got to go? I'm hungry.
I'm hungry.
I'm tired.
I'm tired too.
Children, children, no. We can't stay here.
We can't stay here.
I know you're tired and hungry
but this is the last mountain
we are going to cross.
And then... Then we'll see the Yellow River
and ride across to Sian.
Now, you must think how happy
our good friend Li, who is in heaven
would be for us.
There. Now
try to be brave
just a little longer.
Now.
Come on, children.
Come on.
Look! The river.
Oh. Children, the river!
Oh, Sixpence, look!
Look at the river.
Go. Let's go.
Dr. Robinson.
Have you any news?
No. But today is November 12th
and the trucks are at the depot.
You'll have to leave.
We're not leaving without those children.
That last message said
they were six days away.
That was nearly two weeks ago.
The mountains they are going through
are controlled by the enemy
and almost impassible...
I know, but...
There's practically no chance
for them to get through.
I know. The whole city knows.
That's why we've been praying
night and day for those children.
Why we'll continue to pray and to wait.
I'm sorry, Doctor, but...
This old man
Came rolling home
He played one
He played knick-knack on my drum
With a knick-knack paddywack
Give a dog a bone
The children! The children! They are here!
This old man
The children from Tsechow.
Knick-knack on my shoe
With a knick-knack paddywack
Give a dog a bone
This old man came rolling home
This old man
He played three
He played knick-knack on my knee
With a knick-knack paddywack
Give a dog a bone
This old man came rolling home
This old man
He played four
He played knick-knack on my door
With a knick-knack paddywack
Give a dog a bone
This old man came rolling home
This old man
He played five
He played knick-knack on my hive
With a knick-knack paddywack
Give a dog a bone
This old man came rolling home
This old man
He played six
He played knick-knack on my sticks
With a knick-knack paddywack
Give a dog a bone
This old man came rolling home
This old man, he played seven
He played knick-knack oh, my heaven
With a knick-knack paddywack
Give a dog a bone
This old man came rolling home
This old man
He played eight
Quiet. Quiet. Quiet.
These are the children from the north.
We've been waiting for you.
It was a long journey.
I'm sorry we are late.
Late? Oh!
Dr. Robinson, do you remember me?
My name used to be Gladys Aylward.
Yes.
I remember you.
Gladys Aylward
who wasn't qualified to come to China.
Will you come with us
to our children's village?
No one would be more valuable.
Thank you, but I'm
going back to Yang Cheng.
I'm going home.