War_and_Peace_(1956) ,WEB_MKV_H264(Paramount,Eng,Ita,Rus) 1280x720
As the 19th century began,
a darkening shadow
moved across Europe.
This shadow was propelled
by the voice of one man,
Napoleon Bonaparte.
Only Russia and England
offered impressive resistance.
Over Russia, the weather was clear,
the sun was shining.
Napoleon was 1,000 miles away,
and the streets of Moscow
were excellent for parades.
Splendid sights,
splendid men, eh, Pierre?
- For parades.
- What do you mean by that?
Remember, I've seen
the French marching, too.
Don't tell me
they march better than that.
- Led by the greatest man in Europe.
- Bonaparte?
Bonaparte.
A usurper! A murderer!
A deposer of kings!
A colossus!
A fresh wind! A cleansing force!
What does your father say
when he hears you?
We don't talk about things like that,
my father and I.
- How is he?
- The doctors say he'll die any moment.
- Have you been to see him?
- I'm waiting to be asked.
In heaven, all things will be arranged.
I believe that's the rumour.
This is your home
when you want it to be,
and the Rostovs are your family
when you want them to be.
I smoke too much.
Isn't it lovely? How can you bear
not to go with them?
I can bear it.
If I were a man, I'd be down there,
riding a terrible black horse,
waving a sword.
It's so unfair.
Men are the only people
permitted to have any fun.
What is it, Natasha?
Those handsome young men
marching away to fight.
They could be killed.
Don't be frightened. Come on.
Nicholas!
Now, what's this?
You look so dazzling in your uniform.
And you're going so far away.
Austria's miles,
I looked it up on the map.
That brute, Napoleon.
The Austrians make beautiful
bracelets. I'll bring you one.
- Two! They're wearing them in pairs!
- Two.
Pierre, you remember our cousin,
Sonya. She's come to stay.
Yes, though she was considerably
younger the last time I saw her.
Girls grow up, Pierre. Very fast.
Doesn't he look glorious?
Mama and Papa have
such handsome children!
Did you hear that?
Now, attention!
Ensign Count Nicholas Rostov,
I decorate you with the Order of...
...Absolutely Everything!
Don't laugh when she jokes
about the army.
Well, Petya,
you have to humour women a little!
You do look shiny, Nicholas.
If only I was old enough.
That'll come.
By that time, there won't be
a Frenchman left to be killed!
Don't worry, there'll always be
plenty of Frenchmen.
- Good luck.
- That's very civil of you.
- But why not take a commission?
- It's so easy for you men.
You decide to do something, then do it.
If you were a man, what would you do?
I'd become enormously powerful.
I'd become the Czar's most trusted
minister, and he'd consult me.
And you would sit at my right hand.
Whenever anything was complicated,
the case would be laid before you
as judge.
Why me?
Because your heart is pure
and you're good.
Well done, my dear.
On that note, I think I should leave.
If you had that power,
what would you do?
I?
I would hesitate. Now I must go.
- Pierre, come again soon.
- I'll walk you to the door.
- "Au revoir."
- Come soon again.
Come again soon.
Mama and Papa will be awfully
lonely with Nicholas gone.
- They do love seeing you.
- Of course. I love the whole family.
The whole family?
That's not as simple as you think.
What do you mean?
There are currents and counter-currents.
Au revoir.
Now, where are you going?
Dolokhov's rooms?
I am. How did you know?
I hear things, I hear things.
Go. Go to your night of disgusting,
fascinating debauchery.
Au revoir.
Bravo! Bravo!
- Careful, there's a bet on here.
- Fetch me a bottle of rum!
You two, break this out.
Now, let's get this straight.
Fifty imperials against Prince Anatole
that I drink a bottle of rum
without taking it from my mouth,
balancing on the outside ledge
without touching the sides of the window.
- Want to make it a hundred?
- Fifty is enough for you to lose.
Get down from there, you weaklings.
- Hercules, come on!
- Come on!
You do it!
Hail Moscow!
Give me that!
Don't be crazy, you'll be killed.
Touch me again,
I'll throw you down there.
That goes for every one of you.
Play! Play!
What are we paying you for?
Now then, my friends.
Remember, without taking the bottle
from your lips.
Bravo!
Fifty imperials, Anatole!
And double for anyone else
who will do it.
I'll do it for nothing, without a bet!
- You get dizzy walking up steps!
- Out of my way!
Give me a bottle!
Get down from there.
- Get down from there, Pierre.
- Let him do it.
Your father is calling for you.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
I suggest a little cold water first.
I'll wait for you.
Prince Andrei,
is the old boy really dying?
The doctors are certain
Count Bezukhov won't last the night.
- Are my father and sister there?
- He was there. She was expected.
That's good. I don't have to go.
The family's well represented.
Careful, careful.
You disapprove of me? Of course.
You'd be wrong if you didn't.
Arriving at the deathbed of my father
bleary-eyed, stinking of alcohol.
He disapproves, too, my father.
That's fair enough. I disapprove
of many things about him.
Chiefly, I disapprove of the fact
that he didn't marry my mother.
Perhaps, if I was legitimate...
I have sinned, Lord,
but I have several excellent excuses.
With all that, Andrei,
you still disapprove?
You're not being worthy of yourself.
You're not living up to the best things
in yourself. Be somebody!
That's where the puzzle begins,
be somebody. Be what? Who am I?
Am I the next Count Bezukhov,
lord of vast estates,
with a fixed position,
fixed responsibilities?
Not quite!
My father cannot quite acknowledge
that I am his son.
But he cannot quite acknowledge
that I am not his son.
That makes everybody uncomfortable,
including myself.
- You must aim at something.
- You're right, I agree with you.
Each morning I wake up,
I'm disgusted with myself
with what I did the night before.
I tell myself, "Today, a change."
If my headache is bad enough,
I say, "Pierre...
"...today you must take steps
to become a saint."
I drop into the club
and watch the card-playing,
just order a glass of water to prove
how marvellously I resist temptation.
Then someone comes along
and says, "Just one vodka, Pierre."
Next morning, my headache is worse,
my pockets are emptier.
There must be
something you want to do.
I want to discover... everything!
I want to discover why I know
what's right and still do what's wrong.
I want to discover what happiness is,
and what value there is in suffering.
I want to discover why men go to war,
and what they really say
deep in their hearts when they pray.
I want to discover what men and
women feel when they say they love.
There's enough to keep me busy.
It's hard to understand someone like me.
Everything is so clear for you.
- You know exactly what you must do.
- Oh, exactly!
You're different from me.
You study, you become enlightened.
I study, I become confused.
You love, you marry. You believe,
you act. There's a war, you serve.
If only I really answered
to your description.
- You do.
- Shall I show you how wrong you are?
- I know you. I'm not wrong.
- Know why I'm going to the war?
Because I regard Napoleon
as a monster?
Because I believe we should fight
Austria's battles 2,000 miles away?
Because Russia will be
a greater nation after the war?
Then, why?
Because I married the most loving
and attractive woman in Moscow,
and I can't stand it.
Never marry, Pierre.
Or only when you're old
and good for nothing,
or else everything noble in you
will be lost.
You'll waste yourself on trifles.
Yes. Don't look at me like that.
You talk of Bonaparte's career.
If Bonaparte had married young,
he'd still be on half-pay,
carrying his wife's handbag,
inviting idiots to his house because
his wife wanted invitations to theirs!
- Prince Andrei.
- Princess Hélene.
You told my brother he was expected?
- I did.
- Isn't he coming?
I believe not.
Thank you.
How is he, Prince Vasili?
His confessor is with him.
They are giving him extreme unction.
He was asking for you.
I hope you are in a proper condition
to see him this time.
Follow me.
Go ahead. I'll wait for you here.
If you please, Monsieur Pierre.
He wishes you to kiss him goodbye.
This is for you.
Now he would like to sleep.
Pierre...
So late.
Finally, at the end, he loved me.
He gave me this.
This letter is for the Czar.
- And this one for you, Pierre.
- Open it.
"Your father, in his letter to the Czar,
"he begs that you be legitimately
acknowledged as his son
"and the next Count Bezukhov,
the sole heir to all his estates."
Be worthy, my boy.
Be worthy of your great father.
How often we sin.
How much we deceive, and for what?
It all ends in death.
Kiss your cousin, Hélene,
he has been reborn.
Embrace him. Wish him well.
It's a good thing
we're going back to Moscow.
After three weeks in the country,
I can hardly keep my eyes open.
Still, it was a profitable trip,
wasn't it, Pierre?
Very profitable.
I'll see how long we have to wait.
There's no hurry. It'll give Papa
a few extra winks of sleep.
Andrei!
Pierre!
- Where are you going? Your father's?
- Yes. Tell me your news.
- Are you alone?
- No. Prince Vasili is with me.
And his daughter, too.
We made a tour of inspection of
my estates. It's huge and backward.
Now I'm Count Bezukhov,
I must do something about it.
That's why you went
with Prince Vasili and Hélene.
Prince Vasili helps me
with the administration.
Of course.
Say hello to Lise.
She's miserable at being
stuck in the country.
Hélene loves the country.
It was her idea to come.
I'm sure.
- Children, go away!
- How long are you here?
For ever.
Months and months and months!
Until after the baby is born.
No, thank you.
Andrei's leaving tomorrow.
He thought it'd be better for me here
than alone in Moscow.
How do you feel about it?
I dread it.
Even so, you consented
to bury yourself down here?
Andrei wants me to.
If it were I,
I'd find something else to do.
I suppose so.
But we're very different.
Indeed we are.
- Have you asked her to marry you?
- No.
Are you going to?
I don't know yet.
- Do you want some advice?
- On any subject. Not on this.
All right.
Andrei! Lise!
We thought you'd never come.
Lise, you look so beautiful.
- You, too, Mary.
- No, I'm just a country mouse.
It isn't true what you wrote,
that you're only staying overnight?
- I'm afraid it is.
- Lise, talk to him. Make him stay.
- I've tried.
- Lise's very tired. She'd better rest.
- Yes?
- Your father would like to see you.
Thank you.
You'd better go upstairs, Lise.
You'll see him at dinner.
Come!
Here's the warrior!
Here's the Bolkonsky
that's going to beat Napoleon.
How are you, my boy?
I'm well, Father. How is your health?
The same, boy, the same.
Only fools fall ill.
You know me,
busy from morning till night.
Little to eat, less to drink,
of course I'm well.
- Thank God.
- God has nothing to do with it.
Just a moment, please.
- Don't refuse.
- What is it?
Father's father used to take it
along with him... in all his wars.
If it's not too heavy
and won't break my neck.
Promise that you'll never take it off.
- Promise?
- Yes.
Kiss me here.
Thank you, my boy.
- Why do you thank me, Father?
- For doing your duty.
For not allowing yourself
to be tied to a woman's apron strings.
The army before everything.
Thank you, thank you.
About my wife, Father...
Your wife? Go on, speak.
When her confinement is due,
send to Moscow for a doctor.
- A doctor?
- No one can do nature's work.
But they've been telling her things
and she's had a dream.
She's frightened.
All right, all right.
Give this to Michael Kutuzov.
We were at school together.
He wasn't exactly a bright lad,
but never mind.
I've written to tell him
to keep you away from headquarters.
They're bad places.
Tell him I remember him
and admire him.
Now, goodbye.
Remember this, Prince Andrei.
If they kill you,
it will hurt me, your old father.
But, if you don't behave like the son
of Nicholas Bolkonsky, it will be worse.
I shall be shamed.
You needn't have said that to me, Father.
I... also wanted to ask you,
if I am killed and I have a son,
don't let him be taken away from you.
Let him grow up here.
With you. Please.
What are you waiting for?
We've said goodbye. Go! Go!
Andrei, you're leaving already?
Don't go, don't leave me here.
I'll be so lonely.
I'll leave you here
with my father and Mary.
Stay until tomorrow.
Stay another day.
I can't, Lise, you know that!
You're delighted to go.
You're delighted to get rid of me!
Andrei, Andrei...
Bye, Mary.
Katya, get some smelling salts.
Tell the silly horse to stop shaking
its head. I'll never get it.
You heard the lady,
stop shaking your head.
You see? Animals are much
more reasonable than people.
Might I offer you a million roubles
to paint my portrait?
But you must make me
look at least as good as the horse!
It's not fair to look at it
before it's finished.
- Very unpromising, isn't it?
- Yes, it is.
You needn't be
in such a hurry to agree.
It's not meant to be a work of art.
Papa bought the colt for Nicholas.
I'll send him the picture
to show him what it's like.
- Have you finished?
- For the moment.
Charge! Come on! Hurry!
Come on! Come on!
- Have you heard from Nicholas?
- Papa received a letter. Not me.
Men forget about women when at war.
- Men don't, boys do.
- Nicholas would be furious at that!
- He'd challenge you to a duel.
- It's a better reason than most.
The reason he wrote
was for more money.
He lends money to his captain
who loses it at cards.
The captain sounds a lot like Papa.
His name's Denisov.
He's got moustaches out to here.
He lisps and he's the bravest man
in the world.
Nicholas says
he's having a glorious time,
and we'll win the war soon.
He's beginning to feel quite sorry
for Napoleon.
Kill them! Come on, men!
Take that! Come on, charge!
There's no doubt,
wars must be very amusing.
- I must put it on my list.
- What list?
My list of the greatest human
pleasures in order of importance.
- I'd neglected war.
- What are the other pleasures?
The opera, eternal friendship,
summertime, dancing the mazurka,
the country in spring
and welcoming soldiers home.
- Have you any suggestions?
- Let me think.
To be able to believe in God,
to cause happiness, to love.
Love! Sonya's in love with Nicholas.
She cries every day in the morning
for a full hour.
- Don't you intend to fall in love?
- Many times but only for recreation.
And I'll keep changing partners
like a dance.
When I finally say,
"I love you," and mean it,
it'll be like a defeated general,
surrendering and handing his sword
to his enemy.
You'll change.
When you're young, everybody's
always telling you you'll change.
- Are you dining with us tonight?
- I have a previous engagement.
Oh? With whom?
My cousin, Princess Hélene.
Oh. I'd like to be like her
when I grow up.
I'd have to fill out around here, though.
Tall, proud, beautiful, cold
and untouchable.
With regiments of men
dropping at my feet.
I'm going to marry her, Natasha.
Gently, gently.
Who's surrendering his sword,
you or she?
Be happy, dearest Pierre.
I order you to be supremely happy.
I'll be leaving again directly. Wait.
I must deliver a message
to General Kutuzov immediately.
Well, I...
There's the General's aide.
Talk to him, Ensign.
I've just come from the picket lines.
I've a message
for the Commander-in-Chief.
His Excellency is in a council of war.
Give me the message.
A verbal message.
Deliver it to me now.
My squadron is on picket duty.
We saw the French put out their fires.
- The enemy's on the move, sir.
- Is that all?
Is that all?
I'd say you've seen no action yet,
am I right?
Good luck, my friend.
...it's apparent the enemy
has regrouped his position.
Surely now, you should consider
changing the orders for tomorrow.
Or rather for today,
for it is past midnight.
Gentlemen...
Gentlemen, the orders for tomorrow
cannot now be altered.
You've heard them,
and we shall all do our duty.
But, before a battle,
there is nothing more important...
...than to have a good sleep.
Goodnight.
- Goodnight, sir.
But, sir, if the French are
that far south of Austerlitz...
Plans!
After the battle, they'll have a hundred
reasons why the plans didn't work.
They'll blame everything
but themselves.
How do you think it will go tomorrow?
I think the battle will be lost.
We shall not have lost the war,
Andrei, because of this one battle.
There will be a peace...
...and then a new war.
Men like Napoleon can never stop
till their own ambition destroys them.
The only important battle is the last.
Goodnight.
Fire!
Sir, it looks as if the French
have broken our flank.
Captain, the Hussars must charge.
- You're wounded.
- The wound's not here, it's there!
Stop them!
Stop those cowards, Bolkonsky!
Forward, lads! Forward!
Forward!
That is a fine death.
Oh, he is alive!
Have him attended to
and take him to my bivouac.
Let my doctor examine his wounds.
- So early in the morning, Pierre.
- It's 11 o'clock.
- So early!
- We have a lot of shopping to do.
Oh, Pierre, I'm so tired.
All right, I'll go myself
and come back early.
- The morning papers, sir.
- Thank you.
- Anything amusing in "The Gazette?"
- No, we've lost again.
An armistice is going to be discussed.
Prisoners and wounded on both sides
will be immediately returned.
In a word, we're suing for peace.
- You sound bitter.
- Maybe I am.
What difference does it make,
a piece of Poland changes hands?
It's so boring
to worry about things like that!
- So, no more war.
- For the time being.
For the time being.
- Then the armies will be coming back.
- I suppose so.
Moscow will be very gay and exciting.
Pierre, why don't we stay here
and not go to the country?
Not this year.
It'll be such a gay season.
I'm not interested. Besides, I have
work at the hospital, the school.
They'll do just as well without you
in the hospital and the schools.
I promised those people.
Well, I never liked the idea!
Pierre, come here.
Listen, you know what we can do?
You go to the country all by yourself.
Do what you have to do.
Get the house ready,
then I'll join you in the spring.
The country's so dreary in the winter.
Please don't force it on me, Pierre.
If you must stay, stay,
but I'll be lost without you there.
Nonsense.
It will be good for the both of us.
And you'll appreciate me more when
you haven't seen me for some time.
I couldn't appreciate you more, Hélene.
If you only knew how many things
I have to do, dresses to have made,
lots of shoes and...
Why are you looking at me
like that? Why?
What does it mean?
Nothing, my dear.
They were defeated.
What are they cheering about?
Because they fought, because they're
alive, because they've come home.
I hope nothing's happened.
- Gracious! The young Captain!
- Prokofy!
Prokofy, is everything all right?
- The Lord be thanked. Yes.
- Good!
Nicholas!
Natasha!
You're back!
It's you, my dearest Nicholas!
Sonya!
- Look, it's him!
- Nicholas! Hurray!
- Papa!
- Nicholas!
Nicholas!
Nicholas...
Mama.
- You must be...?
- Your son's friend.
I know, Nicholas wrote to us.
Natasha, Sonya!
Welcome.
- Welcome.
- Sonya, it's wonderful!
Nicholas!
You haven't said hello to Sonya yet.
What's the sense of coming home
from a war, if that's all you do?
- Good morning.
- Ah, my pipe.
Rostov, wake up!
- Why, is it late?
- "It's 10 o'clock. Get up, Nicholas!"
Directly.
Is this your sabre? Or yours?
Get back, you Frenchman!
- Here I come!
- At last!
Why did you stay in bed so long?
I've been waiting for you to get up.
You're quite a man, aren't you?
I'm awfully glad you're my brother.
I want to know what men are like.
Are you the same as all of them?
- Natasha... Sonya's so young.
- Sonya's my dearest friend.
If she loves someone, she does it
for life. She loves us like that.
Remember before you went away?
She told me you're to forget all that.
"I will love him always, but let him
be free." Isn't that lovely and noble?
- I'll never go back on my word.
- But it won't do.
Because if you marry her
because of a promise,
it'll seem you're marrying her because
you must, and that wouldn't be right.
We'll talk it over later.
I'm so glad I have you!
- Are you still true to Pierre?
- Don't be silly!
I'll be a dancer and never marry.
Don't tell anyone.
Get dressed and we'll have breakfast.
Andrei!
Did you get my letter?
I met the doctor at the last relay point.
Are we in time?
- Let's hope so. We must pray for her.
- What a strange fate.
My darling, God is merciful.
I love you. I love you all.
I've never done any harm to anyone.
Why must I suffer so?
Andrei, please help me!
My boy, you have to leave now.
There, there, my dear.
No... no!
Upon my word, Rostov,
if I were to see fifty more operas,
I wager I might wind up liking them!
But... I do like the intermissions.
- I say, Rostov, that one, there.
- Yes?
She's superb.
But wait. Well!
- Where's the husband?
- Pierre...
He spends most of his time
in the country nowadays.
If I were the husband,
I'd come up from the country fast!
To the Emperor!
Listen, we took the bear
to the house of that actress,
and when the police tried to arrest us,
we tied one of them
on the back of the bear
and shoved them both into the river!
There they were, both swimming,
the man and the bear.
- Wake up! The party's still young!
- Don't be rough with him.
Always be polite to the husbands
of pretty women.
Let's drink to the health
of beautiful women!
Yes, to the health
of lovely women, huh, Pierre?
And to their lovers!
Here, look at this. It's a new song
written about General Kutuzov.
- That interests me.
- What?
I said that interests me.
Express your regrets
and he'll accept them.
No. What is there to talk about?
Is everything ready?
- No apologies.
- First, tell me how to use this thing.
It's very simple.
You cock it, there's the trigger.
Yes, I know, I just forgot.
No apologies. None whatever.
On the count of three,
begin to advance.
One, two, three.
Get away from here!
It's not over!
To your barrier! Stay where you are!
Cover yourself, you fool!
Well, now, the hero!
The dashing duellist!
My protector!
Thank you for defending my honour.
You believed that Dolokhov
was my lover. What did you prove?
That you are a fool! Now I'll be
the laughing stock of all Moscow!
Everyone will say
that you were drunk.
Challenging a man that
you were jealous of, without cause!
A man that is a better man
than you are in every way!
- We'd better separate.
- Separate?
That's a charming idea!
It's a wonderful idea!
It's the best idea you've had
in your whole life!
We'll separate, but you will pay for it!
You'll give me a fortune for it!
No!
Get out!
The count is waiting for you upstairs.
- What have you heard?
- Dolokhov won't die.
Thank God.
It's only easier to kill good men.
Men like Dolokhov
are only good for wars.
In between wars, they ought
to be locked up in cages. Here.
I'd like to leave Moscow.
I want to get away from these people
who believe it's normal to kill.
At the banquet,
when Dolokhov made the toast,
I looked across at him smiling at me,
I was convinced
of the guilt of my wife.
Is that a reason to kill?
Hélene was guilty, not Dolokhov.
I might have done the same thing.
Maybe it's even certain.
There we were, in the snow,
facing each other with pistols.
- You know who's guilty? I, only I.
- Pierre, don't be silly.
And you know why? Because
I married her without loving her.
I had to have her,
so I made myself blind.
I lied when I said to her, "I love you."
Because of that
there's Dolokhov stretched in pain,
alive only by the grace of God.
Because of my weakness, my lie.
I'm guilty. I must suffer for it.
You must stop thinking like this,
or it'll become an obsession.
Look, if you'll agree,
we'll all go to our place in the country.
And Nicholas wants to show it
to Denisov. Come with us?
Of course you'll come.
I'll tell the family. Mama!
Natasha, Sonya, Petya! Hurry!
We start for the country tonight.
Why didn't you tell me
Pierre was here?
We must start while the moon is high.
Ilya, what has happened?
What moon are you speaking of?
Is there more than one, my pet?
How long must we wait for Nicholas?
I'm happy you made up your mind.
The snow will be gone tomorrow!
Sonya, hurry.
- Order the troikas.
- Immediately!
We're off! Hurry, Nicholas,
you're delaying the trip to the country.
- The country?
- You can show Denisov. Come on!
- You'll like this.
- I was just beginning to enjoy Moscow!
Faster, faster, faster!
Faster, Nitka!
As we ride in the troika, you and I
Stars are twinkling up in the sky
Strains of sweet balalaika soft and low
Sleigh bells tinkling across the snow
Hold me close and kiss me, Katiusha
Let's be happy and gay, hey!
When I'm gone you'll miss me, Katiusha
Miss me many a day!
Nicholas!
- Come on, Pierre, it's your turn now!
- Hurry, hurry!
Young Nicholas!
Petya!
Ever since Nicholas joined the army,
he's become terribly efficient.
- I quite agree with you.
- Just a minute...
That's my friend, Prince Andrei
Bolkonsky. Can he join us?
- By all means!
- Do ask him.
Come on, Natasha!
Greetings! Good to see you.
I didn't know you were in the country.
The Rostovs invite you
to join the hunt.
I'm afraid anyone else's society would
give me more pain than pleasure.
Prince Andrei, may I present
the Countess Rostova.
And her brother, Petya Rostov.
I hope Pierre's convinced you to come.
It's the year's best hunt.
The huntsman's found a wolf
and cubs. We'd be so delighted if...
What I mean is you would enjoy it.
Perhaps I'll join you later.
- And stay to dinner?
- Possibly.
But you just said...
- Shall I come now?
- Wonderful!
- I'm glad you stayed tonight.
- So am I.
- The Rostovs are charming, no?
- Charming.
It's wonderful to watch them together,
like a race of handsome, healthy,
thoughtless animals.
- Thoughtless?
- Their most charming characteristic.
- All of them?
- All of them.
No.
Within a year or two,
Natasha will begin to think.
It'll make her even more charming
but less of a Rostov. Follow?
I think so.
Andrei, I think it's bad for you,
it's wrong to stay down here,
year after year, brooding,
living the life of a hermit.
Bad? Wrong?
Only two things in this life
are really wrong, Pierre,
remorse and illness, and
when I've recovered from them both,
- I'll go out in the world again.
- Why are you remorseful?
I was too late.
I let Lise die feeling unloved.
I was too busy on the trail of glory
to take the time to comfort my wife.
Well, I found glory.
I stopped the retreat of 100 men
for five minutes.
I was left for dead on a lost battlefield
in a lost war.
I'll stop being a hermit,
when I can forget all those things.
Well, I think I'd better go to bed now.
Goodnight, Pierre.
And thank you again.
Goodnight, Andrei.
- Natasha, come to bed, you'll catch cold!
- I can't sleep.
After a day like this,
it's impossible to sleep.
Come and see the moon.
Look how glorious it is.
- Sonya?
- Yes?
- Do you think Prince Andrei likes us?
- Of course.
He's so silent. It's as though
he's passing judgement on us.
- I'm frightened of him, aren't you?
- No.
I'm a little frightened, and yet
I wanted to take him by the hand,
look in his eyes and sing just for him.
Poor man, he'd never come again
if I'd done that.
Did you notice
he almost never smiles?
While I was singing,
I caught him looking at me.
He was smiling then.
And I felt...
It's almost impossible to describe.
I felt as if someone had given me
the most enormous, beautiful present.
- Come to bed, Natasha.
- You try to spoil everything!
On a night like this, I feel like
hugging myself tight and flying away!
- Take care, you'll fall.
- All right.
But it's a shame to go in
on such a night.
It's like hearing wonderful music,
and you know it's going to be
the most beautiful you've ever heard.
And being pulled away
and missing it for ever.
- For ever.
- Natasha!
All right.
- Nicholas, the expression on my face.
- What about it?
- Do I look disdainful?
- No!
- I'm sure I look disdainful.
- What for?
If I look disdainful, nobody will
notice this is my first ever ball.
- How's this? Better?
- That's much better.
Good.
You must promise
not to dance with me.
- No!
- No matter if no one says a word to me.
- Promise not to dance with me.
- Why?
Because it would be humiliating
if only my brother asks me to dance...
...out of pity.
- Promise?
- I promise.
- Nicholas, is everybody looking at me?
- Can't you see for yourself?
Not without changing the expression
on my face.
- There's one awful thing about you.
- Tell me! The whole truth!
No girl I'll ever meet
will be able to amuse me like you.
Don't talk like that.
Go and leave us to our fate.
- Nicholas, look after your mother.
- Comfortable, Mother?
Yes, my darling.
What a horrible mistake.
I shouldn't have come.
Nothing is going to happen.
The night is going to be one horrible,
black, degrading zero.
Count Denilov, meet my family.
Madame Maria Peronskaya.
You know my wife.
My niece, Sonya,
and my daughter, Natasha.
May I have the pleasure?
Oh, dear.
Perhaps I shall be more fortunate
later on. I shall try again.
- "Adieu."
- "Au revoir."
Denilov is our hostess' first cousin,
worth millions!
Second cousin, dear.
Ah, there's the French ambassador!
He looks as if he were a king.
You're rather late, you know?
Most of my dances are gone.
Why must I keep thinking
of Prince Andrei?
Am I so much in love with him
that all others seem ridiculous?
We saw so little of each other,
and yet I remember every moment.
If only he could have
brought me here tonight.
Why doesn't he like the city?
It isn't right for a man
to shut himself off as he does.
I am so delighted to see you again.
Will you honour me with this dance?
- Pierre, nice to see you.
- Pierre, my boy.
Will you honour me with this dance?
- Don't you just love dances?
- Not ordinarily.
- This is my first in two years.
- I'm so glad you did come.
I mean... Mama and Papa said it was
nice for you to visit after the hunt...
Tell them I intend to come and visit often.
- Very often, if they'll permit me.
- I shall tell them.
On moonlit nights, do you still want
to fly off to the moon?
- Where did you hear?
- My window was just below yours.
What a disaster! You heard everything.
No. You disappeared too soon.
- You must think I'm an utter idiot.
- No.
I don't think you're an idiot. I think...
Permit me. May I have
the pleasure of this dance?
Thank you.
What a joy it is to dance with her.
Like holding springtime in your arms.
Like holding a branch of lilac,
or a kitten.
Look at her now.
If she looks back at me
and smiles on the next turn,
she'll be my wife.
Guide us with thine infinite wisdom...
...teach us to abide in thy mercy,
and if it be thy will,
let this bed be my grave.
- I must talk to you just once more.
- Well, well...
It's about Prince Andrei, I suppose?
Thursday, Friday,
Saturday, Sunday, Monday...
Five days he hasn't been heard from.
First, he comes to see me every day
and quite turns my head,
then nothing happens.
Now, I'll tell you about myself
when I was young.
I had a cousin,
a handsome young man.
Yes, really handsome.
I know. Cyril Matveich.
- Must everything end up in nothing?
- You're being impulsive.
You must be patient. Very patient.
Wait till a proper proposal has been
made to you. He'll show up.
The last time, his proposal was
on the tip of his tongue.
He seemed so in love.
I'm always a little afraid
in his presence. What does it mean?
Does it mean that it's real love?
- Are you asleep?
- No, my pet.
I'm a little frightened myself.
- Now go.
- All the same, I shan't sleep.
Such a thing has never happened
to me before.
Could we ever
have thought it last spring
that we should meet at the ball?
It must be fate.
Clearly, it must be fate,
if everything led up to this.
Need one be ashamed of a widower?
No, darling, pray to God.
Marriages are made in heaven.
Mama, how I love you. I'm so happy!
Little Countess, are you asleep?
Yes, dear, I'm asleep. Goodnight.
Marry? Marry?
As though life were not
complicated enough as it is!
In such a hurry! You thought you
knew what you were doing last time!
- This is completely different.
- It always is!
Before I met her, life was sad,
meaningless, hopeless.
When you're over thirty, a man's life
should be sad and hopeless!
- Father...
- All right, all right.
Let's be reasonable.
Her family is nothing.
Nothing, compared to the Bolkonskys.
Her father was known
to chase every woman in Moscow.
Without success!
Now that he's grown older,
he's known to play
in every card game in Moscow.
Equally without success!
They're a happy family.
That's a success, too.
Perhaps the greatest success.
But you think
you're being fair to the girl?
You're much older than she.
You have a son to bring up.
Who'll take the responsibility?
A little chit of a girl?
I beg of you, put it off for just one year
and go abroad.
There's a peace mission to Prussia
for the signing of a treaty.
I know you wanted to go
on the mission.
After a year, if you still have this love
or obstinacy, you marry her.
That is my last word on the subject.
It's my last word!
Is it possible that I, Natasha, will be
the wife of this strange, dear man,
whom even my father looks up to?
Can it be true that there can be
no more playing with life?
That on me now lies the responsibility
of my every word and deed?
I have loved you
from the first moment I saw you.
- Do you love me?
- Yes, yes!
What is it? What's the matter?
I'm so happy.
- Did your mother explain?
- There's nothing to explain.
She told you it can't be for a year?
You're young, I want you to be sure.
- I am sure.
- One year's not long and you'll be free.
Lf, within that year,
you find you don't love me...
Don't say anything like that again!
- A year? I'm not going to see you?
- Of course.
- I must go to Poland for a few months.
- Is there nothing that can be done?
It's awful, I'll die waiting a year!
It's impossible, it's...!
No. I'll do anything, whatever you say.
We have the rest of our lives!
At Tilsit in Prussia,
on June 13th 1807,
Napoleon met with
Emperor Alexander of Russia,
for the purpose
of discussing a treaty of peace.
They can't help liking me.
I'm so willing
to do anything they wish.
So ready to be fond of him
for being his father.
- I'm Mary Bolkonsky.
- Charmed. My daughter, Natasha.
- How do you do?
- Good afternoon.
Excuse my father. He's not well
and asks me to welcome you.
Some tea?
- That would be...
- No, thank you.
No, thank you.
I suppose you've heard from Andrei?
Yes.
Father!
You're the young Countess Rostov.
I didn't know
you were paying me a visit.
Excuse my costume,
I came to speak to Mary.
Why wasn't I told?
Count Rostov? I've heard a great deal
about you, a great deal about you.
As the Lord is my witness,
nobody told me they were here.
This house, utter confusion, chaos!
People coming and going.
You can't find anything.
Even the papers in my desk.
You must excuse me.
I'm not prepared to entertain.
I can't stand Moscow, anyhow.
I wouldn't be here, except I've no
alternative. I'm forced to be here.
We'd better leave now. Princess.
Wait, I must talk to you.
Dear Natasha, I'm certain my brother
has found happiness.
Princess, I think it is not convenient
to speak of that now.
Isn't it wonderful?
Aren't you glad you came?
Until Andrei comes back,
I can't be glad about anything.
It's only a few weeks.
- You see that tall man over there?
- What about him?
When we passed, I heard him say,
"That's the Countess Rostov.
"The one who's going to marry
Bolkonsky. Lucky man."
- He said, "Lucky man"?
- "Lucky man."
I must write that to Andrei.
He can tell his horrible father.
- Countess Bezukhov has arrived.
- Bezukhov?
One of my favourites!
I must call on her.
Countess Bezukhov, I'm delighted
to see you back in Moscow.
The city hasn't been the same
in your absence.
I've brought my two girls with me,
as you can see.
Well...
Magnificent woman!
You can understand
how men must fall in love with her.
Dolokhov, see the girl in that box?
Yes, she's lovely, but...
...for you? No, Anatole,
she's not exactly your type.
May I borrow your daughter
to sit with me in the next act?
Countess, how charming.
Natasha, come along.
- Isn't it exciting?
- Yes.
Enchanting! You mustn't bury her
in the country again.
You're too kind. Natasha, sit down.
Now we can tear
all our friends to pieces.
No one in the theatre is talking
of anyone but you and your match.
- You know?
- It's the news of the season.
Prince Andrei Bolkonsky!
Every woman here is jealous of you
at this moment.
Why, Anatole!
May I present my brother?
Countess Natasha Rostov.
He's the centre of fashion in Moscow.
He drinks too much
and plays for too high stakes.
He also sees
the most amusing people.
Get him to tell you
everything to do this season.
- Countess!
- You've been neglecting me.
I was convinced you were dead.
When I saw you at the ball,
six weeks ago,
I thought, "What a pretty girl."
That's all I thought.
But tonight...
- But you felt it, too?
- I felt...?
When our eyes met. Don't look guilty.
What's there to be ashamed of?
Are you enjoying the opera?
It's very good, isn't it?
Oh, is it? I haven't noticed.
I haven't looked at the stage tonight.
I must see you again.
You must come to my sister's house.
Very soon.
I think...
My mother's in the country,
I may go up to be with her.
She's enchanting.
- Go away, Anatole, you'll distract us.
- All right, all right.
You'll come.
I'll take this as a pledge.
My brother is very amusing, isn't he?
Bravo, bravo!
How lovely she is.
I don't think so when I look at you.
Natasha, come!
- Did you enjoy it?
- Yes, thank you.
You're enchanting.
From the moment I saw you,
I never ceased worshipping you.
- I hope you don't think us too informal.
- Oh, Countess, well...
I'm madly in love with you.
- Papa, we must leave.
- We can't go now.
...like one big heart,
palpitating with emotion.
His Majesty the King was so moved,
tears came streaming down his face...
My cloak, please.
I can't. You know I can't.
"Dearest Natasha, my fate has been
sealed, to be loved by you or die.
"Your parents won't give you to me
for reasons I will reveal only to you.
"But if you love me,
you need only say the word yes.
"Anatole."
You're back.
How was your evening?
Did you amuse yourself?
Yes. I made excuses for you.
I was worried about you.
How's your headache?
- You read that letter.
- Yes.
I'm glad. I couldn't keep it
from you any longer.
- "You know we love one another."
- But Anatole Kuragin?
- How happy I am.
- And Andrei?
You don't know what love is.
You don't understand. Listen.
How can you love a man for months
and suddenly...? Why?
You've only seen Anatole three times.
It seems to me
I've never loved anyone before.
I've heard it's happened that way.
It's only now I feel such love.
I felt he was my master and I his slave
and I couldn't help loving him.
Yes, whatever he commands,
I must do. What can I do?
If he loves you, why doesn't
he ask your father honestly
for your engagement to be broken off?
- Why all this secrecy?
- It doesn't matter.
Whatever his reasons,
they are good ones.
- I have no will, I love him.
- I won't let it come to that.
I shall tell.
You wouldn't tell anyone. Don't
torture me, I can't live without him!
What are you saying?
Think about your father and Nicholas.
I don't love anyone but him.
Go, Sonya.
I don't want to quarrel with you.
Go away!
Anatole, where do you mean to take her?
They'll find out about that Polish girl
you had to marry. It'll mean jail.
It will be worth it. Even if it is for
one month or one week with that girl.
Some things in life
are impossible not to have.
- The driver you sent for.
- A drink. You have to drive far.
- Get Metrevna to bring my cloak.
- A gypsy girl again?
- An elopement.
- I like it. Romance, excitement!
There is a priest waiting.
Don't let anyone stop you.
There's a man for you!
- You want me?
- Now, take this. Listen to me.
The girl will be shivering,
she'll have forgotten everything.
Wrap her up, or she'll stampede
back to the house for furs.
Papa awakened, Mama screaming,
tears, recriminations, challenges!
Always keep a young girl warm,
my boy.
Up with the collar and whoosh!
- Take it.
- But my coat.
I will get you another one someday.
All take glasses!
Now, comrade and friend of my youth,
we've had our fling and revelled,
now farewell.
- To your health.
- To your health!
- How sad it is.
- Sure.
- I still think you shouldn't do it.
- So do I.
Sonya? Sonya!
No, I won't open it.
And I've sent for Pierre.
I'll hate you for ever for this.
Open the door.
No, I won't open it.
- What's the matter with you?
- Your sister can't keep things quiet.
- Things such as gossip.
- What?
I know all about the money
you had to send to Poland and why.
- It's not true.
- You must leave Moscow.
Don't tell anyone. Besides your
pleasure, there's others' happiness.
You'll ruin a whole life
for your amusement.
Then amuse yourself with women
of your own rotten breed.
As a man of honour,
you can't talk to me that way.
- Is it satisfaction you want?
- Yes.
I take it back. I'd take it back,
I'd beg you for forgiveness.
Drive this gentleman
wherever he wants to go.
He's gone.
She's in her room.
- What are you doing here?
- I came to stop you.
- Nothing will stop me.
- What do you plan to tell Andrei?
- I wrote to him telling him everything.
- He's not good enough for you?
You crawl after a gambler, a liar,
and a notorious womaniser!
I'm going to marry him!
Whatever he's told you, he's lying.
He's married already.
It isn't true.
Look at me, Natasha.
Could I purposely deceive you?
- The rumour's all over Moscow.
- Who started it?
Prince Andrei has sent back
all her letters.
- That's bad. I am sorry.
- She's been quite ill.
When she knew you were coming,
she insisted upon getting up.
Don't tell her everything. One hasn't the
heart to scold her. She's to be pitied.
I hear he's in Moscow now.
Ask him...
- Ask him to forgive me.
- I will tell him, but...
I know that can never be.
All is over.
Only I'm so tormented
by the wrong I've done him.
Tell him...
Tell him I beg him to forgive...
forgive me for everything.
I will tell him everything.
But remember I'm your friend.
If you want help
or to open your heart to someone,
not now, but when your mind is clearer,
think of me.
- I shall be happy if it's in my power.
- I'm not worth it.
No. You have your whole life
ahead of you.
Ahead of me? No. All is over.
Nonsense, Natasha.
Listen to me, look.
Were I not myself, but the handsomest,
cleverest man in the world,
and if I were free,
I would not hesitate for one moment
to ask for your hand and your love.
- It's not cold, Mishka.
- It must be well below zero.
- Wonderful.
- Where to?
Where? I don't know, Mishka.
Are you looking at the comet, sir?
They say it means war and famine.
- All sorts of woes.
- Nonsense. Life is beautiful. Go!
- Where to? The club?
- No.
- Home?
- No. Just go, Mishka!
"If Your Majesty wishes to avoid
shedding our people's blood
"and consents to the withdrawal
of Your Majesty's troops,
"I will forget what has happened
and agreement will be possible.
"Otherwise, I shall be forced
to repel an aggression
"that has been
totally unprovoked by me.
"The decision whether to preserve
humanity from the disasters of war
"lies in Your Majesty's hands.
"I am, et cetera, Alexander."
So... this letter is very polite.
Very eloquent.
And it is full of fraternal expressions
of devotion from your Czar.
Sentiments, which, I assure you,
are reciprocated by me.
- However, in essence, Colonel...
- Bolkonsky.
...Bolkonsky,
what does this letter express?
It is not for me, as a mere messenger,
to express the wishes of the Czar.
Come, come, my dear fellow,
you must have an opinion. What...?
Where? Where have we met before?
Your face is familiar to me.
On the field at Austerlitz, sire.
Austerlitz... Austerlitz...?
Yes, I do remember.
You were lying
with a banner in your hand.
Yes, sire.
I thought you were dead!
Well, well, here you are again.
I'm glad to see you.
Now, Colonel, this letter,
what do you think it represents?
It can only represent
the Czar's sincere wish to avoid war
and to prevent the shedding
of both Russian and French blood.
A praiseworthy aim,
and one in which I completely concur.
However, what else
would you say was in this letter?
Since you press me, sire,
for a personal opinion, I would say
it is a request for the withdrawal
of your troops from our country.
A personal opinion! That's how
the Czar told his messenger to put it.
You personally say withdrawal, do you?
Say retreat!
I'm a soldier and I use soldiers' words.
I am not a fool!
I've been asked to put my head into
a noose while my enemies conspire!
Sire, it is not my opinion when I say
the Czar is not your enemy
and that he is not conspiring
against you.
If you read his letter carefully...
I will read the letter more carefully
and send the Czar my answer later.
Goodnight to you, Colonel.
Gentlemen, tomorrow at dawn
we cross the Neman into Russia.
We'll talk of peace... in Moscow!
And on 12th June 1812,
Napoleon Bonaparte, at the head
of an army of 200,000 men,
crossed the River Neman into Russia.
To combat this aggressive invasion
of their homeland,
the Russians welcomed the French
with a destroyed storehouse,
a widely desolated land.
Looting, burning!
As soon as Napoleon approaches,
the peasants run off with their grain.
What they can't take with them
they burn.
If we don't put a stop to it somewhere,
it'll be a desert, a scorched earth!
We must fight. The army demands it,
the Czar demands it.
And the people demand it!
What does the army want?
To be destroyed?
Because that would be
what would happen if we fought now.
Does the Czar want
to be brought to his knees?
Because that would be
what would happen if we fought now.
What do the people want?
To be the subjects of Napoleon?
Because that would be
what would happen if we fought now.
Gentlemen,
I have been put in command
to give the army, the Czar
and the people what they want.
And what they want is to drive the last
Frenchman from the soil of Russia!
And that I propose to do when I can.
- But the looting and the burning...
- Let it continue!
Let it increase!
- Soon they'll be at our gates!
- We'll stop him!
- They should call up more men!
- Kutuzov is afraid!
- He's a doddering idiot!
- What's wrong with the Emperor?
We will show Europe
how Russia rises in defence...
"Lord God,
hear us when we pray to Thee.
"Strengthen with Thy might
our most gracious sovereign,
"Emperor Alexander Pavlovich,
"and give him victory over his enemy,
as Thou gavest Moses victory,
"Gideon over Mideon,
David over Goliath.
"Smite down our enemies
and destroy them swiftly
"beneath the feet
of Thy faithful servants.
"Preserve our army, give a bow
of brass to those armed in Thy name
"and gird their loins with strength
for the fight.
"Take up the spear and shield
and arise to help us.
"Confound those
who have devised evil against us.
"May they be, before the faces of
Thy warriors, as dust before the wind.
"May Thy mighty angel
confound them and put them to flight.
"Let them fall
before Thy servants' feet
"and be laid low by our host."
I came to say goodbye.
I'm leaving Moscow today.
- Where are you going?
- To the army to fight Napoleon.
You're going to join up finally?
I don't know...
I have to see what it's like,
what it means for myself.
Prince Andrei is in command
of a regiment. I'll find him.
- When did you decide to do this?
- A long time ago.
- Even you, Pierre?
- You will stay to dinner?
- By all means.
- To say goodbye.
That's good. Come along.
- Lots of my school friends are going.
- You must study.
- Every man is needed.
- Every man not every infant!
I can't study
when our fatherland is in danger.
Be quiet!
- You heard from Andrei.
- Yes, one letter.
Did he...?
How is he?
Well enough, but sad. His father died.
I know. Although his father was
my enemy, I prayed for him.
He was the first person in the world
to disapprove of me.
You're not really grown-up
until that happens to you.
Did Andrei say anything about me
in his letter?
No, Natasha.
Will he ever forgive me?
He has nothing to forgive.
- You must promise me something.
- Yes.
Don't let anything happen to you.
If it did, I'd...
Did you hear me, Pierre?
Yes, I heard you.
I promise.
- And Pierre...
- Yes.
If you do see Andrei, tell him...
Tell him I prayed
for the soul of his father.
Can you tell me
where I'll find Colonel Bolkonsky?
This gentleman's
been asking to see you.
Pierre!
Andrei!
- At last.
- What are you doing here?
It's still hard to say.
I came to see the battle.
Why?
It's hard to explain, Andrei.
It's such an enormous event.
Our lives will be different because
of what will happen here tomorrow.
- I'm sorry about your father's death.
- He was an old man.
He couldn't live with the thought
of being driven away.
How are they taking it in Moscow?
Mary has gone to your aunt's.
It was Nicholas Rostov
who got her out just in time.
So Anatole Kuragin did not honour
Countess Rostov with his hand.
He couldn't. He was married already.
It was all very long ago. She's had
time to forget her disappointment.
- Remember our old discussion...?
- Yes.
I said a fallen woman should be
forgiven. But I can't forgive her.
But you can't compare
Natasha to a fallen woman.
What romantic dreams I had.
You mean, ask for her hand again?
Yes, that would be very noble.
But...
I'm sorry.
How are you?
You seem so strange, disturbed.
The night before a battle is fought,
men are likely to seem disturbed.
It's more than that.
Perhaps it is.
I've been in many battles, but
for the first time I feel I'll die tomorrow.
- Nonsense. Why?
- I just feel it.
Why are you really here, Pierre,
when you hate violence and war?
I don't know.
Because I realised you can't hate
something you've never known.
How will the battle go?
Our position's good.
Success never depends on positions,
orders, plans or even on numbers.
A battle is won
by men determined to win it.
Despite those men at headquarters
who consider war a game,
war is the most horrible thing in life,
and I'd never take prisoners.
The French are my enemies,
they destroyed my home,
exiled my sister and my child.
Now they hope to destroy Moscow.
Taking prisoners is playing at war.
Take no prisoners! Kill and be killed!
Without playing at war, we'd fight only
when it was certain death, as now.
I'm sorry.
Why should I burden you with all this?
If we're both alive tomorrow night,
we'll have a bottle and laugh.
Forgive me, you're sleepy.
Time for me to sleep, too.
I'd like to stay here.
Go. Go!
I have no time for you now.
My only friends now are the men
who'll fight at my side tomorrow.
Goodbye.
Whether we meet again or not.
Take down a proclamation
to all troops.
Soldiers, this is the battle
you have all longed for.
Victory depends on you.
It will give us all we need.
And a speedy return to our country.
Act as you did at Austerlitz,
Friedland, Vitebsk and Smolensk!
Let posterity say with pride
of each of you,
"He was in the great battle
before Moscow."
- What is Paris saying?
- All Paris regrets your absence.
I should say they do. What's in there?
- A surprise.
- What's that?
A present from the Empress
for Your Majesty.
My son.
The King of Rome.
Admirable.
Take him away, De Beausset.
It is too soon for him
to see a field of battle.
Follow me, De Beausset!
You must not leave. Stay and
we'll give you something to tell Paris!
Fire!
There's a lot of wind up there.
It's made of iron!
Get down or next time it won't be
your hat that blows off.
- Excuse me. I didn't realise.
- Number 3, you're too slow!
Ready, fire!
You can't stand here,
you're in the way.
I'll try to keep out of everybody's way.
Up with your sights, you're firing low.
Number 5, quicker with the charges!
- You're not afraid?
- Are you?
They have no mercy, when they
come singing over. Heaven help us.
Ready. Fire!
- Having a pleasant morning, sir?
- Interesting morning.
Interesting?
You hear that, mates? Interesting!
- Here comes a live one!
- Not this way. Towards the infantry!
Found your friend, eh?
Know him well?
Beyond the trees, the French infantry
are advancing en masse.
- Hold your fire!
Lower your sights
and wait for the order to fire!
Fire!
Sire, our infantry regiments
have turned back and are retreating.
The cavalry should have gone first
to clear the way. Send them now!
- There's only four more charges, sir.
- Bring up more.
I'll go, too.
Water.
Take me to a dressing station.
Help me.
Doctor, he needs help.
- How far have you carried him?
- I don't know.
You should have saved yourself
the trouble. He's dead.
Damn you, Napoleon.
Damn you to hell!
Well, we've stood our ground.
We've taken the worst
that Napoleon has to offer.
We must attack tomorrow morning.
You agree, sir?
Yes, I agree. Theoretically.
According to all the rules that
we've ever learned about warfare,
we must attack tomorrow morning,
but we cannot attack.
- We're too exhausted to attack.
- But if we retreat...
We give the ground to the enemy.
But he has paid too high a price for it.
He will bleed to death from this victory.
But we can't make a stand
before Moscow.
Yes, General, you're right.
You mean to abandon Russia's
ancient and sacred capital?
Russia's ancient and sacred capital.
Let me tell you, that question
has no meaning for a Russian.
Such a question cannot be put.
It's senseless!
The question I've asked you
to discuss is a military one!
The question is of saving Russia.
Do we give up Moscow or accept battle
and lose the army and Moscow?
Well, I see I am the one who
has to pay for the broken crockery.
Gentlemen, I've heard your views.
Some of you will not agree with me.
But I, by the authority entrusted
to me by my sovereign and country...
...order a retreat.
Oh, faster! The French will be here
before we're ready to leave.
Now, come on, up!
Put all the glass things
in the front wagons.
And the books... put them
in the low wagons.
Take this and this. And these gloves.
I'll never wear them again.
Thank you.
They are the wounded from Borodino.
Vera, hurry!
Vera, come!
Give me some water.
- Have you seen the wounded men?
- Yes. I said they can live here.
Someone badly wounded?
Just about alive. It's a miracle
His Excellency has lasted this long.
- His Excellency?
- Our colonel.
Miss Sonya.
Don't tell anyone about this. Not yet.
Promise me.
Aunt, Prince Andrei is here,
among the wounded.
- Andrei?
- He's unconscious, terribly wounded.
- Natasha?
- She doesn't know.
- She mustn't know.
- He's dying.
Natasha must not know.
All right, get those wagons moving.
Turn them around!
We've got another load of wounded
back there!
After we've left and
the wounded are here, what then?
I don't know. My orders are to get
back and pick up more wounded.
They're to be left here, deserted,
to be taken prisoner, to die?
- That's in other hands than ours.
- Take those chairs down.
- That's enough. Put it down.
- Papa, we can't do this.
- Oh, the settee...
- The three men will become prisoners.
What three men?
But of course. If we leave the settee,
what will happen to your mother?
- I'll speak to Mother.
- Back in!
You three are to come with us
on that cart.
- Your men must use my house.
- Count, please help.
- Is there a cart for this poor fellow?
- Of course.
Hurry, hurry!
- All those men, Papa.
- I know, it's very sad.
- Still, in a war...
- We must take them with us.
We're going to unload everything
and take every man who can travel.
You're right. So very right.
Take those back. Put that down.
Unload all the carts. Do as you're told!
- Tell your men there's room for all.
- Thank you, sir.
Take those off!
Take this off, take it all down.
Unload the cart.
Unload this cart completely.
Overboard with that.
Take all that down!
Take down that table, we don't need it.
Empty the cart straight away.
All this out. Come and help!
Llya, what is this?
They're unloading everything.
- To make room for the wounded.
- But our things!
Things! Things can be bought.
Think what it means to be left behind.
The government ought to care
for the wounded.
Mama, you can't object.
Look at them.
You'd leave them behind
to save some furniture? Mama!
Suppose Nicholas was one of them.
Or Petya.
Nicholas? Petya?
Of course, you're right, darling.
I'm sorry, llya.
The chicks are teaching the hen!
Ten more minutes!
We leave in ten minutes!
- I'm ready now, llya.
- Come along, girls, in you get.
- In God's name, off.
- In God's name, off!
Dear Moscow, everybody's leaving you.
- Look! Over there by the corner!
- Who is it?
Pierre! Over here! Pierre!
Over here, Pierre!
You're safe. You promised
you'd come back and you have.
You mustn't stay. Come with us.
- Did you see the battle, Pierre?
- Yes, I saw it. I saw too much.
- Come with us.
- I must stay in the city, I've...
- Stop the coach!
...something I must do.
Go on!
Remember me. Remember!
Why wouldn't he come with us?
I don't understand.
- Natasha...
- Sonya!
You're crying. For Pierre?
For us, because we're leaving?
What, then?
- I have to tell her.
- No.
There's someone we know
among the wounded.
Andrei?
He's travelling with us now.
Is he badly hurt?
Why didn't you tell me before?
I didn't know how to tell you.
He told you not to tell me.
No. He's asleep or unconscious.
He didn't speak.
He didn't speak?
Moscow!
Asiatic city of innumerable churches.
Lots of them.
Moscow the holy, here at my feet.
At last!
On the ancient monuments
of barbarism and despotism,
I shall inscribe great words
of justice and mercy. Mercy.
What a splendid reign the Emperor
Alexander's... might have been.
Now, I'm ready to accept
the surrender of the city. Now.
Well, where is the deputation?
There is no one, sire.
The city is empty, half of it on fire.
There is no government.
No one to surrender to you.
That's impossible.
Impossible and ridiculous!
There must be a surrender.
This is an insult!
They're going to pay for this.
The skyline, look. It's a village on fire.
- It could be Mytishchi.
- It's further away than that.
- Moscow's on fire!
- It's so windy and dry.
Moscow! God have mercy.
Oh, it's Moscow, poor Moscow.
Natasha, Sonya, come and look.
Moscow's on fire.
Moscow? Oh, no!
How terrible!
- Natasha!
- Let's go back to bed.
- I must talk to you.
- Again?
- Go back to bed.
- Give me permission to join the army.
You already know it. It's no.
I must go where I can do
the most good for my country.
Your duty now is not what you think.
Your duty is to stay with us.
I'm sorry, Papa.
I've already made up my mind.
Do look. The whole city's on fire.
You can see it from the window.
- You didn't even look.
- Yes. Really, I did.
Go back to sleep.
You'll catch your death of cold.
You, too, Natasha, darling.
Go to sleep.
- Is it the French or us burning the city?
- Who knows?
Please, your officers, where are they?
Officers, Miss?
I don't know. Down there somewhere.
Forgive me, forgive me.
I love you.
Forgive me.
Forgive what?
For everything I have done.
I love you more. Better than before.
- I want all these fires put out.
- Yes, sire.
Let me go! Take your hands off me!
No!
Let me go!
- Where did he come from?
- I don't know.
Ready!
Aim!
Fire!
Cut them down!
- Two others, quickly!
- No, no! Help me! Please!
Please don't let them! No!
No! No!
Please! No!
No!
No, please!
Ready!
Aim!
Fire!
Cut them down!
No, that's all.
The orders were to shoot
only the incendiaries.
Take them back to prison.
Forward march!
Don't brood. It's not for us to judge
whether we're to be spared or not.
Finally, in the world to come,
God will give us a word of explanation.
Here you are. Come here, boy.
You found me again, eh?
That's the little fella. That's right.
Sit down there, be a good boy.
Do you like cold potatoes?
At dinner the potatoes were delicious.
Here you are, boy.
Perhaps you'd like some salt.
- That's better now, huh?
- I'm all right.
- Why did they have to shoot them?
- What a sin. What a sin.
Where there's law, there's injustice.
Come on, boy, get up.
But the maggot eats the cabbage
yet dies first.
What?
Things happen not as we plan,
but as God judges.
Have you got a family estate, sir?
A housewife?
Your old parents, are they still living?
Perhaps you've got little ones?
Never mind, you're young yet
and may have some still.
The great thing is to live in harmony.
Well, I was still living at home,
you know?
We had a well-to-do homestead,
a nice piece of land,
and a house you'd thank God for.
When we went mowing,
we were seven. Real peasants.
Well, one day, I went into someone
else's forest to cut wood.
The keeper found me, I was flogged
and sent to serve as a soldier.
We thought that was a misfortune,
but it turned out to be a blessing.
If I hadn't sinned, my brother would've
gone and he's got five little ones.
Whereas I only had a wife to leave.
We had a little girl,
but God took her before I left.
You've had hard luck.
We can make it into misery or into joy.
Hard luck's like water in a dragnet,
you pull and it bulges.
But when you've drawn it out,
there's nothing in it.
That's how it is, dear boy.
Now I think it's time to sleep.
Lord Jesus Christ, Holy Saint Nicholas,
Frola and Lavra have mercy upon us.
That's the way.
Lay me down like a stone
and raise me up like a loaf.
- What prayer was that?
- I was praying. Don't you pray?
Yes. But what did you say?
Frola and Lavra?
The horse's saints.
One must pity the animals, too.
Come over here.
Get warm and lie down.
That's right.
- I thought you were asleep.
- No. I was watching you.
Enjoying you. Being thankful for you.
- Sleep, my dearest.
- No, not yet.
I want to keep my eyes open.
I want to look at you.
You know, you're not the girl
I saw dancing all night.
The girl who whispered
on the balcony to the moon.
You're something much better.
How serene you are. How valuable.
I love you so much.
It's a terrible thing. Only at a moment
like this can one talk so openly.
Until now, I knew nothing about love.
I was a great hater, Natasha.
I hated so many things,
but most of all I hated you.
You had every right.
I love you more than I've ever loved
anything on this earth.
Maybe this monastery
has something to do with it.
Maybe the monks
really know about love.
Now I'm beginning to understand, too.
Maybe death
is my private monastery.
Where is he? Can I see him?
- Of course. But is that his son?
- Yes.
- And he's called...?
- Kolya.
What a lovely boy.
- Where is he?
- We've sent to ask.
You must be tired, Princess.
We've prepared rooms for you.
- Where is Petya?
- He left. We couldn't control him.
He kept on about going into the army
until we just had to let him go.
The war will probably be over
before he gets his commission.
- Did you receive my letter?
- Yes, that was a good piece of news.
- You and Mary.
- I'm worried about Sonya.
- It's all right, I told her immediately.
- But I wanted to tell her myself.
- Mary.
- Will you stay with us, little man?
Now, my dear...
Come with me, Mary.
Nicholas, you come along.
- Nicholas, I've read your letter.
- I know.
She's a fine woman, isn't she?
- If you want to, Nicholas, you're free.
- Forgive me, Sonya.
Natasha, no one will tell me anything.
How is his wound, his condition?
What did the doctor say?
Is he worse?
- Andrei.
- Hello, Mary.
How did you manage to get here?
Have you brought little Kolya?
- How are you now?
- You must ask the doctor.
You see how strangely
fate has brought us together?
- She looks after me all the time.
- Mary came from Ryazan.
- You've missed Count Nicholas?
- Yes.
He took a great liking to you.
It would be a good thing to marry him.
Why talk of me, Andrei?
Would you like to see Kolya?
He's outside.
I'd be very glad to see him.
Is it too much for you, all this talking?
No. I want to tell Mary
so many things but I'm unable to.
Kiss him, Kolya. Kiss your father.
Kolya...
...no one is permitted to cry
in this room.
Not children and not grown-ups either.
I think you'd better
go out and play now.
He's a handsome little boy.
What is it, Mary? Is it about the child?
You know the gospel.
"The fouls of the air sow not, nor reap,
yet your father feedeth them."
That's why you mustn't cry.
Come sit beside me.
The hardest thing
is to keep alive at sunset.
I had a wonderful dream.
I saw a door. I could see beyond it.
I dreamt that I died.
And as I died, I awoke.
Yes...
...death is an awakening, you see?
It's all so simple.
Is it over?
Where is he now?
Where has he gone?
What is this? What is this?
We are masters of the capital
of the largest country in the world,
not a single civilian mouth to feed
and I get these reports!
"The stocks are dwindling,
food is disappearing,
"the danger point is approaching."
Who writes out these reports?
Who is taking steps to correct them?
I brought the greatest army
in Europe into this city.
What do I see?
A mob of looters and drunkards.
They are not soldiers any more!
They are rag-pickers. Junk men!
Kutuzov must have sent emissaries
to ask for the terms of surrender.
What happened?
Are they detained? Shot?
Sire, I myself have given explicit
instructions to all the commanders.
There have been no emissaries from
the Russian Commander-in-Chief.
The city's burning down
around our ears. House by house!
I've given orders to shoot incendiaries
and even here, you cannot...
...cannot get the stink of smoke
out of your nostrils!
Gentlemen, take hold or
I promise you I will replace you all!
With all your titles
and decorations and batons!
I'll go and pick the first soldiers I find
who are not drunk...
...and put them in your place!
I warn you, gentlemen,
I cannot sit here much longer,
watching my army decay.
Close the windows, someone!
Already the wild geese
are flying south.
What if we are trapped here
through winter?
Time and patience,
patience and time.
The grand army's wounded,
but is it mortally wounded?
An apple should not be plucked
while it's green.
Patience and time.
Yes? Who is it? Come in!
A special courier, Your Excellency.
Excellency, the French are preparing
to leave Moscow.
Come closer.
Excellency, would you like me to...?
O Lord, my creator.
Thou hast heard our prayer.
Russia is saved!
I thank Thee, O Lord.
Russian women.
They're the lice
that live on the conquerors.
They have to leave with them or die.
Attack.
The word "attack"
is always on your tongues.
Gentlemen, they came
into our country like locusts,
leaving nothing behind,
food nor shelter.
Now they are going back the way
they came, through the desolation.
A cold, hungry army,
2,000 miles from home,
doing what every Russian wants,
leaving our country
with all possible speed.
The country is destroying them.
And the Russian army?
Since Borodino, we've been in retreat.
- Now, it must attack!
- For what?
I wouldn't give one Russian soldier
for ten Frenchmen!
Those retreats...
...they've brought about
the destruction of the French army.
And will bring about the liberation
of our country.
The animal is running.
We will follow it...
...and flick its haunches with whips
to encourage it to keep moving.
We will follow it
to the borders of our country.
We will offer the French
a golden bridge to the West.
Get moving, there! Get moving!
All stragglers will be shot!
Get up.
Get up! Keep moving! Get up!
Come on, get into line.
- Get up! Come on, get up!
- I can't.
Get up. Now!
Please...
All right.
971, 972...
...73, 74...
Get up!
Get moving!
Clear the road! Out of the way!
Stand aside! Out of the way!
Move on.
Move on! Keep moving!
- Move on. Move on!
- One, two, three...
What are you counting all the time?
I count to a thousand and start again
to keep my feet going.
You've never needed them before,
have you?
Gentlemen ride in carriages
or on horseback.
I've lived my whole life on foot
and yet you outlast me.
Start again. One, two...
...24, 25, 26...
Get up!
Come on, keep moving!
Are you afraid, too, friend?
One, two, three, four, five...
Halt! Who are you?
Ensign Rostov. I have a dispatch
from the Commander-in-Chief.
Come, then.
- How did you find us?
- Peasants in the village told me.
- Dragoons?
- Yes, sir.
- How many infantrymen?
- Maybe 100.
- Or 200?
- Yes, sir. Perhaps 200.
Perhaps? Get out
before I lose my temper! Out!
- When was he captured?
- Last night. We won't keep him long.
I usually do not take prisoners.
- What is this dispatch?
- It's my general's dispatch, sir.
- Who are you?
- Rostov.
- You have a brother, Nicholas?
- Yes. You know him?
Yes.
"All patrols are to fall back
immediately to join the main army.
"Prepare for a general attack
"when the French attempt to cross
the Beresina River."
Rostov, you didn't find me
to give me this till tomorrow.
Why, sir?
Those French stragglers, I'll attack
them tomorrow. One last fight.
Let me come. I'll say I didn't find you,
if you let me fight.
- No, no!
- Let me come.
It's a bargain. But keep out of trouble
or I'll be in trouble with the General.
Thank you.
Go and eat something.
Now, I will move in through the forest.
You go to the other side of the valley
and attack at my signal.
- Right. Any reserves?
- None.
This is our last fight,
and we'll hold back nothing.
- Ensign. You want some?
- Thank you.
Hungry? Have this.
Thank you very much.
Stay behind me at all times.
Charge!
The Cossacks! The Cossacks!
You must've wished
you'd killed me in that stupid duel.
You probably haven't heard
that Hélene died in St Petersburg.
Finally, I want to ask you
to forgive me for the harm I did you.
Halt!
Take them away.
You know what to do with them.
He wouldn't stay behind.
It was a game for him.
His sabre was a toy.
I never take prisoners!
Stand by your guns!
Fire!
Yes, burn them.
- Hurrah, lads!
- Hurrah!
Hurrah! Hurrah!
I thank you all for your hard
and faithful service.
The victory is complete,
and Russia will not forget you!
Honour to you for ever!
Hurrah! Hurrah!
Well, shall we see what's happened
to the rest of the house?
Come on, Mary.
Sonya, see what the kitchen's like.
Prokofy, you might find some tea.
- Will you look in the cellar?
- Very well.
Mama, Papa!
The north wing is just as it was!
Nothing's happened.
We have a house. Half a house!
Isn't it wonderful?
Mama, you can come and rest.
We're home.
Dunyasha,
make Mama a cold compress.
Take this footstool.
She always liked that.
The baby can go in my room.
Up you go! There.
I hope we find a bottle of port.
You see, Mary? You'll have
a born optimist as a father-in-law.
I have loved you
from the first moment I saw you.
Hurry up, Nicholas! You're delaying
the trip to the country!
Pierre!
We were so worried when we heard
you were taken prisoner.
You've come back.
You're like this house.
You suffer, you show your wounds,
but you stand.