And so it fell out
that at Pharsalia...
... the great might and manhood of Rome
met in bloody civil war...
... and Caesar's legions
destroyed those of the great Pompey...
... so that now only Caesar
stood at the head of Rome.
But there was no joy for Caesar
as in his other triumphs...
... for the dead which his legions
counted and buried and burned...
... were their own countrymen.
The smoke of burning Roman dead
is just as black...
...and the stink no less.
It was Pompey, not I,
who wanted it so.
Let what I have said be set down.
You may stand.
Do not try and impress me by looking
either too penitent or too proud.
As field officers,
you fought miserably for Pompey.
Men under your command will be
permitted to enlist in my legions...
...and returned to Rome as Romans.
You shall have the same privilege.
I'm not magnanimous. Your names
are marked. You'll be watched.
First sign of treachery,
you'll be killed.
What is it, Flavius? Antony?
Oh, yes. Canidius.
With news of Pompey, I hope.
- Hail Caesar!
- Drink that in my name, Canidius.
To all Marc Antony's cavalry,
Caesar's left wing and right arm.
What news of Pompey, or what's left?
Pompey's gone, Caesar.
Slipped through our fingers,
disguised as a peddler.
- Leaving most of his merchandise.
- Gone? Where?
He has a galley waiting at the coast.
Provision enough for Egypt, they say.
Egypt. Possibly.
They owe him a great deal.
He'll ask for sanctuary.
Borrow money, borrow time.
I thought it was over.
It seems it's not.
Rufio, consult the augurers.
I want to know.
In Egypt, will Pompey face me at last?
But surely Caesar will now
return to Rome!
I must go to Egypt in any case.
King Ptolemy and his sister
have a civil war of their own...
...intent on destroying each other,
and in the process, Rome's wheat.
That cannot be so urgent.
Let the Romans welcome
great Caesar properly at last...
...in this greatest of his triumphs.
Triumph? Over what?
Over whom?
- Canidius.
- Caesar?
Leave me the 10th and 12th.
Antony's to take the rest to Rome.
- When can he start?
- Whenever you say.
Then at once.
And in Rome,
Marc Antony is to speak for Caesar.
His authority is not to be questioned.
His word will be yours.
As always, Caesar's word is law.
Of course.
But remind him to keep his legions
intact. They make the law legal.
Caesar.
And even as Caesar's galleys
sailed the great sea to Egypt...
... it was happening that,
just as the Romans...
... so the Egyptians made war,
one upon the other...
... for King Ptolemy would no longer
share the throne...
... with his sister Cleopatra...
... but drove her
from the city of Alexandria...
... and sought to destroy her.
We've arrived on their market day.
Once a week they're allowed
in the royal enclosure.
Where's the guard of honor for Caesar?
Some representative
of the royal or military?
We have the privilege of watching
Caesar battle through our marketplace.
Marcellus, a dozen front-rank men,
swords only.
Clear a direct line
to the palace steps.
Then as many more to keep it open.
It's precisely what they hope we'd do:
Manhandle their people.
No. This is their market day,
we will go marketing.
- You're not serious.
- We'll shop our way to the palace.
Have you my money?
Everything is to be paid for by coin.
Tell them to put away the swords
and carry moneybags.
Olives. Oil of olives.
Ah, the wine of Samos.
How much for your wine? Four drachma.
Sixty of your wine for my men.
Pay him.
You said they'd push the people
and make them angry.
Why aren't they doing
what you said they'd do?
Your king has asked a question,
Lord Chamberlain.
The Romans have degenerated minds,
Most High Majesty.
They do the unexpected.
Particularly one Roman.
Master of the unexpected.
But with so few men.
You all look so impressive.
Any one of you could be king.
His Divine Majesty, my Lord Ptolemy...
...Iord of the Upper
and Lower regions...
...son of Ra, of Horus and of Thoth,
beloved of...
Et cetera, et cetera. You welcome me.
And I, Gaius Julius Caesar,
Pontifex Maximus...
...et cetera, et cetera, thank you.
From the Senate and people
of Rome, hail King Ptolemy.
And his sister and co-ruler,
Queen Cleopatra?
They won't tell you so,
but Cleopatra's dead.
She tried to kill me,
and we chased her into the desert.
And there she died.
Whereas it is true
that His Majesty's sister...
...repeatedly plotted
to have him killed...
...it is not true
that Cleopatra is dead.
Whereas it is true that she
fled from Alexandria...
I seem to always interrupt you...
...but the search for truth
can go on and on.
Pothinus, is it not?
Lord Chamberlain and chief eunuch
to King Ptolemy. An exalted rank.
Obtained not without certain,
shall we say, sacrifice.
Theodotus, am I right?
Tutor to His Majesty in history,
philosophy and ambition.
And Achillas.
They say you're a good soldier.
- As one to another, where is Cleopatra?
- With her army.
And how many of your men
between her and Alexandria?
- Enough.
- May I speak?
Surely you have come in peace.
And we present ourselves to you
in warm and respectful welcome.
Our only problem being an
internal one, of concern only to us...
...why have you come, Caesar?
As we all know, when the father
of both Ptolemy and Cleopatra died...
...he named the two of them
to rule jointly over Egypt.
Rome was appointed their guardian
and the executor of his will.
I have come in the name of Rome to ask
why Cleopatra has been deposed...
...to resolve the differences
between her and King Ptolemy...
...and to see that they peacefully
resume their joint rule of Egypt.
That will be difficult.
Cleopatra has forfeited her right.
I shall try to decide justly.
Don't you see he'll send for her?
He'll bring her back!
The sun which sheds its grace
upon the ruler of the two lands...
...burns too brightly perhaps.
If Lord Ptolemy wishes to retire...
I wish nothing of the kind!
I won't be put out of the way
until I've watched you give him that!
A thousand pardons,
I had almost forgotten.
Lord Ptolemy wishes to enhance his
welcome by a gift of some importance.
Most generous.
The ring. Give him Pompey's ring.
And now the token of
His Majesty's affection for Rome...
...and regard for Caesar.
Pompey the Great.
Dead men, they say, do not bite.
Does it please you, Caesar?
They said it would
please you very much.
The sun does shed its grace
too brightly.
It has become too hot here for kings.
My Lord Ptolemy will retire.
For His Majesty,
a Roman guard of honor.
It was not by your hand, of course.
Lf, as you say, you've been told
of me, you know better, Caesar.
My men shall be
properly housed and fed.
- May I speak?
- Not until you're spoken to.
I'll require rooms in the palace.
I shall consider myself
honored to escort you.
Anyone but you.
Find the rest of Pompey.
Tear out a thousand tongues,
but find him.
Have him purified...
...the coin in the mouth
and the rest, honorably.
Of course.
For now, this is what we must hold.
Moon gate and three others.
Here, here and here.
How are we placed?
The 10th slingers on the moon gate.
The rest in reserve.
The 12th holding all other positions.
Very thin.
For now, deep enough.
- And the wells?
- The water's brackish, but drinkable.
So far. Keep an eye on them.
Watch the corn and wheat.
With our supplies secure,
we can hold indefinitely.
For a week, perhaps,
but for the time being, time enough.
What do you want?
Is the man to be trusted?
Seems someone's brought me a gift...
...from Queen Cleopatra.
Apparently, a rug peddler.
Flavius doubts it.
He seems to know the palace very well.
He appeared through a secret passage
which none of the men knew.
Pothinus might send an assassin
in Cleopatra's name.
Have the man brought in.
Are you the one
who brings a gift from Cleopatra?
Put it down and go.
It is the command of my queen
I deliver her gift personally.
I am Caesar. Lay it here before me.
Forgive me, Admiral Agrippa,
but you're not Caesar.
Nor you, General Rufio.
Nor you, Germanicus.
My queen's gift is for
the eyes of Caesar...
...alone.
- It seems harmless enough.
- No, Caesar!
You can lend me your sword, Rufio.
It may require some cutting.
Odd way to carry a rug.
Isn't it easier
to sling it over your shoulder?
It was less comfortable that way.
- For you or the rug?
- That sword, Caesar.
The rug is such a delicate weave.
If I may untie it for you.
Turn it over first.
- The rug is right-side up.
- I want it the wrong side up.
- Should I flip it over with my sword?
- No.
I find one can tell more
about the quality of merchandise...
...by examining the back side first.
All hail Cleopatra,
kindred of Horus and Ra...
...beloved of the moon and sun,
daughter to Isis...
...and of Upper and Lower Egypt,
queen.
Thank you.
Here.
Take this to the captain
of the night watch.
He'll see the queen's quarters
are made ready to her.
Stay where you are.
- Have I dismissed you?
- No, Your Majesty.
This is my palace, Caesar.
All of it
is available to me at my will.
I am not your prisoner.
If anything, you are my guest.
Most kind.
And as for having my quarters,
as you put it, made ready...
...my chief handmaiden has, by now,
brought the others out of hiding.
They should almost be finished.
Impossible.
The doors are under guard.
There are doors, and doors.
Of course.
You must take me on a tour someday
within the walls of your palace.
- What are you waiting for?
- Permission to leave.
Granted.
Apollodorus.
Thank you.
I'm pleased you received my summons
and were able to...
Summons? I'm pleased to say
I received nothing of the kind.
I'm surprised you thought
I would answer one.
Young lady, the voyage
in your carpet...
...has apparently not tired you,
but I'm exhausted.
Caesar, it is essential
we understand each other.
Only through me
can you hope to escape...
...the desperate situation
in which you find yourself.
I wouldn't bite into that.
Did you bring it with you?
Have you had it tasted?
If neither, it's probably poisoned.
At least it's another way out of the
desperate situation in which I'm found.
You're being tolerant of me,
aren't you?
Is it because you're so much older?
Your maps are inferior.
Out-of-date, compared to mine.
They and I have aged together.
The lakes to the west
are poorly marked...
...certain important hill positions
not even noted.
I must arrange for you to address
my mapmakers and general staff.
We've gotten off to a bad start,
haven't we?
I've rubbed you the wrong way.
I'm not sure I want to be
rubbed by you at all, young lady.
It is permissible
for me to sit, is it not?
As quickly as possible you must
set me alone on the throne of Egypt.
My mission is to put to an end
to your tiresome squabbling.
You're not a fool. Or are you?
Lmmodestly, perhaps, no.
You've seen my brother
and listened to him?
And that truly evil man
to whom he belongs?
Yes.
Shall we agree upon what Rome
really wants...
...has always wanted of Egypt?
Corn, grain, treasure.
It's the old story.
Roman greatness built
upon Egyptian riches.
You shall have them.
You shall have them all and in peace.
But there is only one way.
My way. Make me queen.
That sounds very much
like an ultimatum.
There is no other way.
For one whose assets,
up to a few moments ago...
...was a devoted slave
and a rolled-up carpet...
But I have you now, Caesar.
Besides, there are my armies...
...and the simple fact that
no mortal hand can destroy me.
Yes, I recall some
mention of an obsession...
...you have about your divinity.
Isis, is it not?
I shall have to insist
that you mind what you say.
I am Isis. I am worshiped
by millions who believe it.
Do not confuse what I am...
...with the so-called divine origin...
...that every Roman general acquires
together with his shield.
It was Venus you chose to be
descended from, wasn't it?
I must now do a little
insisting of my own.
The journey has tired you
and you wish to retire.
I am not your servant, Caesar.
Do not dismiss me.
Secondly, you have no armies,
young lady.
They are gone because
you could not pay them.
Egypt's riches are not
available for your use...
...much less to give away.
Perhaps in a day or two...
...we can speak again.
- That may be too late...
...for both of us.
Your safety will be
my responsibility.
And what about your own?
I am prepared, I believe,
for the time being.
I hope so.
I hope you are as wise,
as brilliant...
...the god they say you are.
You Roman generals
become divine so quickly.
A few victories, a few massacres.
Only yesterday, Pompey was a god.
- They murdered him, didn't they?
- Yes.
Because they thought
it would please you.
- It didn't, did it?
- No.
Today I found myself remembering
how much my daughter loved him.
She died trying
to bear him a son.
Gave him this ring.
Sleep well tonight, Caesar.
These next days may
be difficult for you.
Good night.
Germanicus, a guard to escort
Queen Cleopatra to her apartments.
Guards!
The corridors are dark, gentlemen.
But you mustn't be afraid.
Haven't we covered everything
we can tonight, sir?
- Perhaps a fresh start in the morning.
- No, a few more matters.
Rufio, has it occurred to you
that our maps of this area...
...are not quite what they should be?
Why, no. What makes you
think they're not?
I have an instinct about these things.
- Actually of Macedonian descent.
No officially admitted Egyptian blood.
"Reputed to be extremely intelligent
and sharp of wit.
Queen Cleopatra is widely read.
Well-versed in the sciences...
...and mathematics.
She speaks seven languages
proficiently.
Were she not a woman, she'd be
considered an intellectual."
Nothing bores me so much
as an intellectual.
Makes a better admiral of you,
Agrippa.
Here's something
of more interest to the navy:
"In obtaining her objectives, she has
been known to use torture, poison...
...and even her own sexual talents,
which are said to be considerable.
Her lovers, I am told, are listed
more easily by number than by name.
It is said that she chooses
in the manner of a man...
...rather than wait to be chosen
in womanly fashion."
Well, there's more reason
than we thought...
...for not wanting to leave
you two alone, eh, sir?
I'm sorry, I wasn't listening.
Are you inclined to trust Cleopatra?
Trust? Not for a minute.
"Trust." The word has always
made me apprehensive.
Like wine, whenever I've tried it,
the aftereffects have not been good.
So I've given up wine...
...and trusting.
Oh, it's been a long
and difficult day, gentlemen.
The next few may be even longer
and more difficult.
- Good night.
Flavius!
"It is autumn again,
My best-loved Lesbia
Look, the torrents of Roman leaves
Are falling, falling
And lovers revive in kisses
The promise of spring
Which will end the winter world
With new nightingales calling."
I taste your food, daughter of Isis...
...and if there be harm in it,
let the harm fall upon me.
"But love must bring
Despair one day
As beauty, sorrow."
- Why do you stop, Phoebus?
- In the corridor, there is movement.
That's how the Romans
frighten the enemy...
...by stamping their elephant feet.
- No, this is one man...
...followed by others.
- Caesar, I would say.
- Would you?
We must not disappoint
the mighty Caesar.
The Romans tell fabulous tales
of my bath...
...and handmaidens...
...and my morals.
Cleopatra's requested my presence.
- That was yesterday, Caesar.
- I've been occupied.
The queen is occupied with her bath.
Perhaps Caesar could return later...
...or tomorrow.
- I'm afraid not. Hold him.
No, don't hurt him.
You're a good man, Apollodorus.
I hope you're appreciated.
Wait here for me.
"Ah, then let us live and love
Without one thought
For the gossip of virgins
Now grown old and stale
Suns go down and may return
But once put out
Our own brief light
We sleep through
One eternal night."
An intruder! A man!
Oh, it's you.
You wanted to see me?
I summoned you yesterday...
...to an audience in my throne room.
I was told I was not
permitted to go there.
It's too close to the quarters
occupied by your brother and the rest.
I will not be told where
I can go and where I cannot go!
Since there's nothing you want...
Except my throne!
At least you've dressed
properly for my presence.
Your best armor?
Almost, but I'm afraid
it's not being worn in your honor.
I know.
This morning, you paid a formal
visit to the tomb of Alexander.
You remained alone beside
the sarcophagus for some time.
I'd like to know
how you know.
Just staring down at him.
And then you cried.
Why did you cry, Caesar?
That man recites beautifully.
- Is he blind?
- Don't you hurt him.
I won't. Not anyone
who speaks Catullus so well.
Catullus doesn't approve of you.
Why haven't you had him killed?
Because I approve of him.
"My desire to please you,
Caesar, is very slight
Nor do I greatly care to know
If you are black or white."
Achillas is moving
his entire army to Alexandria.
By tonight, he'll outnumber you
20-to-1, 30-to-1.
He'll have the royal enclosure
entirely surrounded.
Except to the sea.
Do you plan to sail away,
great Caesar?
Not for the time being.
Achillas may attack tomorrow,
the next day...
...whenever it suits him!
- Very probable.
In your wildest dreams, Caesar,
how can you possibly hope to hold...
...the gates of this enclosure
against such odds?
And if you say once more,
"For the time being..."
My officers say anything
from a week to indefinitely.
What would you estimate?
Before you're without water...
...without food...
...your troops slaughtered,
picked off from the rooftops...
...poisoned in the brothels?
A few days, Caesar.
At the most, a few days.
I'm inclined to agree with you.
Young man, do you know this
of Catullus?
"Give me a thousand
And a thousand kisses
When we have many more,
We'll scramble them
And forget the score
So evil envy will not know
How high the count
And cast its evil eye."
It couldn't have been
as pleasant in the throne room.
"My desire to please you, Caesar,
Is very slight..."
Be still!
Caesar, a word. It's important.
The Egyptian galleys in the harbor
have been taking on men and armaments.
- When will they be prepared?
- Tomorrow, with the morning wind.
Burn them tonight.
Their ships lie close to shore.
- The fire may spread to the city.
- Let's hope it doesn't.
I can't risk a blockade.
Remember, not before tonight.
Prepare as secretly as possible.
I need this day.
Good luck.
Why not before tonight, my lord?
Why does Caesar need this day?
I can't give you that information,
for the time being.
Flavius.
Here it is, Caesar. Just arrived.
The gods shouldn't
tantalize us so, Rufio.
It's even better than I'd hoped.
- Be on your way, you haven't much time.
- Hail Caesar.
It's called an epilepse because of the
arching caused by muscular spasms...
...the contortions.
The early Greeks considered...
...those who suffered from it
to be favored by the gods.
The great Alexander, they say...
...had this falling sickness.
And, so they say,
the mighty Caesar too.
Your Majesty, forgive me.
Sosigenes, the library.
- What are you saying?
- The Romans set fire...
...to the Egyptian fleet.
- It's about time.
Come see for yourself.
The fire's spread to the city.
- The city?
- Just a few buildings...
...but the library is burning.
The great library.
Aristotle's manuscripts.
The Platonic commentaries,
the plays, the histories.
The Testament of the Hebrew god.
The Book of Books.
- Wind blew into the merchant shipping.
- Four burned and sank right here.
- And our ships?
- Safe and dry.
Prisoners are surrendering in droves.
I need help.
- Not one man. I may need your sailors.
- Halt!
Take your hands off me!
You should attack my guards more
often. Battle seems to become you.
You grow more beautiful
each time I see you.
And you grow bolder.
And busier.
- Actually, we're extremely busy...
- Do you smell smoke?
We found it necessary
to burn the Egyptian fleet.
The ships were in the water.
Did you find it necessary
to burn them in the streets?
Merchant ships caught fire.
The burning masts fell.
Some houses...
One of them, the great
Library of Alexandria.
Yes, I've been told.
I'm extremely sorry.
- Now, if you don't mind, I must ask...
- I do mind.
Are you putting the fire out?
We're forming prisoners
into fire brigades.
Oh, I see. Romans only start fires,
is that it?
Have you left the nursery
to come irritate the adults?
Another time, we're working.
- Shall we remove her for you, Caesar?
- Use Roman genius for destruction.
Tear down pyramids, wipe out cities!
How dare you and the rest of your
barbarians set fire to my library?
Play conqueror all you want,
mighty Caesar.
Rape, murder, pillage thousands,
millions of human beings.
But neither you nor
any other barbarian...
...has the right to destroy
one human thought!
Enough!
Leave me alone with her.
I will send for you when I finish.
It won't be long.
Swords? Javelins?
Or are you going to set me on fire?
The time has come for us
to understand each other.
Whatever else I may be, in your
opinion, first of all, I am Caesar.
And I am Cleopatra,
queen, daughter of Isis!
If I say so and when I say so,
you are what I say you are...
...nothing more.
Hail Caesar!
You, descendant of inbred generations
of incestuous mental defectives...
...how dare you call me barbarian.
- Barbarian!
Daughter of a drunkard who
bribed his way to the throne.
- Your price was too high, remember?
- I've had enough of you pretenders...
...parading on ruins of past glories.
- Only the future concerns me.
- Keep out of my affairs, do as I say.
- Do as you say?
Literally?
As if I were something
you had conquered?
If I choose to regard you as such.
Am I to understand that you're free
to do with me whatever you want...
...whenever you want?
Yes, I want that understood.
Won't you at least wear
your laurel wreath...
...so I can be reminded it's
the divine Caesar that honors me so?
You talk too much.
I promise you...
...you won't like me this way.
Caesar! An attack on the moon gate!
The moon gate.
An attack in force!
Those ballistas need eliminating.
Send out a turtle.
Form the turtle!
Now is the time for us to attack!
- No.
- We have a full legion in reserve.
We hold our positions here.
Two hours till dawn.
We'll hold where we are.
- And what happens at dawn?
- I thought you knew.
The sun comes up.
Tell the men they've won.
Liberty and wine
for defenders of the gate.
All reserves, cavalry, every man
available, move out behind Achillas.
- We have him in a vise.
- What is the other half?
Rufio and the armies of Mithradates.
He went out last night.
Mithradates? How could
he get here this fast?
I sent him when we sailed for Egypt.
No general in his right mind can
hold Alexandria with two legions...
...as you and others have repeatedly
pointed out to me.
I taste your drink,
daughter of Isis...
...and if there be harm in it,
let the harm fall upon me.
Lotus.
You wiped the rim of the cup
after you tasted it. Why?
Why? So my mouth would not soil it.
Lotus...
...taste it again.
Pothinus said he would have me killed.
Forgive me, Majesty.
Forgive me. Forgive me.
I forgive you.
Now drink it.
Apollodorus!
Great silence
for Gaius Julius Caesar...
...senate consul of the people
of Rome.
You will all stand.
Let what is said be recorded...
...as the judgment and decree
of the Senate and people of Rome.
There is no judgment here.
And the decree not Rome's,
but Cleopatra's.
She has lied to you, Caesar.
She and her slaves lie to you.
You have not been accused, Pothinus.
Thus far.
You are now charged with inciting and
abetting war against the Roman army...
...and plotting to assassinate
Queen Cleopatra.
You are guilty of both.
You are sentenced to death.
It's too bright in here.
Shut out some of the sun.
Are you going to kill me too, Caesar?
What am I accused of?
King Ptolemy is hereby removed
from the protective custody of Rome.
He'll leave within the hour...
...and be conducted safely
to the camp of Achillas.
Achillas! You're going to send me
back to my own troops?
He is to be accompanied
by his learned tutor, Theodotus.
Do you hear that?
You'll be saved along with me.
Stop grinning, you little idiot.
May I speak?
You know that Achillas is trapped...
...between your own legions
and the armies of Mithradates.
To send His Majesty to fight
may mean his death.
An occupational hazard
for those who are king.
But then certainly not I, Caesar.
I'm no king, nor general.
What do I know of war?
A simple scholar.
A man of thoughts and words.
Too many words. Enough.
Let all be done properly as decreed.
Flavius.
Find Apollodorus.
Return his dagger to him.
You might clean it first.
It has Pothinus all over it.
Yes, yes, I know I'm tired.
I promise I'll sleep.
You have my apologies
for what almost happened to you.
Caesar, will you talk with me
for just a minute?
Yesterday was full.
Tonight was long.
This morning has not been uneventful.
Did you know that Apollodorus
would kill Pothinus?
He was kind enough to wait until Rome
had passed sentence of death.
And my brother...
...and Theodotus?
They too will be killed, possibly.
Probably.
Your Majesty, I'm truly weary.
You knew all along, didn't you,
that there was no real danger.
That Mithradates was on his way
to reinforce you.
- Why didn't you tell me?
- You wouldn't believe me.
- I really must insist...
- I would've believed you.
- You didn't trust me.
- Not for an instant.
And yet, in these last few minutes...
...you have made me undisputed queen.
The sole ruler of Egypt. Why?
Perhaps tomorrow we could talk.
- Why, Caesar?
- It was best for Rome!
- Best for Egypt.
- For Egypt too.
Cleopatra, get out.
I beg of you, get out.
That will not be needed.
It wasn't necessary
for me to betray myself.
I could have
called out for Flavius.
How many new spy-holes
have you dug in the walls?
Are we being watched
even now?
If you see Flavius,
you might send him to me.
- Still trying to dismiss me?
- What is it you want?
- What more do you want?
- To be of help to you.
There never has been help.
There never will be.
Now there is.
One day it'll happen
where I cannot hide.
Where the world will see me fall.
I shall tumble down before the mob...
...and foam at the mouth
and make them laugh.
And they'll tear me to pieces.
The gods themselves had your sickness.
Hannibal, even the great Alexander.
And in the end, they fell.
Were torn to pieces by the mob.
Not you.
I will see to that.
In the name of the Senate and the
people of Rome and by their will.
Isis herself would surrender her place
in heaven to be as beautiful as you.
You're not supposed
to look at me. No one is.
If they aren't looking,
how do they know I am?
You should be kneeling.
Would that do
before all these visiting kings?
Making believe
they're not watching us?
You have such bony knees.
Not only bony, but unaccustomed
to this sort of thing.
If we're to get an early start
in the morning...
What will it be tomorrow?
More wheat?
What I've seen could feed
more legions than Rome ever had.
There's enough to feed the world.
More gold then.
Why not buy the world?
Surely you have enough.
At least enough to pay more legions
than even Rome has ever had.
More granite, more marble...
...more millions of slaves
to build whatever needs building.
Better routes to India,
shorter routes to the East.
What can there be in Egypt
that I haven't seen?
Egypt itself. The reason for Egypt.
My responsibility is Rome.
Alexander understood it...
...that from Egypt
he could rule the world.
He was very young.
And you, even younger.
At your age, such dreams have a
reality which grows less in time.
Caesar no longer dreams?
Dangerous to a man of my calling.
Necessary, I would have thought.
I can't stay away from Rome too long.
There are problems.
Messages from Marc Antony
endlessly demanding my return.
And on my way back, wars
to be fought in the east and north.
Even in Rome itself
I'm not without opposition.
Do to them
what you did to Achillas.
This is opposition
of a different sort.
They weave it cleverly, lightly,
like a cobweb.
You know what happens when cobwebs
are not regularly swept away.
Do you trust this Marc Antony?
If anyone in the world,
I trust Antony.
Let him brush away the cobwebs
for you and stay with me.
You've been declared
dictator for a year.
You can do what you want
with your time.
Everything but make it stand still.
If... When you return to Rome...
...these wars that have to be fought
on the way, are they important?
Well, there's no such thing
as an unimportant war.
I've been reading in your commentaries
about your campaigns in Gaul.
How does my writing
compare with Catullus?
Well, it's different.
Dull.
Perhaps a little
too much description.
You're being tactful.
Some of my critics, Brutus, for one...
...tell me my Latin is not only
ungrammatical, but common.
You spared his life more than once.
People say it's because
Brutus is your son.
Is that true?
I have no son.
- Calpurnia, your third wife...
- Fourth.
...married to you how long?
12 years?
And still, Caesar has no son,
no child at all.
It is well-known that
Calpurnia is barren.
A woman who cannot bear children...
...is like a river that is dry.
I see no purpose in discussing
the subject further.
A woman, too, must make
the barren land fruitful.
She must make life grow
where there was no life.
Just as the Mother Nile feeds
and replenishes the earth.
I am the Nile.
I will bear many sons.
Isis has told me.
My breasts are filled
with love and life.
My hips are rounded
and well apart.
Such women, they say...
...have sons.
That first time
when you stood here alone...
...why did you cry?
Will you tell me now?
Because I had lost something.
- What?
- A lifetime.
- Mine.
- Nonsense.
Having conquered the world,
he died at 32.
I am 52.
My remaining ambition is to keep
the world from conquering me.
Your ambitions
must always have been his.
They still must be.
Shall I tell you something?
When I was 32 in Spain...
...I came upon a statue of Alexander.
I wept then too.
Even then.
I want you to have his sword
to take back with you.
- Too deeply embedded.
- It can be removed.
It's buried in time.
- And Alexander's mantle?
- Too heavy for Caesar.
His dream then.
Make his dream yours, Caesar.
His grand design.
Pick it up where he left off.
Out of the patchwork of conquests...
...one world.
And out of one world, one nation.
One people on earth living in peace.
So you have told me at last
what it is you want of me.
Of us!
At the center, the capital of this
world, one people, one nation...
...Alexandria?
- He chose it.
- I am Roman.
He was Greek! What will it matter
when we're all one people?
I am 52. He was 32 and failed.
We will succeed.
Your dreams, your ambitions.
One lifetime is not enough
for such dreams, such ambitions.
The cloak of Alexander
cannot be too heavy...
...for Rome and Egypt
to carry together.
And what if his sword
is too deeply embedded?
Yours will replace it, Caesar.
You have a way of mixing
politics and passion.
Where does one begin
and the other leave off?
That did not start,
nor will it end with me.
Cleopatra, whatever it is,
however it comes out...
...leave me my destiny.
Your destiny
is no longer just yours.
It's mine too.
Soon, there will be someone to
carry both the cloak of Alexander...
...and the sword of Caesar...
...and the name of Caesar.
And in that name he will rule Egypt.
And whatever part or all
of the world that we give him...
...our child...
...will be a son for you, Caesar.
By Isis, I swear it.
Could you put off
your return to Rome...
...just long enough?
I came as quickly as I could.
Antony is welcome to Caesar's house
as often and as quickly as he likes.
As Caesar's wife, before truth
is distorted into vicious gossip...
...I wanted you to hear...
- That my husband has married Cleopatra.
There's some fresh wine.
One of your many favorites.
The ceremony, according to vicious
gossip, was in the Egyptian religion.
Even if true, that can't be
taken seriously.
During which he was formally
declared an Egyptian god.
Officially divine, at last.
That must have pleased Caesar.
Calpurnia, we know Caesar, you and I.
This so-called marriage
has no validity under Roman law.
There must be political purpose.
Perhaps a symbolic ceremony
to ratify our bond with Egypt.
Perhaps merely
indulging some barbaric custom.
You've been loyal and kind.
You came as quickly
as you could.
Unhappily, vicious gossip
travels even faster than you...
...and the truth.
Have you heard, for instance, that
Cleopatra is carrying Caesar's child?
Yes, Antony.
We know him...
...you and I.
There shall be...
...Rome.
Mighty and alone and unloved.
A mistress.
A mistress shall raise thee again
from earth to heaven...
...and all the world shall know
a golden age of justice and of love.
A son shall be born to Isis!
Rome shall know him in cloth of gold.
The East shall see him laden
with jewels and treasure.
A son of Egypt and of Rome!
Here shall he find his destiny!
Do exactly as I tell you.
When the child is born...
...after he is anointed
and named royal prince...
...take him to Caesar.
Bring Caesar here.
No. Exactly as I tell you.
Take the child to Caesar,
in front of his men.
Do you understand?
In front of all the Romans.
Lay him at Caesar's feet.
At Caesar's feet.
I will do just as you say.
Fear not.
We have never lost a Caesar.
That remark was insubordinate
and in bad taste!
Caesar, remember Roman law.
If you pick up this child
you acknowledge it's yours...
...and a citizen of Rome,
as your heir.
A son.
I have a son!
- Hail Caesar!
He's been made king of Egypt.
They have named their bastard
Caesarion.
Prince Caesarion.
What better name for the heir
to the throne of Rome.
There is no throne of Rome.
Nor shall there be,
nor would Caesar tolerate one.
But a son!
We know how much he's wanted one.
I am happy for Caesar.
Your happiness
is understandable enough.
Now that Caesar has
publicly recognized a son...
...one need no longer
wonder about Brutus.
Is it a relief not to be
wondered about, Casca?
To be known openly
as you are for what you are:
Liar, swindler, bully and coward.
Brutus, you'll turn Casca's head
with your flattery.
And Casca's head, if turned,
will see Marc Antony.
A part of Caesar more to be feared
than his infant son.
But it is for the good of Rome that
Caesar has stayed so long in Egypt.
In his absence, the people
have come to worship him as a god.
Why should he return to show himself
as mortal as the rest?
There are those
who fear Caesar's ambition.
But what is to fear?
That he will destroy the republic?
Yes, he will.
I promise you he will.
Your tongue is old but sharp, Cicero.
Be careful how you waggle it.
It may cut off your head.
It will more likely
be your sword, Antony.
'Tis just as sharp and quicker...
...and frightened of heads.
There'll be a strong smell
of wine in the Senate today.
We must breathe with restraint.
Octavian, this what's his name,
this son of Caesar...
...does it upset you?
No.
You run off at the mouth so...
...one thinks your words
are as precious as your gold.
Like my gold, I use them
where they are worth most.
And your virtue?
My friend has a friend.
That too.
You know, it's quite possible
that when you die...
...you will die without
ever having been alive.
I can't leave without saying
goodbye to my son and to you.
We thought, your son and I,
that if we came to you...
...we would have those
few minutes more.
A good thing to remember, my son...
...what you will not let go,
no one will take from you.
Hail and farewell, little Caesar.
Was it a century ago when I was dropped
at your feet, wrapped in a carpet?
Or was it last night?
When will you send for us? When?
- Soon.
- How soon? When?
So much time must go by
before even I reach Rome.
And then how soon?
Within reasonable time.
Time is never reasonable.
Time is our enemy, Caesar.
Am I to conquer it for you?
What plan of battle do you suggest?
I must bring your son to Rome.
Rome must see Caesar's son...
...who will one day rule
over Caesar's world.
Caesar?
I'm afraid the tides
will soon be against you.
Not only time, but the tides.
Even as divinities, there seems
little we can do about either.
But only after more than two years...
... and many wars
in Africa and Asia Minor...
... was Caesar able to cross over
to Italy and come home at last...
... to celebrate his triumphs
and see to his affairs.
"In recognition, the Senate
has bestowed upon Caesar...
...the rank, privilege and title
of dictator of Rome for life."
Dictator for life!
At long last, he is master of Rome.
Apollodorus,
everything must be made ready at once.
- Ships, servants...
- We are prepared.
Surely now nothing
can prevent his sending for us...
...if only to attend
his coronation as he did mine.
- Your Majesty...
- Three long, wasted years!
Why should the Senate
have taken so long...
...to recognize what the world
has already known?
That Caesar was master of Rome.
Rufio wishes to speak.
Your Majesty seems to misunderstand.
It seems quite clear. Caesar has been
declared dictator of Rome for life.
True. But there is a vast difference
between dictator and master.
No man can call himself
master of Rome.
Why not?
It has a meaning far too close
to a word no Roman will tolerate:
King.
And to be dictator of Rome for life?
Is to be granted the lifelong respect
and honor of the Roman people.
And the dictates of the dictator?
Must in each case, of course,
be approved by the Senate of Rome.
Thank you, Rufio.
The enemy! The enemy! The enemy!
Sosigenes.
You must think it odd that I propose
an invitation to Queen Cleopatra.
Do you?
Egypt, after all, has been
officially declared ally of Rome.
Still, I confess I was surprised
at some of those who voted in favor.
Were you?
May I express my gratitude for being
permitted to visit today's session?
It was truly inspiring...
...to witness the free will
of free men so fearlessly expressed.
He seemed most anxious to be present.
- I saw no harm in granting permission.
- Didn't you?
After today, never again shall I
doubt the extent of Egypt's wealth.
I don't like Cicero's implication.
There's not enough gold in Egypt
to buy a Roman senator.
More than enough, it seems,
to buy his vote.
How was it now?
"Rome will know him in cloth of gold."
By reports, the reception
in the streets is extraordinary.
The queen has instructed
the procession to move slowly...
...for the people's enjoyment.
I might almost believe Cleopatra set
out to capture the citizens of Rome.
One would have every reason
for believing exactly that.
Nothing like this has come
into Rome since Romulus and Remus.
How unafraid he is.
Your queen has conquered
the people of Rome.
The people, yes.
Now then, walk like a king.
Head up.
Listen to them cheer.
Take your throne.
Bow to the right, left.
Now an angry glance at someone
who's displeased you.
Very good. I tremble.
See me tremble?
No, don't smile.
Not when they're trembling.
It makes them stop.
Now the prisoners
are dragged before you, one by one.
This one has no power anywhere,
therefore means nothing.
But you wish to be known
as a noble ruler. What do you say?
"I pardon you."
Louder. You pardon somebody,
you want it known.
"I pardon you!"
Ah, now, who comes here?
Once your friend. You trusted him,
and he turned against you.
He has power, wealth and family.
He kneels.
He begs you to be his friend again.
To have you trust him again.
And then? What then, little king?
Caesar must wish
what needs commanding.
To drain the Pontine Marshes.
To free Rome from malaria.
To fill my belly.
To control the Tiber's floods.
To improve the harbor at Ostia.
To please my ambition.
And must I wish roads to be built,
libraries for public use?
The men of Italy to be equal
to those of Rome?
Many of these have merits
and merit our approval.
"Merit your approval." Is Caesar
to come before the Senate each day...
...like a schoolboy,
now passing, now failing?
Do you suggest the Senate no longer
deliberate the welfare of Rome?
To end the process of Roman law?
I must be the law! And my word
must be the welfare of Rome.
Else, take from me
this meaningless title of dictator.
I've carried a sword for too long.
I cannot now pretend
with an empty scabbard.
Surely Caesar recalls the symbolic
nature of the title "dictator"...
...at the time it was conferred.
It was to honor Caesar
above all men...
...and to indicate Rome's gratitude
for your triumphs in its name.
Brutus, I recall them well,
those triumphs.
Do you?
Pharsalia, for one.
You trembled in Antony's hand...
...when he was hot
to separate you from your head...
...with just cause.
My command spared your life.
There was no deliberating body.
It was not my wish, but my command.
By my dictate that you stand here
dribbling virtue out of your mouth.
Sit down.
No, I want no more meaningless
privileges and considerations.
No more honors designed to pacify me.
I would rather have nothing.
Remain what I am at heart.
A humble man, anxious only to serve.
Why are the eyes of a statue
always without life?
Have any of you here seen the Nile?
Spare yourselves the journey.
She carries it within her eyes.
I suggest, Caesar,
that the hour is late.
Very late for Rome.
I was speaking, Cassius! I was...
Now, where was I?
"Anxious to serve."
Yes, I've served.
Served for all of my life.
I've won for Rome
more than half of the world.
Most of you owe your honors
and fortunes to me.
And now I want you to do as I say.
You will appoint me...
...emperor of Rome.
There is no need to resume your seats.
On behalf of all, thank you,
Majesty, for your hospitality.
Good night.
Thank you and good night.
They resent being summoned here for
meetings properly held in the Senate.
Resent it, do they?
I cannot understand...
...that the eyes of a statue
should be always without life.
They resent me.
To flaunt me like this.
They'll use it to keep from you
that which is yours.
By divine right, is that not so?
Yes. It is.
By divine right.
We shall have the Senate,
in its deliberations, deliberate that.
Are you quite sure
what it is you want...
...so desperately?
I've always been sure.
And Caesar?
Does anyone speak for him?
No.
Good night.
Tell me, Brutus, is it proper
to stand before this goddess...
...Caesar's set here in the temple?
- Or must we, as Romans, kneel?
Not yet. See there, where room
has been left for another deity?
When the god Caesar stands beside the
goddess Cleopatra...
...then Rome will crawl before them.
When that day comes, if it comes.
- He demanded we make him emperor.
- Only once, and it was his sickness.
His sickness grows worse.
Soon it will kill us.
He asked once to be made emperor,
but he's since decreed himself god!
Emperor and god. No longer just king,
but emperor and god!
- Brutus, open your eyes!
- What do you want of me?
When the people think
upon the honor of Rome...
...they think upon one man:
Brutus.
By that honor and
by the responsibility you carry...
...Brutus, save Rome from Caesar!
You cannot ask me to destroy him.
Then let Caesar destroy Rome.
Antony has just come from a meeting
of my friends with good news.
Tomorrow at the Senate, Lucius Cotta
will move that I be made king.
It will pass.
But I don't understand.
King and emperor.
And it will pass?
The last few months,
I've been enjoying...
...one of the few privileges
of being dictator.
I have been appointing senators.
Slightly more than half the Senate
has been appointed by me.
Once again, the army of Mithradates...
...on its way all the time.
It will pass.
Tomorrow, the ides of March,
a day to be remembered...
...the Senate will declare me
king of Rome.
King, yes, but not of Rome.
Not of Rome? What are you saying?
They'll offer you king
of the Roman Empire, outside Italy.
They're afraid, Caesar.
Even your friends.
Afraid of the people.
- Perhaps in time...
- To be afraid of the people.
To waste time on the people.
King of all but Rome?
What is there? The huts of Gaul?
The caves of Britain?
The whole of the empire outside Italy.
I will not accept.
They mean it to be an empty gesture.
Another title to please your fancy,
flatter your ego.
Nothing more.
And it will pass.
Then accept it, Caesar.
I have never settled
for half a victory.
Nor will you now.
Caesar, mighty Caesar...
...all I can say
is what you've taught me:
Take a little, then a little more
until finally you have it all.
Let them declare you king.
Even if it's only
of a tree in Asia Minor.
The rest will come to you.
To redo once more everything
I have already done?
It's what you have never done, what
you never conquered that waits for you.
The great legions of Rome in the outer
empire that will become your legions.
The gold, the power of Egypt.
Your Egypt.
Caesar, you can conquer
and hold the world as your own.
Won't you understand?
Kings are not elected.
Gods are not elected.
Why, not only Rome but all of Italy
upon which Rome stands...
...must fall in your hands
like a drop of sweat.
Let them make you what they choose.
I'll serve with you.
My legions with yours.
Together we'll conquer a world beyond
the wildest dreams of Alexander.
Rome.
What was Rome when Sulla died...
...when Crassus lost the armies
in Parthia?
These same men came after me
through the streets...
...howling like frightened dogs,
"Caesar, save us!"
They would've made me king then.
I wouldn't let them then.
He was thrown over the wall.
It's not a pretty sight.
Titus, the moneylender.
Why should he be killed savagely
and brought here?
Obviously, I am being warned.
Perhaps I am next.
They dare to threaten you?
- Caesarion. Where was my son...?
- Not far away.
It frightened him.
- Lepidus, how many legions has he now?
- Fifteen. Perhaps more.
- Where?
- Scythia.
You and I will dine
with Lepidus tonight.
We'll talk of armies and battlefields
and lists of men to die.
Tomorrow in the Senate, let them offer
the sands of Libya as my kingdom...
...I will accept.
This is great Caesar...
...beloved by Rome...
...and at least one of us...
...who must die so that Rome may live.
If it must be done, then let us do it
unashamed and unafraid.
If the world is to know that
Rome will not have a king...
...then let us make it the honorable
act of free men in the light of day.
In the light of what day, Brutus?
Tomorrow?
In the curia of the Senate?
And shall we be armed, all of us?
Decimus, come to Caesar's villa early
tomorrow to escort him to the Senate.
Cimber, Marc Antony must not enter
the curia with Caesar.
On a pretext, lead him aside to speak
of what you heard at Lepidus' house.
I remember something odd.
At one point,
Caesar asked of each of us...
...what manner of death
we would choose.
And Caesar, when it came to him,
looked straight at me and said:
"Sudden."
Odd, isn't it?
I was afraid I'd find you
still asleep.
Caesarion is.
He was awake most of the night.
Did the storm frighten him?
He said not, but it did.
I could tell.
Have you time to come in?
Decimus awaits. He came by expressly
to accompany me to the Senate.
Decimus? Has he done this before?
A shrewd politician.
He hopes to benefit
by arriving with me, this day of days.
Keep Antony close by.
You too?
The ladies of Rome seem to have caught
each other's fears this morning.
Like a head cold.
Calpurnia pleaded with me
not to go to the Senate at all.
Why? Why would she
not want you to go?
Oh, the bad night. Nothing else.
She awoke screaming in her sleep.
The thunder, the lightning.
She dreamed that she saw me murdered.
That she saw me...
...or a statue of me covered in blood.
The servants told her of seeing
men of fire in the heavens...
...odd happenings and so forth.
Strange birds were seen in the Forum.
One flew into the Senate carrying a
sprig of laurel which it dropped...
...at the base of Pompey's statue.
Pompey?
- Caesar, I'm afraid.
- You must not tell me to stay away.
Shall I too be afraid?
Can it be said of Caesar, he gave up
the world because of a thunderstorm?
That such divinity that was in him ran
before mortal superstition?
I feel you need me now...
...and I cannot help you.
Then help me to live as I have lived,
always differently from the rest.
The others, for whom life is merely
an endless fear of dying.
Your gods...
...and mine go with you, Caesar.
The world, except for you,
is filled with little men.
Fire burns.
The winds of destruction blow.
Rome...
...mighty and alone, the winds of
destruction blow down upon thee!
Storms and hail
shall cut down wheat...
...shall cut down birds
and living things of earth.
The heavens...
...and the gods themselves.
My son!
Caesar! Caesar!
There has been much to do.
And it seems you have
done it extremely well.
Is that where...?
Yes.
In Egypt, we build eternal monuments
to our dead heroes.
Here, you burn them like rubbish.
Goodbye.
I've brought the 10th Legion.
You have nothing to fear.
Nothing to fear?
That's no reason for staying.
So much has happened so quickly.
Suddenly I have the pieces
of a broken world to pick up:
Caesar, you running off
at night like this.
Do you suggest that I stay? Why?
Don't ask me to be clear about
my feelings right now. I'm tired.
And with you,
it's never easy to say my meaning.
But you speak so well, Antony.
I've been told how excitingly
you read Caesar's will...
...to the sobbing, murdering,
free citizens of Rome.
Naming as his heir
his great nephew, Octavian!
I knew Caesar's will
and the reasons for it.
If Octavian hadn't been named...
...how many hours or minutes
would you have survived?
And if Caesar had become truly king...
...do you believe he would
still have named Octavian?
In any case, it's over.
Caesar...
...and the dream
that was murdered with him.
First Alexander's...
...then Caesar's.
Now over. Finished.
- First, Rome must be put in order.
- Rome again.
Brutus and the others
must be found and killed.
- Then?
- In death...
...Caesar must be granted the power
and title he was denied in life.
A dead king, a dead god.
Safe enough even for Rome.
Caesarion as Caesar's son could claim
the title of king and his deification.
And to what court of law
would my son and I take our claim?
I will present it
to the Roman Senate myself.
I believe you would.
And after the noble senators
have stopped laughing...
...do my son and I
then declare war on Rome?
No. For this,
a Caesar would be needed.
You have very little time.
Another Caesar.
But thank you.
I shall remember your kindness to us.
- You give up too easily.
- Do I?
Let me come to Alexandria
and talk more with you.
- Whenever you like.
- Now. Tonight, if I could.
In any case, try to remember.