The white zone is for loading
and unloading of passengers only.
There is no stopping in the red zone.
The white zone is for loading
and unloading of passengers only.
There is no stopping in the red zone.
Hello. Take this flower from
the Religious Consciousness Church.
- Would you care to make a donation?
- No, but thank you anyway.
The red zone is for loading
and unloading of passengers only.
There's no stopping
in the white zone.
No. The white zone
is for loading and unloading.
There's no stopping in the red zone.
The red zone's always been
for loading and unloading.
There's never stopping
in a white zone.
Don't tell me which zone's for
stopping and which is for loading.
Listen, Betty, don't start up
with your white zone shit again.
Hello. Take this flower from
the Religious Consciousness Church.
Would you like to make a donation?
No, thanks. We gave at the office.
Would you put all your metal objects
into this dish, please?
There's just no stopping
in a white zone.
Really, Vernon, why pretend?
We both know
what you're talking about.
You want me to have an abortion.
It's the only sensible thing to do.
If it's done properly,
therapeutically,
there's no danger involved.
Taxi!
I'll be back in a minute.
Hello, sir, take this flower from
the Religious Consciousness Church.
Would you care...
- Hey, Larry, where's the forklift?
- Forklift?
It's over there
by the baggage loader.
Look out!
- Elaine.
- Ted!
I came home early
and found your note.
I guess you meant for me to read
it later. I've got to talk to you.
I don't want to go over it any more.
Things haven't been right
for a long time,
but it'll be different,
like in the beginning.
Just be patient
and I'll work things out.
I have been patient
and I've tried to help,
but you wouldn't even let me do that.
Don't you feel anything
for me any more?
It takes so many things
to make love last.
Most of all, it takes respect.
I can't live with a man
I don't respect!
What a pisser.
Captain Oveur, white courtesy phone.
Captain Clarence Oveur,
white courtesy phone.
No, the white phone!
This is Captain Oveur.
One moment for your call
from the Mayo Clinic.
Captain Oveur, white courtesy phone.
- I've got it!
- Thank you.
Go ahead with your call.
This is Dr Brody at the Mayo Clinic.
There's a passenger
on your Chicago flight,
a little girl named Lisa Davis,
en route to Minneapolis.
She's scheduled
for a heart transplant.
Tell her mother we found a donor.
The heart is ready for surgery.
We must have the recipient on
the operating table within six hours.
Make sure she's kept
in a reclined position,
that a continuous watch
is kept on her IV.
It's very important
she remain calm...
Excuse me, this is the operator.
I have an emergency call
on line five from Mr Hamm.
Give me Hamm on five, hold the Mayo.
You'll be back tomorrow night.
We'll have dinner.
We'll talk things over.
I won't be back.
I've requested the Atlanta run.
Elaine... I promise I can change.
Then why didn't you take the job that
Louie Netz offered you at Boeing?
I haven't been able to get near
a plane since the war.
And they wouldn't hire me
because of my war record.
War record? You're the only one
keeping that alive.
For everyone else,
it's ancient history.
- You expect me to believe that?
- It's the truth.
What's hurt you the most
is your record since the war -
different cities, different jobs -
and not one of them shows you
can accept any real responsibility.
- Elaine, just give me one more...
- It's too late, Ted.
When I get back to Chicago,
I'm going to start my life
all over again. I'm sorry.
Excuse me, take this flower
from the Church of Religious...
Hi! Well, good evening.
There you go.
Just follow them to the back.
Any word on that storm lifting
over Salt Lake, Clarence?
No, not likely, Victor.
I just reviewed the area report
for 1600 hours through 2400.
There's an occluded front
stalled over the Dakotas,
backed up all the way to Utah.
If she decides to push over the Great
Lakes, it could get plenty soupy.
What about that southern route
around Tulsa?
I double-checked
the terminal forecast,
and the wind's aloft
and IFR ceilings all the way.
Where do they top out?
Light scattered cover
at 20,000, icing around 18.
- Looks like over Denver is best.
- Denver it is.
Sorry, Clarence.
Latest report shows everything's
socked in from Salt Lake to Lincoln.
Hi, Roger. Glad to have you aboard.
Victor, this is Roger Murdock.
Victor Basta.
- How do you do?
- Nice to meet you.
I was telling Victor
I reviewed the area report
for 1600 hours through 2400.
There's an occluded front
stalled over the Dakotas.
There you go. Thank you.
Is Elaine Dickinson on this flight?
The whole flight crew has boarded.
Let me see.
Oh, yes. She is on board.
I'd like one ticket to Chicago.
No baggage.
- Smoking or non-smoking?
- Smoking, please.
There. Have a nice trip.
Striker, this is Red Leader Four.
Primary target covered by fog.
Decision to proceed is yours.
The decision is yours...
is yours... is yours...
Golly, that white fellow
should stay away from my wife,
or I will punch him.
Yes, he is wrong for doing that.
I knew a man
in a similar predicament,
and he ended up being sorry.
Don't be naive, Arthur.
Each of us faces
a clear moral choice.
Early to bed, early to rise makes
a man healthy, wealthy and wise.
How true!
Golly!
Nervous?
Yes.
First time?
No. I've been nervous lots of times.
Hi. We'll be taking off real soon,
so I better fasten you in tight.
Thank you.
Oh, Mother, this is so exciting!
I know, but remember,
you must get some rest.
That's good advice. You relax,
and I'll be back after takeoff.
Thank you.
- I'm going to miss you so much.
- I'm going to miss you, too.
Promise you'll write?
Every day.
Bill!
Better get on board, son.
All aboard!
209er to ground control.
We're ready to taxi.
- Goodbye, Bill!
- Goodbye, darling!
I love you, darling!
209er, taxi to runway 19er.
Goodbye, darling!
Have your picture taken the minute
you get there and send me one.
OK. Here, hurry.
It's your watch. You shouldn't.
You're going to need this.
It's all right. It doesn't work.
- Bill!
- Goodbye, darling!
Bill!
Bill! Bill!
I'll keep it with me all the time.
Goodbye, darling.
Take care of yourself. Goodbye.
- Flight 209er - clear for takeoff.
- Roger.
- LA departure frequency 123.9er.
- Request vector. Over.
- What?
Flight 209er, clear for vector 324.
- We have clearance, Clarence.
- Roger, Roger.
What's our vector, Victor?
- I want radio clearance. Over.
- That's Clarence Oveur. Over.
- Roger.
- Huh?
- Roger. Over.
- Huh? Who?
Do you feel all right, sir?
Oh, I haven't flown for a long time.
Good evening.
This is Captain Oveur speaking.
We'll be cruising
at 36,000 feet this evening...
Relax and enjoy your flight.
Would you like something to read?
Do you have anything light?
How about this leaflet,
"Famous Jewish Sports Legends"?
Yes. Thank you.
- Ted! What are you doing here?
- I've got to talk to you.
You shouldn't have come.
I don't have time now.
- Stewardess?
- Excuse me.
But...
No wonder you're upset. She's lovely.
And a darling figure.
Supple, pouting breasts, firm thighs.
It's a shame you two
don't get along.
Yes, I know.
Things used to be different.
I remember when we first met.
It was during the war.
I was in the air force,
stationed in Drambuie,
off the Barbary Coast.
I used to hang out
at the Magumba Bar.
It was a rough place.
The seediest dive on the wharf,
populated with every reject and
cut-throat from Bombay to Calcutta.
It was worse than Detroit.
The mood in the place was ugly.
You wouldn't be there unless
you knew how to use your fists.
A fight broke out almost every night.
I didn't go there that night
to fall in love.
I just wanted a couple of drinks.
And suddenly, there she was.
I was captivated, entranced.
It hit me like a thunderbolt.
I had to asked this guy to pinch me
to make sure I wasn't dreaming.
I was afraid to approach her,
but that night, fate was on my side.
We laughed, we talked, we danced.
I never wanted it to end.
I guess I still don't.
Enough about me. I hope
this hasn't been boring for you.
Whenever I talk about Elaine,
I get carried away.
I lose all track of time.
Would you like to order dinner?
Joey will have steak.
We'll have fish.
When can I see the cockpit?
The pilots are probably too busy
flying the plane for that.
Aw, gee whizz!
I'll talk to the captain
and see what I can arrange.
Gee, that'd be swell!
Would you care to order your dinners?
I would like the steak, please.
I'll have the fish.
Excuse me, I happened to be passing.
I thought you might like some coffee.
That's very nice of you. Thank you.
- Won't you sit down?
- Thank you.
- Cream?
- No, I take it black.
Like my men.
Ted, I never knew
I could be so happy.
These past few months
have been wonderful.
Tomorrow, why don't we drive
to that little seafood place and...
- What's the matter?
- My orders came through.
My squadron ships out tomorrow.
We're bombing the storage depots
at Daiquiri at 1800 hours.
We're coming in
from the north, below their radar.
When will you be back?
I can't tell you that.
It's classified.
Oh, Ted, please be careful.
I worry about you so much.
I love you, Elaine.
I love you.
Flight 209er,
this is Denver flight control.
You're approaching rough weather.
Please climb to 42,000 feet.
- Roger, Denver.
- We have a visitor.
Hello.
Captain Oveur, Mr Murdock,
and Mr Basta, this is Joey Hammen.
- Hi, Joey.
- Come up here.
This is for special visitors.
Would you like to have it?
- Thank you. Thanks a lot.
- Sure. Ever been in a cockpit?
No, I've never been up
in a plane before.
Have you ever seen a grown man naked?
- Shall I check the weather?
- No, why don't you take care of it?
Joey, do you ever hang around
a gymnasium?
- We'd better get back.
- No, Joey can stay for a while.
- Could I?
- OK, if you don't get in the way.
Flight 209er to Denver,
climbing to cruise at 42,000.
Will report again over Lincoln.
Over and out.
Wait a minute, I know you.
You're Kareem Abdul Jabbar.
You play basketball
for the Los Angeles Lakers.
Sorry, you have me confused
with someone else.
My name's Roger Murdock.
I'm the co-pilot.
You are Kareem! I've seen you play.
My dad's got season tickets.
You should go back to your seat now.
Right, Clarence?
No, he's not bothering anyone.
Let him stay here.
All right, but just remember
my name is Roger Murdock.
I'm an airline pilot.
I think you're the greatest,
but my dad says you don't work hard
enough on defence.
And he says lots of times
you don't even run downcourt.
And you don't try,
except during play-offs.
The hell I don't!
Listen, kid, I've been hearing
that crap ever since I was at UCLA.
I'm out there busting my buns
every night.
Tell your old man
to drag Walton and Lanier
up and down the court for 48 minutes.
Joey...
Do you like movies about gladiators?
Elaine, just hear me out.
Things haven't been right
for a long time,
but it'll be different,
like in the beginning, remember?
I remember everything.
All I have is memories.
Mostly, I remember the nights
we were together.
I remember how you used to hold me,
and how I used to sit on your face
and wriggle, and...
afterwards, how we'd watch
till the sun came up.
When it did, it was almost like...
like each new day was
created only for us.
That's the way
I've always wanted it to be.
But it won't be.
Not as long as you insist
on living in the past!
You're too low, Ted! You're too low!
The mind plays tricks on you.
He looks so happy today, doesn't he?
You look so happy today.
OK, Robert, slip them down.
This won't hurt much.
You got a telegram
from headquarters today.
Headquarters? What is it?
A big building where generals meet,
but that's not important.
They've cleared you of any blame
for what happened on that raid.
- Isn't that good news?
- Is it?
Because of my mistake,
six men didn't return from that raid.
Seven.
Lieutenant Zip died this morning.
But Dr Sandler says you'll be out
in a week. Isn't that wonderful?
I wish I could say the same
for George Zip.
Be patient, Ted. Nobody expects you
to get over this immediately.
Hey, Striker, how about a break?
I'm getting tired.
Yeah, all right. Take five.
Thanks.
I found a wonderful apartment for us.
It has a brick fireplace
and a cute bedroom
with mirrors on the ceiling and...
Red Leader!
Red Leader, I'm going down!
Captain Geline. He think he's
a pilot, still fighting the war.
I've found the tunnel, Johnson!
It's this way!
$25 for a cigarette is too much!
- What's his problem?
- It's Lieutenant Hurwitz.
Severe shell shock.
He thinks he's Ethel Merman.
War is hell.
Excuse me, sir. Would you
like coffee before dinner?
No. No, thank you.
- Would you like another cup?
- I will, but Jim won't.
I think I will have
another cup of coffee.
Jim never has a second
cup of coffee at home.
- Excuse me, sister.
- Yes?
There's a little girl
onboard who's ill.
Oh, yes, I saw. Poor child.
Could I borrow your guitar?
I thought maybe I could cheer her up.
- Of course.
- Thank you.
- Hi.
Do you mind if I talk
to your daughter?
I think that'd would be nice.
- Hi, I'm Randy.
- I'm Lisa.
Oh, you have a guitar!
I thought maybe you'd
like to hear a song.
I'd love to.
OK. Let's see...
This is one of my favorites.
You're late. We've been waiting.
- Who's first?
- Go ahead, Clarence.
How's the weather?
We got some heavy stuff ahead.
We've got to climb on top.
Yeah, after the war, I wanted
to get as far away as possible,
so Elaine and I
joined the Peace Corps.
We were assigned
to an isolated tribe, the Molombos.
They'd never seen Americans before.
It was really a challenge,
introducing them
to our western culture.
At first, they didn't know
what to think of us.
But soon, we gained their trust.
It'll help you better
prepare storing foods
for the up and coming
monsoon months.
Also, Supperware products
are ideal for storing leftovers
to help stretch your food dollar.
This two-quart
"Seals-M-Rite" container
keeps hot dog buns fresh for days.
These people had been completely
isolated from civilization.
No one had outlined a physical
fitness program for them,
and they had no athletic equipment.
I started them
on simple calisthenics,
worked up to rudimentary game skills,
and finally,
advanced competitive theory.
I was patient,
and they were eager to learn.
They seemed to enjoy themselves.
Probably due to advanced
American teaching techniques,
we bridged the generations
of isolation,
and communicated successfully
with the Molombos.
They're getting the hang of it.
When we re-enlist,
I'll teach them baseball.
Ted, I don't want to stay here.
It's time to go home
to the plans we made before the war.
A lot of people made plans
before the war. Like George Zip.
At that moment, I realised Elaine
had doubts about our relationship.
And that, as much as anything else,
led to my drinking problem.
We did come back to the States.
I tried a number of jobs.
I could go on,
but I'd probably bore you.
I couldn't blame Elaine.
She wanted a career.
- I can't stand it.
- What is it?
- Yes?
- It's my stomach.
I haven't felt this awful
since we saw that Ronald Reagan film.
I'll see if I can find
some dramamine.
Captain, a woman passenger
is very sick.
Airsick?
I think so,
but I've never seen it so acute.
Find out if a doctor's onboard
as quietly as you can.
Joey, have you ever been
in a Turkish prison?
I shouldn't have had
that second cup of coffee.
Jim never vomits at home.
Sorry to wake you.
I'm looking for a doctor.
There's nothing to worry about.
Stewardess, I think the man
next to me is a doctor.
Sir, excuse me. Sorry to wake you,
are you a doctor?
- That's right.
- We have sick passengers.
- Could you come look at them?
- Yes. Yes, of course.
Let me see your tongue.
I'll be back in a minute.
Tell the captain to land.
She must go to a hospital.
A hospital! What is it?
It's a big building with patients,
but that's not important.
- I must speak to the captain.
- Certainly.
Victor, we're running into heavy...
Roger, take over!
- Captain, how soon can you land?
- I can't tell.
- You can tell me. I'm a doctor.
- No, I'm not sure.
- Can't you take a guess?
- Not for another two hours.
You can't take a guess
for another two hours?
No, we can't land.
Fog has closed down everything.
We've got to get through to Chicago.
Get him out of there!
What is it, Doctor? What's going on?
I'm not sure.
Haven't seen anything like this
since the Anita Bryant Concert.
- What did we have for dinner?
- We had a choice - steak or fish.
Yes, I remember. I had Lasagna.
- What did he have?
- He had fish.
Doctor, two more are sick.
The other passengers are worried.
We'll handle the passengers.
Find out what the sick people
had for dinner.
This is Captain Oveur speaking.
It's bumpy, but we'll be past it
in a few minutes.
We're now flying over Hoover Dam,
and later we'll pass south
of the Grand Canyon.
Meanwhile, relax
and enjoy your flight, OK?
Chicago, this is flight 209er.
We're in trouble.
We need traffic below us cleared
and priority landing in Chicago.
Yes?
My husband's very sick.
Can you do something?
The doctor will be with you
in just a moment.
Do you know what he had for dinner?
Yes, we both had fish. Why?
It's nothing to be alarmed about.
We'll be back to you very quickly.
Doctor, Mr Hammen ate fish,
and Randy said there are five
more cases, and they all had fish.
The co-pilot had fish.
What did the navigator have?
He had fish.
All right, now we know
what we're up against.
Those who had fish for dinner
will soon become violently ill.
- Just how serious is it?
- Extremely serious.
It starts with a slight fever,
dryness of the throat.
When the virus penetrates,
the victim becomes dizzy,
and begins to experience
an itching rash.
From there, the poison works
on the central nervous system,
causing severe muscle spasms,
followed by the inevitable drooling.
At this point,
the digestive system collapses,
accompanied
by uncontrollable flatulence.
Until, finally,
the poor bastard is reduced
to a quivering,
wasted piece of jelly.
Put it on... automatic pilot.
Automatic pilot, automatic pilot...
There it is!
I'll go back to the passengers.
Come in, 209er. This is Chicago.
Flight 209er, come in.
This is Elaine Dickinson,
the stewardess.
Captain Oveur's passed out.
We've lost the co-pilot
and navigator, too. We're in trouble.
Roger. I'm Steve McCroskey,
Chicago air control.
I'll be back in a moment.
Hold all takeoffs.
When 508 reports,
bring it straight in.
Suspend all meal service
on flights leaving Los Angeles.
Tell all dispatchers
to remain at the post.
- How about coffee?
- No, thanks.
I want the weather
on every available landing field.
You understand?
Any place available
to land that plane!
Go to the tower
and get a runway diagram.
Check down the field
for emergency equipment.
Chief, we got fog every place
east of the Rockies.
They'll have
to come through to Chicago.
Looks like I picked the wrong week
to quit smoking.
Get the best available man
who won't crack under pressure.
How about Mr Rogers?
Get me Rex Kramer.
Next to the throttle
is the air speed gauge.
What speed does it indicate?
- 520 miles per hour.
- Good. Very good.
Now, check your altitude.
That's the dial below and right
of the speed indicator.
35,000 feet.
No, wait. 34,000 feet.
No. It's dropping!
It's dropping fast!
Why is it doing that?
Oh, my God! The automatic pilot,
it's deflating!
Elaine, don't panic.
On his belt line
there's a hollow tube.
That's the manual inflation nozzle.
Pull it out and blow on it.
What the hell's going on up there?
- Elaine.
- Yes, Doctor?
Elaine, you're a member of this crew.
- Can you face some unpleasant facts?
- No.
Unless we hospitalise
those people quickly,
I can't be sure
of saving their lives.
Is there anyone on board
who can land this plane?
Well...
No. No one I know of.
You ought to know our chances.
Our lives depend on just one thing -
finding someone to fly this plane
who didn't have fish for dinner.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is your stewardess speaking.
We regret any inconvenience
the sudden cabin movement caused.
This is due to periodic air pockets.
There's no reason to become alarmed.
We hope you enjoy your flight.
By the way, is there anyone
on board who can fly a plane?
Hello. I'm Paul Carey
from the airline.
- I'm here to pick up Captain Kramer.
- Yes. Come in, Paul.
Rex will be right out.
Shep, sit. Sit!
I understand there's an emergency.
Something like that. There wasn't
time to tell me very much...
Shep, no!
I'll bet exciting things
happen all the time down there.
Airline business
does have its moments.
After a while, you get used to it.
Shep! Come!
He gets so excited
when new people are here.
- Are you a pilot?
- No, I'm in...
a training program.
It's unbelievable.
It's just unbelievable.
How many times have I warned
about food inspection?
You'd think
someone would listen to you.
Well, airport management,
the FAA, and the airlines...
they're all cheats and liars.
All right. Let's get out of here.
I'm sorry, I was just looking
for someone with flying experience.
When they built those roads,
they didn't think about drainage,
so we had to take a special jeep
up to the main road.
We were lucky to get a jeep,
since, just the day before,
only one we had broke down.
It had a bad axle...
Excuse me, sir.
There's a problem in the cockpit.
The cockpit? What is it?
The little room where the pilot sits.
That's not important.
The first officer is ill,
and the captain needs someone
to help him with the radio.
Do you know anything about planes?
I flew in the war years ago.
I wouldn't know anything about it.
Would you go up, please?
The stewardess said...
- Both pilots?
- Can you fly this plane and land it?
Surely, you can't be serious.
I am serious,
and don't call me Shirley.
Doctor, I've checked everyone.
Mr Striker's the only one.
What's your flying experience?
I flew single-engine fighters,
but this plane has four engines.
It's an entirely different
kind of flying... altogether.
kind of flying.
I haven't touched
any kind of plane in six years.
Mr Striker,
I know nothing about flying.
You're the only one on this plane
who can possibly fly it.
You're the only chance we've got.
That's right. That's what I said.
You heard me.
Tell Omaha to acknowledge
and stand by.
Every piece
of emergency equipment available.
Alert rescue units every mile
of the way, from here to the Rockies.
Chief!
We'll need
a free-landing flight check. Fast.
- It's your wife.
- I want the kids in bed by nine,
the dog fed, the yard watered,
the gate locked.
Get a note to the milkman -
"No more cheese."
Where the hell is Kramer?
No, he can't do that.
The risk of a flame-out's too great.
Keep him at 24,000... No, feet.
A passenger is going
to land that plane.
- Is that possible?
- It's a hundred to one shot.
- I know this guy.
- You do? Who is it?
Ted striker.
I flew with him during the war.
It won't make my job easier.
Ted Striker was a crack
flight leader.
He was one of those men who...
felt too much inside.
Maybe you know that kind.
He went all to pieces
on a particular mission.
Let's just hope
that doesn't happen tonight.
Let's see... Altitude, 24,000 feet.
Level flight. Speed, 520 knots.
Course Zero Niner Zero.
Trim, mixture.
Wash, soap, rinse, spin.
Ted! What are you doing here?
You can't fly this plane!
That's what I'm trying to tell them.
Elaine. I don't have time to be
gentle, so I'll be very direct.
Everyone is in a desperate situation.
Mr Striker is the only hope we got.
Those are the flaps.
This is the thrust.
This must turn on the landing lights.
- Mayday! Mayday!
- Mayday? What the hell is that?
May Day's the Russian new year.
We'll have a big parade and serve...
I can't stand it any more.
I've got to get out of here!
Calm down! Get a hold of yourself!
- Please let me handle this.
- I've got to get out...
Calm down. Get to your seat.
I'll handle it.
Calm down. Get ahold of yourself.
Doctor, you're wanted on the phone.
Everything will be all right.
- Sister, I can handle this.
- Got to get out of here!
We'd like you to have this flower.
Excuse me, sir, would you...
Donations for Reverend Moon?
Jews for Jesus?
Read about Jehovah's Witness?
How about Buddhism?
Help Jerry's kids?
- Scientology?
- For nuclear power?
Your attention, please.
No-frills passengers now arriving.
Please have your baggage
claim checks ready to show
upon leaving the terminal.
This guy has no airline experience.
He's a menace
to everything in the air.
Yes, birds, too.
OK, he's a terrible risk,
but what other choice have we got?
That's the whole story, Rex.
Everything we know.
Let's face a few facts.
I flew with Striker during the war.
He can't afford to worry about those
times when... things weren't so good.
- Right now things aren't so good.
- Let me tell you something.
Striker was a top-notch
squadron leader long ago.
Get on the horn
and talk that guy down.
Let him get the feel
of that airplane,
then you'll have to talk him
right down to the ground.
Very well.
Put Striker on the speaker.
Use my radio.
I took the wrong week
to quit drinking.
You can work them direct
from here, Captain.
Striker? Striker, this is
Captain Rex Kramer speaking.
Yes, Captain Kramer.
Read you loud and clear.
All right.
It's obvious you remember me.
What do you say we forget about
everything, except what we must do?
Let's not kid each other, Kramer.
You know I've never flown
a bucket like this.
- I'll need all the luck there is.
- Stand by, Striker.
Our one hope is to build this man up.
I've got to give him confidence.
Striker, you ever flown
a multi-engine plane?
- No, never.
- Shit! It's a goddamn waste of time.
There's no way he can land it!
You got to talk him down! You got to!
Route him into Lake Michigan. At
least avoid killing innocent people.
You're the only chance they've got.
All right.
Striker, you listen,
and you listen close.
Flying a plane
is like riding a bicycle.
It's just harder
to put baseball cards in the spokes.
First, get the feel of the plane.
Later, we'll run down
the landing procedure.
All right.
Disengage the automatic pilot.
Make no violent control movements
like you did in the fighter planes.
All right.
I'll unlock the automatic pilot.
The controls will feel very heavy
compared to a fighter.
Don't worry about that.
It's perfectly normal.
Now, one more thing.
Can somebody work the radio
and leave you free for flying?
The stewardess is here with me.
Good. Have her sit
in the co-pilot seat.
Elaine, he wants you
to sit in the co-pilot seat.
What's going on?
We have a right to know the truth.
All right, I'll level with you all.
The most important thing
is that you remain calm.
There's no reason to panic.
It's true
one of the crew members is ill.
Slightly ill.
The other two pilots are fine.
They're flying the plane,
free to pursue
a life of religious fulfilment.
The radio is all yours. Keep an eye
on number three engine gauge.
It's running a little hot.
Striker,
first I'd like to say something.
I know things must look
pretty rough up there.
If you do what I tell you
when I tell you,
there's no reason
you should lack confidence
in your chances of coming out
alive and in one piece.
What weather are you in?
- Rain.
- And a little ice.
And a little ice.
- How's it handling?
- Sluggish. Like a wet sponge.
Sluggish. Like a wet sponge.
All right, Striker.
You're doing just fine.
It's damn good
he doesn't know I hate his guts.
you don't know he hates your guts.
Can I get you something?
I'm sorry. I don't understand.
- Stewardess. I speak jive.
- Good.
He said he's in great pain,
and he wants to know
if you can help him?
Tell him to relax.
I'll be back with some medicine.
Call Captain Oveur's wife
and let her know what's going on.
This weather bulletin
just came off the wire.
What can you make out of this?
This? I can make a hat
or a brooch or pterodactyl...
- Hello?
- Mrs Oveur?
Yes, this is Mrs Oveur.
This is Ed Macias
calling from the airport.
There's trouble
on your husband's flight.
We don't know how serious it is,
but Steve McCroskey thought you'd
want to come over right away.
Yes. I'll be right down.
I've got to go to the airport.
You can let yourself
out the back door.
There's juice in the refrigerator.
Doctor says the sick people
are getting worse.
We're running out of time.
I've got to concentrate.
Hello?
Echo!
Pinch hitting for Pedro Bourbone,
Manny Mota.
- How you doing, honey?
- Jack, I'm so hot, I'm burning up.
I'll turn on some air.
- What's going on?
- Close the window!
Chicago,
the passengers are panicking.
When do we start down?
Not yet. You'll be in radar range
any second now.
They should have been in range
10 minutes ago.
Gunderson, check the radar range.
Anything yet?
About two more minutes, chief.
Two minutes?
They could be miles off course.
Impossible! They're on instruments.
This is going to be a real sweat.
Gunderson,
let me know when you get anything.
Got a cigarette, Nels?
I can't take much more of this.
Looks like I picked the wrong week
to quit amphetamines.
- Johnny, how about some more coffee?
- No, thanks.
These reporters want a statement.
- How much longer can they hold out?
- 30, 45 minutes.
- Who's flying the plane?
- A passenger.
He's an experienced air force pilot.
No cause for alarm.
- Take over.
- What kind of plane?
It's a big, pretty white plane
with red stripes,
curtains and wheels.
It looks like a big tylenol.
OK, boys. Let's get some pictures.
This bulletin just handed to me.
Stricken airliner
approaching Chicago...
Shana, they bought their tickets.
They knew what
they were getting into.
I say, let them crash!
- Would you like some whisky, ma'am?
- Certainly not!
How are the passengers?
I won't deceive you, Mr Striker.
We're running out of time.
Surely, there's something you can do.
I'm doing everything I can...
and stop calling me Shirley.
Randy, are you all right?
Oh, Dr Rumack.
I'm scared.
I've never been so scared...
And besides,
I'm 26 and I'm not married.
We're going to make it.
You've got to believe that.
Dr Rumack, do you have any idea
when we'll be landing?
Pretty soon. How are you bearing up?
To be honest,
I've never been so scared,
but at least I have a husband.
Stay in formation.
Target's just ahead.
Target should be clear
if you go in low enough.
You'll have to decide.
Stay in formation.
Target's just ahead.
Target should be clear
if you go in low enough.
You'll have to decide.
Oh, rats! Lost number four.
What happened? What went wrong?
I forgot to check the oil pressure.
When Kramer hears about this,
the shit's going to hit the fan.
I told him to watch that
oil temperature. What's he doing?
Stiker, that plane can't land itself.
Ease off. It's not his fault.
It could happen to any pilot.
It happened to Barbara Stanwyck.
Can't push him too hard. Might break.
Remember who you're dealing with.
Nick, Pete, Jerry,
there's a fire in the barn.
He's right.
I can't take the pressure.
I was crazy to think
I could land this plane.
- But, Ted, you're the only...
- I don't care.
I don't have what it takes.
They would be better off with someone
who's never flown before.
Bad news. Fog's getting thicker.
And Leon's getting larger.
I know what you're going to say,
so save your breath.
Well, I don't have a thing to say.
You've done the best you could.
You really have. The best you could.
We can't expect to win them all.
I want to tell you something I've
kept to myself through these years.
I was in the war. Medical corps.
One night, they brought in
a badly wounded pilot from one raid.
He could barely talk.
He looked up at me, he said,
"The odds were against us there,
but we went in anyway.
"I'm glad.
Captain made the right decision."
The pilot's name was George Zip.
George Zip said that?
The last thing he said to me,
"Doc," he said, "Sometime...
"...the crew is up against it.
"The breaks are beating the boys.
"Tell them to give it all they've got
"and win just one for the Zipper.
"I don't know
where I'll be then," he said...
"but I won't smell too good,
that's for sure."
Excuse me, doc.
I've got a plane to land.
You'd better stay up there a bit.
When the fog lifts,
we'll bring you in.
I'll take it, Elaine.
Listen, Dr Rumack says the sick
people are in critical condition.
Every minute counts.
We've got to land now.
Don't be a fool, Striker. You know
what landing like this means.
I'm ordering you to stay up there.
No dice, Chicago.
I'm giving the orders,
and we're coming in.
I guess the foot's
on the other hand now.
He'll never make it in this soup.
But it's his ship now.
He's in charge.
He's boss, head man, top dog,
big cheese, head honcho...
Captain, look at this.
"Passengers certain to die."
"Airline negligent."
There's a sale at Penny's!
I'll need three men in the tower.
You, Neubauer, you, Macias.
Me John. Big tree.
Striker, we're going to the tower.
Good luck.
They're going to the tower.
The tower! The tower!
Rapunzel! Rapunzel!
Stewardess, how soon till we land?
It won't be long now.
Try not to worry.
We're all ready, sir.
Captain McCroskey,
this is Captain Roberts.
Captain Kramer,
this is Captain Colosimo.
Captain Hinshaw,
this is Captain Gantz.
Captain Kramer, Captain Gantz.
Captain Hinshaw, Captain Roberts.
Colosimo, you work the relay.
Roberts, check air traffic.
Get that finger out of your ear.
You don't know where it's been.
- Steve!
- Got a cigarette, Nels?
Linda, your husband and the others
are alive but unconscious.
Just like Gerald Ford.
There's a chance we can save them
if Striker lands that plane in time.
That isn't much of a chance.
I don't know. We're doing
everything we can. Now excuse me.
Where did you get that dress?
It's awful!
And those shoes and that coat! Geez!
8 miles. Turn right to heading 044.
We're now at 2,000 feet
beginning our descent.
- Pour every light onto that field.
- It's being done.
Tower to emergency vehicles,
runway is niner.
Airport vehicles,
take positions one and two.
Civilian equipment, number three.
Air force, positions four and five.
All ambulances go to number three.
Air Israel, please clear the runway.
In a moment, we'll ask you
to assume crash positions.
Life jackets are under your seat.
Place it over your head.
When I give the word,
pull the cord on the right side flap.
Your seat cushions are also equipped
with a flotation device.
WZAZ in Chicago,
where disco lives forever.
Your altitude's too erratic.
You can't come straight in.
You've got enough fuel for two hours.
I'll take it, Elaine.
Listen to me, Kramer.
We have people up here who will die
in less than an hour.
I may bend your precious airplane,
but I'll get it down.
- The passengers are ready.
- Thanks, Randy.
You better leave, sweetheart.
You might get hurt up here.
- Ted...
- Yes?
I wanted you to know... now...
I'm very proud.
Tell them the gear is down
and we're ready to land.
The gear is down,
He's on final now.
Put out all runway lights
except niner.
Captain, maybe we ought
to turn on the searchlights.
No.
That's just what they'll
be expecting us to do.
I want to tell you both good luck.
We're all counting on you.
Now listen carefully.
You'll see the runway at 300 feet.
Touch down a third of the way.
A slight cross wind, so be ready.
Land too fast,
use your emergency brakes.
Red handle's right in front.
If that doesn't stop you...
If that doesn't stop you,
cut the four ignition switches.
Can you see us now? You should
be able to see the field.
- Sure is quiet out there.
- Yeah, too quiet.
Looks like I picked the wrong week
to quit sniffing glue.
There it is.
There he is!
Striker, you're coming in too fast.
I know, I know!
He knows, he knows!
Below 700 now. Still going down.
675, 650, 625, he's holding.
No, he's down, he's down.
Sound your alarm now.
Now, everybody,
get in crash positions.
Put down 30 degrees of flap.
All right, listen to me.
Remember your brakes and switches.
Get ready to flare it out!
He's all over the place.
900 up to 1,300 feet.
What an asshole.
More left rudder. Put down more flap.
Just kidding!
Striker, lift your nose.
Straighten your wings.
Coming in too fast. Watch your speed.
He's coming right at us!
Coming in too hot.
Ease up on the throttle.
Watch out for that cross wind.
Level it out.
You'll have to dip your left wing.
You're drifting. Keep your eyes
on the far end of the runway.
You're too low, damn it!
Watch your stall speed.
Flare it out!
Ease her down. Down!
The brake! Pull the red handle!
I want to tell you both good luck.
We're all counting on you.
Flight 209 now arriving
at gate eight.
Gate nine.
Gate ten.
Pull out of it! Push that button!
Gate 13... Gate 14.
Gate 15...
Auntie Em! Toto! It's a twister!
Gate 23, 24, 25...
I want to tell you both good luck.
We're all counting on you.
Striker?
- Striker, are you all right?
- Yeah. We're OK.
Ted, that was probably
the lousiest landing
in the history of this airport.
But some of us, particularly me,
would like to buy you a
drink and shake your hand.
And, Ted, when the going got rough...
Have a nice day. OK.
Have a nice day and thank you
for flying TransAmerican.
Loneliness, that's the bottom line.
I was never happy as a child.
Christmas,
what does that mean to you?
Mine was living hell.
Do you know what it's like
to fall in the mud
and get kicked in the head
by an iron boot?
Of course not. It never happens.
Sorry. That's a dumb question.
Skip that.
There you go. Have a nice day.
Municipal bonds, Ted.
Talking double "A" rating.
Best investment in America.
Well, I'll give him
another 20 minutes, but that's it.