Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
There once was
a peculiar doctor,
known for his
extraordinary ability.
He could talk to animals.
Dr. Dolittle's reputation
spread far and wide.
Even the queen of England called on him.
So grateful for his help,
she gifted him
a wondrous sanctuary,
whose doors were open
to all creatures.
His days belonged
to the animals,
but his heart belonged
to one woman:
Lily, the fearless explorer.
They traveled the globe
going on great adventures,
defending creatures who could
not defend themselves.
They made
an extraordinary team.
Soon, that team
became a family.
With Lily by his side,
Dolittle never felt more alive,
until one day,
she left on an adventure.
Lily died at sea.
Heartbroken, he locked
the gates of the manor
and completely retreated
from the world.
As for me and the animals
whose lives he'd saved,
we were left to wonder...
could anyone save his?
Until one morning,
a most unlikely creature
found its way
into Dolittle's life.
A very special boy.
In a time where people
thought of animals
only as possessions,
food or sport,
this boy felt
quite differently.
This way,
me scattered squirrel.
Right.
Junior flushes 'em.
You shoot 'em. Yeah?
Right. Good plan, Dad.
Get ready.
- Shoulder your gun.
- Do I have to, Uncle?
Come on, boy.
Duck!
Duck! Duck, duck!
- Duck! Duck!
- There, there they go.
Shoot, shoot, shoot.
You got him. You got him.
You got him.
Shoot, shoot, shoot.
- Oh, oh, no, I can't.
- Shoot, shoot, shoot!
You can't keep
missing on purpose.
Oh, look.
He hit something this time.
Oh, no.
We have to help him.
Aye.
We never leave
an animal suffering.
Not on our error.
Here you go.
He's a very odd boy.
Follow Poly.
"Home of Dr. John
and Lily Dolittle.
We treat all animals."
Ah-ah.
Follow Poly.
Secret entrance.
P-Poly? Where'd you go?
Good... good... good dog.
Big, hairy...
It's not good.
As far as I'm concerned,
I'm the only human here.
Just ignore them.
There's no getting past
a Kalahari snare, Doc.
It's an ingenious design.
I think you just
caught yourself a boy.
Let me see.
Wait, I don't want to see.
Just make it go away.
Deep breaths, Doc.
Dab-Dab's got your back.
Don't be afraid, John.
It's just a boy.
This is an opportunity.
Oh, this is a nightmare!
- Oh, come on.
- Pardon me.
Whatever are you
doing up there?
I've come from
Buckingham Palace
on urgent business.
Can you tell me if this is
the home of John Dolittle?
Who are you?
You may call me Lady Rose.
And you are?
Stubbins.
Could you help me down?
This goes against
Dolittle's rules.
Why are humans
against the rules again?
If you let humans too close,
you'll get hurt
more than you would if
you didn't let them in at all.
Isn't that right, Doc?
That's enough, everybody.
Back to our routine.
- We have a very full day.
- John!
Pull yourself together.
You can't ignore people
just because they're...
people.
What if they need help?
Possum. Play dead.
This is ridiculous.
Chee-Chee,
will you answer the door?
You're the only one with arms.
I think chess was
enough pressure for one day.
Chee-Chee, boy,
this is what we trained for.
Be brave and get rid of 'em.
And don't forget your mantra.
I am not a prisoner of fear?
You are not a prisoner of fear.
Have you been here before?
The queen's told me
all about it.
It's a most unusual place.
I'm prepared for anything.
Wonderful.
A gorilla answering the door.
Just as the queen said.
Oh, wait a minute.
I have an injured squirrel.
I should never have let you go.
Hello?
Oh, look at you.
Aren't you peculiar
posing as a twig?
Move, please.
This is my hiding spot.
Not here.
Are you all right down there?
Yeah. Fine.
- Go on.
- Dr. Dolittle?
- Yeah, right.
- You have been summoned
to Buckingham Palace
by the queen herself.
Hoo-ha.
Go on.
You should know,
she's fallen gravely ill.
Do you understand
what I'm saying?
Do you understand what
I'm saying?
Go... on.
Go on and be gone!
I don't care about anyone,
anything, anywhere anymore.
The birds will show you out.
Right, everything's tidy.
Lunch will be served in a minute now.
Mmm!
Smells lovely, Doc.
Thanks very much.
Hey, Doc, save some
for us this time.
Sorry, Doc.
Guess I'm scared of kids, too.
Don't worry about that.
Come on, let's eat.
I'm going to be offering today
a brothy soup.
You'll never believe
what we caught in the net.
The queen has asked for you
by name, sir.
Are you hard of hearing?
I told you,
I'm closed for business.
What business?
Treating humans.
Intruder alert.
Don't worry. I'm fine.
Well, I'm not.
My house is descending
into chaos.
I-Is he yours?
I don't own anybody.
Yoshi had an issue
that he came to me with.
He's always cold.
I have an injured squirrel.
I don't know what to do.
How was he injured?
I...
I-I shot him.
What? I can't hear you.
I shot him,
but it was an accident.
Of course,
an accidental firing upon.
Humans never change.
He's very hurt.
Please help him.
Take that.
And this.
I...
I... I...
I'm too beautiful to die.
Oh.
Yes?
He's with us.
Dab-Dab, Jip, light the lamps
and disinfect the surgery.
You will not tend to a squirrel
while the queen of England's
life hangs in the balance.
Oh, you don't know me
very well, do you?
Don't drop him.
We got a code red.
Code red, code red, everybody.
The doctor is back!
Hang on, little buddy.
Whew!
I haven't done this in a while.
Let's get everything
the way Doc likes it.
Don't worry. We got you, pal.
Righto. Let's save
this squirrel, shall we?
Okay.
When you wake up,
everything will be fine.
If I die, I swear
I will haunt your house.
Sterilize the scalpels.
Do not lick any instruments.
Patient's condition
has stabilized.
They're understanding him,
and he's understanding them,
in their own languages.
Going through the left
ventricle... it's brilliant.
Wow.
Dab-Dab, forceps, please.
Here you go.
That's a piece of celery.
Forceps, Dab-Dab.
Oh, sorry. Here you go.
Still celery.
Forceps?
- Carrot, that is.
- Forceps?
That's a different piece
of celery.
Got it. Forceps.
No, still celery.
Never mind. I'll get it myself.
I want to know how to talk
to the animals.
Chee-Chee, brow.
My brow as well,
when you've got a second.
Right. Sorry.
I'm going to come here
and be Dolittle's apprentice.
Her Majesty has designated
this land a nature preserve.
If she dies,
the deed will be owned
by the Treasury,
and this place goes away.
- Shut down?
- Mm-hmm.
There you are.
Whoo, still got it, Doc.
Oh, wow.
Ah.
There, Cheech.
That's the spot.
Keep an eye on Kevin, shall we?
He may be prickly
when the anesthetic wears off.
Revenge.
Okay, okay.
Enough with the pampering.
You need to go
and help the queen.
There are things
I no longer do:
work with humans
or leave the house.
- Or bathe.
- Oh, exercise.
Express emotional
vulnerability.
Wake up, John.
If the queen dies,
the Treasury takes the deed,
and we'd lose this house.
You're talking out of
your tail feathers, Poly.
The deed was for life.
The last time I checked,
I was very much alive.
The queen's life, John,
not yours.
Look at that.
It just rolls off my back.
I knew I shouldn't have let
monkeys proofread the contract.
Elliot, Elsie, you are fired!
It gets worse. We'll be
thrown out of these gates
right in the middle
of hunting season!
- What?
- No, no, no.
Breathe, Chee-Chee.
We get kicked out
if the queen dies?
- We're gonna be hunted!
- Everybody, calm down.
- Look at the state of him now.
- Fear not.
I have an in at, uh,
Regent's Park Zoo.
Everyone, pack your bags!
Ah-ah.
You help the queen,
or we are leaving.
- You're bluffing.
- Don't make me count.
Don't make me count.
One.
Three!
Two.
All right!
I'll do it.
Marvelous.
Right, let's get you
ready to go, honey.
- I'll go as I am.
- Not looking like that.
- Just grab my doctor's bag.
- Get him.
Apologies, Doc.
Hold still, now.
Take your paws off me!
- This isn't gonna hurt a bit.
- Let's clean him up.
How dare you.
- Whoa.
- Oh, hey, guys.
Arthur? How long have you
been living in there?
I don't know.
What year is it?
Dab-Dab's got the razor.
That's still celery.
Nighty-night, Doc.
Dolittle used to
travel all around the world.
Look.
Rummaging through
my private projects, is it?
How is he?
Well, first things first,
the squirrel's name is Kevin.
Expect a full recovery.
And after some violent
grooming, it's been decided.
We will accompany you
to Buckingham Palace after all.
Hmm.
You are going back
to whatever burrow
you emerged from.
Try not to shoot anything
on your way home.
Maybe I-I should stay here.
I don't do well in crowds.
We'll look after you, Cheech.
But we all go together,
just like the old days.
Oh, don't forget Doc's forceps.
That's a leek, Dab-Dab.
Sure it is.
Styx?
No.
Where are you? Oh.
So, uh, would you care
to come along?
I know.
I had other plans as well.
Hurry up. Hurry up.
Shh!
Prepare my ride.
Today's gonna be a good day.
I'm gonna do nothing...
just prance around,
think my own thoughts and...
- Oh, he's walking this way. Not a great sign.
- Oh, uh...
He's got no beard.
He looks motivated.
Uh, no. Plimpton, don't be alarmed.
People only say that when
they're about to be alarming.
- Look, I know it's been a while.
- Sorry about this.
- And sorry about that.
- All right.
I'm unavailable.
Unavailable for the man
who changed your life?
We're going to save
the queen, bro!
I am not your bro.
You should be
an Eskimo's rug by now.
- Ow. Claws.
- Ow! Beak!
- Claws.
- Beak!
Now, now, gentlemen.
Oh, you've gained weight.
Why are you riding me?
There's, like, four horses
in front of us.
Cheer up, angry bird.
Kick back and enjoy the ride.
I am the ride.
Buckingham Palace.
We've hit the big time!
Full speed no longer required!
Whoa.
Welcome home, milady.
Guards! Guards!
Your ladyship, Rose.
They are the queen's
own guests.
Treat them accordingly.
You better
give us a wide berth.
Make way, boys.
Plimpton, don't. Stop.
- Don't stop? Odd decision, but...
- Stop!
Whoa!
Aah! Can't see!
Oh, my God.
Oh, uh...
Okay.
I blame the hat.
Dr. Müdfly.
Lord Badgley.
My lord.
I come from the House of Lords.
There is great concern
for Her Majesty's health.
I shall continue to leech
to circulate the vapors
in the bloodstream.
She'll be lucky
to last the week.
This is not the first time
Dr. Dolittle's been here.
You got a dying queen?
Not for long.
Dr. Dolittle is in the...
Oh, uh, wait. Wait for me!
A stowaway, my lady,
who claims to be Dr....
Dr. Dolittle's apprentice.
It's quite all right, Gareth.
Well, if he was my apprentice,
he should fetch my bags
and keep his gob shut.
- A bird.
- A duck.
Animals in the queen's chamber?
I demand their
immediate remov...
Ah, Lady Rose.
My apologies.
Please forgive me.
I didn't realize
that you were part of...
John Dolittle?
- Is that Blaine?
- Blair.
Poopfling?
- No.
- It was Mudflap?
- No, it's Müdfly.
- It was... Müdfly.
- With an umlaut.
- Yes.
- From the German.
- Of course.
- From the Germans.
- Why is he here?
Her Majesty has personally
requested Dr. Dolittle.
Well, then, let's get to work.
All right, Jip,
give her a good sniff.
- That dog is licking the queen.
- Don't worry, my love.
This is outrageous.
Oh, bark.
- You all right, fellow?
- Something smelled wrong.
And that's coming from a guy
who loves the smell of butts.
Oh, you do love butt.
I detected a whiff
of something else.
Floral, with earthy...
I'm perplexed, Doc.
I've never smelt anything
like it before.
Uh, clearly, Jipsy and I
are out of our depths.
- May we consult?
- Well, of course.
I'd be more than happy
to help illuminate...
John and I were students
at Edinburgh years ago.
Some thought he had
a gift for observation.
One minute.
Oh, sorry about that, Mini.
Stay here.
Dab-Dab, clear out the humans.
Boyo, fetch the "Botanical
Index" and the tea tin.
Everyone out.
Do you understand the words
coming out of my bill?
What do you smell, Jip?
Elderberries?
Hemlock?
Negative.
Aye, aye.
What have you found, Dolittle?
Well, quite possibly,
the answer to everything.
Exposure to toxic...
God, he was like this
at school.
"Lean in, lean in.
I'm saying something
interesting."
I am interested.
The queen's symptoms
are due to the effect
of a rare Sumatran plant
known as the nightshade flower.
A solar eclipse will occur
on the 17th of this very month.
If she has not received
the antidote by then,
she will perish.
Is that a Turner?
Must be.
What a fine painting.
I say, Dolittle,
what is your plan?
The plan?
Uh, I suppose we do need one.
Well, the queen's only hope
is a cure that's
never been tested,
from a tree
that's never been seen,
on an island
that's never been found.
Sounds ridiculous
saying it out loud.
But regardless of that...
...we have no choice
but to embark
on this perilous journey
to obtain the fruit
of the Eden Tree.
What?
Eden Tree. Oh, my. Fantastic.
The Dolittles with
their Eden Tree Island.
- Isn't it enough that your wife...
- Shut up, Blair!
Sorry, I-I meant to say:
"Lovely to see you
again, Blair."
We're off now. Ta-ra.
Oh, its fruit is said to cure
every malady known to man,
grant eternal life,
even restore
the hair on your head.
You must let nothing
pass her lips
that hasn't been made
and served by you.
Clear?
Yes, I'll see to it.
That's us to the carriage.
Jip, you need to stay behind
and guard the queen.
- Very important.
- Right, guard dog mode.
Stand back, everyone,
while I secure the perimeter.
Excuse me.
I do so admire
how you don't give up.
The queen is counting
on both of you.
Good luck.
Right. Chop-chop.
We got a long voyage
in front of us,
and the boat isn't
gonna sail itself.
Deep breath, Yoshi.
We haven't got all day.
Seems like she's full up.
Maybe we could
squeeze in one more.
Plenty of room.
- Oh, no.
- Uh, Plimpton.
I mean, one more stop,
good fellow.
I can't hear you,
because I am not here.
Well, I believe it's time
to go our separate ways.
Uh, I'm going with you.
Certainly not.
It's far too treacherous.
I'm your apprentice.
You? No, no, no.
Oh, you have an apprentice?
You don't need an apprentice
and an ostrich.
I'll go home.
I didn't want
to be embarrassed,
so I pretended you belonged.
I was helpful in there,
wasn't I?
- Hmm...
- The animals like me.
I don't take up much space.
I think I belong here.
Don't make me go home.
Please.
What is that around your neck?
Come on.
I'm worried about the boy,
Bethan.
Give him time. Time is all.
We're hunters, Bethan.
Hunters.
It has a certain...
We hunt things.
He frees things.
Like rabbits and mice.
He carries spiders outside.
Nobody likes spiders...
not even spiders.
I don't know how your sister
put up with him.
Ugh. Ugh.
Poly?
What are you doing here?
Making sure
you don't miss the boat.
A-Am I talking to an animal,
just like Dolittle?
Oh, no.
I'm speaking human.
Better than any parrot
ever has, actually.
Now, let's pack some clothes.
Come on.
But Dolittle said
I belong here.
Little help, Tutu?
Well, I never heard him say
anything of the sort.
There's something special
about you, Stubbins.
Something I've only seen
in two other humans.
You belong with us, kid.
And you let me worry
about Dolittle. That's my job.
So, are you ready for
the adventure of a lifetime?
I'm in.
Of course you are.
Poly, let's move.
We got a boat to catch,
and we're burning daylight.
Fret not, ma chérie.
We have the perfect plan.
New plan!
Come on!
Don't let them get away!
Why are they chasing us?
We're not criminals.
Speak for yourself.
We're wanted in three forests.
And it's not an escape mission
unless you're being chased.
Whoa!
That tickles!
Which way, Tutu?
- Down!
- Whoa!
Clear the way!
Hey! This way!
Get off the road, ma chérie.
See you later, suckers.
Whew. We've done it.
We've done it. We...
Missed it.
Okay, boss,
what's our next move?
We cut our losses,
change our identities,
ditch the kid in the river.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, easy.
Wh-Wh-What about that bridge?
Yes, the bridge.
Uh, that was
my next suggestion.
Let's go!
Come on, Doc.
At least get out
of the hammock.
Your seasickness will wear off.
Try some of this ginger root.
You'll get your sea legs back.
You look terrible.
Ah, button it.
Who put me in this hammock?
I am the captain
of this ship, right?
Raise the blasted sails, will you?
Uh, that's a big bite.
Everyone, look.
Is that the boy?
He's coming to finish the job!
He won't rest till I'm dead!
He's obsessed!
- John, slow the boat down.
- No.
- I want to go faster. I want...
- Sorry, kid. Doc says no.
We're going to miss
all the good current!
- I hope you make it.
- Me, too, Dabs.
- All right, Bets, moment of truth.
- Okay.
Oh, big hole, 12 o'clock!
Maybe this is a bad idea.
- Let's go, Stubbins, let's go!
- Come on, kid.
Get on the boat!
I've run out of track!
But not courage!
- Fly and be free!
- Whoa!
Vive la résistance!
- Is that thing up to code?
Whoa. Whoa.
No!
No.
Jump, murderer.
You got this.
Oh, I can't look.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
Do it again! Do it again!
- Do it again! Do it again!
- Yes!
- Crushed it, kid.
- Do it again! Do it again!
You made it.
Why y'all cheering
for the kid who shot me?
Ah, he's all right.
Darling.
- Can I have a word, please? Huh.
- Glad you came around
and saw things my...
What was she thinking?
The boy nearly killed himself.
Oi! This is my ship, right?
And I'm its sovereign.
And there are consequences...
To ignoring me.
- Is that what you were going to say?
- No, no.
Don't mince my words.
And stop messing
with my routine.
But look at the state of you.
You're sick as a dog.
Uh, but actually,
I have my medicine.
See? This licorice root
is working a treat.
Sit down, John.
Don't embarrass me
in front of the crew.
I'm sparing you embarrassment.
You need a trim.
All right, all right, be quick.
It's important to maintain
my status, yeah?
This ship is dangerous...
no place for a... Ow.
- Ow!
- What? - Huh?
Hurts, man!
Private conversation.
- Oh, okay. - Okay.
- Sorry.
I know this particular voyage
is hard for you, John.
It is for me, too.
I brought you Lily
just when you needed her,
and now you need
one of your own kind again.
Someone without feathers
or fur.
Fine, the boy can stay,
but it'll be on my terms.
And I'll keep him quite busy.
You'll do it
with a smile on your face.
Crew!
Seems you got a new shipmate.
As I just told Poly,
we are a bit shorthanded
after all, so...
You won't regret it.
Welcome aboard.
I hear you could be
a big help...
...by cleaning this up.
That, too,
if you wouldn't mind.
Oops. Those as well.
And that.
I got these.
Careful with that
medical equipment.
Because a parrot's in charge
of my ship! Brilliant!
He's absolutely thrilled
to have you.
Hmm.
Hello there, little squid.
You don't understand me,
do you?
That would be preposterous.
- Müdfly.
- I wasn't talking to the squid!
I'm dispatching a frigate,
the Britannia,
to follow Dolittle.
But you must not support him
in his foolishness, my lord.
England has enemies everywhere
waiting for the slightest
sign of weakness.
Entrusting beloved Britain
to a child queen?
That is lunacy.
So, while I remain here
ensuring no one prevents me
from taking the throne,
you will be on the Britannia
making certain
Dolittle never returns.
Great. Round two, yeah?
You got me on the ropes,
you have, Cheech.
Come on. One, two.
Jab, jab, cross.
The best form of defense
is attack.
I really don't want
to fight you.
We're not fighting, are we?
It's a therapeutic session.
I-I think I'm getting this.
I'm actually starting
to understand.
Stop worrying, John.
Every step is planned out
in my journal.
I'll be back
before you even miss me.
Are you all right?
I think I'm beginning
to understand
a little bit of what
the animals are saying.
Seems you are, boyo.
What kind of polar bear
works on their tan?
Well, what kind of bird...
Wait, are you even a bird?
- Of course I am.
- Well, can you fly?
- No.
- Can you swim?
No.
Well, what can you do?
- I can run.
What bird stuff can you do?
Well, what bear stuff
can you do?
You win this round.
Ro...
Pickles?
Oh, you were saying "warship."
Weird time to be asking
for pickles.
I mean, who could eat
when we're under attack?
Enemy, starboard aft.
Elliott, you and Elsie
ready the machine.
We're gonna need speed.
Send out the call.
Which way are the lifeboats?
This whole thing is
a death boat.
Mini, mind the lookout.
Stubbins, boy, I need you
now more than ever...
- to stand still.
- I surrender!
We surrender!
Oh...
hello, Blair,
you chinless wonder.
He said something
about my chin, didn't he?
It's a magnificent chin, sir.
We're in their sights.
Cannons are taking aim.
Let's turn this ship!
I'm on my way.
It is time for me to slip into
something less comfortable.
Hello...!
I bought a front-row seat
to crazy town.
Once Humphrey's been secured,
you pull me out
on Yoshi's signal.
Me? No, I-I can't handle
that type of pressure, Doc.
I'm a "cheer quietly from
the sidelines" kind of gorilla.
Don't worry, Cheech.
You'll rise
to the occasion, huh?
You're stronger than you know.
Now, remember, courage
is not the absence of fear.
Wait. You got cut off.
I-I can't hear you.
I need the second part!
No time, Cheech. Let's go.
Oh, look, look.
They're already
abandoning ship.
Boom!
Oh, this is gonna be cold.
But I'm coming in hot!
Humphrey here.
Let's hook it up.
Where we headed?
South.
Okay, I can do this.
I can do this.
Full steam ahead!
Go, Humphrey, go!
Are they pulling away?
Do it, whale, do it!
Whoo-hoo!
- It's working!
- How is this possible?
- Well, sir, it appears
Dolittle and a polar bear
have harnessed a whale...
It was a rhetorical question.
Just fire!
I dropped the rope!
I failed.
I knew I couldn't do it.
- Yoshi!
- Hang on.
I'm coming, kid!
- No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
- You're doing great.
Oh, this is gonna
murder my back.
Quit complaining,
you oversized flamingo.
Oh, no, no, no.
Oh, no.
- Oh, no.
- Oh!
- Yes!
I let you down, Doc.
Look at me.
I'm fine. We're all fine.
- I froze.
- No, no, no, Cheech.
It's okay to be scared.
Mm-mm.
You saved me, did you?
Fair play.
Thanks very much.
Well done, everybody.
Feel like you belong now, kid?
I guess I do.
- We lost 'em.
- I guess I do.
Great work, gang.
Eat our dust, Mudfly.
- They've gotten away, sir.
- Oh, really?
I thought they disappeared
into thin air.
I'm afraid not, sir.
They've escaped.
Read the room, Lieutenant!
I can see they've escaped.
But not for long.
It's a miracle.
That must mean
I am the chosen one.
I'm gonna change the wor...
Whale power.
Dolittle had to write
a paper about it,
which, of course,
nobody took seriously.
This one even theorizes
the existence of dragons.
Just preposterous.
Sir, I'm afraid your obsession
with Dolittle is...
What obsession?
I'm not obsessed with Dolittle.
You're obsessed with Dolittle.
You're the one obsessing
about my obsession with Dol...
I'm loath to admit it,
but he's more valuable alive
for now.
But luckily,
I think I know
where he's going.
Kevin's log, day seven.
I'm now totally isolated.
The enemy has
ingratiated himself
with the captain and crew.
No sign of promised
tropical island
or the magic fruit.
But I will endure.
Take the wheel, Stubbins.
- Really?
- Yeah, yeah.
I have to calculate
our route coordinates.
The bees are buzzing about you.
Seems you are getting
a rudimentary grasp
of their language.
35 degrees portside.
Well, I-I have noticed when
they fly in a zigzag pattern,
they sort of go...
Which means: "Back off, kid."
But when Dab-Dab goes, uh...
That means: "Look at this."
Mm. "Look at me."
- Oh, close.
- Not bad, though.
Oh, uh...
No, when Chee-Chee says...
When Chee-Chee says...
That means:
"Where's my... blanket?"
Very good.
Is that the map
of Eden Tree Island?
The Eden Tree cannot
be found on any map.
And to call it an island
is to suggest
that it is of our world,
and it is anything but.
That is why we must first go
to Monteverde,
birthplace of the only person
to ever chart a course
to the tree.
Her name was Lily.
She wrote the route
in a journal,
but on her voyage,
she was shipwrecked.
The world lost the greatest
explorer I've ever known.
The journal
from that expedition
was all that survived.
Elliot, Elsie, do you mind?
So, anyway,
you get the picture.
To have any chance
of finding the tree,
we have to go to Monteverde and
steal that flippin' journal.
Steal the journal?
Did I say that?
Well, what's the worst
that can happen?
Don't worry.
I know an omen when I see one,
and that was not an omen.
Stealing the journal
is not a big deal.
In fact,
Monteverde itself
is not a big deal.
The stop at Monteverde
was a very big deal.
After all, this island
of bandits and thieves
was once a place Dolittle,
Lily and I called home.
Until the doctor
made an enemy of the island's
notorious ruler, King Rassouli.
And just our luck...
his most prized possession
was the very journal
we needed to steal.
So Dolittle needed a disguise.
While I was left watching
over the rest of the crew,
Dolittle and Stubbins
snuck into the palace.
I'm about to die!
Once inside, their path ended
at a heavily bolted door,
naturally.
But Dolittle still had
questionable contacts
on the island.
Hut, hut, hut,
hut, hut, hut, hut, hut, hut...
The opening bid will suffice.
You have my attention.
Don Carpenterino,
I'm here on behalf
of these humans.
They will pay you handsomely
for your family's
lock-picking skills.
You come to me for this,
on the day of
my daughter's wedding?
Wait a minute.
Which daughter?
It's not... Sh-Sheila?
My Sheila?
She's getting married?
- To a scorpion named Dylan.
- Sorry, Boy Scout.
I guess Sheila's
into bad boys now.
We were gonna spend the rest
of our life spans together.
Move on, James.
What's your human's best offer?
Two more now...
and two later. Huh?
Okay.
You have yourself a deal.
See you around, Boy Scout.
Guys, I'm no Boy Scout.
Also, what's a scorpion got
that I don't got?
- Besides a massive stinger.
- Get over her, James.
You dated for two weeks.
These bars are new.
Totally messing up my plan.
I can fit through them.
No, no, no.
It's too dangerous, man.
Can't go in there on your own.
Let me take him in, Doc.
I need something to distract me
from this Sheila reveal.
Are you sure your head's
in the right place, James?
Oh, yeah.
I'll get the kid in
and then fly headfirst
into a brick.
Just kidding. I'm fine.
Aye. All right.
James will look after you.
It's fine.
Listen closely.
Get the journal
and get out of there.
Go through the room quietly.
Look for the tiger's eye.
Go down the hidden staircase.
And most importantly,
keep your disguise on.
There's just one
little thing you should know.
Rassouli loves his cats.
But that's no problem for us,
'cause we can just fly
right over... Wait.
Uh, I see the mistake
I made here.
You can't fly.
Hey. Oh. Watch out.
Kitty cat on your six.
Oh, God.
Oh, oh! Whoa, whoa!
Hey!
Slick move, kid.
We make a pretty good team.
A real couple of bad boys.
Okay, partner,
you know where to go.
I'll keep watch on these lions.
That's what a bad boy
dragonfly does.
Would Dylan get
this close to a lion?
Would he get this close?
How about this close?
Oh, sh...
This is bad.
This is... very bad.
"Lily...
Dolittle."
We got the journal! Open up!
Just kidding. He blew it.
- Bye!
- Oh, dear.
Stubbins.
Former resident here.
- Don't move.
- Huh?
Don't touch.
All I wanted was my daughter
to marry wisely,
and instead, I got
the ringleader of a circus.
I never understood
what Lily saw in you.
A common complaint
the world over
for fathers
of beloved daughters,
but in this instance,
I think we can all agree
it is particularly accurate.
Come here.
Come here. Come here.
Um, so,
you didn't mean any of that.
It was her journal.
The only thing of hers
my men found in the wreckage.
It belongs here.
All you had to do was
never show your face again
and even at that...
you failed.
Now you'll pay
for taking Lily away from me.
You knew what would happen
if you returned.
Yes.
Barry! Barry!
Barry! Barry! Barry!
You should go.
Come on, Barry!
It's my past that's caught up
with me, not yours.
- Yeah?
- But you're my friend.
Go. Don't look back.
You're better off
without him, kid.
Um... I'm in compliance.
Yes!
Finally, some action down here.
Boy, was it getting boring.
You know, Doc,
I hate to tell you, but you're
going down, my friend.
You'd do well to keep
your buckteeth together.
What is that smell?
Hey, fellas,
I think Dr. Dolittle
did a little doo-doo.
Did Dr. Dolittle do
a little doo-doo?
Perhaps when I'm out of here,
I'll teach you some manners
and accept your lucky foot
as payment.
Oh, this lucky foot?
Don't worry about it, Doc,
'cause both of my lucky feet
are gonna be tap-dancing
on your grave
when my guy's done with you.
Taking bets over here.
In the right corner,
wearing golden stripes,
with a sparkling record
of 872 kills,
Barry "The Butcher" Bernstein!
Dr. Dolittle, remember me,
your old patient?
It's Barry.
Barry.
How could I forget you?
Oh, but you did, Doc.
We were just starting
to make progress,
and then you run off
with Rassouli's daughter
and abandon me.
Well, uh, I'm back now.
Uh, perhaps we should just
pick up where we left off...
Enjoy the feast.
What will happen to Dolittle?
Oh. Well, he's a dead man.
Yeah.
He'll think he can talk
his way out of it, but, uh,
Barry has gone completely nuts.
But you...
you are one of us now.
To Dolittle's death!
- Psst.
- Hey, it's you.
You made it.
I need you to get a message
to my friends on our boat.
A message? Sure.
When have I ever let you down?
All I hear day after day is:
"Oh, Barry,
you're such a disappointment.
"Why can't you be
more like your brother?
He eats poachers
for a living, you know."
"Yes, Mother, I know!
The whole jungle knows."
Oh, my head.
Your migraines are brought on
by severe maternal issues
and compounded
by sibling rivalry.
Please make it stop.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
- Lie down.
- Oh, my head.
We could resume your treatment.
Oh, the stress is unbearable.
I... I just want
to be a good boy.
I just want
to make Mummy proud.
There we are.
No one I eat
will ever be good enough.
There's the release.
Release it.
I will never be good enough.
Unless I eat you.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Because every mother
wants their son
to grow up and eat a doctor.
You're a sick kitty.
Come here, Doc.
I'll make it quick.
I've got another
one of these in an hour.
Give up, Dolittle.
You can't outsmart...
Oh, what was that?
Oh, wait.
Now it's over there, huh?
And now it's over here.
Now it's back over there.
Got it.
And now it's over here.
Oh, I lost it.
I've got to get it.
A cat is still a cat.
- I got it.
- Easily distracted.
New game, Doc.
Get back down here.
Come on down, Doc.
Okay, James,
you can't let this kid down.
You got to deliver
this message.
Oh, no. It's James.
From now on, no more focusing
on relationships and...
Whoa. Poly?
- Is that you?
- James?
- Ooh, your feathers really filled out nice.
- James, James!
- What happened, James?
- Oh, right. Message.
My bad.
The kid's been captured
by Rassouli,
and Barry's about to have
Dolittle for lunch.
Looks like we're going ashore
after all.
Be a darling and grab
my dynamite, will you?
We need to split up if
we're going to pull this off.
Chee-Chee,
you're coming with me.
Where are we going?
No, no, no, don't tell me.
Just tell me when we get there.
Yoshi, create a distraction.
Hope this is enough.
We are being attacked!
Come on down, Doc.
Therapy's the answer.
Oh, no.
Worse than I expected.
- I got you, Doc.
- Back off, Barry!
Poly, don't!
An appetizer.
I got you, Poly.
Any final diagnosis, Doc?
Don't you want to be
the best Barry you could be?
Oh, I'm about to.
I am not a prisoner of fear!
I'm not a prisoner of fear?
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
It's okay to be scared.
- Ow, ow.
- Oh, oh!
It's okay to be scared.
- You should be scared.
- It's okay to be scared!
- Give him a good hiding.
- Okay, we're doing this.
We are doing this.
We're not doing this.
Hit him in the low area.
Down there.
Ah.
Ooh, that's got to hurt.
Ow! My Barry berries.
That will work.
Cheap shot, ape.
Wait. I...
I haven't finished
my treatment.
♪ Go to sleep, baby tiger ♪
♪ Time to put
those claws away. ♪
Anyway...
You need this more than I do.
Tell me I'm enough, Mummy.
I had 50 grand riding on that.
Well, I won't pay that.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we have a winner.
Thanks for sticking
with me, Doc.
I have it.
- I have the j...
- Stop! - Halt!
And now I'll have it.
Hmm.
She had such a sure hand.
Exactly what
the doctor ordered.
What did they offer you,
Mudfly,
to murder the queen of England?
Quite a few things, actually.
Knighthood.
Windward House.
Chair of the Royal College.
In no particular order.
Oh, and the icing
on the madeleine
will be the scientific
accolades that accrue
from the proper study
of the Eden Tree.
All thanks to Lily Dolittle.
Actually, no,
that's still madeleine.
The icing is knowing
that you know I won.
Oh, and, Dolittle, I'm so sorry
for that hole in your boat.
What hole?
Abandon ship!
Everyone, overboard!
Oh, not good.
Don't look back.
Help!
I'm on it, Doc.
I can't fly.
And I can't swim.
Got you, buddy.
Plimpton,
I'm not losing you, bro.
Step away from the light.
There is no light.
I'm alive.
I'm alive,
thanks to you, Yoshi.
You've always been so kind.
It's difficult to say goodbye.
Please don't say that.
It's all right.
You've done your best.
Your queen is proud.
Where are you, Dolittle?
Hey, big bird, you doing okay?
No.
Nothing about me is okay.
My father was right about me.
I should have been an omelet.
I know how you feel.
My dad said he was going out
for a pack of seals one night
and never came back.
I guess we got something
in common after all, Plimpton.
What is this feeling?
I'm all warm and fuzzy inside.
That's friendship, bro.
Huh.
Not bad... bro.
I'm not crying. You're crying.
Right.
Gather round, shall we?
Huh? Let's have a look
where we are now.
That's the spirit, John.
Oh, this is gonna be good.
I'm already getting duck bumps.
- We are finished.
- What?
Is this a pep talk?
'Cause it's a weird one.
I can sniff defeat
like a truffle pig.
This can't be the end.
- Yeah.
- We...
- I smell it.
- We can still save the queen.
- Nope.
- We can still save your house.
I believe in you.
We can keep going.
Oh, you got a point there.
Except the journal's gone,
we have no way to find
the Eden Tree,
and our boat is sunk.
He makes a strong argument.
On the plus side,
you are all cured.
Chee-Chee, you are brave now.
Plimpton and Yoshi
are getting along.
Ow! Remember, back! Back!
Sort of.
And, Stubbins,
you've made friends,
and you can even talk to 'em.
You don't need me.
I'll stay here
and offer medical services
to this island
of random bandits and outlaws.
The doctor's here!
Seeking new patients.
- Cash only.
- Ladies, gentlemen,
who'd like to dance?
I got a bad case
of dancing fever.
So, watch out, it's infectious.
Ch-ch-ch-ch-ch-cha!
- Come on, Doc.
- Can't help him.
That explorer
you told me about...
she would have never given up.
She was your wife, wasn't she?
You want to know
the ironic bit?
I don't know
what "ironic" means.
Irony is when you find a woman
and she makes your life
more wonderful
than it had any right to be,
and then, poof, she's gone,
and it's all your fault.
This journey was my chance
to finish what she started.
Lily insisted I care
for the animals at home,
so I stayed behind.
Rassouli's right.
I should have been with her.
Now all I have left of her
is the ghost I see
when I hold our rings.
So, you see her, too?
Not only did you lose
my daughter's journal...
...but your polar bear
blew up my village.
No.
We don't know that.
And your gorilla
beat up my tiger.
No good.
- Let's go.
- No, no. Stay.
No, no, no, no, no.
Mm. Yeah.
Irony...
is me wanting to kill you
with every fiber of my being...
...but loving my daughter more.
I miss her, too.
She would have wanted you to...
to keep going.
So!
Get going...
before I stop feeling
sentimental.
She's saying
we don't have a ship.
Well, uh...
I have the perfect vessel
for you.
Bit of a fixer-upper.
It's got good bones.
At least it floats.
We'll just have to make
the best of it, won't we?
Ooh! Company.
Uh, who's that?
Hi.
I'm Jeff.
Crikey.
If Lily's research was correct,
then Mudfly was well on his way
to Eden Tree Island.
All we needed to do
was track Mudfly.
But how do we do that?
Whales, boyo.
Whales.
I can't believe
you're flipping him off.
I know.
That man has no chin.
Ah.
We found him. Follow us.
Eden Tree Island.
- Yeah!
- Oh, wow.
- Wow.
- Extraordinary.
This must be it.
The map points us directly into
the center of this mountain.
Don't look down.
Let's keep our beaks up,
shall we?
Trying to stay positive.
What the heck
are we doing up here?
Going in the back way,
my feathered buddy.
What are you complaining about?
This is the widest branch
I've ever scurried on.
Don't look down.
Look at me.
Whoa.
A big cave.
Stay close. Keep quiet.
Kevin's log, day 12.
Some force
beyond my comprehension
still compels me to follow
this crew of lunatics,
the squirrel killer
and their deranged leader.
Perhaps it's the magic tree
that draws me.
- Rifle troop! Fall in!
- Hide. They're close.
Turn it down now. Stay down.
Fox fire fungus.
We must be near it now.
Look, Doc.
It's lighting a path
all the way...
to the man who wants us dead.
Stay right there.
Oh.
Go on, then, soldier boy.
Spoil yourself.
Hello, Blair.
Get over there!
Looking for a tree, is it?
Trees don't often grow
in caves.
Didn't you pay attention
in botany class?
No, but pay attention
to this, Dolittle.
I beat you.
You filthy animal...
Move it. Come on, beasts.
...hoarder!
So...
where is it?
Where's what?
The Eden Tree.
Truth is, I haven't got a clue.
Don't be ridiculous.
You're John Dolittle.
You get everything you want.
Not today, I don't.
You really don't have
any idea, do you?
How does ignorance feel?
Oh.
Well, very freeing, actually.
One must hug uncertainty,
don't you think?
That's how Lily lived her life.
Embrace the unknown, and...
the answers will be revealed.
You sad, misguided nut,
Dolittle.
Give that to me.
Give me that.
I will find this damn tree
on my own,
and by God,
history will remember me.
Yeah. Something interesting
going on now.
My God, that feels
a lot larger than all of us.
Let's go!
- What is that?
- Something's moving!
Look out!
Retreat!
Down over here!
The lot of you! Come on!
Yoshi, stay down.
He saved me.
I have a second chance
to live a life of-of kindness
and-and-and generosity and...
Take him, not me!
I'm a good person now.
Tell you what we're gonna do...
we're gonna make a run
for that ditch
while she's distracted...
- Yoshi!
- Get this off of me!
Cheech.
Help me! Plimpton!
I'll save you, bro.
Right. Think fast. Uh...
Get this off of me!
This will likely
upset her a bit.
No! Doc!
- No! - No!
- John!
Dolittle!
Help!
Is he speaking dragon?
You may be able
to speak my language,
but that does not make you
worthy of the fruit.
I know protecting the tree's
your duty,
but you won't be able
to continue much longer...
considering
the damage you've taken
and the pain you're in.
Oh, you know
nothing of my pain.
But I do.
I've felt it as well.
The kind that doesn't come
from a bullet or a blade,
but cuts much deeper.
And now in every moment
and every movement,
you feel that pain again.
Yeah?
It's hard to carry on...
...when you've lost
the one you love.
Just leave!
Uh, what just happened?
Oh, broken hearts.
What the heck
are you doing here?
Don't worry, guys.
I got this.
We're both dragons.
Hey, just wondering,
you know, dragon to dragon,
if you wouldn't mind
telling me where...
Ow, ow, ow!
She's really mad.
I'll wait for
whoever survives outside.
John, let's just get
out of here while we still can.
No.
I think we're here to help her.
Yeah.
- We haven't got much time.
- Hmm?
I-I imagine
it's a bit tender here.
Oh...
I'm unarmed.
I pose no threat to you.
The emotional stress
over the years
has done damage
to your stomach.
Get away from me.
You have a severe
impaction of the colon,
and if I don't manually
fragment it, it'll go septic.
You won't be able to protect
anything anymore.
Ooh, that sounds like
some tummy ache.
Tell you what,
give us five minutes.
If you don't feel better,
you can fry us all.
Stop talking.
Just get on with it.
We have to get you
on your side.
We need to perform
an emergency extraction.
Extraction?
Uh, what are we pulling out?
- Go get 'em, gang.
- Got your back, Doc.
It's showtime.
Three, two, one.
Turn.
Chee-Chee,
chuck me the forceps.
Knew it would come in handy.
Told you!
Everybody knows what to do.
Just breathe. Works for me.
It's okay. Just hold on
to my wing, sweetie.
Dab-Dab's here.
Oi.
You are my apprentice.
You keep her calm.
Did you know the leek is
the national emblem of Wales?
And very useful it is, too.
You might feel
a bit of pressure.
I got her.
Oh, good heavens!
Oh, no, you didn't.
Oh, my gosh!
Just clearing the way.
Is that armor?
You got the whole
Spanish army in here.
Give us a deep breath.
Hold it.
Word of warning.
What's up, Doc?
When removing the blockage...
Yoshi, now.
...there may be an initial
release of wind.
Ach-ah-vee!
Respect.
It's all right.
Nobody heard that.
Nothing to be ashamed of.
We all do it.
We're all animals.
I can taste it!
- Okay, I'm back.
- Right.
What did I miss? Oh, my gosh!
This is the big one.
We're in the homestretch now.
Cheech, get behind me.
I'm with you, Doc.
On your call.
Heave!
Oh, it's breaching.
Blood rushing to my head.
Everything turning red.
One last push, madam,
if you please.
Thank you.
We did it.
Teamwork makes the dream work.
That was a lot,
but we did good.
To put it simply,
more leafy greens
and less armor in your diet.
I've seen armies of every kind,
but nothing like you.
What unites
such a group of creatures?
Well, we may not look it,
right, but somehow...
- Who's a good boy? Good boy.
- ...we just belong together.
Now let me help you.
Lily would have loved it, John.
We would never have found it
without her.
Wow. I just got the chills,
and I'm not even cold.
Thank you for showing me
the way, my love.
We know, O Lord, that there is
no word impossible to thee;
and that, if thou wilst,
thou canst yet raise her up
and restore her to a longer
continuance amongst us.
O Father of mercies
and Lord of all comfort...
I'm sorry we couldn't save you,
Your Majesty.
...her disillusion
draweth near.
It is with great sadness...
Wait a minute.
I smell something.
It smells like...
Hope.
...that I have to announce...
...that the queen is no more.
Somebody call a doctor?
My mates!
A very dramatic entrance, boys.
Well played.
- We've arrived.
- Dolittle!
Clear a path.
There isn't a moment to waste.
I have procured that which
is said to not exist.
Behold, the fruit
of the Eden Tree.
I said clear a path.
Seize them!
Sorry but... sorry.
I got him!
- Go.
- Seize them!
You were born for this moment.
I born.
Mini, take flight.
Get him!
Freeze!
Go, go, go!
No.
No, no, no, no!
Kevin's log, day unknown.
The killing has ended.
Let there be life.
Lady Rose.
Is there a giraffe
in my bedchamber?
Yes. Oh, yes.
And a polar bear
and a gorilla and a parrot
and a duck, an ostrich.
Our humble thanks be to God.
And well done, Dr. Dolittle.
Not quite done, are we?
Interesting.
Carry on, Styx. I'm all ears.
What's that?
Uh, Styx here agreed
to stay behind,
keep his 12 eyes on things.
He's just catching me up.
Like all leaf insects,
he speaks in
eight-syllable phrases,
and he states...
"Lord Badgley
did poison the queen."
What? He did?
Really,
Dolittle, this is too much.
You're certain?
Well, this would be the time.
No. I'm sorry.
Styx is quite adamant.
"In his right pocket,
the vial."
Ugh, that's only seven.
Oh, "in his right pocket,
the vial of
deathly nightshade."
Let's have a look, shall we?
You can't possibly believe
that he's talking to an insect.
Well, I've...
I've spoken to ladybugs.
Making a wish
before they fly away.
Let's have a look.
Ooh.
No one messes with my family.
Take one more step, and I'll
rip you a brand-new a...
Come on.
Get...
Hah.
To the Tower with him.
Oh, someone's been a bad boy.
Come on.
And I don't know why
you're all standing there.
Nobody's died.
Leave me in peace.
You, too.
Your Majesty.
Not you, Dr. Dolittle.
A moment, if you would, please.
Lady Rose, who is this person,
and why is he staring at me?
He's Stubbins.
I-I want to be
an animal doctor.
He saved your life.
Thank you.
It's good to have you back,
Doctor.
Poly.
Anything
you'd like to say to me?
Aye, you were right.
I suppose it is nice
to get out of the house
every once in a while.
Stubbins, Mini.
Enough. We have far less
important places to be.
Our story ends
the way it began.
I have a letter
for Dr. Dolittle!
Somebody get me down!
Mostly.
There once was
a peculiar doctor...
...who found he was
at his best when sharing
his extraordinary ability...
- ...with others.
- Excellent.
Soon, Dr. Dolittle
reopened his gates,
as Lily would have wanted.
Three more in the queue, gang.
Copy that.
Dolittle discovered his
place in the world once again.
After all,
it's only by helping others
that we can truly
help ourselves.
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
Oh, and in case
you're wondering...
Psst.
You bats.
Show me the way out of here.
Psst.
Bing.
You understand me.
No, wait.
Wait, wait, wait.