[soft dreamy music playing]
Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull
[car door opens]
- [birds chirping]
- [exhales]
[Monica speaking Korean]
[Jacob speaking Korean]
[Anne in English]
David, look!
[Jacob speaking Korean]
[Anne in English]
Look at that! Look!
- Wheels!
- Wheels?
There are wheels.
It's like a big car.
- [Jacob speaking Korean]
- Yes?
- [in English] Okay.
[Jacob grunting]
- [Jacob grunting]
- [Anne giggles]
[David] Whoa!
[Jacob speaking Korean]
[in English] Come on.
[Monica speaking Korean]
[Jacob speaking Korean]
- [Monica grunts]
- [in English] Okay. Whoa.
[grunts] Okay.
- [David] Is that a house?
- [Anne] I don't see any houses.
[David] Over there.
[kids speaking indistinctly]
[Monica speaking Korean]
- [Jacob speaking Korean]
- [David speaking Korean]
[soft dreamy music playing]
[birds chirping]
[bee buzzing]
[chuckles]
[twig snaps]
[David speaking Korean]
[Monica speaking Korean]
[Jacob speaking Korean]
[Monica scoffs]
[kids chattering]
David!
[in English] Garden is small.
No!
Garden of Eden is big!
Like this!
[Monica speaking Korean]
[Anne in English] You okay?
[air hissing]
[speaking Korean]
[in English] Is the heart
murmur getting louder?
[speaking Korean]
[scoffs, clicks tongue]
- [exclaiming playfully]
- [giggles]
[heart thumping]
[heart continues thumping]
[man in English] Back her up.
Nice and slow.
There you go now,
nice and slow.
And...
[chicks chirping]
All right, listen up,
everyone!
Now this here is Mr. Jacob,
and this is Monica Yi.
Mr. Yi is an expert
chicken sexer.
He's worked in California
and Seattle, so, uh,
let's give him a big
Arkansas welcome!
This way.
Okay, here we put
the males in the blue bin
and the females
in the white bin.
Okay, go to work.
[speaking Korean]
David.
[in English] Okay.
You read the E volume
and I'll read the C volume.
[David groans]
[chuckles]
[speaking Korean]
Oh.
[in English]
Mom, what can I do?
[speaking Korean]
[sighs]
[Jacob grunts]
[David speaking]
[Jacob speaking]
[Jacob chuckles]
Hmm...
[in English] It's good.
[Jacob laughing]
[speaking Korean]
[exhales sharply]
[Jacob sighs]
[Jacob speaking]
[thunder rumbling]
- [TV playing indistinctly]
- [chicks chirping]
[in English]
Let's give them Mountain Dew.
No! Only water. Okay?
- [door opens, closes]
- [Jacob sighs]
Okay...
[speaking Korean]
[panting]
- [TV continues playing]
- [Jacob exhales]
[Jacob breathing heavily]
[thunder cracks]
[Anne speaking]
[TV resumes playing]
[Jacob speaking]
[Jacob sighs]
[exhales deeply]
[Jacob and Monica arguing
indistinctly]
[in English] Write it big.
[David] Okay.
[argument continues]
[thunder rumbling]
[speaking Korean]
[Jacob speaking]
[thunder rumbling]
[clicks tongue]
[birds chirping]
[yawns]
[in English] Oh, no.
[show host on TV] Well,
the mobile home was set up
approximately three weeks ago,
and the owner had
yet to tie it down.
When the wind came,
it just started rolling.
[TV continues playing
indistinctly]
[in English]
My favorite. My favorite.
[speaking Korean]
[Anne] Mmm.
[TV switches off]
[speaking Korean]
[chuckles softly]
[Monica] Hmm...
[Anne speaking]
- [Anne speaks]
- [Jacob clears throat]
[door closes]
[Anne speaking]
[Dan, in English]
Just set it down anywhere.
- Is it down?
- [David] Yes.
I'm... I'm thinkin'
about water.
I think about water,
let the stick do the rest.
I find it every time.
So that's $250
for one good,
clean water well
and, uh, $300 for two.
[Dan exhales]
[Jacob] $300?
I tell you what then.
Fella before you thought
he could save money, too.
You know what happened
to him, huh?
[Jacob] No, we don't need.
Let's go back.
[Jacob speaking Korean]
[in English] Okay?
We use our minds.
[speaking Korean]
[in English]
where will the water go?
High place or low place?
Low place.
[speaking Korean]
- [in English] There?
- [chuckles]
[speaking Korean]
[in English] There?
Okay.
[speaking Korean]
[in English] There.
[in English] Why?
'Cause trees like water.
[speaking Korean]
[laughing]
[lively music playing]
[Jacob grunting]
David?
[in English] For the house,
we have to pay for water.
Huh?
[speaks Korean]
[grunts]
- [trash pops]
- [Monica yelps]
[Jacob panting]
David.
[Jacob chuckles]
[sighs]
[whoops]
[both whooping]
[whoops louder]
[David screeching]
- [Monica speaking]
- [Anne speaking]
[Randy, in English] Now you're
a common sense man, Mr. Yi,
taking land
folks are too scared to buy.
- I admire a thinking man.
- [Jacob] Thank you.
Now, let me tell you,
with farming these days,
you gotta go big or go home,
that's just how it is.
[CHUCKLING]
It's a good time for it.
Reagan's out to make sure
that the farmers are happy.
And I'll be right here
to help you.
Thank you very much.
You brought your helper.
[Jacob chuckles]
Would you like a sucker?
I bet you would like
the blue one.
What do you say?
Thank you.
[Randy] You're welcome.
[Paul] If there's something
wrong, you can call the owner.
I'm just the one hauling it.
Hey, there.
My name's Paul.
[Jacob speaking Korean]
[in English] Say hello.
Okay. Two thousand.
Thank you.
You know, Mr. Yi,
if you want,
I drive these things all day.
I drive them in my sleep.
I'm a good worker.
Thank you,
but these are Korean
vegetables, Korean fruits.
Korean?
[sighs, chuckles]
I wanna show you something.
[sighs]
You better take
a look at this.
Look at this.
[Jacob chuckles]
This is old money.
It's Korean War money.
Yes, sir. I was there.
It was a hard time.
I'm sure you know.
Here, you wanna take it?
- [Jacob] David. What do you say?
- [Paul chuckles]
You know, it's funny.
The minute I saw you,
I knew
we were gonna be friends.
Can I pray?
- Sorry?
- Just wait a minute.
[sniffs] Thank you.
Thank you, God.
Thank you for the Yi family.
[chuckles]
Thank you
for this divine appointment.
[speaks in tongues]
Hallelujah. Hallelujah.
[speaking in tongues]
Amen! Yes, yes,
yes, yes, yes!
[exhales sharply]
Big things!
You got big things
for this family. [chuckles]
Okay.
[door opens]
[speaking Korean]
[indistinct conversation]
[Jacob speaking]
[laughing]
[Jacob sighs]
[in English]
Yeah, of course.
[chuckles]
[laughing] What?
[speaking Korean]
[Jacob clears throat]
[soft instrumental music
playing]
[Jacob chuckles]
[Jacob exhales deeply]
[choral music
playing on tape]
[Monica speaking English]
[speaking Korean]
[blowing]
David...
[camera lens whirring]
[Monica gasps]
- [camera clicks]
- [car horn honks]
[car door closes]
[gasps] Wow!
[Jacob speaking]
[Soonja gasps]
[Anne speaking]
Oh!
- [Soonja speaking]
- [Monica] David!
[Jacob speaking]
[exhales sharply]
[voice breaking]
[Soonja chuckles]
[gasps]
Mmm.
[Monica sobbing]
[Monica chuckles]
[sniffling]
[Soonja speaking]
David?
[in English] David, come.
[Soonja speaking Korean]
[whispering indistinctly]
[whispers]
- [whispering indistinctly]
- [gasps]
[Monica exclaims]
[Monica speaking]
[exclaims disapprovingly]
[Monica gasps]
[Monica speaking]
[in English]
Thank you, Grandma. Hmm?
[Soonja speaking Korean]
[Monica speaking]
[soft instrumental music
playing]
[grunting]
[in English] You know,
you might wanna think about
doing something out here.
- You know...
- [Jacob] Huh?
You know
what an exorcism is?
[Jacob chuckles] Yeah.
[speaks Korean]
[grunts]
[Paul, in English]
You know...
What happened out here,
it's no good.
Something like that.
Yeah... Real good.
[breathily] Out!
Out!
[loudly] Out in the name
of Jesus! Out!
Out!
♪ In the name of Jesus
Out! ♪
[Jacob chuckles]
[Jacob] Okay.
Now things...
Things will grow.
[Jacob chuckles]
How come you're putting them
so close together?
You don't wanna put them
so close together like that.
You gotta put them like,
further apart, like that.
No. Is that right?
Yeah, this is right.
Otherwise, you just gonna
grow tiny little lettuces.
You wanna grow like,
grow them up!
No, is here to here.
Shoot, man. We'll grow them
the Arkansas way.
You know? You'll be happy.
[laughing]
I'm telling you.
[both laughing]
You'll be happy.
♪ You'll be happy
I'll be happy... ♪
Paul.
[exclaiming, burbles]
No, no, no. Get that away
from me in the name of Jesus.
In the name of Jesus, get that away.
Choo, choo, choo.
You crazy, man.
You... You crazy.
[Paul] Just don't pass
those cigarettes to me.
Okay. Just do it. Okay.
Come on,
let's get this soil wet.
- Okay, ready?
- [Jacob] Yeah.
Wow. Okay.
[motor whirring]
That's free water.
- [Monica speaking Korean]
- [Soonja speaking Korean]
[Soonja speaks indistinctly]
[Monica speaking]
[Soonja speaking]
[gasps]
[in English] Stop, David.
[speaking Korean]
[Anne in English] Go back!
David, go back to your room!
- Stop!
- David.
David, go to your room.
David, come.
There's a Korea smell!
[Anne] You've never even
been to Korea!
[David] Grandma smells
like Korea.
- David.
- [Jacob exclaims]
[speaking Korean]
[Soonja snoring]
[Soonja speaking Korean]
[Anne speaking]
[Soonja] Hmm.
[Soonja exclaims]
[David, in English]
I want some.
No, this is mine.
Yours is right there.
[David sighs]
[speaking Korean]
[Anne sighs]
- [David speaking Korean]
- [Soonja speaking Korean]
[Soonja] Hmm...
[Soonja exclaims, laughs]
David!
[chicks chirping]
[Mrs. Oh speaking]
Ah...
[Anne in English]
You know, she can't even read.
She isn't like
a real grandma.
You like Grandma.
[laughs]
Thank you.
[chuckles]
[speaking Korean]
- David.
- [Soonja speaking]
[Anne speaking]
- [in English] I'm going down.
- David!
[exclaims]
[Soonja speaking Korean]
[Anne in English]
David, come up here now!
I'm telling Mom.
[David speaking Korean]
[sighs]
[speaking Korean on TV]
[Soonja] Mmm.
[in English]
Good boy. Mmm.
Good boy.
[Korean song playing on TV]
Mmm.
[speaking Korean]
[David speaking Korean]
[Soonja] Hmm.
[song continues]
[Soonja speaking]
[singing in Korean on TV]
[song ends]
[Monica speaking]
[in English]
Only for kids.
Do you want to try?
- [Soonja speaking Korean]
- [Monica gasps]
[laughs]
[David yawns]
[chicks chirping]
[Jacob speaking]
[Monica sighs]
[Jacob sighs]
[grunts]
[Monica] David...
[in English] "Is this a dream?
Is this a dream?"
[speaking Korean]
[in English] Hmm? Okay?
Penis-uh broken.
[Monica speaking Korean]
[in English]
It's not called a penis!
It's called a ding-dong!
[Soonja] Huh?
- Ding-dong. Ding-dong.
- [Monica chuckles]
[piano playing hymn]
[music stops]
[Brother Roy, in English]
What a wonderful day
to be in the house
of the Lord.
If you're here with us
for the first time,
please stand.
Now, don't be ashamed.
Y'all stand up.
[Monica whispers in Korean]
[Brother Roy, in English]
What a beautiful family.
I'm glad you're here.
Okay, you can be seated.
Thank you.
- [soft contemporary gospel music playing]
- [indistinct chatter]
[Monica] Hi, I'm Monica.
How long y'all been in town?
Uh... [chuckles]
Where you been hiding?
I'm sorry,
my English not so good.
Oh, it's okay,
we'll teach you English.
- [Bonnie] You're just too cute!
- [laughter]
- [Monica laughs] Thank you!
- Okay.
- Okay, thank you.
- So cute.
[speaking Korean]
[in English] Hey.
Can you stop me if I say
something in your language?
Um...
Sure.
Chinga-chinga-chon
chama-chama-choo?
Why is your face
so flat?
It isn't.
My name is Johnnie.
What's yours?
David.
Nice to meet you, David.
Hey, David.
Blow pomo como lomo?
Oh. Como...
That means aunt in Korean.
That is so neat!
[indistinct chatter
and laughter]
[David speaking Korean]
[in English]
But I don't like Grandma!
[shushes]
[speaking Korean]
[in English]
No? Why can't you?
Why?
[in English] Broken ding-dong.
Ding-dong broken.
[Monica speaking Korean]
[Jacob speaking]
[chuckles]
[in English]
Paul, what are you doing?
It's, uh... It's Sunday.
This is my church.
[Jacob] Okay.
Do you need a ride?
No, I gotta finish this.
I'll see you Monday.
[chuckles]
See you, Paul.
[Jacob speaking Korean]
[Jacob laughing]
[Soonja speaking]
[wrestling commentary on TV]
[laughs]
[exclaims]
[in English] Pretty boy!
Pretty boy! Pretty...
I'm not pretty!
I'm good-looking!
[chuckles]
[wrestling commentator
exclaiming]
[speaking Korean]
[in English] It is a dream.
This isn't real.
[urinating]
[indistinct TV chatter]
[exclaiming]
[gasps]
[in English] Good boy!
Good boy! Good boy! Good boy!
Good boy! Good boy.
[exclaiming]
[gags, spits]
[Soonja YELLS]
[yelling in Korean]
[instrumental music playing]
[panting]
[panting heavily]
[heart thumping]
[thumping continues]
David!
[in English] Okay?
[Jacob speaking Korean]
[Soonja speaking Korean]
[Monica speaking]
- [thuds]
- [Soonja exclaims]
[Jacob speaking]
[door opens, closes]
[crickets chirping]
[clicks tongue]
[Jacob speaking]
[Soonja laughs]
[Paul shouting in tongues]
[soft dreamy music playing]
[trash popping]
[metal clanging]
- Paul.
- [Paul, in English] Yeah.
Why is this so dry?
It is dry.
Is that dry over there?
Yeah, it's pretty much
dry all over.
This one, too.
There's no water. Bone dry.
We better check that well.
[grunts]
If it's water table well,
you won't get much further.
[grunts]
You know, if you wanted,
you could try with this.
You could try
with these guys.
You ever see
one of these guys?
[mumbling]
Oh, not there. Not there.
[Jacob grunts]
[Paul] We need to
find water somewhere.
[panting]
If that soil ain't wet,
you're gonna lose the crop.
[exhales]
[continues panting]
[Jacob inhales sharply]
[speaking Korean]
[groans]
[continues groaning]
[Jacob moans]
Ow!
[Monica chuckles]
[Jacob sighs]
[grunts]
[water rushing in pipe]
[Paul, in English] There's
some good stuff out here,
Mr. Jacob Yi.
There's some good stuff
out here, Mr. Jacob Yi.
Oh, it's so beautiful.
It's so beautiful,
Mr. Jacob Yi.
I think we better
send it to Dallas.
- Paul.
- Yeah?
Good job.
Very good job.
[Paul, softly] Good job.
Good job.
[both laughing]
Okay, that's...
That's enough.
[Jacob speaking Korean]
Uh...
- [in English] Paul! Come on!
- What?
- [Jacob] Take it back!
- What for?
[Jacob] Put it back.
[Paul] What happened?
Take it back?
[Jacob sighs]
[Paul] Whoa...
Where are they getting
their produce at?
California.
They just change it
like that on you?
You know,
we still got some time, Jacob.
we'll find someplace else.
It ain't rotting
on the vines.
Korean people, big city,
you never trust them!
Well, forget...
Just forget about Dallas.
Forget about Dallas.
There's always Oklahoma City.
Or Memphis...
I'm still paying for water!
[Paul] We'll try and get the...
[Jacob groans in frustration]
[Paul] It's okay.
It's gonna be all right.
I have to go to work, okay?
To go to work.
[Paul] It's gonna be
all right!
[chicks chirping]
[speaking Korean]
Oh. [chuckles]
[wrestling show
playing on TV]
David. David!
[in English] David, go change.
It's time to go.
- [David] Where?
- Church picnic.
[Anne speaking Korean]
[David grunts]
- [basket clatters]
- [Jacob groans softly]
[chicks chirping]
[Mrs. Oh speaking]
[breathing heavily]
[Soonja speaking]
[continues breathing heavily]
[car horn honks]
[Anne in English] This just
gets better and better.
[speaking Korean]
[blows]
[in English] Okay. Okay.
[speaking Korean]
[gasps]
[in English] Strong!
Strong boy! Mmm!
Strong boy. Mmm!
[speaking Korean]
[David giggling]
[Soonja chuckles]
[Soonja speaking]
[laughing]
[David]
♪ Minari, minari, minari ♪
♪ Wonderful, wonderful minari ♪
[Soonja speaking Korean]
[in English] Wonderful,
wonderful minari.
[speaking Korean]
[exclaims]
[Soonja chuckles]
- [Monica speaking]
- [Soonja speaking]
[door closes]
[Monica speaking]
[in English]
I wanna come, too.
[Jacob sighs]
[Jacob speaking Korean]
[exclaims]
[Monica speaking]
[soft instrumental music
playing]
[sighs]
[Soonja speaking]
[in English] Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
[speaking Korean]
♪ Minari, minari ♪
[in English]
♪ Wonderful, wonderful ♪
♪ Minari ♪
♪ Wonderful ♪
♪ Minari... ♪
[shushing]
♪ Minari, minari ♪
♪ Wonderful, wonderful ♪
♪ Minari ♪
[birds chirping]
[insect buzzing]
- [knocks on door]
- [Anne in English] What?
[speaking Korean]
[Soonja] Hmm.
[David speaking]
[insect buzzing]
[Soonja grunting]
[continues grunting]
[whispers in English]
Why is she like that?
We'll call Mom from church.
Get dressed.
[piano playing hymn]
[Brother Roy]
When Jesus comes again,
what a glorious day
that's gonna be.
But what are you gonna say
when He asks...
[whispers] I'm going to go
call Mom, okay?
Okay.
[Brother Roy]
...Sue from the bank...
[Anne whispers]
Excuse me.
[Brother Roy] ...why is Earl
from the grocery store
not with us?
Why didn't you preach
the good news of salvation
to those precious people?
[Anne] David...
[speaking Korean]
[in English]
When will they come home?
[in English] I don't know.
- [Anne sighs]
- [boy] There's that cross guy.
[kids laughing]
[Johnnie] You think he saw?
I heard he got dirt floors
and he shits in a bucket.
He got no water
where he lives.
[kids laughing]
[Monica speaking Korean]
[Anne speaking]
[Monica] Oh.
[in English] How's Grandma?
Mom said we could stay
with friends.
Really?
[country music
playing on radio]
[Johnnie] My mom's friend
keeps this here.
He don't mind.
- [music continues]
- [David chuckles]
[rattling]
Wanna try some?
Does it hurt?
[Johnnie] Put it like this.
It only hurts if you eat it.
So don't eat it, stupid!
[in southern accent]
I'm a cowboy!
[David chuckles]
[David] You won't get points
that way.
Get a junk card.
You'll get more money.
- This one?
- Yeah!
[speaking Korean]
[in English]
This is a great game.
[in English] Yeah.
[spits]
[David laughing]
[Billy] All right, boys,
breakfast
is right here.
There you go.
Come here, boo. Give me a hug.
Come on over here.
Come here. [grunts]
Get over here. Let me look
at you. You sleep good?
That's your buddy, huh?
Hey, it's good to meet you.
Go on, eat your breakfast.
[Billy clears throat]
- [water fizzing]
- [grunts]
How's your daddy
like that new farm?
Hmm?
Good.
He growing things good,
doing things right?
Yes.
That's good.
I knew the fella
who was there before.
- Who?
- Bucky Reed.
He went flat broke.
Boom. [chuckles]
I guess
it's what a man does.
You tell your mom
I was here all night.
[Johnnie] Okay.
And you help your dad
on that farm. All right?
You hear me?
All right, Johnnie,
I'll see you
in a little while, all right?
I'm going to work.
[soft instrumental music
playing]
[music continues]
[Anne speaking Korean]
[Soonja gasps]
[Monica speaking]
[in English] Mom wants to
go back to California
because of Grandma.
When?
First, they're going to check your
heart, and then decide.
Would you rather live
with Mom or Dad?
I don't know.
Me neither.
[Monica] David. David.
Paul.
Oh. Thank you so much.
[Monica speaking Korean]
- [Paul] Hmm.
- [in English] Oh, sorry.
But don't put that kimchi too far away.
I like it. [chuckles]
[Monica] Oh!
- It made me sweat on my head.
- [both laugh]
- You know?
- You okay?
I'm good.
[Monica]
You're our first guest here.
[Paul] I'm honored.
Hmm.
[exhales]
[breathing sharply]
I'm gonna
put some oil in here.
[speaking in tongues]
Paul, she sees something here.
- Right here?
- Yeah, yeah.
Look out.
Look out, it's gonna...
[shooing]
Cast you out!
Hear our prayer,
oh, Heavenly Father.
Hear this prayer. Come down,
Jesus, to me, oh, Lord.
Only you can heal.
Only you can heal her.
[continues praying
indistinctly]
It feels different,
doesn't it?
[Monica] Mmm, yeah.
- [Paul] It feels like, lighter.
- [Monica chuckles] Yes, yes.
- [Paul] I feel light.
- [Monica] Ah!
Thank you. Thank you, Paul.
Thank you so much.
- [Paul] Thank you.
- [Monica] Uh, wait here.
- I have something here. Yeah.
- [Paul] Okay.
Hey.
Do you...
Do you want me to...
To pray for you and...
If you want.
Why?
No need.
I meant...
Come early tomorrow, okay?
Lot of work.
[speaking Korean]
[Jacob scoffs]
[footsteps stomping]
[door opens, closes]
[utensils clanging]
[whispering]
[in English]
108 degrees today,
which beats the record
all to smithereens.
It was 101 set way on back
in the 50s.
Let's take a look right now
at the full heat wave.
There it is,
17 days' worth. And...
[speaking Korean]
- [clattering]
- [Monica exclaims]
[Soonja] Mmm-hmm.
[Soonja speaking]
[Soonja] Hmm.
[Paul mumbling]
[Paul, in English]
You're good. This one's good.
- This one's good.
- [Jacob] Okay.
[Paul] They're all good.
Wait, wait, wait.
[laughing]
Okay, just one more thing.
[clears throat]
It's good. What do you think
they're gonna say
when they see that?
Jacob.
This good.
Okay, this good.
It's good. Yes.
[exhales deeply]
Hey.
They won't say no.
- [chuckles]
- Okay. Okay.
I love these.
It's a very exciting move.
It's a very important move.
Jacob...
- O... Okay.
- Yes!
[soft music playing]
[grunts softly]
[speaking Korean]
[sighs]
[in English] Thank you.
[door closes]
[sighs]
[lab tech] All right.
All right, buddy.
You can sit up,
get dressed,
and go wait in the waiting room.
How's that sound?
- Good. Thank you.
- Thank you.
[exclaims softly]
[speaking Korean]
[Anne speaks Korean]
[Jacob sighs]
[door opens]
[Doctor, in English]
Mr. and Mrs. Yi?
Ready to see you now.
[Jacob clears throat]
[Jacob speaking Korean]
[Doctor, in English]
Okay, see,
this is where blood flows out,
like a door.
Open, close, open, close.
You see how close
the hole is here?
Now this is why the California
doctor wanted to wait
till he's a bit older
before surgery.
But, and are you ready?
It looks like the hole
is getting smaller.
- What?
- It's still there,
but in comparing measurements,
it's a significant
improvement.
All right, this means
we can rule out surgery,
and we can see if the hole
closes up on its own.
This is very good news.
But sound has
gotten louder.
[Doctor] Yes. Sometimes,
as the hole gets smaller,
the sound gets louder.
Loud is good.
Are we happy?
Yes, I'm happy.
Thank you.
[Anne speaking Korean]
[Doctor, in English]
Must be the Ozark water.
Whatever it is you're doing,
don't change a thing.
[chuckles]
[speaking Korean]
[Anne speaking]
[David, in English]
Hey, what are these?
[Anne] I'm guessing
some kind of...
[speaking Korean]
[David, in English]
Or maybe it's seeds.
[Anne] It kind of
looks like peanuts.
- [speaking Korean]
- [Anne speaking]
[in English] Kinda looks like
peanuts chopped in half.
[David] Yeah.
[shop owner speaking Korean]
[in English] Okay.
[speaking Korean]
- [shop owner] Oh.
- [speaking Korean]
[all speaking at once]
[Jacob speaking]
[Jacob sighs]
[sighs]
- [car door closes]
- [sighs]
[sighs]
[exhales]
[door opening]
[sniffles]
[footsteps receding]
[crickets chirping]
[gasps]
[car accelerates]
- [Jacob speaking]
- [Anne shouts in Korean]
[coughing]
[Soonja gasping]
[David speaking]
[object crashing]
[Anne and David speaking]
[coughing]
- [coughing]
- [Jacob speaking]
- [sobbing]
- [kids continue shouting]
[coughs]
[Anne and David speaking]
[both coughing]
[Anne speaking]
[David coughs]
[coughing]
[Jacob speaking]
[shouting]
[continues coughing]
[continues shouting]
[Monica speaking]
- [Monica coughing]
- [Jacob grunting]
[both coughing]
[soft instrumental music
playing]
[both continue coughing]
[Monica sobbing]
[Anne, in Korean] Grandma!
[Anne speaking]
[David speaking]
[music continues]
[panting]
[in Korean] Grandma!
[David speaking]
[music stops]
[crickets chirping]
[birds chirping]
[soft instrumental music
playing]
[music continues]
[in English]
Yeah. Mark it.
That be where it is.
[Jacob speaking indistinctly]
[speaking Korean]
David.
[grunts]
[in English] Here, David.
[soft instrumental music
playing]
Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull
[crickets chirping]