Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull
Okay, here's
what I owe ya.
Okay. Thank you.
You take care
of yourself.
♪♪ What Child is this
♪♪ Who laid to rest
♪♪ On Mary's lap is sleeping?
♪♪ Whom Angels greet
with anthems sweet...
♪♪ While shepherds watch
are keeping? ♪♪
I don't see
your reservation.
I'm on the Amazon
CamperForce list.
Oh.
Try M‐C‐D.
- There it is.
- Yeah.
Hmm...
Good morning, everybody.
How's everybody doing today?
All right,
let me get a safety tip.
- Three‐point contact.
- Why is it important
to maintain
three points of contact?
So you don't fall
down the stairs.
So you don't
fall down the stairs.
Can I get a standard
work tip from you?
He's an oddball, right?
Ed? He's an oddball.
That's not even
long enough.
Now, okay...
Some plastic...
- This is Carl.
- Hi.
- This is Angela.
- Hey.
- Doug.
- Hi, Fern.
- Ryan. Teresa.
- Hey, Fern.
- Karie.
- Good to meet you.
And your
good ol' friend...
...Linda May.
And I'm Fern.
- This is my friend Fern.
- Hey.
- Hi, everybody.
- Hey, how're you, Fern?
Another Smith lyric
I have is,
"When you're laughing and
dancing, and finally living,
"you hear my voice in your
head and think of me kindly."
And then also the one that
means the most to me is,
"Home, is it just a word?
"Or is it something that
you carry within you?"
- All right.
- So...
- Yeah, we like that.
- I like that one.
- Yeah.
- Me, too.
Like,
his lyrics are very deep.
- And then you also have...
- Yeah.
Ah!
- Yes?
- No.
So, the guy
that had the van before,
he just had a mattress
in the back,
but I didn't wanna
keep it that way.
I wanted to
build the bed up
so I could have
storage underneath.
And I got these
storage drawers,
one set in the front
so I could get in them
from the inside,
and then another
on the outside.
- Very smart.
- I thought so.
You see that?
What is this?
This is my husband's
old fishing box.
I put this little latch on
it, and then when I open it,
the stopper holds it
and creates
- more counterspace.
- Ah...
And then I keep my
really nice stuff inside.
My dishes that my dad gave me.
He collected these,
Linda May, from yard sales,
and when I graduated
from high school,
- he gave me the whole set.
- Oh!
- They are beautiful.
- Isn't that great?
Yeah, it's called
Autumn Leaf.
I don't have that many pieces
with me, but you know.
What did you name your van?
Vanguard.
Oh, that is
very strong.
She is. Mmm.
Hey. Hey.
Hey, what are you doing?
...the bears held
at the Polar Bear
Holding Facility
are troublemakers
who are kept imprisoned
until they settle down,
which can take anywhere
from two to thirty days.
Hey, girls.
It's Mrs. M.
Fern.
Hey, Brandy.
- Oh, hi, Fern.
- Hi, kids.
- Hi.
- Say hi to Mrs. M.
How are you?
- I'm good.
- Good.
It's nice to see you.
It's been a while.
- How've you been?
- Good.
- Good. You look good.
- Thanks.
- You cut your hair.
- Yeah, I cut it.
- I like it. I like it a lot.
- Thank you.
Are you working
at Amazon again?
- Yeah, I am.
- You like it?
Uh, yeah. Great money.
Are you still doing
the van thing?
Yeah. I'm parked over at
the Desert Rose R. V. Park.
Oh, we just drove
by there today.
Didn't we, girls?
- How's your mom?
- She's wonderful.
She misses you
a lot.
Please tell her
I miss her, too.
I will. I will.
But really, Fern,
if you need
a place to stay,
you can come over
and stay with us.
We're worried
about you.
Thanks.
Don't worry about me.
I'll let you know.
I promise.
Okay. Okay.
- See you, Aubrey.
- Bye.
Hey.
- Hey.
- Hi.
You still the smartest
kid in school?
- Yeah, kinda.
- Mmm‐hmm.
You remember anything that we
worked on when I tutored ya?
Uh...
Yes.
Um... "Tomorrow, and
tomorrow, and tomorrow.
"And all of our yesterdays
have lighted fools.
"The way to dusty death.
Out, out, brief candle."
That's really good.
- Thank you.
Um...
My mom says that you're homeless.
Is that true?
No, I'm not homeless.
I'm just houseless.
Not the same thing, right?
No.
Don't worry about me.
I'm okay.
Okay.
Hey, Santa,
Bellweather Auto has a ho,
ho, whole lotta great deals
on new and used cars
and trucks.
So come on in and find...
Before I moved
into the Squeeze Inn,
I was out looking for work
and putting in applications...
2008, and it was just tough.
And I got to a really,
really low point.
And I thought about suicide,
and I decided
I was gonna go buy
a bottle of booze,
turn on the propane stove...
and I was gonna drink that
booze until I passed out.
And if I woke up...
I was gonna light a cigarette,
and I was gonna
blow us all up.
And I looked at my two sweet
little trusting dogs,
my Cocker Spaniel
and my little Toy Poodle,
and I just couldn't
do that to them.
And I thought, well,
I can't do that to me, either.
So, I was
getting close to 62
and I went online to look
at my social security benefit.
It said $550.
Fern, I had worked
my whole life.
I'd worked since
I was 12 years old,
raised two daughters.
I couldn't believe it.
So I'm online,
and I find Bob Wells
Cheap RV Living.
I could live in an RV,
travel
and not have to work
for the rest of my life.
The RTR is a bootcamp
for beginner nomads.
Bob Wells looks
just like Santa Claus.
Doesn't he?
Everybody says that.
What's RTR
stand for?
Rubber Tramp Rendezvous.
It is in
Quartzsite, Arizona,
out in the middle
of the desert, on BLM land.
You should come.
I'm gonna make you
a map.
No, I don't think
I'm gonna go.
Oh, I hope you come.
I'm gonna make you
a map anyway.
So,
that's what the RTR is.
It is a support system
for people
who need help now.
See you next year, Fern.
Happy holidays.
Yeah, you, too, Doug.
Carl had
a stroke.
- Is he dead?
- No.
No, no. His daughter came
and took him back East.
- Oh.
- Yeah.
But they didn't
take the dog?
They couldn't take him.
Would you like
to have him?
- Uh...
- He's really a good dog.
- No. No.
- He's real friendly.
Okay, so you are leaving
on Thursday, right?
- Yeah.
- Okay. Um...
I just finished
Amazon yesterday.
Okay. Amazon pays
through Thursday.
And then after that,
it's $375 a month.
Well, is there a discount
if I don't use
the electric and dump,
'cause I just have
my van, you know?
No, but since you're in a
van, it's easy for you to move
and to go south
to a warmer place.
Yeah, but I wanted to get
a job around here first.
Oh. Good luck with that.
- Mmm. Mmm‐hmm.
- That's tough.
- Bye, Patty.
- Bye, Fern.
We'll see you next year.
Thank you. Have a nice day.
My husband worked
at the USG mine in Empire
and I worked
in human resources there
for a few years.
That was
my last full‐time job.
I did a lot of
part‐time jobs.
I cashiered
at the Empire Store.
I was a substitute teacher at
the school for five years...
Didn't the Empire Mine
shut down
and then all of the resident
workers had to relocate?
- Yeah, about a year ago.
- Wow.
So, when do you need
to get back to work?
Now?
It is a tough time
right now.
You may want
to consider
registering for
early retirement.
I don't think I can get by
on the benefits, and, um...
I need work. I like work.
I'm not sure exactly what
you would be eligible for.
- Hi, there.
- Hi!
I'm Rachel.
I'm the manager here at Fox Peak.
Hi, I'm Fern.
Hi, Fern.
Um, I asked someone, they said
I could park here overnight.
Oh, you're fine.
You're more than welcome.
But you know,
the temperature is gonna drop.
It gets really cold
here at night.
- Yeah, I know. I can tell.
- Really cold.
Yeah.
I don't want to overstep
my bounds here.
There is a church
down by 7‐Eleven.
It's a Baptist church,
and they do have open beds.
I'm gonna be good.
Okay. Okay. We're here
if you need anything.
Thank you.
Mmm.
Linda? Linda?
Hey.
Shh.
So glad you came.
- That's Bob Wells.
- Sit here. Keep the chair.
Thank you.
And the odd thing
is that we...
We not only accept
the tyranny of the dollar,
the tyranny
of the marketplace,
we embrace it.
We gladly throw the yoke
of the tyranny
of the dollar on
and live by it
our whole lives.
I think of an analogy
as a workhorse.
The workhorse that is willing
to work itself to death
and then be
put out to pasture.
And that's what happens
to so many of us.
If society
was throwing us away
and sending us, the workhorse,
out to the pasture,
we workhorses
had to gather together
and take care
of each other.
And that's what
this is all about.
The way I see it is that
the Titanic is sinking
and economic times
are changing.
And so my goal is
to get the lifeboats out
and get as many people
into the lifeboats as I can.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
There's plenty.
Yeah. We got plenty.
Jump and shout.
How many vegans
we got here?
Let you know, huh?
- What's that?
- Vegan.
This is vegan.
- No, I'm... I'm a carnivore.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- Thank you. Yes.
Okay. Thank you,
though.
- Looks good.
- Another carnivore?
- She's a carnivore.
- Okay.
Mac 'n' cheese.
Just tell me when?
You good? More?
Oh! She likes
the red peppers.
- Cilantro?
- No!
No!
No! No, no.
I'm a Vietnam vet.
And, um, I got PTSD.
I really can't handle
loud noises,
uh, big crowds, fireworks.
I got a pickup truck
and a camper.
I can live out here...
and be at peace.
I had, um,
finally convinced my grandpa,
and my papa, and my mama,
that we should
take off in an RV
and see the country.
But then both of them were
told that they had cancer,
they passed away
three weeks apart.
I began watching
Bob Wells' videos
on van‐dwelling.
Then I bought my van...
Paint, because she takes me
where I ain't.
And
started my healing journey
two and a half years ago.
Um, I worked
for corporate America,
you know, for 20 years.
And my friend, Bill,
worked for the same company,
and he had liver failure.
A week before
he was due to retire,
HR called him in hospice,
and said...
"Let's talk about
your retirement."
And he died 10 days later,
having never been able
to take that sailboat
that he bought
out of his driveway.
And he missed out
on everything.
And he told me
before he died,
"Just don't waste
any time, Merle.
"Don't waste any time."
So I retired
as soon as I could.
I didn't want
my sailboat
to be in the driveway
when I died...
so, yeah...
And it's not.
My sailboat's out here
in the desert.
I can't imagine
what you're going through,
the loss of your husband,
and the loss of your whole
town, and friends,
and village,
and that kind of loss
is never easy.
And I wish I had
an easy answer for you.
But I think you've come
to the right place
to find an answer.
I think that...
I think connecting to nature
and to a real true community
and tribe,
will make all the difference
for you.
I hope so.
Hey, Fern.
Hey, Linda.
Come over and join us.
No, I'm just gonna
take a little walk.
- Okay.
- Be back soon.
Hey. Good morning...
- Bob.
- Morning.
One of the questions
that I get all the time is,
"Bob, I have to live
in the city.
"I'd like to be out here,
but I can't.
"How can I avoid the
famous knock on the door?"
So, I've developed what I call
the Ten Commandments
of Stealth Parking.
Stop being so quiet.
And then, in and out.
Just make...
You gotta make
the hole bigger
so the rope fits.
Very... Yeah. That's it.
That's perfect.
- Oh, my God. Ladies.
- Then you go...
I love this lifestyle.
It is a lifestyle of freedom
and beauty,
and connection to the Earth.
Yet there is a trade‐off.
You gotta learn how to
take care of your own shit.
Most of us, in this lifestyle,
use a five‐gallon bucket.
Most of us are in vans
or something larger.
I'm in a Prius,
so I use a two‐gallon bucket.
If you have bad knees,
you could use
a seven‐gallon bucket.
- Hi, Fern.
- Hi, guys.
- Got these for you.
- Thank you. These are nice.
Yeah.
She always has
some nice appliances.
Here, you should
take this one.
That one's kind of funky.
Oh. These yours?
Yeah.
There's a black hole in every van.
Specially mine. One time I had
seven of these can openers.
Doesn't happen to me.
Trade you for a potholder.
I make 'em.
Okay, sure. Wow.
What is this? Crochet?
No. Something different.
- Nice.
- Wow, that is nice.
- Yeah.
- Wow.
Uh‐uh‐uh.
It's going home with me.
Okay.
See ya.
- Thank you.
- Yep.
Seems like the work is
not gonna be horrible.
Uh‐oh, uh‐oh,
it's sliding.
- Do you take resumes?
- Um...
I'll leave it with
you, just in case.
- No. Just go on...
- Go online?
- Yeah.
- Oh, okay.
I got a four‐pack
for $100.
Just like that.
Whoa!
Did you feel it?
That's what
it does to people.
- It scared me.
- It scares them away.
You guys know how much
money is sitting here?
It's like they're,
uh, dinosaurs.
Nope. Watch out, watch out.
Watch the steps.
Welcome aboard.
Whoa.
- Whoa.
- It's like a disco.
Oh, my gosh.
Oh, the lighting
is beautiful.
- Washer and dryer.
- Oh, my gosh.
You're kidding.
Oh, man.
Okay, ladies,
where are we going?
- Hawaii.
- No, no.
Well, yeah.
Well, there's water
between here and there.
Let's not go
to the East Coast.
There's no place big
enough over there
to park something this size.
This is a magic bus.
We could go to Hawaii.
Okay. Hawaii.
♪♪ In our vans again
♪♪ Goin' places
That we've never been
♪♪ Going places
♪♪ We may never go again
♪♪ And we can't wait
to get in our vans again
♪♪ Rubber tramps again
♪♪ Like a band of Gypsies
We go down to Quartzsite
♪♪ We'll see Bob again ♪♪
All right.
In Quartzsite, Arizona,
especially in
the Quartzsite Yacht Club,
line dancing is
a long‐standing tradition,
so here we go.
♪♪ Well
I went down to Quartzsite
♪♪ Been trying
to sell my wares
♪♪ I got a great selection
You can't find just anywhere
♪♪ Well, I know I've got no
money I hear it all the time
♪♪ I bet they'll be back
tomorrow
♪♪ 'Cause that's
your favorite line
♪♪ Well, I'm selling drink
at half‐price
♪♪ I'm taking out a loan
♪♪ Man, if I don't make
some money soon
♪♪ I'll never get back home
♪♪ I got
the Quartzsite vendor blues ♪♪
Looks like you got a
hankering to go out there.
No.
You sure?
Okay.
- Come on.
- All right.
♪♪ And we can start over
♪♪ With what could've been
There are
no professionals here.
♪♪ We'll hold
each other close
♪♪ And fall in love again
♪♪ We'll hold
each other close
♪♪ And fall in love again
♪♪ So have you ever thought of
getting back with me
♪♪ And maybe friends can be
the way they used to be
♪♪ I swear
I'll never hurt you
♪♪ I'll never set you free
♪♪ If you ever think
of getting back with me ♪♪
Goodbye, Fern!
Nice.
...for your
security while on the road,
or out in the boondocks,
so if there are any questions
that you may have
regarding RV system design,
maintenance,
and troubleshooting,
stop on by today,
and bring your rig,
so that we can help you
take advantage
of what Mother Nature
is offering for free.
Hey, Ron.
Can you come here a second?
These guys have some
really nice stuff.
This is Noodle, Roxy.
That's Ron.
- How's it going, Ron?
- Noodle.
Trying to make
some gas money.
- Roxy.
- Nice to meet you.
Yeah, I think these
are really nice, Ron.
Look at that work.
- It's got nice whoop‐de‐doos.
- Yeah, look at that.
- Yeah. Look, look.
- I see those.
Ron, look.
Hello, ma'am.
You by chance have
an extra cigarette?
Yeah, sure.
Need a light?
I'd love one.
Need it?
Well, sure.
Thank you.
- Yep.
- What's your name?
- Fern.
- Fern, Derek.
Hi, Derek.
- Well, it's nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you.
- I'll be seeing you.
- Mmm‐hmm.
What?
It's Fern, it's Fern, Swankie.
It's Fern.
- Hey. Hi.
- Didn't you see the flag?
- Yeah, yeah. I'm sorry.
- It means
- I don't wanna be disturbed.
- I know.
I need a ride to town.
Why?
I blew my tire.
Well, go change it.
I don't have
a spare.
You don't have a spare?
You're out in the boondocks
and you don't have a spare?
You can die out here.
You're out in the wilderness,
far away from anybody.
You can die out here.
Don't you understand that?
You have to
take it seriously.
You have to have
a way to get help.
You have to be able
to change your own tire.
I appreciate it.
Thanks, Swankie.
All right.
You can...
You can pay me back.
I'm gonna go on this trip.
I'm getting ready to leave.
I got a lot to do.
I can't get it all
done fast enough.
Yeah, sure.
I owe ya. I owe ya.
You can help me
finish things up.
- I really appreciate it.
- You got it.
Here's what I suggest.
Don't get AAA, okay?
You gotta get something
like a SPOT device.
A satellite
tracking device.
We need to soak
the sandpaper.
- It's called wet and dry.
- Mmm‐hmm.
We need it
to be wet.
Ready?
Ready. Yep.
Now we need to mask
the fender off,
because white paint will
land on the fender, too.
Put plastic over this.
All right, let me just say
that this is a lot more
complicated than I thought.
Oh, it's very,
very complicated.
- Uh‐huh.
- And it's taking me
a long time to patch all the
peeling paint on this van.
- So are you quitting on me?
- Okay.
No, no,
I'm not quitting.
When we get done
with all this,
I'm gonna give you
all my paint.
I don't want to take
any more of it with me,
you can have it all 'cause
your van looks kind of...
ratty.
No, it doesn't.
She does not.
She just needs a wash.
No. You take my paint.
Ratty.
Ugh. Ugh.
Fern. It's Swankie.
What? I'm indisposed.
Where did I get
all this stuff?
- Yeah? Well, it adds up.
- Where'd it come from?
I just put on Facebook,
Quartzsite Chatter,
the other day
that I was givin'
all this stuff away
and I asked people
to come get it.
So, I'm hopin'
they do.
I love this.
Take it.
- You kidding?
- It's yours.
Whoa, that's nice.
You look really good
in that chair.
And that's called
red, white, and blue jasper.
What's that?
That's petrified palm wood.
And that's part of
the same...
- rock, and, uh...
- Mmm‐hmm.
Ouch!
Um...
- Careful, your arm.
- That's another one
of the red,
white, and blue.
- What's going on? What?
- I don't feel very good.
- I got a headache.
- Hey.
Here. Sit down.
Got it?
What's goin' on?
What do you need?
My head hurts really,
really bad
and I'm nauseated.
Water'll help?
Would water help?
Oh, yeah.
- Oh, boy.
- Here.
Careful, your arm.
Mrs. McQuarry
reminded me of someone.
- You all right?
- Mmm‐hmm.
I...
I guess I'm all right.
You okay?
Um...
Doctors told me that...
Well, I had cancer removed
from my lung a while back
and, small cell carcinoma.
And they told me
it's spread to my brain.
And they've only given me
seven or eight months to live.
I'm sorry.
I'm gonna
take my trip.
I'm gonna go back
to Alaska again,
because of some good memories.
And, um,
just do
what I have to do.
I have this book called
Final Exitby Dr. Kevorkian.
Some people call him
Dr. Death.
And it's like,
various ways
that you can end your
life if you need to.
And, um,
it's kind of like a recipe.
I have it, if I have to fall
back on it for some ideas,
but I'm not gonna
spend any more time
indoors in a hospital.
No, thanks.
I'm gonna be 75
this year
and I think I've lived
a pretty good life.
I've seen some
really neat things,
kayaking, all those places.
And, you know,
moose in the wild.
A moose family
on a river in Idaho.
Um...
And big,
white pelicans landin'
just six feet over my kayak
on a lake in Colorado.
Or, uh...
um, come around a bend,
was a cliff,
and find hundreds and hundreds
of swallow nests
on the wall of the cliff.
And the swallows
flyin' all around.
And reflecting in the water
so it looks like I'm flying
with the swallows
and they're under me,
and over me,
and all around me.
And the little babies
are hatchin' out
and egg shells are fallin' out
of the nests,
landin' on the water
and floatin' on the water.
These little white shells.
It's like, well,
it's just so awesome.
I felt like I'd done enough.
My life was complete.
If I died right then,
that moment,
it'd be perfectly fine.
I don't know.
Maybe when I die,
my friends will gather
around the fire
and toss a rock into the fire
in memory of me.
Oh, I see somethin' neat.
Here we go.
And then pull it up
and close it up.
- How's that?
- Oh.
Oh! Look at this.
My grandmother made that
for me, and gave it to me.
So, enjoy.
Take good care of it.
- Thank you.
- Bye.
Can I tell you
somethin', Swankie?
What?
Been thinkin' a lot
about my husband Bo.
When it got really bad
at the end,
they had him
in the hospital
on morphine drip
and I would sit there
at night, in the hospital.
And...
I'd wanna put my thumb down
on that morphine drip
just a little bit longer...
so I could let him go.
Maybe I should have
tried harder
so he could have gone sooner
without all that pain.
Well, maybe he wouldn't have
wanted that.
Maybe he was tryin' to stay
with you as long as he could.
I'm sure you took
good care of him, Fern.
I did.
Bye, Fern.
All right.
♪♪ Hey, hey,
how 'bout a drink?
♪♪ How about a toast
to our friends?
♪♪ Not the friends you're
gonna see every day, no
♪♪ Instead we're gonna drink
to the friends
♪♪ Who had to go away
♪♪ I bet you know
just who I mean
♪♪ The friends
who had to depart
♪♪ The friends in our heart
♪♪ Ya hear the blues
♪♪ In my boogie
♪♪ Can you see
the blood in my beer
♪♪ Just help me laugh at pain
♪♪ Help me smile away
the tears ♪♪
Fern!
- Hey. How you doin'?
- Hi, there.
- Thank you very much.
- Yeah, sure.
- It's just black, so...
- Ah, that's good.
Hello. Coffee?
- I know you.
- Yeah, hi. Dave. Right?
Guess.
- Fern.
- Yes.
I have your
can opener.
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah, you do.
Are you working
here now or...
Yeah, first year.
So, coffee?
Uh...
Yeah, sure.
- Yeah.
- That's good.
Black, so...
If you want
anything in it,
you gotta put it in.
So, see ya.
- Yeah. Have a good day.
- I'm your camp host.
One thing you
wanna make sure
that you always do
is put on gloves.
You need to protect
your health.
We have people from all
over the world coming here.
Give 'em a little puff.
And that's it.
The walls, too?
Or just that silver thing?
- Oh, walls, too. Yes.
- Walls, too. Okay.
Where do you go
and find scenery like this?
- Right here is where you go.
- Yeah.
- The Badlands.
We be the bitches
of the Badlands.
Look. Look.
Ew!
I don't want those on me. No.
Some people.
Oh, that's almost
a whole bag of Doritos.
- Excuse me.
- Yeah?
Hey.
Are you
the camp host?
Yeah. I'm Fern.
That's Linda May.
- How you guys doin'?
- Good.
- I'd shake your hand...
- I'm Victor.
...but you wouldn't.
Not now.
- Yeah.
- You don't wanna touch these.
Well, the power's
out here.
We're tryin' to have our
daughter's birthday party.
Is it on?
- It's on!
- All right!
Do you want me to tie this
one on your wrist, too?
Oh, no!
The wind's picking up!
Oh, my. Oops.
Which hand
do you want it on?
That one?
What beautiful hands.
- Thank you.
- There you go.
Welcome to
Badlands Spa.
Can I please have a volunteer
from the audience?
- Pick me.
- Okay.
Oh, doesn't that
feel wonderful?
What's your name, miss?
- Linda.
Hi,
may I help you?
Yes. We're here
for the tour.
The tour will be
in about 15 minutes.
Should we wait
right here?
You can wait
if you want, here.
I got a great map of
the local area, here.
We have a schedule
of some of the summer
- activities right here.
- Hi.
- You can take one.
- Oh, wonderful.
- There you go.
- Okay.
This is gonna be
really exciting.
Rub two stones together.
And you'll see
what happens
as they start
to get like sand.
That's why it's so easy
for a paleontologist
to find fossils
in here.
Why are there holes
in the rocks?
That's a...
That's a very good question.
At one time,
there was air inside these rocks.
Like little pockets,
little bubbles of gas.
And they're trapped
inside the rocks.
That's what makes them
so, uh, breakable.
Hey, hey!
Find anything
interesting?
Rocks!
Hey, Fern!
Hey, Greg.
Line that up.
Salud!
To the earthship.
- To the earthship, Linda May.
- To the earthship.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Thank you.
- Oh, yeah.
- Mmm‐hmm.
Oh,
makes your voice go high.
Oh, yeah. Mmm!
Okay.
This is my land
in Arizona.
I'm gonna build an earthship
that's a totally
self‐contained house,
built out of tires,
and bottles, and cans.
So it has no waste.
It in no way harms
the land, this house.
- Self‐sufficient?
- Self‐sufficient.
It looks like
a living piece of art
that you've made with
your own two hands.
It's something that I can
leave to my grandchildren.
This house would be there
for generations.
Outlive us all.
That's a good thing.
There. Now we're on.
When you get old,
you get personality.
Yeah.
I'm not gonna
see you for a while.
But... But...
Oh... Oh...
You come and see me.
You come and stay
as long as you like.
- Whenever you like.
- Mmm.
- Okay.
- Thank you.
- Oh...
- Thank you, Linda May.
Oh, thank you.
You have given me
so much.
- Okay. Okay.
Hi, Fern.
Hey.
I was at the gas
station, and, uh,
and I think it's
better if you don't
drive through the park
when it's dark
for your cigarettes,
so I got you these.
What are they?
Uh, licorice sticks.
I can't smoke
licorice sticks, Dave.
I know,
but you can chew on these,
and, you know,
they help curb the urge.
I'm not gonna
quit smoking, Dave.
Yeah, I know,
but you should try these.
They're good for
the digestion, too.
Fine. Thanks.
- What's going on?
- Ants. I've got ants.
Oh, ants. They're okay.
No, they're not.
They're in my food, Dave!
I can do it.
Thanks.
Where do you want this?
Oh...
Fern, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry,
I didn't know that...
Go over there!
You don't have
to shout. Okay?
Stay over there.
I'm going.
Okay.
No, we're closed.
You are
one of those lucky people
that is from
the United States.
- Of the US of A.
- Yes.
- Yes, I am.
- And you can travel anywhere.
Yes, ma'am.
I know.
And they sometimes call you
- nomads...
- Yeah.
...or people
who don't have a home.
I see that
you have this ring.
- Mmm‐hmm.
- Are you married?
I am,
but my husband died.
And so...
I'm not gonna take that off.
- That ring is a circle.
- Mmm‐hmm.
And it never ends.
And that means that
your love never ends.
And you may not be able to
take it off if you tried.
I don't think I could.
No.
Got a nice setup.
The best one.
He has a case
of diverticulitis.
Which is inflammation
of his intestines.
Uh‐huh.
So, earlier
the surgeon went in
and did
a laparoscopic surgery.
He had surgery?
Ooh, Cup Noodles.
Yeah. Well, it's good
for when you're sick.
- Wow.
- Animal crackers.
And...
for you.
That's my favorite.
I know.
Thanks, Fern.
So, what are you
gonna do next?
Uh, I'm gonna go to the
beet harvest in Nebraska.
Uh, that doesn't start
till October.
How 'bout you?
I'm gonna start in
at Wall Drug.
Yeah, I did that
last year.
I can see if they
have another opening.
- For me?
- Yeah.
Got a great place
to park.
Enjoy your kippers.
Get better. Bye.
- How's it going?
- Good, good, good.
One...
- Hey, Michael!
- Hey! How's it goin'?
Good. Can I take
these tomatoes and onions?
Yes. Absolutely.
Thank you.
I don't like it.
One up over
the right side there.
Okay.
Please don't let her
face get near me.
Oh, sheesh.
- Oh, my gosh.
- Isn't she beautiful?
I'm kinda kidding,
but I'm not, really.
Oh, no. It's really
squeezing my arm a lot.
That's me.
Okay.
Yeah!
He didn't get it.
Oh, my God,
look at how gross it is.
Ew. No! Get out of there,
Terry. Get out! Get out!
He's fine, Fern.
Fern, he's fine.
- No, no. No, no.
- He's fine, he's fine.
Look. Just look.
What is it?
What's he feeding them? Oh!
Probably chicken
or something like that.
No. It's rabbits.
Look at that.
- Look at his eyes.
- Yeah, yeah. He wants you.
He wants you next.
You get in there.
I don't wanna
be the one.
He's gonna come right
through the glass.
Pack in,
pack out.
I think they were
actually this big.
First thing
we need to do is ask you
to turn off
your bright lights.
- I can.
- Oh, it's right there.
Right,
straight up, overhead.
That's the star, Vega.
But it's 24
light years away.
- Wow.
So what that means
is the light
that you're looking at
left Vega in 1987.
Wow.
And it just got here?
And it just got here.
So the telescope
is set up on Jupiter.
Jupiter is the
largest planet in our
entire solar system.
Stars blow up,
and they shoot plasma
and atoms out into space.
Sometimes land on Earth.
Nourish the soil.
They become part of you.
So, hold out
your right hand
- and look at a star.
- Wow.
Because
there are atoms
from stars that
blew up eons ago
that landed
on this planet,
and now they're
in your hand.
- Hi.
Sorry, we're closed.
Uh... I'm looking
for Dave.
I'm his son,
James.
He's in the kitchen.
Around the counter there.
- That one?
- Yeah.
In Nashville,
we recorded a record...
I got it. I got it. I got it.
I've been through here.
- Oh, yeah?
- A couple of times, yeah.
Huh.
This place, man.
I don't know why anybody
would wanna live here.
Well, I can think
of worse places.
You wanna know a good way
to get to know a place?
What?
AA meetings.
- Really?
- I mean, for me.
Back when I was with the band,
and I was travelin' around,
I used to go to AA
meetings everywhere.
It was a great way
to get to know people
and to get to
know a place.
How's the burger?
- Well, it's not bad.
- Yeah?
He's a good cook, your dad.
It's not that hard
to make a burger.
Cold.
- That's his wife, Emily.
- Oh, she's cute.
Hope she's older
than she looks.
She's gonna
have a baby.
You're gonna be
a grandpa.
When's she due?
In two weeks,
he said.
He's on his way home now.
- Asked me to come with him.
- You should go.
I was...
I was, uh...
He didn't like it very much
that I wasn't around
when he was...
when he was young.
I tried to be around
when he was older,
but he was into his thing,
and I was into mine
and I guess,
I just forgot how to be a dad.
Anyway, I wasn't
very good at it.
Don't think about it
too much, Dave.
Just go.
Be a grandfather.
You wanna come with me?
Maybe I can visit sometime.
Great.
'Night.
♪♪ It's been
many years since
♪♪ I started out
for that gold
♪♪ Findin' bits and pieces
All worth their reach...
♪♪ I've carried on ♪♪
Huh.
You made it, Swankie.
Thanks, man.
Then I'm gonna get the big G
right here. For Georgia.
And the big bulldog
right here.
It'll be a full half sleeve
for the Georgia Bulldogs.
Oh, Jesus!
No overnight parking.
You can't sleep here.
I'm leaving. I'm leaving.
Okay, what we've got
is parts and labor,
- $2,300 and tax.
- Okay.
I just looked up
the value on your van.
With that high a mileage,
you're lookin' about
$5,000 at the most.
I'd probably
recommend, um,
taking that money
and putting it
towards a different
vehicle so that you...
No, no. Well, I can't do that.
I can't do that. See, 'cause...
All right. Um...
I, uh,
spent a lot of time and money
building the inside out,
and, um,
a lot of people
don't understand
the value of that.
But it's not somethin',
like, we can...
I live in there.
It's my home.
Why can't you just wire it to
me, Doll?
I can pay you...
I can...
Dolly, listen,
I can pay you back.
I'm gonna do
Amazon again soon.
I'll be able to pay you back
as soon as I get that check.
It's gonna be...
Yeah... I'm being stubborn?
Well, I think
you're being a bitch.
Hi.
Hi, Fern.
The doorbell works.
Yeah, well,
I didn't hear it, so...
Hey.
You want yours
with cheese on it? All right.
- Got my famous four‐egg cake.
- All right.
Dolly talked me into it.
Where do you want it?
Okay. Yeah,
put it there, Fern.
Here? Okay.
- All right.
- Ooh, that looks good.
- Mmm‐hmm.
- I want that one.
All right,
that's yours.
- It's got your name on it.
- Double cheese,
- please.
- You want cheese?
- I want two slices, please.
- Okay.
Uh, this is
my sister, Fern.
- Fern?
- Hi, Fern. I'm Jim.
Hi. Sorry. Lime on my hand.
Nice to meet you.
This is my wife, Pam.
- Hi, Pam. Sorry, wet hand.
- Hi.
Jim has been working
with George for a long time.
Yeah, George actually
sold us our first house
before I got
in real estate.
Did they tell you
how they met?
No.
I introduced them.
I introduced you to George,
but I knew George before.
So, I took her out and I
said, "Listen, um...
"George is a really
good friend of mine.
"I don't want you
to mess this up.
"If you're not serious
about him,
"don't mess with him."
And I didn't
mess it up.
And you said,
"What are you talkin' about?"
And so, how many years
have you been together?
30 plus.
- Worked out pretty good.
- Yeah, worked out pretty good.
I was able to take care of it on my
own, actually,
- after that introduction.
- You're welcome.
Things are
looking good right now.
The prices are goin' up.
2012 was a winner.
I mean, I wish I would
have had the money
in 2008
to buy everything,
so I could
sell it now.
Seems like real estate
always ends up on the upside.
I don't wanna
disagree with you,
but I have
to say I do.
It's strange that
you encourage people
to invest their whole
life savings, go into debt,
just to buy a house
they can't afford.
Fern,
that's a rather limited
look at what we do.
Is it limited, George?
I mean,
we're not all in a position to just
chuck everything
and hit the road.
Oh, you think that's what
I've done, George?
I chucked everything to hit
the road? Is that what I did?
All right.
I'm sorry.
You know, I think that, um,
what the nomads are doing
is not that different than
what the pioneers did.
I think Fern's part
of an American tradition.
I think it's great.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Here you go.
Okay. Yeah, thanks.
You know I'll pay you
back, right?
Mmm‐hmm.
- I will.
- Mmm‐hmm.
Why don't you move in with us?
I can't live here.
I can't live in this room.
I can't sleep in this bed.
Thank you, but I can't...
I know,
we're not as interesting
as the people you meet
out there.
That's not what
I'm talkin' about.
No, that's what it is.
It's always what's out there
that's more interesting.
You left home
as soon as you could,
you married Bo after just
knowing him a few months,
and then you moved to the
middle of nowhere with him.
And then
even after Bo passed away,
you still stayed
in Empire.
I just didn't get it.
I mean, you could have left...
Yeah.
See, that's why
I can't come here.
I never said this
to you before,
and maybe I should have...
You know,
when you were growin' up,
you were eccentric
to other people.
You maybe seemed weird,
but it was just because
you were braver,
and more honest
than everybody else.
And you could see me when I
was hiding from everybody.
And sometimes you could
see me before I saw myself.
I needed that in my life.
And you're my sister.
I would have loved having
you around all these years.
You left a big hole
by leaving.
That one's on me.
Hey.
Hi. Want a sandwich?
You hungry?
I think
I've met you before.
Yeah, I'm Fern.
I was workin' at T‐Rock
in Quartzsite.
- Fern.
- Mmm‐hmm.
You let Noodle sell his rocks
there, didn't you?
Yeah.
Would you like
a beer?
Uh...
Yeah, okay.
I'll trade you for a sandwich.
- Well, here you go.
- Thanks.
It's cold, you know.
You should sit down
by the fire.
Got a little trouble
with my knees, though.
Can you help me?
- Of course.
- Thanks, man.
Yeah, that'll do it. Yeah.
- All right.
- Great. Thanks.
You gave me a light
back in Quartzsite.
Mmm‐hmm.
You still have it?
No, that's long gone.
But I do have this for ya.
Want you to have it.
Thanks.
It's really beautiful.
What is that?
What's that stone?
That there
is dinosaur bone.
Really?
Uh, I think so.
But I only know what they tell me.
Where are your
mom and dad?
Back home in Wisconsin.
You think
they worry about you?
You don't get lonely?
Got a girlfriend anywhere?
Well,
to be truthful,
well, there is one.
Mmm‐hmm.
She lives up
in the North Country.
Small farm.
She's happy
with her life there.
I...
write letters to her.
Oh, smart man. Very good.
Letters are good.
I just can't ever
write about anything
I reckon
she'd care about.
You ever try poems?
Can't say I have.
I don't think I know a one.
Do you know any?
How about one that I
used for my wedding vow?
When I was not
much older than you.
Oh, right on.
Mind if I hear it?
Okay. Let's see
if I can remember it.
Um...
"Shall I compare thee
to a summer's day?
"Thou art more lovely
and more temperate.
"Rough winds do shake
the darling buds of May.
"And summer's lease
hath all too short a date.
"Sometime too hot
the eye of heaven shines.
"And often is
his gold complexion dimmed.
"And every fair from fair
sometimes declines.
"By chance or nature's
changing course undimmed.
"But thy eternal summer
shall not fade.
"Nor lose possession
of that fair thou ow'st.
"Nor
"shall...
"Nor shall death brag
thou walkest in his shade.
"When in eternal lines to time
thou grow'st.
"So long as men can breathe
and eyes can see.
"So long lives this,
and this gives life to thee."
Fern!
- Hey!
- Hi!
Hey.
Hi. You made it.
Yeah.
Good.
- Hey. Yeah. It's nice.
- Wow. Wow.
Well, hey.
Come here.
Come on in.
- I'll get that.
- Okay.
This is Emily,
my daughter‐in‐law.
- I'm Fern.
- So nice to meet you.
- Hi.
- Welcome.
- Hey, everybody.
- Hey! There you are!
This is Fern.
Hey. Hi, I'm Mike.
- Hi.
- Nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you. Thank you.
- Welcome, welcome.
And you know James.
Hi, James.
How are you?
Hi. How are you?
It's nice to see you.
Thanks for having me.
- Who's that? Is that the guy?
- This is Damien.
- Hi.
- He's the guy.
- Hi, Damien.
- Say hi.
How's your drive?
It was great.
Little hairy on the end.
That's a scary road.
In your van?
I've heard about your van.
- Yeah, yeah.
- I'd like to see it.
I'll, uh, introduce you at some point.
Thanks. Yeah.
Okay.
Where you comin' from?
That's Peter.
Hey!
Can I get you somethin'?
Uh, yeah. Water would be great.
Thanks.
Great. Sure.
Oh.
Been on
the road long?
Um... Yeah.
I worked for a while,
but I've been travelin'
since I last saw you, yeah.
- All right, cool.
- Here you go.
Uh‐oh, uh‐oh.
Okay, I'll give you
to mommy.
- You had a flat.
- Did you eat something?
Eat something?
Huh?
You had a flat tire
on your van, Dave.
Oh, okay.
I hadn't noticed.
'Cause you're stayin'?
Yeah.
Good.
Yeah,
I never expected to.
Never thought I'd spend
another night
under a roof, but...
Well, this is
a really nice place, Dave.
Yeah, you can stay.
Oh, good, thanks.
I need to do laundry.
You know, I meant
stay longer, Fern.
They do have
a guest house.
I'm serious.
What'd they think
about that?
I already asked them.
I like you.
You're a good person.
You...
You get along with people
for the most part.
You know...
I like being around you.
What's up? What's up?
You don't wanna be that way?
You wanna be like this,
don't you? Yeah.
Yeah.
♪♪ Sometimes you get
a notion
♪♪ To jump into
the ocean ♪♪
Here. He might be
getting a little tired.
Here. I've gotta go
to the kitchen.
Okay. Okay.
Just, just...
Don't be gone long, Dave.
Okay?
Oh!
...aren't you?
Go ahead. Go ahead.
Come here.
Here they come.
Look at all those.
How many do you have?
I don't know
how many we have.
That one's beautiful.
Look at those feathers.
Hey. Where's that
little puffed one?
I don't want him
sneakin' up on me.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Can you give me
some more stuffing...
- Corn?
- ...and a little corn?
What is
that called?
Thanks, Fern.
That's good.
Gravy?
This turkey
is so moist.
This is
incredible food.
Thank you, Em.
Thank you, James,
and just wanna say
a little somethin'.
Uh... To welcome... To Fern.
- Yeah.
- To this...
- To this feast of a...
- Thanks!
...a feast of a family,
and to the new one,
and I guess
the old ones, too,
and everybody in between.
- Yeah.
- So, welcome, Fern.
- Welcome.
- Thank you very much.
- Happy Thanksgiving.
Yay!
Cheers, all.
Ah, the bells
of Acrosanti.
That's the problem.
And they're not...
No, they're terrible.
Yeah.
I like that name, Empire.
You know, we had
an airport, public pool,
a golf course.
Wow. Sounds nice.
What was your house
like there?
Nothing special.
Just a company tract house.
Actually,
it was special.
We were right
on the edge of town.
And our backyard looks out
at this huge open space.
It was just desert,
desert, desert,
all the way to the mountains.
There was nothin' in our way.
You know,
I'm really glad you're here.
Dave really likes you.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- He talks about you a lot.
- Hmm.
Happy New Year.
Happy New Year!
Because she loved rocks.
See you down the road,
Swankie.
Bo never knew his parents
and we never had kids.
If I didn't stay,
if I left, it would be like
he never existed.
I couldn't pack up
and move on.
He loved Empire.
He loved his work so much.
He loved being there.
Everybody loved him.
So I stayed.
Same town, same house.
It's like my dad used to say,
"What's remembered lives."
I maybe spent
too much of my life
just remembering, Bob.
You know what I mean?
I can...
I can relate.
Um...
I rarely ever talk
about my son.
But, uh, today would be...
Today would be
his 33rd birthday,
and five years ago,
he took his life.
And I can still barely
say that in a sentence.
And for a long time,
every day was, uh...
The question was...
how can I be alive
on this Earth,
when he's not?
And I didn't have an answer.
And those were some hard,
hard days.
But...
I realized that
I could honor him by, uh,
helping people,
and serving people.
It gives me a reason to go
through the day.
Some days that's all I've got.
And out here,
there's a lot of people our age.
Inevitably,
there's grief and loss.
And a lot of 'em don't
get over it either.
And that's okay.
That's okay.
One of the things I love
most about this life
is that
there's no final goodbye.
You know, I've met
hundreds of people out here
and I don't ever say
a final goodbye.
I always just say,
"I'll see you down the road."
And I do.
And whether it's a month,
or a year,
or sometimes years,
I see them again.
And I can look
down the road
and I can be certain
in my heart
that I'll see
my son again.
You'll see Bo again.
And you can remember
your lives together then.
Are you sure you don't
need any of this stuff?
No, don't need any of it.
I'm good.
I'm not gonna miss
one thing.
Well, we'll see
you later.
Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull
♪♪ It's been many years since
♪♪ I started out
for that gold
♪♪ Findin' bits and pieces
All worth their reach
♪♪ I've carried on
♪♪ Somewhere in the light
♪♪ I followed my eyes
and went alone
♪♪ Ended up here with
the fear, gripping a stone
♪♪ Drifting away, I go
♪♪ Driving down the highway
♪♪ Roll down the window,
watch it go
♪♪ Listen to the secrets of
my tires rolling down the road
♪♪ Somewhere in the night
♪♪ She knows that I'm all right
when I'm alone
♪♪ But everything breezing
keep me company when I roll
♪♪ Drifting away, I go
♪♪ Driving all day
♪♪ Driving all night
♪♪ Drifting away, I go
♪♪ Drifting away, I go ♪♪