Transcript by Synchronized
When I was 7 years old,
the elders and I withessed
the battle across the river.
It was crowded with people,
all looking at that building.
My father told me,
they are all heroes.
They are protecting us.
I didn't know
what happened at the time.
I only remember the
fermented rice balls tasted good.
Ever since then,
my father would visit
the warehouse every year
to light a candle
and leave a bowl
of fermented rice balls.
Now my father's gone,
I still go by myself.
I can never forget what he said,
the people inside
are protecting us, right?
Hurry up!
What are you waiting for?
Up ahead is Shanghai!
The city's fate
depends on you!
I'm telling you all now,
you are the faces of
the Hubei Security Corps.
Look lively!
Everyone move faster!
Ignore those who are falling behind.
Keep moving!
If you want to live!
Number 9,
honour the elders.
Number 10,
cherish your life.
What does glass-half-full mean?
Zhou Yi said,
how much further to Shanghai?
Should be soon!
To be a good person,
one must persist in doing good.
Stop!
Fall in!
Quick!
Hurry!
Hurry up!
Come in tighter!
Where are we?
Dachang.
What the hell is this...
No NRA (National Revolutionary Army) troops.
No military police.
Not even a single Japanese!
- Fight?
- Uncle.
What are we fighting?
- Brother is there.
- I'm afraid we're Killing the bandits.
What are we gonna do?
- Don't move!
- If I must say just two words.
Go back!
What?
Go back?
There isn't even a car here!
How are we supposed to go back?
Harvest is about to start.
Why don't you going back?
Donkey cart, horse
cart, train, doesn't matter.
A couple days and nights
and we'll be back home.
To all our fallen comrades!
Salute!
Fire!
Attention!
Pay attention!
Who is over there?
There is a Chinese here!
Got a Chinese here!
Uncle!
Run!
Captain Fujita, don't let him go!
Japanese!
Run!
Don't just run around!
March the team!
Take cover!
Open fire!
Duan Wu!
Brother!
Don't just run around!
Uncle!
Kill them all!
Shoot!
Next!
Orders from the senior official:
Deserters must be punished!
- Go!
- Mercy, Sir!
We're just scattered!
I'm begging you, please!
Ready!
- I still can fight!
- Shoot!
Don't kill me!
I don't want to die!
Next up!
The division commander's dead.
We can't find the colonel!
We don't have leader!
Please let me go!
I can still fight!
Help me.
Uncle!
He's from our hometown!
He's our fellow!
We can't save him.
Let's go!
Sorry.
There are so many people.
Are they here to help?
You idiot!
Japanese are over there.
The NRA is retreating!
Uncle, let's go over there.
Tell the commander,
we just fell behind.
Fell behind?
More like deserters!
If they catch us we're dead!
Go!
Go! Go!
New troops!
Get in line!
And keep pace!
Keep up!
Brother.
You deserters.
Hurry up!
Go.
1st Battalion, Machine Gun Company,
Lei Xiong reporting for duty!
Open the door!
Brothers!
Now is the 26th year
of the Republic of China,
October the 26th,
10:07 in the evening.
The total of Shanghai's
remaining troops are all here.
Brothers!
Now that we are here,
we need to be prepared
and willing to die!
Each of us
mustn't rely on luck
or hang onto an ignoble
existence, understand?
Yes, sir!
Colonel is here!
Attention!
Reporting to Colonel Xie,
Machine Gun Company commander,
Lei Xiong, reporting in.
Seven wounded,
caught sixteen deserters along the way.
Return to your places.
Yes, sir!
Lights off!
Brothers,
there are hundreds of
thousands of Japanese troops out there,
there's no chance of
survival once we engage in battle.
It would be a miracle
if we could hold up for half a day.
The whole of Shanghai's eyes
will be on us tomorrow,
Sihang warehouse is our last stand.
This place will be our grave.
Let's get to work.
Keep building fortifications!
You come up here!
All of you
who are still breathing, get up!
Line up!
Declare your unit number!
Declare my ass.
Using me as a scapegoat.
Pussy.
Say that again?
Get up!
I can't.
So what?
Get up!
Either shoot us in the head,
or let us go.
Don't move!
Let go!
Squad 7!
Here!
Take these worthless deserters out.
Execute them!
Yes, sir!
Zhu!
Take these deserters out,
have them repair the fortifications.
Line up!
Sir,
we aren't deserters,
we were scattered.
The Huangpi County HQ sent us
to protect Shanghai.
Kid, come up here.
Come up here.
That's an order!
First, work on protecting yourself.
Steady the landmine!
Don't bury it!
Place the flag!
Mark the landmines!
When it's over,
they will kill us all.
Be careful!
There's a situation!
Sergeant Jiangjing,
situation on the North side!
Get down!
Quickly get down!
On guard!
Halt the landmines!
Someone here!
Alert!
Take cover!
Attention!
Search the boundaries!
Form defensive positions!
No need to aim, these are refugees.
No need to aim!
These are refugees!
Don't let citizens enter the mine zone!
Past the Lese Bridge are
the international concessions.
Watch out for the landmines!
Take a right ahead to the Lese Bridge.
Watch out for landmines.
Grab Xiao Hubei and follow me.
Uncle, Uncle!
Past the Lese Bridge are
the international concessions.
Get to work!
Go on!
Watch out for landmines!
Lese Bridge is ahead and to the right.
Past the Lese Bridge are
the international concessions.
Please wait for your turn
to get into the concessions.
Chinese Nationals turn to your left.
Please state your name,
your occupation,
and show your legal documents.
Out the way, move!
Leave your large luggage out.
Only small belongings are allowed.
That soldier!
Come here!
Soldiers are not
allowed to get in here!
I'm just a farmer.
You are in military uniform,
soldiers are not allowed
into the concession!
Hey! Do not let them in!
Do not push!
Keep calm.
OK, next.
Girl, what's your name?
My name is Summer.
Old man.
We can't allow soldiers to get in.
We are all Chinese,
please just let me in.
Here is the concession,
this bridge is the only way in.
If one soldier gets in,
then the Japanese
will be able to get in too.
If the Japanese get in,
we're done for.
Get out!
Open the door!
Stop sitting around!
Take the supplies to the fourth floor.
Faster!
Move all the gunny sacks over here.
What are you doing?
Quick! Follow up!
Move faster!
The ones behind!
Follow up!
What's the hold up?
Sounds like an angel.
What's she singing?
I don't know.
Stop staring!
Get back to work.
Line up!
You two!
Head over there now.
Colonel wants to see you.
Colonel!
How do you like this one?
Name?
Age?
They call me Xiao Hubei.
I'm 13.
My family name is Zhu.
My great grandpa told me,
we are the eighteenth-generation
descendants of the Hong Wu Emperor.
Then do you know
how the Ming Dynasty collapsed?
Take him under your wing.
When I'm dead,
you take my place.
That side is so pretty.
That side is the concession.
Over there is heaven...
Then here is hell.
This used to be the
warehouse for four banks.
The walls are more than a meter thick,
even cannons can't get through it.
It's more solid than
the gates of General Zhang's house.
You served General Zhang?
Yan and Feng,
- I served them all!
- It's very accurate,
this is my lifeblood.
Could you please give it back to me?
When the bullets fly,
I can tell where they
fell with my eyes closed!
It's inherited.
Please give it back.
One division after another,
all gone in half an hour.
A white horse!
Don't move.
Why is the horse out?
The horse is spooked!
Don't shoot!
Lower your gun!
Don't move! Stand still!
Come here.
Don't be scared.
Don't move!
Come and get your hot dog!
There's more people coming every day.
Hot dogs!
Get your hot dog.
More people are arriving from the North.
How are they all going to fit in here?
I used to sleep like a baby,
I couldn't fell asleep last night.
Isn't that weird?
No way!
The shelling has already stopped.
I heard they retreated.
If everyone retreated,
then we'd all be safe!
The Japs won't reach us here.
It's good enough to
just keep the business running.
No need to fight over it!
Just get in line and wait your turn.
The senior officials asked us,
the Youth Military Field Service,
to distribute emergency supplies.
Everyone has one portion!
Everyone has a share.
Don't fight. Keep in order.
Victory!
You, as a real man,
doing nothing but watching everyday.
What does it have to do with you anyway?
If you dare, why don't you
get enlisted to fight the Japanese?
You wouldn't dare.
We can't afford groceries,
can't afford to eat.
You don't care about the kids either.
Do you even want this family?
Gunshots!
Enemies!
Take cover now!
Groups of three! Prepare to battle!
Hasaba Squadron, get in formation!
Mama, how come they're fighting again?
Didn't the National Army retreat?
I'm telling you,
the British military
is protecting our area.
The Japanese won't break in.
They already retreated.
Why provoke them again?
Everyone who wanted to flee has fled.
What's the point in fighting?
If the Japanese keep advancing
we'll be at risk here.
All the Brits will stay here, right?
What about your house on Xiafei Road?
The French will never let
the Japanese in.
Of course not!
It's the French Concession.
Here you go.
Doesn't Professor Zhang
have any classes today?
He's just watching over all day long.
Danjiang University has closed
due to the War.
Anyway, without his salary,
how are we supposed to get by?
Quick!
Converge!
Fast!
Landmines!
Take cover!
Help the injured!
Get away!
You're making me feel anxious.
Stop running around!
Don't move!
Scouts, go ahead and check it out!
Spread out and move forward!
Move forward!
All the soldiers have run off,
just left us here!
Open the door!
Pull him back here, pull him back here!
Don't get us all killed!
Pull him back here!
Don't hold me!
I'm going out!
Don't drag us down with
you if you want to die!
All clear!
Just a few deserters!
Charge!
We're trapped!
Fight back!
Cut the rope!
There's an ambush!
Keep calm!
Fight!
Take control!
What's happening?
Haven't the Chinese soldiers retreated?
That doesn't look good at all.
We should be safe on this side.
Those stupid Chinese!
Be careful! The flour might explode!
Hold steady!
Do not mind the targets!
Keep on shooting!
No retreat!
Second floor!
Watch out the second floor!
Go to hell!
Get everyone out here!
Everyone!
Come out!
Hurry up!
Move fast!
Clean up the battlefield!
Half of you follow him,
the rest come with me!
If you see any Japanese, shoot them!
Out of the way!
Japanese!
- Stop!
- Out of the way!
The Japanese is coming!
Hurry up!
Don't miss a single one!
Kill the survivors!
Clean up the battlefield!
Collect weapons and gear!
Reinforce the fortifications!
Be prepared for attack at any time!
Hurry up!
Hurry!
Move faster!
Long live the Mikado!
Alert!
Keep clearing the field!
What are you doing?
You want to die?
Sergeant Zhu!
Sergeant Zhu come here!
Come take a look!
Gas bomb! Fire!
Gas bombs!
Toxic gas!
They used it before in Luodian!
Brothers!
Put on your gas masks!
Spread out!
Much appreciated! Give me some!
I don't have urine now, I can't pee.
What are you waiting for?
Pee on a towel, then
cover your mouth with it!
It won't come out.
Ture on the exhaust fan!
Dispel toxic gas!
Turn on the exhaust fan!
Is this gas toxic?
I don't know. Don't frighten me.
Everybody, listen up!
The Japs used the same
weapon in North China.
It's toxic. Evacuate now!
Evacuate!
Mustard Gas.
Don't shut the door!
Let me in!
What are you doing? Drop the money!
Close the door!
Beat anyone who tries to get in!
Let's go!
Nobody run!
What's scary about the Japs?
We are the greatest country!
With 400 million compatriots!
A mouthful of spit from
each of us could drown them!
You stupid scholar.
What's wrong?
They released toxic gas!
Open the door!
Let us in!
Don't panic!
Don't run!
Get the injured to the exit!
Hurry up!
Move!
Pay respects to the martyr!
Get out here.
At ease.
Mr. Fang.
We need to swap to another car.
2nd Division, check your weapons!
Stab!
Kill!
Faster!
Keep pace!
Sihang Warehouse used to be
the headquarter
of the NRA's 88th Division.
It stores thousands of packs of food
along with supplies like
cowhides, silk and tung oil.
There are huge quantities of
medical supplies and ammunition.
Mr. Fang is here.
Come in!
The 524th Regiment of 88th Division
is defending the warehouse now.
The 88th Division?
The so-called Hateful Zhabei Division.
Yes.
The division is equipped
with German weapons.
Please go on.
For three months,
the 524th Regiment increased troop
strength on five occasions.
Supplementary troops sourced
mainly from Hubei, Hunan,
and Zhejiang Security Corps.
Currently there's no
accurate information on
the number of men and their weapons.
Thank you for your hard work.
Please come with me for your reward.
We should go now.
We'll be on our way.
Get Kyohko Hasegawa's squad
ready for an onslaught.
Quickly take down the enemy.
Yes, sir!
Commander Lei!
The fifth and sixth floors are on fire!
Put out the fire immediately!
Restore the fortifications!
Send the injured to the East building!
Yes, sir!
2nd Platoon,
come and push out the fire!
Be careful! The horse is running again!
- Be careful!
- The horse is off again!
Commander Lei!
This one is still breathing!
Leave a few of them alive!
Yes, sir!
Horse!
There's a horse!
Look! There's a horse!
Have nothing better to do?
You'll attract bullets over here.
A scene like this,
is just like a show.
Watch your mouth.
I mean we are all worried.
Chinese troops!
Commander!
Look at that!
What's happening to these soldiers,
is what's coming to you all!
Chinese troops, surrender your weapons.
Otherwise,
you will be just like them!
- Dismembered!
- It's Jiangjing's squad.
It's our periphery defence troops!
Aim at the Japs, shoot!
What's happening to these soldiers
is what's coming to you all!
Chinese troops, surrender your weapons.
Otherwise,
you will be just like them,
dismembered, piece by piece.
Duan Wu!
Look after Xiao Hubei!
Survive!
And bring him home!
As a NRA soldier,
those unwilling to die
on the battlefield should be punished.
Japs are killing our brothers.
I'm giving you all one last chance.
Attention!
Kill me now!
Brother, I'm from the 1st Battalion
of the Zhejiang Security Corps,
Advisor for Internal Affairs.
You can call me the 'Old Abacus'.
It is my obligation to serve my country,
but my job is just to do the accounts.
I don't know how to use this thing.
So commander, don't force me to...
Force my ass!
Do it!
I don't know how to kill.
He knows!
He used to serve General Zhang.
Don't bullshit me!
I said, you!
Come and kill me!
Come on!
The Zhejiang Security Corps
are all dead.
Only you bastard left
bringing shame to them all.
- One!
- Fire!
You dare to shoot me?
Two!
Sorry.
You useless ragtag soldiers,
are the reason
the Japs are winning.
If you chicken out again...
No punishment is too harsh!
I heard you served General Zhang?
Yes, sir!
Then you're up next!
The toxic gas burnt my eyes,
I can't see very well.
You can't see very well?
When they were killing
your brothers and raping your sisters,
did you see then?
Those who cling to life
and are afraid of death,
deserve to be slaughtered!
Shoot!
Bastard! Where are you shooting at?
Can you aim?
You fucking pussy!
Where are you shooting at?
On your knees!
I'm artillery!
Put the gun down.
Long live the Mikado!
Next!
Don't chicken out!
Shoot him!
I don't want to kill.
You don't want to kill?
I don't want to kill people, let me go!
- I don't want to kill!
- Hold your gun!
One!
Two!
Help me!
Pull the trigger.
No!
Help me.
Pull the trigger! Pull the damn trigger!
He killed your uncle.
Your cousin isn't here.
Just head back now.
Just a second, sir.
I need to see him today.
Once you get over it,
you won't be afraid again.
How old are you?
Why do we have to keep
fighting back and forth?
My uncle, my brother, and I,
we are just farmers.
Where are we?
Kiddo?
Sir,
I studied at a private
school back in my hometown,
I've never been out of the county.
I just wanted to see
what Shanghai was like.
I didn't realize...
I thought we are just here
to clean up the battlefield.
My mom is waiting for me at home.
Please let me go.
Xiao Hubei.
Commander Yang.
- Commander Shangguan is here.
- Come down here.
Shangguan Zhibiao and
surgeon Tang Pinxin are here to report.
Tell us about the outside.
From Shanghai Rowe Restaurant,
all the foreigners eat this.
They say if you eat this
you will grow up faster.
Why don't you eat?
It's for kids.
Eat it.
Eat up.
Brother Qiyue,
can you tell me
why does the horse obey you?
I don't know,
But since I was a kid,
I herded a big flock of sheep by myself.
They all follow my orders.
Kiddo!
Don't play with fire!
That's a gas tank, it can explode!
Don't let the British soldier find us.
Quick!
Where are you going?
I'm going for a scout.
Go.
Let's go together.
Climb faster.
Each Squad, keep up!
Keep up!
Climb faster!
Xiao Hubei!
Run!
Captain, we're exposed!
Xiao Hubei!
What are you doing there?
Japanese!
Quickly enter the warehouse!
Advance!
The Japanese are here!
The Japanese crossed the boundary!
They crossed the boundary!
The Japanese are here!
Everybody!
They climbed up!
Lights on!
Aim it at the warehouse!
The Japanese have broken in!
Get your guns!
Quick!
Get your gun!
Cut down their ladders!
Load your weapons!
Secure the doors and windows!
Charge!
Go to hell!
Third floor!
The Japs are coming
in from the third floor!
Take this!
Get to the third floor!
Follow me!
Go!
Get to the third floor!
Everyone to the third floor!
Prepare to fight!
Get out!
I'm begging you, please!
Please!
Get out!
Please, brother, please!
Please! I'm scared!
Please!
Pussy.
Nobody retreats!
Strike!
Move forward!
Concentrate fire!
Throw them out of the windows!
Aim and shoot!
Lights on!
Don't let anyone get close to the banks!
Get to your post! Secure the streets!
Die!
Go to hell!
Clear the battlefield
and check each floor.
See if there's anyone still breathing.
Kill them all.
Two more people here!
Collect weapons and equipment.
Throw out the bodies.
Medic!
Look!
The Colonel Xie is on the roof!
The Japanese have been thrown down.
What a fight!
You guys are heroes!
Good one, boys!
You are heroes!
No Chinese soldiers
are crossing this river!
Or I will shoot you!
Last warning! Turn back, now!
Let's go!
Good job!
The uncles on the other
side are protecting us.
Aren't they great?
After a thorough scout,
we discovered the Japanese's
attempting a stealth attack.
I... We...
Were able to save our brothers
from danger.
He said he's going on a scout.
For what?
Where's the Sichuan soldier?
He...
It's breach to go out of the warehouse.
You don't deserve to be a soldier!
Hundreds of thousands
of the Dongbei troop soldiers
were scared off by 20
thousand of Japanese.
You guys are still deserting?
This is Shanghai.
Nanjing is next.
If our troops fled
we let the Japanese take over Shanghai,
then let the Japanese take over Nanjing?
We've strengthened the sandbag wall.
Block up the waterway.
Close the gate.
Yes, sir!
Fortifications on the north side
were destroyed by the Japanese,
we're fixing it as we speak.
Officer,
the 5th Squad Sergeant
from the 2nd Platoon just got killed.
Their snipers are too sharp,
we should wait until late night.
You let the cadres
repair the fortifications?
Where are those deserters?
Yes, sir!
Check the gear.
Get the sandbags in place.
Repair the damaged fortifications.
Come out!
Don't move!
We are students!
We're here to join the army.
They came in through the waterway.
Watch over them.
They are more valuable than us.
Get down there
and fix the fortification.
We need to keep
the frontline defence strong.
Keep your head down
when you are out there.
Come back the same once
you're finished.
Don't come back,
until the job is done.
Strengthen fortifications!
The Imperial Army
is maintaining
the maximum restraint.
If
Chinese troops drop their weapons,
the Japanese army
will give the most
dignifiable treatment to them.
The Imperial Army
is maintaining
the maximum restraint.
If Chinese troops
drop their weapons...
Too dangerous.
It's too close to the Japanese.
They all aim well.
When we were defending
the Yunzaobang last month,
all those killed
were shot right here.
Two of us should go out,
finish the job cautiously.
Leave the kid out of it.
One of you two follow me.
How about this,
let's follow the NRA tradition.
We draw lots.
Whoever gets the letter side goes out.
You go first.
You should go.
You agreed earlier!
You said...
You...
Newspaper!
Hasegawa's Team, 6th Infantry,
Shanghai Special Marine Corps assembled!
Eyes right!
Eyes front!
Port arms! Salute!
The Japanese will capture
Sihang Warehouse in 3 hours!
Newspaper!
Go away!
The Japanese will
capture Sihang in 3 hours!
One for me!
Sir!
Newspapers!
Imported binoculars!
Binoculars will make it far more vivid!
3 to 1 the Japanese win!
Don't miss it! One o'clock start!
New street drama!
Put down your whip!
Come and watch the show!
Free of charge! Free of charge!
I beg you!
I'm begging you, let him go!
He wants to hit you,
and you still plead for him!
Newspaper! Newspaper!
The Japanese will
capture Sihang Warehouse in 3 hours!
Support the war effort!
Donate money and food!
Make room!
Chairman is here! Chairman is here!
The Chairman!
Chairman is here!
You peasant!
Get off our patch you scroungers!
Miss Lu is here!
Miss Lu!
You're so pretty in real life!
I like your films a lot!
Step aside, excuse me,
keep your distance.
Sister Rong!
The Japanese are about to attack!
They say in just 3 hours,
they will take over the warehouse.
Just now,
I saw the foreigner's monster
flying thing in the sky
and the Japanese ship
on the river.
Seems like war is falling upon us.
Sister,
it seems the casino
won't last much longer.
I think you'd better
consider your options.
You don't need to worry
about these things.
Just take care of my casino.
Don't do anything stupid.
Don't worry.
It's just a little water leak!
Were they killed by the Japanese?
They use water like it's free!
Quit whining!
You think you're the Empress' daughter?
You just get everything you want?
The Japanese are about to attack.
- So annoying.
- What are the Japanese to do with me?
And you just leave it like this!
So much whining.
The military observers are all here?
Yes, Mr. He (Xiangning).
Boting (Chief of Staff).
How long can our men last?
3rd Squad and 4th Squad...
Grenade!
Aim and fire!
Something is wrong.
You take over the 2nd floor!
Stay close!
Go!
Enemy fire is too strong!
We need support on the second floor!
You guys come with me
to the second floor!
Yes, sir! Let's go!
Watch your left!
Colonel Xie!
There're too many of them
approaching the building!
Cover each other and flank attack!
They are targeting the West Wall,
inform Commander Yang!
Arrange the West Wall
firing points immediately!
Yes, sir!
Get the deserters out to fight!
Take this and follow me!
Don't get lost.
Let's go.
You, get up!
Take this!
Go! Go!
Look what time it is, get up!
Pussy...
Everyone!
Join the fight!
Don't chicken out!
Need me to stuff you in a sack again?
Quick!
Go!
Gun! Take it!
Lei Xiong!
Come smash this wall!
Move quick!
Lei Xiong!
Smash it quickly!
Colonel's order to
strengthen West Wall firing spots.
Understood!
Move faster!
I'll shoot you if you
don't bust it open now!
We need support on the third floor!
Break this wall! Quick!
What are you doing?
Qiyue Brother,
there's a strange car.
Are you tired of living?
Get out of the way!
Mind the grenade!
Keep low!
Sergeant!
Grenades won't work!
We have to use explosives.
Their defence is too strong!
Grenades are bouncing off!
Let's go!
Go!
To the horse stable!
They are ramming the building.
We must eliminate them
as soon as possible!
Here.
Get down Commander!
Get down!
Xiao Hubei, Xiao Hubei!
Are you okay?
- Move!
- Brother!
Be careful!
Brother!
Restock ammunition immediately!
Japanese are attacking!
Faster!
Sergeant!
Fucking Japanese fired cannons!
Medic!
Quick!
You bastards!
Who told you to use cannons?
Shut up!
The Japanese have broken through!
My leg!
Go upstairs!
Grenade!
Mind the grenade!
Raise your rifle!
Suppress the enemy fire!
What are you doing?
Let me go! I'm not fighting the war!
I'm going home!
Go!
We were supposed to fight!
You guys go!
Go around!
Look out for enemy fire!
Continue attack!
Go die!
1st Platoon, quickly
occupy the second floor!
Chinese!
Quick, move the injured!
Medic!
Tourniquet!
Are there more bandages?
Defend the window!
Move!
Go! Let's go!
Go to the East Building!
It's safe there!
Spread out!
Brother, help me.
Fill in the defending position.
Help me.
Brother, save me.
Take up the defence position for me.
They are coming up!
I don't want to die...
They've got the window!
Help!
Aqiu, go!
Hurry!
- Come here!
- Grenade!
Shoot!
Aqiu!
I'm not fighting anymore!
I don't want to die!
2nd Platoon, forward!
Forward!
Go back!
Defend the window!
Shoot!
Move the injured!
Quick!
2nd Platoon, get the ladder!
Keep up the attack!
No retreat!
Attack!
Xiao Hubei!
Get down!
What are you thinking!
You want to get yourself killed?
Horse, The horse!
Halt! Grenades!
Forward!
No retreat!
Halt! Watch out for grenades!
Ask the 3rd and 4th Squads
come support on the West side!
Mind the grenade!
Mirror!
Mirror! Fast!
Be quick!
Hold it up!
Cover them! Cover them!
Quick!
Hurry up!
Sappers!
Hold shield formation!
Cover the shield formation!
Grenades won't work.
Dig faster!
Sergeant!
The steel plates are too thick.
Our weapons can't break through!
They are going to detonate the building.
We're all done if the building explodes!
Give this to my mother!
Chen Shusheng!
Japanese are down there!
Concentrate fire on the target!
Quick!
Explosives in!
Chen Shusheng!
Retreat!
2nd Squadron, retreat temporarily!
3nd Platoon, flank on the left!
Fire!
Reset and ready to attack!
Be careful of suicide attacks!
Shield formation!
Motherfuckers!
Machine gun company fall in!
Blow these son of bitches up!
Tighter! Let me blow
up those motherfuckers!
Tie it!
Strap it on tight!
Thanks, kiddo!
Next!
Their defense is tightening up!
Quick, bomb it open!
Jump!
Hubei Tongxian, Li Mancang!
Next!
Mom and dad, I'm sorry!
Mom!
Next!
Hunan Liuyang, Wang Jindou!
Don't spread out!
Reform!
My name is Zhao Mengliang!
My name is Liu Beiwu!
Hubei Tongcheng, Sun Shoucai!
Get down!
Don't film me.
Mom!
I'm leaving!
Temporarily retreat!
Save the wounded!
Medic!
Reload ammo!
All units, confirm personnel
and equipment present!
Ready for another strike!
If only every Chinese
was as brave as them...
the Japanese wouldn't even dare.
Three hours are up!
The Japanese did not
take over the Sihang Warehouse.
Three hours are up!
The Japanese did not
take over the Sihang Warehouse.
We won!
Three hours are up!
Japanese couldn't win!
Our brothers did it!
Shall I shoot?
Aim at the cable roll.
Roger!
Don't let that wire cross the bridge.
Don't hit the Germans.
Roger!
These kids,
they all have parents...
They all are Zhuanzhu
and Yaoli (assassins).
Last name Qi, first name Heizi.
I'm from Qizhuang Village,
Dongchangfu, Liaocheng.
Give this money to my mom.
I'm from Hefei, Anhui.
My dad is Tang Xiaobing,
my mom is He Fangchao.
Give my mother this money.
There's somebody else!
Let's perform "Tiaohuache" tonight?
"The Battle of Changban",
The seven rounds of battle.
What's happening there?
Let's go take a look.
Get down!
Gunfire!
Don't go there!
Do you want to die?
Don't go further!
You will get shot!
Stop!
Let me off!
They are shooting!
Don't go further!
My name is Wang Hu!
From Taixing, Jiangsu province.
Father, mother, I'm sorry.
Bashu Chamber of Commerce.
Shanghai Branch, Young Daozi.
I've always been a fast runner.
I would like to try!
Daozi, be careful!
He is going to get killed.
Be careful! Don't get up!
This is suicide!
Don't come here!
Get out and help!
Provide cover fire!
Don't get up!
Stay covered!
Don't move!
Don't get up!
Fuck you!
Cover fire!
Grab the phone line!
I'm a teacher at Shanghai
St. John University.
We heard the heroes in the warehouse,
have persevered in
their defence of the city.
I came here to offer help,
I brought some food and medicines.
This is Fang Xingwen,
a journalist from Shanghai News.
Colonel, Chairman is on the phone.
Sir, it's Zhongmin.
Thanks for your help.
We were all watching your heroic acts.
But,
none of us had any idea
about the difficulties you are facing.
There's an urgent lack of morphine here,
you have been holding the ground
for three days now,
every soldier has reached their limit.
In reality,
this kind of resistance
will fail eventually.
Every single soldier's life is precious.
If you continue in this way,
what's the point?
The point?
This is our homeland.
Colonel Xie,
how many soldiers do
we have in the warehouse?
420.
800.
So can I tell the journalists,
that there are 800 heroes?
What are you doing?
Taking photos.
To show the people on the outside,
show the situation in here.
What situation?
Whatever the situation is,
you rich people will
just keep enjoying life as before.
We are all concerned.
The entire country is watching you.
Concerned?
Why aren't they coming over
to help if they're concerned?
Just sitting there watching?
Aside from taking photos
as a pussy journalist,
what else can you do?
I want you to take
my photo, can you?
Journalist Fang!
Has anybody seen journalist Fang?
Having a miscarriage? You little sissy.
What are you crying about?
Brother,
out of everyone in here,
only you struck me as a smart one.
If you can really make it out,
send a message for me.
Badaoligou in Andong city,
mention Lao Tie,
everyone will know.
Tell my son,
his dad was not scared of death.
His dad lived only for him.
Brother, tell me your real name!
Brother!
My name is Old Abacus.
You need to relax, just relax.
That picture,
can you mail it to my family?
Sure.
Give me an address.
Show me how it looks like first.
I can't show you right now,
if I open the back of the camera,
the film will be ruined.
When I get back I still
need to develop the film and...
What's your problem?
Are you idiot?
Got any cigarettes?
Journalist Fang!
Let's go.
Coming.
I knew I couldn't trust you.
Fuck off!
If you dare to escape,
I'll kill you with one shot.
Brother,
want to go together?
Brother.
Brother,
look at my hand.
I can't even pull a trigger.
I can't even hold a gun.
What good am I here?
If I stay,
will it annihilate the Japanese?
I'm just scared,
I'm scared if I die,
then that's it.
Brother, brother!
Brother!
Brother,
you have family?
You got land, right?
Are you married?
They arranged a marriage for me
back in my hometown.
They told me,
my wife is chubby and sweet.
I haven't even seen her yet.
All wars must eventually come to an end.
People must keep on living
no matter what.
I only know calculating.
I don't know how to fight.
There must be someone
fighting the Japanese.
There must be someone defending here.
I admire you all.
You guys are hero.
But, I... I don't...
Brother...
I'm begging you.
I'm begging you, brother.
Leave me a way out.
I'm begging you.
There's enough for everyone!
Give me one!
Why are you moping?
Eat it up!
Once your stomach is
full, you won't miss home.
What?
Scared?
Drink this, then you won't be scared.
Cheers.
I'm not scared.
Bravo!
The warehouse urgently needs
sugar, salt, bread, and water!
We kindly ask everyone to contribute!
Every donation matters!
Stand with our soldiers!
Don't cry!
Stop crying!
What are you throwing that for?
What are you doing here?
- Money from a Russian whore is dirty.
- Eva Li.
My father is Chinese.
She's hybrid, mixed blood.
Enjoying the excitement?
It's all fixed.
Not bad, kid.
We have it too,
it's been over 400 years.
They always perform
the story of Guan Yu.
Why did you pick Zhao Zilong?
The story of Guan Yu
is all about brotherhood.
Zhao Zilong is different.
He protects the country.
Today,
you were really going to jump?
Everyone has their own fate.
My family memorial tablet
was prepared a long time ago.
One, two, go!
It's coming!
Pick it up!
Come on! Capture all of this!
Sergeant!
Journalist Fang,
why are you still here?
What are you recording?
Taking photos.
You're one of those people,
who fights any battle
just for the money.
How are you not dead?
I don't have wife or kids.
I'm on my own.
This money is
all for my mother.
You've never slept with a woman?
Ever touched a woman's breast?
What a pity!
Tell me...
what does it feel like?
Give me a pack of cigarettes,
and I'll tell you the feeling.
Cigarettes!
Cigarettes are my life.
Blood?
What does this say?
I can't read.
It's from the kid who
jumped off the building.
Words from the heart.
The warehouse urgently needs
sugar, salt, bread, and water!
6 o'clock!
Colonel Xie has made an appeal!
Let's go have some sweet rice balls!
Sister Rong's donation.
I'm hit!
Xiao Hubei!
What are you shouting for?
I've been hit!
- I've been hit!
- Let me see.
- Shut up!
- I'm going to die!
- Let me take a look.
I've been shot!
You're fine.
It's just a graze.
You're not dying.
Keep alert!
Done.
Who's outside?
A girl!
Get her up.
There's a sniper across from us.
Thank you!
Go report now!
Report quickly!
We are here.
The red circle is Shanghai.
If I die,
who'd tell you that?
Dumb little kid.
You won't die.
Here.
Shame on you.
She's just a girl,
and she swam across the river.
Last night,
you, a big man,
wanted to swim over there?
This helps with the pain.
Does it hurt?
Brother, you are a hero now.
Does she smell good?
Colonel Xie!
Attention!
Brothers!
Yes, sir!
We have just received the order,
the Brussels Conference is
in session as scheduled.
The government wants
the entire world to know,
that the Chinese troops
haven't been defeated!
The Generalissimo's office ordered us,
to defend two more days at all costs.
The longer we defend,
the better chance we will gain support
from the international community.
- Is that understood?
- Understood!
First, let's thank this
girl for her bravery.
Attention!
However, if we raise this flag,
it will be a great provocation
for the Japanese Army.
They will stop at nothing to destroy us.
They may even use heavy artillery.
If that's the case,
forget about two days.
Holding out for even
a few hours will be a struggle.
What do you say?
Colonel,
our superiors' order is to defend
for two more days.
Shouldn't we postpone the flag-raising?
Colonel, holding
out two more days,
If we give it everything we've got,
we have a chance.
But if we raise the flag tomorrow,
we will be unable
to complete this mission.
In my opinion,
compared to holding out
two more days, raising the flag
will better declare to the
international community our attitude
and our people's will!
Raise the flag!
Let's show these sons of bitches
that we are still here!
This is our home,
why the fuck can't we raise our flag?
Raise it!
Only 2 more days to live anyway,
let's do it!
We will raise the flag tomorrow morning!
If anyone wants to leave
any last words to their family,
let this lady deliver them for us.
One at a time please.
Girl, I can't read!
Write one for me!
Everyone listen up!
In consideration of
your valiance in battle.
The Colonel suggests,
formally incorporating you into
the 524th Battalion,
to form an independent squad,
directly reporting to the division.
He expects that you will
all continue to fight bravely.
Raising that flag is death.
Isn't this asking us to die?
Bullshit!
Whoever doesn't want to be
a part of this, dismiss yourself.
Really?
I'm still young.
I'm leaving.
I'm going back.
I'm going home.
Out of my way! I'm going back.
Stop him!
Get off me!
Medic!
Bandage him!
Lock him up!
Yes, sir!
Is there anyone else who wants to leave?
Let me know!
You used to serve the 33rd Division?
Originally the 36th Division.
Commander Song's men never falter.
You will be the squad leader.
Tomorrow morning,
you lead them to raise the flag.
Can you handle it?
Yes, sir!
Attention!
Colonel!
Apart from the guards,
scouts, and the injured,
all 345 soldiers are here.
At ease!
The Colonel will speak!
Brothers of the 88th Division.
Over there,
are observers from the Western nations.
Behind me,
are our own people.
We are not just here
to fight the Japanese,
but to show them all,
Chinese people are still here.
Chinese soldiers are still standing!
We soldiers have not retreated,
not even one step.
As long as we are here,
They took over the Northeast
and the North China.
But now,
because of you,
Shanghai is still standing!
Yes, sir!
Dimond!
Junior apprentice! Come here!
For our fallen brothers.
Fire!
The Chinese nation will not perish!
Long live the Chinese nation!
The Chinese nation will be victorious!
Long live Colonel Xie!
Long live the Chinese nation!
The Chinese nation shall be victorious!
Colonel,
there's incoming attack from the north.
1st Platoon, execute the plan!
Protect the flag!
Yes, sir!
Move!
Machine Gun Company!
Deploy defence to the north!
- Sergeant Yang! Protect the flag!
- Yes, sir!
Sergeant Yang! I'm staying.
- Head to the turret!
- Yes, sir!
Enter the East building!
Prepare for casualties.
Dispatch soldiers to carry ammunition!
Due South!
2000 metres, target in sight!
Loading armor-piercing projectile!
Six o'clock!
Watch your altitude,
look out for enemy fire.
Aim at the flag.
Get ready!
Come on!
Squad 4 Platoon 5, protect the flag!
Others stand by!
Medic!
Tighten it!
Hurry up!
Remove the cartridge! Fast!
The aircraft is coming!
Run!
Hurry! Go get them!
5th Squad 3rd Platoon, protect the flag!
Others stand by!
The barrel is going to burst!
We're out of water, Sir!
Medic!
Help me!
Die!
I'm speaking to the Japanese military.
You must retreat now!
If you continue to proceed,
we will consider it as an Act of War.
I repeat!
Retreat now!
Brothers keep it up!
Hold it up!
Attention all soldiers!
Obey orders!
Don't make unnecessary sacrifices!
No one attacks
without my order!
Act on my command!
Rescue the injured!
No one is allowed to attack
without my order!
Come and save them!
5th Squad go out and retrieve the injured.
The rest standby.
Quickly!
Help them!
Medic!
Stretchers!
Quickly!
Help!
Move faster!
Save the injured!
This is HQ,
plane number 0917,
the British have already
raised objections.
You'll see!
0917, return immediately.
Medic!
Move the injured away.
They left!
They fled!
Clear the battlefield!
Watch the flagpole.
Brother!
Xiao Hubei.
Don't be scared.
I got you.
Brother!
Didn't we agree,
- when we got to Shanghai...
- Brother!
We would take
a ship to England...
with our uncle,
with my mom.
I miss my mom.
There, there...
Xiao Hubei.
Didn't we agree?
Once we are in Shanghai,
we'd take a photo together.
Take a photo together.
Come over here!
Take a photo.
Stretcher coming!
Take a photo together.
They're singing for us.
The NRA troops have
been beaten in every fight.
Today we finally restored some pride.
Devoting oneself to one's country,
is an honour.
Thanks.
The squad leader is here! Quiet!
- Quiet!
- Make yourself at home.
Sit down everybody.
Get seated.
I've spent half of my life
drifting around,
fighting alongside the army.
The lantern swaying in the wind
and reflecting our broken shadow,
I've put my sword in its sheath
and taken off my armour,
and placed them in the horse stable.
Kiddo!
What are you reading?
A letter.
An officer's letter to his wife.
A love letter?
Read it.
To my dear wife Yuzhi,
I'm heading to Luodian with my squad
to support the troops
as is our duty.
Yet I can't help
worrying about our families, my parents
my young wife and my children.
I can't help worrying.
By being frugal,
you will have adequate
food and clothing.
Out parents are frail,
make sure to look after them.
When our kids grow up,
they shall join the army
to avenge their father.
To devote themselves to their country.
There will be a day,
when our flag,
will fly on the peak of Mount Fuji.
So that our descendants,
won't suffer anymore humiliation.
The restoration of the Han
awaits the younger generation.
An announcement
from the Japanese infantry,
of the 5th Brigade in Shanghai.
Why is there a Japanese
vehicle over there?
What are they shouting about?
It sounds like...
The Japanese want to
meet with our Colonel Xie.
Colonel Xie is riding a white horse,
there's Japanese man in front of him!
Are they really retreating?
I think the NRA won't surrender.
I heard they are pulling out!
That will be great. All
of them can survive.
No.
No, it can't be.
You women,
how can you take about
our heroes in that way?
As if they are not worth a thing!
Watch your mouth!
Move out of the way!
Alright everyone, shut up!
There'll be trouble tonight.
Help me! Give me a hand.
Look! Flare! It's the Japanese!
Flare!
What are all the soldiers
doing outside?
I'm from the Japanese infantry
of the 5th Brigade in Shanghai...
They've come right to our doorstep.
Colonel, just let me kill him.
I'll go.
Colonel! This could be an ambush.
Commander Yang and Shangguan,
if anything goes wrong,
you two take over command.
Colonel.
Colonel, are you really going?
Don't worry.
He's riding a horse,
you're just walking over.
I'm Colonel Konoe Isao
of the Japanese Infantry,
5th Brigade, 68th Regiment.
NRA 88th Division,
524th Regiment, Colonel Xie Jinyuan.
You are quite tenacious!
For the past three months,
you have been
the most admirable opponent.
I understand you have
received order to retreat.
I've also received order
to use heavy artillery tomorrow.
Thus, our battle will
finally come to an end.
Henceforth, people will
no longer pay attention to this battle.
That's none of my business.
It is your business!
After this, there will be a new
commander filling in for me.
I will become a failure.
So,
I'm not here representing the army.
Go on.
Tomorrow, we will have
one last chance to battle.
It is a battle of honour
between you and me.
This is also a fight
between us two men.
There are only a few hours left
before the battle starts.
Brothers!
Get it together!
This is our last fight.
Right now you are laying
your own graves!
Carry those who die first over here.
Kiddo,
you don't even know my name.
88th Division, 524th
Regiment, 1st Battalion,
Qi Jiaming.
Bottom up.
Shangguan,
their bodies are all they have.
Nobody knows who is
going to collect their bodies.
According to our ancient tradition,
before seeing the ancestors in heaven,
they need to be washed.
Boil some water from the river.
Let them clean themselves.
Commissioner,
Colonel is having a migraine.
He sent me down for you.
Instruction from the Generalissimo.
At midnight tonight,
the defenders in Sihang warehouse,
shall evacuate the warehouse
to the British concession.
Here is the order.
October 30th, 1937.
Zhongmin, cheers.
Boil the water,
put in the bucket.
Got it!
Commissioner,
our determination to guard the warehouse
has been passed onto
the Chief by Zhang Boting.
I believe our brave efforts
can gain us international
support at the conference.
The Nine-Power Treaty conference
has been postponed.
Or one could say,
preemptively aborted.
The delegation has already
found out the stance of each nation.
The British and the US
care more about their own interests.
No one is willing to help us.
Shangguan, it's the end.
Just wash up!
Our sacrifices couldn't have
just been a show for the foreigners?
We fought and failed for 3 months.
The NRA stood for
the nation and totally collapsed.
People feel defeated,
soldiers are afraid to fight.
Commissioner, I believe this battle
will reinvigorate the
soldiers' morale and confidence.
So what? The outcome
is a foregone conclusion.
Shanghai will be occupied by the enemy.
If 700,000 NRA failed,
what makes you think
400 of you can succeed?
Xu Jiahui.
Shangguan Zhibiao.
In 1932,
the Japanese also attacked Shanghai.
One gasoline bomb,
wiped out half of a company.
He's considered lucky,
he hung onto his life.
3rd Platoon, 1st Squad...
Look across the bank.
The people's eyes are on us.
Their support for the
resistance against Japan
is getting stronger.
Soon it will fade away.
The passion of these people,
can not change the war.
I don't believe it!
This will leave a mark in history.
These people will be remembered.
Then let's leave it to
the later generations to discuss.
I'll be honest with you.
The Generalissimo
orders you to remain here,
is just a show put on
for the western world.
If your men persevere,
you will not be warriors anymore.
Have you seen the actors
on the boat across the river?
Don't turn this heroic undertaking
into a bigger joke, Zhongmin.
This is how you
all define this battle?
Zhongmin,
the nature of war
is always politics.
3rd Platoon, 7th Squad!
Yes, sir!
7th Squad fall out!
The concessions have
already agreed to take you in.
Retreat.
It's meaningless to keep
on fighting this war.
The little hope you brought
- will eventually become a great desperation.
- Sir, 7th Squad all present!
- Proceed.
- Yes, sir!
If you leave the warehouse,
the glory will be gone,
but at least your soldiers
will survive.
They are all flesh and blood,
they all have parents and siblings.
As a soldier, I wish...
to defend us in this time
of danger for our ancestors.
300,000 soldiers were killed out there!
Now you're telling me
they all have flesh and blood?
All have parents and siblings?
The government thought that
if they stopped the invasion.
There would be room for negotiation.
But the fact is
our military strength
doesn't even come close.
If the war keeps on going,
spreading all over the country
eventually the civilians
will suffer the most.
They will suffer even
more attacks, death and separation.
This country
has gone through enough.
Win or lose,
I just hope this
war can end sooner.
So the civilians can suffer less.
So the nation can suffer less.
Compared to these civilians.
Xie Jinyuan's glory
is not important.
Zhongmin,
the Generalissimo's central army
has been greatly reduced.
Save some of our elites.
When retreating,
don't instigate new battles.
Have the miscellaneous
troops provide cover.
Attention!
Brothers.
The Japanese have
already warned the concessions.
Regardless of the consequences,
they will use all available methods
including heavy artillery.
If the gas tank is ignited,
the concessions will
turn into a sea of fire.
2 million fellow Chinese
will die with us.
Therefore, the superiors
have given the command.
Tonight at midnight,
when the British turn off
the searchlights,
we retreat to the concession.
The British requested us
to retreat via the bridge.
Look sharp and stay organised!
Any soldier who tries to swim across
will not be granted access.
The entire world is watching us.
Keep your chins up!
- Yes, sir!
- This retreat...
needs to be well equipped
and meticulously organized.
So I will be in it with all of you.
In order to get more people out of here,
some people need to stay behind
to cover the retreat.
Who volunteers to stay behind?
Write down your name.
The brother who choose to stay,
- Stay alive.
- We are the forlorn hope
to attack the enemy.
I'll stay.
To buy more time for
our brothers to cross the bridge.
I'm here for vengeance.
It is true that...
we lost this battle.
But why?
Because our nation is sick!
Letting others bully us like this!
We should be asking ourselves
if we've done our best!
I'll stay.
Count me in.
Will you help carry me over there?
Count me in as well.
Can you mail that photo to my hometown?
- I don't want to die.
- I've promised you.
Jinyang County, Shanxi Province,
Zhangkou Village, the Shi carpenters,
it's all for my mother.
I'll take care of it.
And this...
it's from the kid who
jumped off the building.
Brothers of the 88th Division!
Yes, sir!
You are all well-trained,
German equipped forces.
Each of you is one of
this country's most elite soldiers.
You are also
the best medicine for this country.
The 400 of us showed
the people across the river
that there is still hope for China!
In order of squad number, move!
1st Company, 2nd Platoon,
1st Squad, Get ready!
1st Company, 4th Platoon, 5th Squad,
get ready!
These citizens
will be the seed to awaken more people!
Brothers, remember!
You need to survive tonight.
As long as there's one of us alive,
then our glory will never disappear!
Those who survived
will represent us
to join the national counterattack.
For tonight's retreat,
your mission is to survive.
Remember!
Survival is victory!
I learned Guiguzi's tactics
in order to rob graves.
But now we are building graves!
We were digging graves
from the beginning.
You're growing stubble.
Pussy, where are you going?
Pussy, pussy... You're the pussy!
Greasy old fellow!
Pussy,
want cigarettes?
Tell me,
what does it feel like?
Once you lay
your eyes on them,
then your head is dizzy.
When you grab and rub them,
your hand is soaked
in the tenderness.
Tremors softly like water,
and your body just trembles.
So nice...
In my next life...
I'll give it a good try.
Inform all companies,
cross the bridge in groups of twenty.
- We need to be fast.
- Yes, sir.
- Attention all companies!
- Where is Xiao Hubei?
Break into groups of twenty,
charge across the bridge!
We need to be fast!
Attention all companies!
Groups of twenty,
charge across the bridge.
Turn off the lights and
watch out for snipers.
Find cover when the lights go on.
Groups of twenty,
charge across the bridge!
Colonel, my great grandpa
told me when I was a kid.
The Zhu's Empire
was taken over by the Manchus.
None of his descendants fought back.
It wasn't right.
Now the Japanese are here,
I shouldn't run again,
right, Colonel?
Look at the other side.
Just the 400 of us aren't
enough to fight back.
We need to rely on
the 400 million people behind us.
We are going out there to wake them up.
No one knows what this country
will become in the future.
So you need to survive,
grow up well.
When you grow up,
you will be able to see
this country become better.
Pussy, let me send you off?
Sure.
Pussy,
cigarettes are your life.
Brothers.
See you in next life!
Let's go!
Everyone, get ready!
Yes, sir!
Japanese.
Shoot the lights off.
Jun and Lei! Get on it!
Yes, sir!
Flare!
Take cover!
Everyone move inside!
Hurry up!
The Japanese have been waiting for us.
Send one group first.
Draw out the enemies' firing positions.
- I'll lead the squad.
- Colonel, I'll go.
- Colonel!
- Everyone shut up!
Commander Yang will take
over the command, give me the gun!
Yes, sir!
Then charge across
the bridge in squad order.
Each life that makes it
counts, understand?
Understood!
Everyone!
Take cover!
Stand by!
Everyone stand by!
1st Platoon ready!
This letter arrived just in time,
God brought Huang Zhong
a chance to claim victory.
He stands outside of the military
camp shouting out his commands:
All soldiers, listen carefully!
First beat, preparing the food.
Second beat,
tightening up the armours.
Third beat, pulling out the knives.
Fourth beat, starting the battle.
Follow the commands
no matter what,
those who defy orders
will be executed.
Then we will return with victory!
They are standing in positions!
Prepare to attack!
All squads report!
Sir, enemies sighted!
Everyone! Battle position!
Stand still!
Stop there or we will open fire!
Ready!
Fire!
Colonel, the counter-fire has begun!
Charge!
Cross the bridge now!
Don't look back! Run!
Get up! Get up now!
Charge!
2nd group, get ready!
2nd Squad and 3rd Squad are up!
2nd Squad and
3rd Squad, follow me!
Go! Keep up the pace!
Provide cover fire!
Get ready to help!
North! Four shooting points!
Don't shoot at the concession area!
Aim at your target!
Help! Leave no man behind!
Don't get caught up with fight!
Increase firepower!
Don't let them cross the bridge!
There's a firing point to the west!
Take cover!
Anyone who can still move,
keep crawling forward.
Cross even if you have to crawl!
Save me sir!
I'm a soldier from,
Sichuan, the 26th Division!
Keep crawling!
Save them!
I'll go support the Colonel,
I'm leaving the team with you!
Zhang Zhigiang and Jiao
Yousan! Come with me!
Commander Yang!
Fucking Japanese!
Bastards.
Shameless!
Get out of the way!
Morphine
Sister Rong, go ahead!
I'll pick it up!
Kill that officer!
Suppress enemy fire!
Protect the Colonel! Fall out!
All soldiers!
Move forward and fall in!
Wait for my command!
Cover each other!
They are all our compatriots!
Save them!
I can't do this anymore!
Just shoot me!
Let me answer the
question you asked earlier.
No one knows,
how this history will be written.
I don't have faith in today's
political situation either.
But I believe...
our descendants
will remember this place.
Our country,
will remember
everything you did.
Your people
are the true Chinese people.
These are my honest thoughts.
Everyone charge across the bridge!
All soldiers, form two rows!
Don't return fire!
Don't get caught up with fighting!
Assist the injured!
All soldiers!
Charge across the
bridge as fast as possible.
Our fellow people across
the river are watching us.
Be courageous!
Yes, sir!
Wait for my order!
Ready!
Charge!
Transcript by Synchronized