Wow! Bob, take it easy!
- Easy? Where does that get you?
- On dry land, I hope!
It's doing 150 or better.
He's coming in, believe it or not.
Help Miss Daniels off.
- I'm making another run.
- It's not safe out there!
That's why you'll just watch.
- It's starting to kick up, Mr Merrick.
- You keep this engine toned, that's all.
What's wrong with him?
Hasn't he got any brains?
He doesn't have to.
He's got four million bucks.
He must be doing
better than 180 now.
I knew that would happen!
Miss Daniels, phone Emergency right
away! Come on, Joe, hurry up!
- He's starting to breathe, Bill.
- I'll switch off the ventilator.
- That was a close one.
- Bob Merrick just lives right.
- Is that the ambulance?
- Yeah. Nothing more we can do here now.
All right, everybody. There's nothing
to see. You can take off now.
181. Come in, 181. 181, come in.
Go ahead.
Return the resuscitator to Dr Phillips'
home as soon as possible. Emergency.
181. Understood.
They want the resuscitator
right away, Bill.
Leaving assignment now. Victim being
picked up by a hospital ambulance.
- Return the resuscitator...
- Yes, I know.
Returning the resuscitator
to Dr Phillips.
- Did they say why they wanted it?
- Just to rush it back to Dr Phillips' house.
Hurry. Dr Phillips. An accident.
- What's the trouble, Miss Ashford?
- Take it inside to Dr Phillips, Bill.
- Did you see Mrs Phillips' car anywhere?
- No, we didn't.
Oh, I hope they get back in time.
181 reporting.
We're at Dr Phillips'.
Is it too chilly to eat on the terrace? We
could fix the tables with hurricane lamps.
Helen, it's a lot of swank for practically
no reason. You bought out half the town.
Isn't a wedding anniversary
enough reason to have a party?
- Wait till you get married.
- But a six months anniversary?
I've never been married six months before
and I want to tell the world that I love it.
Shouldn't you have
given Dad some hint?
I should say not! He'd have
nine reasons at the hospital
why he couldn't come
home for dinner.
Wayne can invent an emergency
operation at the drop of a hat
if he knows he's to be the guest
of honour at a dinner party.
Now what's the matter?
I was just thinking of the
toast I'd give you two.
To Wayne Phillips, a great surgeon,
a fine man and my wonderful father.
And to you. Love and
affection to my mother.
Mother? Oh, Joyce, you wouldn't.
You married my father. You're certainly
the only mother I've ever known.
And I'm all in favour
of the arrangement.
I sure feel sorry for them.
Oh, Joyce, it's so pleasant. We can have
dinner outside without any trouble at all.
- Helen...
- Nancy, what are you doing over here?
- Oh, Helen...
- What's the matter?
- It's Wayne.
- What?
He's had an accident.
Dr Dodge is with him.
- Where is he?
- Here. Oh, Helen...
Helen...
- Wayne had an attack and...
- No.
Dad!
Those poor girls.
He was such a wonderful man.
He did so much for people.
Why, Dr Dodge? Why?
How many times I've been
asked that question.
I've never learned the answer.
Nancy, you go in with her.
Joyce, I know there's
nothing I can say.
What happened, Derwin?
Nancy and I had come from the hospital
to go sailing with him this afternoon.
He must have had the occlusion just
a few minutes before we got here.
We saw him down at the
pier, all slumped over.
- The resuscitator didn't help at all?
- No. It wasn't here.
- It wasn't here?!
- No.
But Dad's kept it here for years because
he had a coronary. You knew that.
In heaven's name, where was it?
Bob Merrick capsized his boat
at the other end of the lake.
- The police came for it just before this...
- Bob Merrick!
Oh, you don't know him. I do.
He's a stupid, spoilt darn fool.
And now, to think Bob Merrick is
alive because of Dad's resuscitator
and Dad is dead...
I could kill him!
Helen...
I loved him so much, Derwin.
With all my heart.
And we only had these few
short months together.
I don't know how you're supposed to do it.
Just take the barge out and get her up.
Don't bother me with
excuses. Get it done.
When does Campbell
get in from Detroit?
I don't want anybody else touching
those engines. Don't argue.
- If I may take your temperature.
- Nonsense. I'm not even lukewarm.
That's better. And have Jerry call me as
soon as he hears about the insurance.
- Am I getting out of here today?
- The very instant you're able to leave
we shall be happy to
sign your discharge.
- But first...
- This is ridiculous. I'm perfectly healthy.
A small respiratory infection, a slight
concussion, but no subdural clot.
A subdural clot, Doctor, is a haematoma
anywhere in the cranial cavity.
Thank you. I merely wondered where
you acquired that piece of information.
Let me have a line. I was in med
school when my father died.
I haven't wasted all my time.
Why did you quit?
Too rough for a Merrick?
I'll tell you why.
My father died at 42...
Hello. Val?
Who?
No.
Suddenly it seemed sensible to enjoy life
while I could. Let me have another line.
My, how you've succeeded
Hello, Val. How have
you been, baby?
Don't go in, Nancy. You have to make a
formal request to take his temperature.
When I think Dr Phillips died
so that he could live.
Yes. What a complete waste.
- Have you talked to Helen today?
- No. Not since yesterday.
She's coming over this morning to
go through the doctor's things.
You can count on it, baby.
It's a date. Goodbye.
Would you do me a favour? Get Dr Phillips
down here to look at me so I can get out.
- Here.
- Look, I haven't got a temperature.
It's immaterial to me, Mr Merrick,
but I'm going to take your
temperature one way or another.
- A human being.
- Under the tongue, please.
Where have you been all week?
What kind of an establishment
is this? Will you tell me?
I've been here five days and I'm
treated like a leper. No visitors.
- It seemed advisable.
- My doctor doesn't even come.
No, when Dr Albert
talked to Dr Dodge,
he agreed the case didn't warrant his
coming up. He's very busy in New York.
Then why don't I get Wayne Phillips?
It's his hospital, isn't it?
It's obvious I get to pay his bill.
- Don't look shocked. I'm used to it.
- I wasn't shocked, Mr Merrick.
- I was only thinking.
- You were thinking what?
I was thinking, when your father left
you the Merrick Motor Company millions,
what a pity he couldn't also bequeath
you a little common courtesy.
I don't know where you got those
pyjamas, or these cigarettes...
your pharyngitis is bad
enough without them.
In words of one syllable, Mr
Merrick, you talk too much.
Now that's settled, how about getting Doc
Phillips to give me my separation papers?
The reason the staff may have
seemed so distant, Mr Merrick,
is that Dr Phillips
died a few days ago.
It was rather sudden and he was
quite admired by all of us.
- All you had to do was tell me.
- It hasn't been easy to talk about.
When will I get out? I have too
many things to do that can't wait.
I can't say. Perhaps in a few days.
Wanna bet?
Brightwood Hospital.
- Miss Phillips, these came this morning.
- Oh, thanks.
- Is Mrs Phillips in?
- Yes, she is.
They're still coming. Amazing,
isn't it? Oh, I'm sorry.
Yes, thank you. All right,
we'll see you. Goodbye.
That was Tom. He's in the
village and coming over.
He seemed a little more
urgent than he had to be.
I suspect that lawyer of mine just
wanted to spend the afternoon with you.
Dottore Vittorio Laradetti, Rome.
I had no idea there were so many
people who respected Dad so much.
And who felt so much in his debt.
From all over the country.
From all over the world.
Listen to this, Joyce.
"Dear Mrs Dr Phillips, you don't know me,
but I owe everything to Dr Phillips."
Yes, come in.
Sorry, but there's another lady
here to see you. A Mrs Eden.
She says she has to talk to you.
- Want me to talk to her?
- No... Have her come in, Nancy.
- Mrs Eden.
- Thank you.
- Mrs Phillips, Mrs Eden.
- How do you do, my dear?
- How do you do? Won't you sit down?
- Thank you.
We'll have to be very firm
about visitors, for her sake.
Yesterday afternoon there were eight.
This morning it's beginning again.
Apparently Dad had helped
them meet some crisis.
- Money?
- No, not always. Sometimes just advice.
But when you try to pin them down as
to how they became indebted to Dad,
they stammer and dodge, as though they
belonged with him to some secret society.
It's strange.
Dr Phillips insisted
that it be kept secret.
But now that he's dead, I suppose
I can talk about it, don't you?
Certainly.
It came to $4,000 all together,
and I want to pay you back.
Why didn't you return
it to Dr Phillips?
Oh, my dear, I tried so many
times, but he wouldn't take it.
He'd become excited and say,
"You haven't told anyone?"
I'd say, "Of course not.
You told us not to."
Then he'd say, "That's right, Mrs Eden.
Any help I give you is just between us."
- And he wouldn't let you repay it?
- He said he couldn't because...
he'd already used it all up.
And then he'd say to invest it.
"Invest in what?" I'd say.
And he'd say, "Any poor devil."
Wasn't that strange?
Mrs Eden, what did he mean
when he said "used it all up"?
I've tried to think so many times.
Don't you know, Mrs Phillips?
No. It's very odd. In four letters this
week, there's exactly the same expression.
But it is a debt, and I
want to take care of it.
You don't owe me
anything, Mrs Eden.
If Dr Phillips couldn't accept
this, then neither can I.
Well... if that's what you
want, Mrs Phillips, but...
You keep it and use it...
for any poor devil.
All right.
He was a very remarkable
man, wasn't he?
Yes, he was.
Perhaps more remarkable
than any of us knew.
- Hello, darling. How are you?
- Much better now that you're here.
- How's Helen feeling?
- Oh, you know.
- Oh, golly, Tom. I've missed you.
- I've missed you too.
Hello, Tom. Thank you for
coming all this way.
Helen. I wish I'd been able to come
up Sunday, but I've been swamped.
I wanted to talk to both
of you about the estate.
The estate? I hadn't
even thought of it.
Neither had I. I should have
been a better attorney.
I've made a complete survey
of Wayne's finances, and I...
- I doubt you'll have any money at all.
- Not even insurance?
Wayne had a $100,000 policy,
but he borrowed the maximum on it.
- The rest might pay the taxes and debts.
- But what happened, Tom?
But some of Dad's fees...
the Talleyrand operation...
When Wayne removed the neoplasm from
the Talleyrand boy, he received $25,000.
It was all withdrawn within seven weeks
in four cheques, all made out to "cash".
The account's full of cash withdrawals.
Where did all this money go, Helen?
Wayne didn't discuss money with me.
I really wouldn't know.
That leaves you and Joyce with
the house and little else.
And the hospital is liable to
be in very rocky shape too.
Can't something be worked out, Tom?
I want to go over his records and find
out what other assets he might have.
Those you'll let me
collect for you, that is.
And after that, well, we'll
see where you stand exactly.
Well, thank you very much
for all your trouble.
And you do as you feel best.
- Will you excuse me?
- Certainly.
I have to go to the house. The gardener's
confused about what bulbs to lift this fall.
I promised I'd do it.
It can't wait any longer.
I'll see you both at the house.
- Can I help?
- I suspect you could help... tremendously.
Are you all right?
Adequate as can be.
- Going to the village?
- Yes. Can I give you a lift?
You certainly can.
I'll make it. I'll make it.
- What seems to be the trouble?
- Long story. You wouldn't be interested.
You live around here?
Yes.
I should have collapsed on
one of these roads long ago.
- I meant it in the nicest way.
- I'm sure you did.
- You don't sound like it.
- I'm sorry, but I have a lot on my mind.
That's all right. So do I.
Can't we talk about it better
after I take you to lunch?
I think not.
Before you decide I'm just a character
who stumbled out of the woods, Miss P...
Monogram on your purse.
20/20. Always keep 'em open.
My name is Phillips...
Mrs Wayne Phillips.
Oh.
I'm sorry, Mrs Phillips.
You know, I just heard
about your husband.
I'm really sorry. He must have
been a really great person.
It's a rough way to go.
Maybe they'll get another
resuscitator now.
Resuscitator? Did they
try to use one on him?
We'd have had his at the house, but
there was an accident on the lake
and the police took it there.
You mean...
the accident Bob Merrick had?
Yes. Bob Merrick.
So...
Bob Merrick is alive,
and only because your husband...
Let me out up here, will you?
- Thanks.
- Are you sure you're all right?
He can't have just disappeared.
Miss O'Malley, flash Dr Dodge.
All right, thanks.
There's work to do.
Have Dr Dodge report to the
front desk immediately.
- Helen. What's the matter?
- I just gave a man a ride on the lake road.
He's in shock or exhausted.
He's in the car.
Frank, get a stretcher.
It's Bob Merrick.
Who?
Come on. I want you to rest
a little while, Helen.
It's... It just came
before I was ready for it.
I know, darling.
- I'm all right, Nancy.
- Don't talk about it.
Come in and lie down
a little while.
I don't know, Nancy.
Maybe it's just as well.
I'll never have to see him again.
Brightwood Hospital.
Mrs Phillips?
I'm sorry, I can't ring her.
Yes, Mr Merrick?
- Is my bill ready?
- Yes, sir.
Mrs Phillips is in Dr Phillips' office
and she's asked me to hold her calls.
Thank you. I will give Mrs
Phillips your message.
Your bill, Mr Merrick.
You've answered so many questions that
have been puzzling me, Mr Randolph.
Several people in the last few days
have mentioned Wayne's way of life.
And when they talk about "using it all up",
I had no idea what they meant.
I'm so happy that
you could tell me.
You don't talk much
about this belief.
When someone's ready for
it, they accept it.
Perhaps Wayne felt you weren't ready...
or that you were pretty perfect without it.
Well, I must be going.
Wayne mentioned so many times how
anxious he was for me to meet you.
I'm sorry it was under
these circumstances.
I flew up from Mexico as soon as I heard.
I thought possibly I might be able to...
Make it a little easier for me?
Well, you have.
Thank you.
- We'll be seeing you very soon, I hope.
- Yes. I'll be back in my studio now.
Mrs Phillips,
I want to talk to you.
- I'm very busy.
- Oh, I was just leaving.
- Goodbye.
- Goodbye, and thank you.
You and I don't have
anything to talk about.
- I know how you feel about me.
- Please leave me alone.
Your husband was an
eminent surgeon.
Everybody's saying that a character like me
is still around while your husband is...
Here.
- And what is that supposed to do?
- Supposed to do?
Most people'd be
very glad to get it.
Will paying thousands help
you forget it happened?
It's all very simple to you... a cheque
can take care of anything, any time.
Most people would be very
happy to receive $25,000.
Was it my fault? I didn't ask
you for your resuscitator.
Smash up somebody's car,
write out a cheque.
Get in a mess with a showgirl,
And when a man dies, write out a cheque
to his widow... account paid in full.
- Listen...
- Leave me alone!
When you go to Mexico City,
you must hear Rosario.
His voice is just divine.
It does things for me.
Good for you. But he doesn't
sound like my type.
Pardon me.
It's one of the most beautiful
things I've ever seen.
- The owner must have spent a fortune.
- Good for him.
It's got all kinds of gadgets.
It's got... red-spoke wheels...
What did they do to
you in that joint?
I know your big trouble, honey.
You need Val to take care of you.
The principal
difficulty seems to be,
the anaesthetics you get in these bars are
never as effective as the customer hopes.
- What, honey?
- Good night, baby.
- How about a drink, Val?
- No, thank you.
- Don't you want to take me home?
- That's an interesting idea.
I'll call you.
So long and farewell.
- Yes?
- I'm sorry to bother you this time of night.
I just clobbered my car
in the ditch. Look.
That's all right. Come in.
Thank you for your hospitality.
It's a nice place you have here.
A very nice place indeed.
- Are you all right?
- Me? Of course.
It takes more than pranging up a car
to incapacitate old Bob Merrick,
pride of the Merrick clan.
You're Bob Merrick, eh?
- Who are you?
- Edward Randolph.
- How do you... Who?
- It's all right. I live here.
Edward... may I please bother you...
for a telephone, please?
- Of course.
- Wait a minute.
Gotta call somebody to
come and pick me up.
- Must tell 'em to wear their safety belts.
- Right back here.
- Where?
Oh.
Go slow.
Hello?
Hello there.
- Ed, did you do these pictures?
- Yes.
Nice.
As far as I'm concerned,
Art is just a guy's name.
- Williams?
- Shouldn't you dial?
Shh! Williams.
This is Robert Merrick Esquire.
I had a little trouble with my car. Would
you come over and pick me up, please?
Williams?
Don't snore, old man. Wake up.
Hardest thing these days,
getting good help.
Very nice job.
Where have we met? Don't tell
me, don't tell me. I met you...
- Is that?
- It's a portrait I did of Wayne Phillips.
Phillips.
He's the man who's haunting me.
You know what?
I almost drowned, but a resuscitator
saved me. Whose is it? Dr Phillips'.
They shoot me to a hospital to make old
Merrick good for another 20,000 miles.
Whose hospital? Dr Phillips'.
Then I meet her. A girl.
A girl who is...
a very beautiful girl.
Whose wife is she? One guess, pal.
- Now look here, Merrick...
- Tell me where we've met.
In the hospital.
In Dr Phillips' office.
Dr Phillips.
You see?
He is haunting me.
- I'm glad you made it.
- I'm not sure I have.
Try this anyway.
Do you mind telling
me what happened?
Oh... I wrecked the
car, in a ditch.
Yes. The right front wheel. I called your
house and asked someone to come over.
- I hope you don't mind.
- Not at all.
- Think a shower'd help?
- I certainly do.
Make it a cold one. Up those
stairs and to the right.
Thanks a lot.
I hope I wasn't too much
trouble last night.
When I pass out, I usually
like to be in my own bed.
No trouble.
Oh, I know where I saw you.
With Helen Phillips.
That's right, Merrick.
Will you take these?
- Have you known her long?
- No.
But Wayne Phillips was
the best friend I had.
Coffee's ready.
Yes, the portrait you did of him.
It's really good.
You're quite a painter.
Well, maybe I am now.
If so, I have Phillips to thank. He's
the one who unlocked everything.
- Phillips did?
- Yes. I met him some years ago
when I was still trying to find my
way in painting, getting nowhere.
I spent my life making fairly
adequate copies of the masters.
I always wanted to
create like they did.
But I just never could.
Until Phillips showed me
how to get what I wanted.
How did he do that?
How could a surgeon help?
Well, he taught me...
He showed me how to establish contact
with a source of infinite power.
That sounds fine.
What does it mean?
Well, let me put it this way.
This lamp isn't working now.
It's cold, and it's dark. All the parts
are there, it's a perfect light, but...
- It's just not turned on.
- Right.
But if I turn the switch
and establish contact,
the bulb will draw power
from the powerhouse
and it'll do what it was meant
to do, which is to make light.
So you're saying that people
have a sort of powerhouse too.
Establish contact with that and you
can do what you're meant to do.
- You can fulfil your destiny.
- I can turn on a light.
I don't think that's your destiny.
- Do you?
- No, I guess not.
Assuming there is a power of some kind,
how do you establish contact with it?
It's very simple: Just be
of real service to people.
Find people who need
help, and help them.
But always in secret.
Never let it be known.
And never ask to be repaid.
But why does it have
to be kept secret?
That's probably the most
important part of this belief.
Let's go back to the powerhouse.
If the wires in the dynamo are
not protected by insulation,
the power will be dissipated.
The same goes for us.
Most personalities are just grounded.
That's all that ails them.
I see. You mean keeping
these good deeds secret
is like insulating the
power of your personality.
- Yeah, that's near enough.
- If it works, fine. Obviously it helped you.
Isn't there anything in
the world that you need
that you haven't been able
to get in the ordinary way?
Not a thing.
Except...
I'd like to square myself
with Helen Phillips.
Oh?
But if I just help out some poor joker, why
does it follow that she'll listen to me?
I think you might be
surprised at what follows
after trying this way of life.
Well, if it's as simple as all that,
why, I'll certainly give it a chance.
Wait, Merrick.
Don't try this unless you're ready. You
can't just try it for a week like a new car.
And if you think you can feather your
own nest with it, just forget it.
Besides, this is dangerous stuff.
One of the first men who used it
went to the cross at the age of 33.
Excuse me.
- Won't you come in, please?
- I understand that Mr Merrick...
- I'm here, Williams.
- Good morning, Mr Merrick.
Well, goodbye. And thanks. You take
good care of a drunk and his hangover.
I ought to know how by this time.
I've been there myself.
Mr Merrick! It's good to
see you around again.
Hello, Dan.
No. Another look you owe me.
- How's the family?
- Not so hot. We lost the baby, you know.
- Oh?
- The missus is still in the hospital.
- The bills are pretty rough.
- I'm sorry to hear it, Dan.
- Say, Dan.
- Yes, Mr Merrick?
How much do you need
for all the expenses?
About $300 would do it.
- Mr Merrick...
- It's yours. On two conditions.
- Anything.
- Don't tell anybody.
- I've got to tell my wife.
- No, not even your wife.
And never try to pay it back.
I don't want it.
- Anything you say.
- Good.
But this is sure a funny way
to help a guy out, isn't it?
I think you're absolutely right.
- I don't believe it!
- Your order, Mr Merrick?
It does work.
Thank you, Phyllis. Joyce and I will see
you again soon. We won't hibernate.
- I'm glad of that.
- Goodbye.
Mrs Phillips. This is more than just a
coincidence. I've got to talk to you.
- I was just leaving.
- You have two minutes, haven't you?
Perhaps I wasn't as diplomatic as I could
have been, but I did mean well, really.
We've all been under a strain. Sorry
if I said anything I shouldn't have.
What I can't understand is how we've
avoided knowing each other before this.
It wasn't intentional,
I assure you.
I think we ought to correct
that mistake. Don't you?
Of course. I'm very late.
Mrs Phillips.
We haven't decided where we're
going to have dinner tonight.
I have a previous engagement.
Excuse me.
Please don't go!
I'd like to ask you... about
this theory of Dr Phillips'
that Edward Randolph
was telling me about.
- Why would he talk to you about it?
- I guess he believes in it.
I guess I'm starting to,
after meeting you here.
What has meeting me
got to do with it?
Well, I... I just did something.
I'm going to go find somebody that
needs a couple of thousand bucks
and my worries will be over.
I think you've twisted my husband's
beliefs into something very cheap.
Taxi!
Wait a minute!
- 15 Lake Drive, please.
- Mrs Phillips.
- I wouldn't offend you for the world.
- Just drive on.
- Wait here. Mrs Phillips...
- Please don't start a scene.
I'm only trying to tell you that...
Look out!
Brightwood Hospital.
The line is busy. Will you hold?
I'll try to locate him for you.
Brightwood Hospital.
I'll take a message.
I can connect you now.
Brightwood Hospital.
- Is there any chance at all?
- No.
How about the x-ray findings?
They leave no hope.
She's lucky to be alive.
Will you tell them, Nancy?
- All right.
- Thank you.
Miss Ashford...
Joyce.
She's going to live.
And she'll be all right in time?
Not completely. There's
an inoperable lesion.
- What is it?
- Where?
Well... Her eyes.
Tell me, Nancy.
Let me have it straight.
She'll be blind.
- Blind?
- It can't be.
Oh, no!
- Miss Ashford, could I see her?
- Haven't you done enough?!
- Joyce...
- It's the truth. Why shouldn't I say it?
She'll never see again, thanks to you.
Write a cheque for that, Mr Merrick!
No, Nancy. No.
Darling, don't you think if
you just talk to him once...
What good would it do?
What could he possibly say?
And what difference
would it make now?
I don't blame him for
anything, Nancy.
It's just that I feel it's better
if I don't see him at all.
Well... I'll send him away.
I'm sorry, Mr Merrick.
She won't see you.
Nancy?
Yes, darling.
I know I'm right.
He'll finally give up.
- Your things are on the beach, Helen.
- Thank you, Nancy.
- Is Judy there?
- Yes. She's waiting for us.
- Call me when you're ready to go down.
- I will.
- Some more tea, Helen?
- Yes, thank you.
- Is Nancy staying with you?
- No.
She comes and takes me down
to the beach, picks me up later,
whenever she can get
away from the hospital.
- I'm going to miss you terribly, Ed.
- Well, I hate to say goodbye.
But I've refused the
gallery so many times,
and I do have to be in Chicago
at least once this year.
You've been wonderful all these months,
and I apologise for being a handful.
Uh-uh, Helen. Quiet.
Well, I'd have thrown me in the
drink if I were me. Thank you.
But, Ed, I get so tired of
learning how to eat and dressing
and finding out where
the heck things are.
I get so tense, and then I'm
a problem to everybody.
Of course you have to have
people around to help you.
So do several geniuses
that I could mention.
But you're such a good friend.
- And don't forget that.
- No.
Sorry I had to miss Joyce.
Say goodbye for me.
Yes, I will. She's in town. It's
about that accident insurance.
Thank goodness for that.
It's kept us going.
Well, goodbye.
You'll be hearing from me.
God bless you.
- I'll get Nancy.
- No, not yet.
Where's my radar?
No, no, no. As a farewell present for
you, I'm going to try something.
For the first time, in your honour,
down to the cove all by myself.
- But you've never gone down there alone.
- Well, it's about time I start.
- I'd better go partway with you.
- Oh, no. Just stay and watch.
I know these steps by heart.
One...
two...
three...
Helen?
Where did Helen go?
- That's progress for you.
- It's remarkable!
Judy!
Hi, Helen!
Say, what do you know!
- You started exploring by yourself!
- How about that!
- I'm sorry I'm late, Judy.
- Me too. I gotta get back early.
I thought you weren't coming, so I
went ahead and read the whole chapter.
Serves me right for being late.
What happened?
Well, old Huckleberry's on
this crazy raft with Jim,
and they run into this
old, deserted houseboat.
- Huck... Here's a step.
- Oh. Thank you.
One, two, three, four, five steps.
Now let's see.
Where was I? Oh, yes.
Huck thinks maybe they
can scrounge something,
so he starts to investigate in
all this dirt and disorder.
He opens this door and finds two fellas
talking in a very rough fashion.
Well, here we are.
Take it easy, now.
These characters are
very hostile indeed.
And?
Tune in tomorrow,
same time, same station.
Shall do.
What's going on out
on the lake, Judy?
Oh, I'd say there's
about a ten-knot blow,
and about a half-dozen
snipes having a race.
And a couple of stars foolin'
around by the yacht club.
And a real gone daddy zoomin'
around with his inboard.
Aw, some babe's water-skiing.
Not so hot. She's usin' both hands.
- Sounds like a big day.
- Yeah!
Hate to rush, Helen, but OK
if I do the newspaper now?
Sure. But what's the hurry?
Mother stuck me with Susan
Shacker's birthday party.
Can you imagine me in a dress?
Well... In Europe,
things aren't so hot.
In the Pacific,
And in Washington...
If you want to know my opinion,
things are pretty fouled up all over.
Page 3. Here's a girdle and bra ad... which
I won't be needing for quite a while.
I'm a dog to run off, I know. But what
can you do with parents, eh, Helen?
Nothing, I guess. But we'll
be together tomorrow.
Sure. Want me to
take you back up?
No, I think I'll sit here for
a while. I'm all right.
OK. You're a big girl now.
- See you!
- Bye.
Hey, handsome!
Yeah, you, Tarzan!
I'm stuck! Wanna help
me launch my boat?
A girl's in real tough shape when she's
got no figure and no muscles either.
Thanks! Stick around!
I think we can use you!
Bye, Helen!
Goodbye!
Thank you for your help.
Sure.
I didn't know anyone else was here.
Do you come to the cove often?
Well... lately a little.
I've noticed you and
Judy a few times.
Well, I'm Mrs Phillips.
And I hope any friend of
Judy's is a friend of mine.
How do you do, Mrs Phillips?
- And you're?
- Rob... My name's Robinson.
Well, you know, it's a bit
chillier than I thought.
Oh, dear. I'm sorry, but would you
help me find my shawl? I don't see.
Of course.
I'm very awkward, I guess, but
Judy's a wonderful builder-upper.
I don't think anybody could come
through any better than you have.
- With a subdural haematoma like yours...
- That's where I met you. At the hospital.
- You're a doctor.
- No. We've never met.
I know a little about medicine.
I studied to be a surgeon once.
- But I have heard your voice, haven't I?
- I don't think so, Mrs Phillips.
- Is there anything else I can do?
- No, thank you. I'm very comfortable.
Mrs Phillips, I wonder...
Would it be all right if
I came by occasionally?
Just for launching outboards
and general morale purposes?
- I hope I'm not imposing.
- Of course not.
We'll hope to see you
again very soon.
Yes. Soon.
- Goodbye.
I hope that I've been able
to make myself clear.
What you say you want to do is the
best news that anyone could tell me.
But I warn you, the investment
of one's life in others
and the alignment of oneself with
the forces that lead up and on,
- this does not come cheap.
- I don't expect it to be.
Once you go into it, you're bound.
You'll never be able to give it up.
You'll find this furnishes your
motive power. It will obsess you.
But, believe me, it'll be
a magnificent obsession.
- Thank you, Williams.
- A Mr Masterson is here.
- Any mail?
- Yes, sir. On your desk.
- Sorry I'm late.
- I haven't waited long.
- Cigarette?
- Yes. Thank you.
How are plans developing?
I made the last deposit to
Mrs Phillips' account today.
Sit down.
That completes the
amount you wanted paid.
- Good. Any problems?
- No, but...
Joyce asked some very
pertinent questions.
It is a lot of money. But they're
both convinced it was insurance.
- You haven't mentioned this to anyone?
- No.
Good.
- You don't approve of me, do you?
- Well, I...
Perkins and Little have been the
Merrick attorneys for years.
So I thought it strange
you called me last month.
That's why. Nobody would suspect anything
from you as originating with me.
And you can start practising some more,
because here comes a high, fast one.
I talked to Dr Giraud
at the medical centre.
- The brain man?
- Yes. Best diagnostician in the country.
I once studied with him.
He says there's some chance...
a very, very small chance...
that Helen Phillips' prognosis
may not be hopeless.
Really?
He says if doctors like Emil Hofer in
Zrich, Fuss in Vienna, Lehman in Munich
could be persuaded to take her case, they
might be able to devise a way to operate.
But you couldn't get them all
over here in a million years.
We could get her over there. Hofer won't
leave Zrich, so it has to be Switzerland.
Today Dr Giraud heard from Fuss. He
and Lehman could be there this spring
for periodic consultations.
They're willing to tell her they're taking
the case as a gesture to her late husband.
You get all kinds of people to do
what you want, don't you, Merrick?
That's fine, but... the expense. Somebody
will have to be with her all those months.
Persuade her and Joyce
to sell the house.
Who'd buy it?
I know somebody who needs a
place exactly like that.
He'll pay what some people might
think is a lot more than it's worth.
Think it over. Figure out the best
way to present it all to her.
Of course, don't let anyone
know about this either.
- No one.
- No, of course not.
Um... What are you going
to do with the house?
I don't want any part of it.
You'll find a worthy use for it.
Merrick, I, uh...
I take back a lot of things
I thought about you.
That's nice of you to say so.
- What's all this?
- False knots.
One of the first things
you learn in med school.
You are wrapped up in this. Well,
goodbye. I'll be talking to you.
Thanks. I'll find my way out.
What you're asking is to change your manner
of living... which is your business...
but also to pick up a
career which you dropped.
Probably the most demanding
career you could choose.
If you don't go on this time, we've tied
up good people and priceless facilities...
- which is my business.
- I'm still asking it.
If I can go back and graduate, will you
let me intern here at the medical centre?
All right, Bob Merrick.
We'll try it.
I've done a lot of things in medicine
I was warned were impossible.
You won't regret it.
When you studied with me years ago,
why weren't you so enthusiastic?
- What a lot of time you've wasted!
- Yes, what a lot of time.
Thank you, Doctor.
The marshal gets on his white horse
and rides off with Wise Eagle.
The marshal says, "Wise Eagle, ya reckon
them varmints'll head through the pass?"
- Wise Eagle says...
- "Ug!"
The marshal says, "We gotta
head 'em off. Come on."
Next picture's the sheriff's office.
The marshal says:
"Sheriff, what idea you got in that ornery
head of yours to stop them desperadoes?"
The sheriff says...
"Marshal, I don't like using shootin'
irons, but if I gotta use shootin' irons,
I tell you, there ain't no
hombre this side of the Pecos
is any better with shootin'
irons, less'n it's you."
And Wise Eagle says...
Oh. "Ug!"
We're gettin' better!
Listen, you two. Forget about the funnies.
I can't keep quiet any longer.
- Silence, Judith.
- OK, Helen. Shoot.
First of all, some of the best eye
doctors in Europe are interested in me,
because of my husband, I guess.
They want me to come
over for a consultation.
- Helen, I couldn't be happier.
- Gee, that's marvellous! For free?
Practically. But not the trip itself...
that's the other good news.
So many wonderful
things have happened.
We have the most fabulous offer for
the house and the lake frontage.
Enough for an income
for Joyce and me.
If the buyer takes the Brightwood acreage,
the hospital will be in good shape too.
It's about time your life turned.
It's ironic... I've never been to Europe,
and when I go, I won't be able to see it.
But what a place to open your eyes.
I have to leave by the end of
the month for Switzerland.
I'll miss you two, for a long time.
Heck, Helen. I'll write.
Switzerland sounds dreamy! You can get
a Swiss watch and learn to yodel!
She's practically lived on the beach.
This Robinson must be a dreamboat.
- Haven't you met him yet?
- She's keeping him all to herself.
I think it's wonderful. It looks as if
they really mean a lot to each other.
You know, it's very strange
knowing you only like this.
So well, it seems, and yet...
I've never seen your face.
- Hi, Joyce!
- Hi, Judy!
- Any room left on the beach for us?
- Sure. You kiddin'?
Helen, the news sounds just wonderful,
but I'm afraid I have to go.
Oh, no. No, don't go. It's Joyce, and
now you'll have a chance to meet her.
Joyce!
Happy Sunday, Helen.
Joyce dragged me along.
At long last, everybody. This is
Joyce Phillips, Tom Masterson,
and this is Robbie Robinson I've
been telling you so much about.
- Hello.
- How do you do, Mr... Robinson?
How do you do?
I'm sorry. I'm just on my way to the
village. I'm glad to have met you.
Don't forget tomorrow.
Goodbye, Helen.
Goodbye.
- Mr Robinson!
- Joyce!
Could I ask you a favour?
- Tom!
- Yes, Helen?
- Tom, what's wrong?
- Why, nothing, Helen.
- What is this?
- Look, Joyce, you don't understand.
I sure don't. Hasn't she had enough trouble
from you without this fantastic lie?
Believe me, I'm only trying to make
her life a little less lonely.
Fine. Wouldn't it be wonderful for her to
fall in love with someone named Robinson
and then open her eyes
and see that it's you?
That would make us all glad
we're living, wouldn't it?
Get out, Merrick. Get out
of her life and stay out.
So long, pardner!
- Goodbye, Helen.
- Goodbye, Tom.
Come on, Helen.
- Goodbye, Nancy.
Hurry up, Joyce.
I love you, darling.
I'm coming.
- Bye, darling.
- Goodbye, dear.
Hello, Merrick.
Everything's going to be all right.
Now, Mrs Phillips, tell me
if you see a little light.
Do you?
No.
Do you notice a light now?
No, I'm sorry, gentlemen.
Mrs Phillips, do you
have headaches?
Yes.
Constantly, or periodically?
- Periodically.
- Mm-hm.
Where?
In the back of my head.
Any dizzy spells?
Occasionally.
Difficulties in walking?
No... No.
Well, I think that
does it for today.
Well, Doctors? What's the verdict?
You must be patient, Mrs
Phillips, you know.
There are tests and tests.
We are making progress.
But I did distinguish some light yesterday,
and it was the same test, wasn't it?
What does it mean?
If you can bear with us, madame,
in time we'll find out.
Oh, I don't know how
they dare call this tea.
Back home it'd be a
six-course lunch.
Why did I ever memorise
that calorie chart?
I'm glad that's finished. Now I'm
only three letters behind Tom.
- Want some tea, dear?
- Yes, thank you, Nancy.
- Joyce?
- Yes?
I'd like to send a note to Robbie Robinson,
if it wouldn't be too much trouble.
Well, no.
- Aren't you tired? It can wait, can't it?
- You should rest and relax,
- not worry about your social obligations.
- It's no obligation. He'll be interested.
And I want it to make the next
plane... just a note, Joyce.
And you can say...
that the tests have started
and we're all very optimistic.
And, uh... tell him
that I miss him...
and to say hello to Judy...
and the only part of Switzerland that
we've encountered is a hospital.
is a hospital.
How do you explain it, Doctor? Her letter
sounds so optimistic, yet your reports...
Now, now, Bob. How long has
she been there? A few weeks?
Only Fuss and Hofer
have seen her so far.
Naturally their reports to us
are going to sound cautious.
Cautious? I'd say they
were pessimistic.
Don't worry so much. Everything which
can be done for her is being done.
I know.
After all, we never anticipated more
than a medical possibility, did we?
A medical possibility.
Mrs Phillips! Good morning.
- You're Dr Fuss?
- Yes. Dr Fuss.
- Please, sit down, Mrs Phillips.
- Oh, and you're Dr Hofer.
- Jawohl.
- Good morning, madame.
- And you're Dr Lehman.
- You're right.
You see? I'm beginning
to recognise all of you.
Well, at long last, the great day.
I want you to know that
I've shot the works, too.
That's American slang. That
means a new dress, a new hat...
Now I want to know when you're going
to make a new girl out of me.
Mrs Phillips, you have been close
to medicine for a few years.
You know the relationship
of doctor and patient.
You know that there is very little to
be gained by not facing the facts.
Why, of course.
By all means, face the facts.
What are they?
We are very sorry, Mrs Phillips,
but we are agreed that, for the
present, we can do nothing.
No operation?
- Nothing?
- We've searched every avenue, I believe.
That's not to say there is no hope.
In a case like yours, after
several years sometimes...
Several years, Doctor?!
We feel that it would be unwise and
unkind to submit you to surgery now.
But you know that I'll let you experiment
if there's any chance at all...
the longest chance in the world.
We regret to say, but the
indications are not there.
Oh.
Well, if the indications
aren't there, then...
I guess that's that.
You've done everything
that you could.
It was a gamble.
We all knew that it was
a gamble and I just...
well, I just lost, that's all.
But... I want to thank you.
I want to thank you for
being so kind to me and...
and giving me all your time.
I really can't thank you enough.
- Goodbye.
- And...
- Goodbye, Mrs Phillips.
The last must be Dr Lehman.
My child...
I am so sorry.
Well, I... I thought I was
going to get rid of these.
Isn't it nice that... that
I didn't throw them away?
She's sound asleep.
What has she done that
all this happens to her?
Golly. How she took it today...
I don't know how she stands
up under everything.
If it happened to me, I'd go to pot
in a handbasket. I think I'd even...
I'm proud of you, Joyce.
It hasn't been an easy
year for you either.
Well, I'll go get these drops and
this new prescription filled.
- Nancy, do me a favour.
- Of course. What?
Stay away from here for a while
and relax yourself for a change.
All right. I do need some fresh air.
I'll be back in an hour.
- Darling. I thought you were asleep.
- I heard the door. Was it Nancy?
Yes. She went out for a while. I can get
you one of your pills and some hot milk.
Joyce, I don't need any sleep.
Oh, yes, I do too.
It's so awful in bed.
It's funny, but... the
night-time is the worst time.
It does get darker, you know.
And then, when I finally
do get to sleep,
I know that, when I wake up in the
morning, there won't be any dawn.
Joyce...
Joyce, forgive me.
I didn't mean to
parade my emotions.
Maybe I do need a pill.
Would you mind getting
me some warm milk?
Of course not.
Just sit down here.
I'll only be gone a moment.
I'll just go down to the hotel
kitchen and warm some milk.
- Are you all right?
- Yes, dear, I'm all right.
Joyce?
No.
It's Rob.
Rob?
Oh, I can't believe it.
- It's been so long.
- Much too long.
When you didn't come to the plane,
and you hardly wrote all these months...
Oh, I'm so glad you're here!
You must have known how
much I need you now.
Darling.
Robbie, my trip has been wasted.
- I found out today my case is hopeless.
- Don't talk about it.
I came to tell you you're gonna
have the time of your life with me.
I'll take you all the places you've been too
busy to visit, show you how to have fun.
- But I'll be such trouble.
- Listen, Helen.
You used to let me read you the funnies.
Let me be your eyes again.
Now get dressed. Something
to bowl everybody ever.
I'm not only gonna show you the town,
I'm gonna show the town you.
Oh, Robbie.
Joyce?
Yes, Helen?
Look who's here. Robbie Robinson.
It's like Old Home Week.
This is a surprise.
- Hello.
We're gonna get dressed up to the teeth.
I'm going to initiate that new net dress.
Joyce, will you please
come and help me?
Oh!
Oh, I'm all right.
I won't be very long.
- I'll be back in just a moment, Helen.
- All right, Joyce.
Bob Merrick, I...
I want to apologise.
You? For what?
That girl you just saw is quite a
change from the girl this afternoon.
They told her she's
never going to see.
I know. I just came
from the institute.
They've been keeping
in touch with me.
Anybody that can do what you've
done for her is OK with me.
I never believed names
were too important anyway.
- Joyce!
- Coming!
It's wonderful being with you.
I don't want it to end, ever.
Let's not think of it.
Tonight is our night.
Yes, tonight is our night.
Oh, and the fragrance
in the air... What is it?
- Lilacs?
- Mm-hm.
And there's a moon...
as there should be.
Oh, and just ahead there's
lights of a little old town.
Just as there should be.
Excuse me a second, darling.
- Ich nehme diesen hier.
- Danke.
I thought you might like these.
- Lilacs?
- Mm-hm. For luck.
And more lilacs.
What's going on?
Let's find out.
Wenn ich das erklren darf?
- Das ist ein lokales Volksfest.
- It's a local festival.
- Man verbrennt die Hexe.
- They're burning a witch.
- Damit wir eine gute Ernte haben.
- For a good harvest.
- Mit Musik und Feuerwerk.
- With music and fireworks.
There she is, darling. Way up on top of
a pile of branches about 20 feet high.
Poor old gal's stuffed with straw,
just like our scarecrows back home.
And on the ground just below her, boys
and girls in peasant dress are dancing.
Now they're setting fire to her.
There she goes.
Fireworks bursting
all over the place.
- Now everybody's starting to dance.
- I'd like to dance too.
You would?
I always dance with my
eyes closed anyway.
- I won't tell you what time it is.
- I don't want it to stop.
I don't want to lose this place,
or the music, or the night.
You don't have to lose it.
I'd forgotten how happy I could be.
You've helped me know that the world
isn't such a bad place after all.
- You don't hate it any more?
- Not any more.
Could you... forgive anything now?
I think so.
Yes.
Even... Bob Merrick?
Why...
Yes, Bob.
Of course.
How long have you known?
I don't really remember when I first had
the feeling that... Does it really matter?
I love you, and I
want to marry you.
Darling, if we only could.
But I couldn't have you pitied
because of me. I love you too much.
- Helen, I need you more than anything.
- Bob... Tomorrow.
Let me tell you tomorrow.
All right.
Starting tomorrow,
we'll never be apart.
Tomorrow.
Well... it's really
good night this time.
Oh, I wish it weren't.
There's a brand-new
day in a few hours.
Even better.
Nothing could be better, darling.
I love you.
Oh, Bob.
Oh. The key.
The key.
Helen!
- Did you have a good time?
- A wonderful time.
How pretty.
- Good night.
- I'll see you in the morning.
- Yes.
- Good night.
- Good night, Nancy.
I'll take the flowers, Helen.
Oh, they're so pretty.
It was too wonderful, Nancy.
He wants to do so much for me.
Helen, what's the matter?
He wants to marry me, Nancy.
I love him. I can't let him do it.
- Well, if you love him and he loves you...
- I don't know. I don't know.
I don't know anything any more.
- Nancy, please don't leave me.
- Of course I won't.
You've got to help me.
Helen?
Nancy?
Where is everybody?
Hello?
Oh, yes, please. Have him come up.
Helen, Rob...
Hello? Get me the desk, please.
Come in.
I see.
Good morning. Couldn't order
a better day if we tried.
Thank you. Thank you very much.
Is Helen dressed? I hope
you're not allergic to lilacs.
Bob... What happened
to you two last night?
- Did you tell her who you were?
- Yes. But she knew anyway. Joyce...
I, uh... I asked her to marry me.
Oh, Bob.
- She's gone.
- She's?
- Where?
- I don't know.
Away with Nancy,
early this morning.
Oh, here. She left
this note for you.
"Dear Bob. Goodbye."
"I'm sure this is
best for both of us."
"You have your study and work now,
and I could only be a burden."
"If you love me,
don't try to find me."
"Just know you made me happier than
I dreamed I could ever be again. Helen."
I phoned downstairs. Nobody
knows where she went.
- We've got to go after her.
- But, Bob...
We'll talk about it on the way.
We've got to find her.
Miss Phillips, Mr Merrick, we are
doing everything to trace them...
as are the police all over Europe.
But from Milano... nothing to report.
Paris... no findings. Rome... nothing.
You'd think in five weeks we'd
be able to find some trace.
I am truly sorry, sir.
But, you know,
even in your country,
if someone really wants to
disappear, it is not too difficult.
- However, we shall not give up.
- Thank you, Captain. Goodbye.
I know what a sense of loss and
disappointment you both have,
but look at these telegrams.
Our Inter-Europa Agency has
tried everything, I assure you.
Da ist ein Telegramm fr mich?
Dankeschn.
We have exhausted
all possibilities.
Inter-Europa.
Oui, madame. Lundi,
cinq... Exactement.
Pas de quoi, madame.
But we will be in touch
with our New York people.
And I will keep on the lookout here
for the two of them booking
passage to America.
Here are your tickets.
Bon voyage. Have a nice trip.
It was a pleasure serving you.
Darling, you're home.
Oh, am I glad to see you!
- Welcome home, Bob.
- Hello, Tom. Good to see you.
- Nothing? No trace?
- None.
She must come back to the States.
Sooner or later they'll get in touch.
- Strange how things work out, isn't it?
- Yeah, strange.
What are your plans?
I don't know. I guess I'll...
go up to Brightwood for a while.
The marshal gets on his white horse
and rides off with Wise Eagle.
The marshal says, "Wise Eagle, ya reckon
them varmints'll head through the pass?"
- Wise Eagle says...
- "Ug"
- Mr Merrick?
- Yes.
Mr Randolph had to leave
Brightwood for a few months.
Will you excuse me? I just came
over to close up the house.
Yes, certainly.
Once you go into it, you're bound.
You'll never give it up.
You'll find it'll furnish your motive
power. It will obsess you.
But, believe me, it'll be
a magnificent obsession.
- Chris, here's Doctor.
- Dr Merrick!
- All ready to leave us, Chris?
- All set.
- Good!
- I wanna show you something.
Oh. All right.
Look at me.
Not dizzy or anything. You
sure know how to operate!
Dr Barnes had more to
do with it than I did.
Now I can go to that new school out in
the country. They got horses and dogs.
That's just fine. Goodbye, Chris.
Just a minute, Doctor. Chris,
I want to talk to Doctor a minute.
Dr Merrick, you've
been wonderful to us.
Not just here in the hospital.
You arranged that school for Chris,
and my husband's job at the plant.
- You haven't told him that I?
- No. That's just between us, like you said.
But in a few years, when Chris
understands about money...
No, Mrs Miller. I told you
there's nothing to repay.
In a few years it'll
be all used up anyway.
- All used up?
- That's right, Mrs Miller. Goodbye.
I had quite an experience at the golf club.
After 20 years I almost got a hole in one.
I took her to a beautiful French restaurant,
but all she wanted was spaghetti.
Bob Merrick!
Dr Giraud! For heaven's sake!
How are you?
- You're underweight, but you look fine.
- I feel fine.
Doctors, please! This
is a very tense moment.
Check.
Say, what are you doing here?
Just been seeing your chief. He told me
you did a nice job on that trephining.
I told him I taught you all you know.
You'll be a real neurosurgeon after all.
That's the idea, Doctor.
Never hurts to take time off
to build up the batteries.
I took a week off. Went to Joyce
and Tom Masterson's wedding.
- When was that?
- Well, let's see.
She's in Maternity now with her first baby.
It must have been a year ago.
Maybe work is the best answer.
You... never heard anything again?
No. I never heard from her. Supposedly
she and Nancy came back to the States.
Dr Merrick, please.
You're being paged. Must be
an important man, Doctor.
Don't stay away so long, Doctor.
We need critics around here. Goodbye.
The book says if they don't
gain it back in five days...
Book, shmook. There ought to be a law
new fathers couldn't read anything.
Come in.
- Hello, Doctor.
- Tom.
- How's the little mother?
- A lot littler.
I have a formal complaint. Some nurse
came and took my baby away.
All you can supply is psychological
nourishment, which she doesn't need yet.
- Everything all right?
- Fine. I go home Monday.
Good. I'll look in on you tomorrow.
- Give little Helen an extra hug for me.
- Sure.
Goodbye, Doctor.
He's doing his life
over the hard way.
I imagine any other way
would be the hard way now.
- Good evening, Doctor.
- Good evening, Williams. Thank you.
- Hello, Bob.
- Edward Randolph. Good to see you.
How long have you been here?
I phoned the hospital. They
said you were on your way home.
And...
What is it?
Helen.
- Do you know where she is?
- Nancy called.
Said she was breaking her word...
thank goodness she did.
- Helen must be desperately ill, Bob.
- What?!
They're afraid of pneumonia,
other complications.
- Where are they?
- In a little hospital in New Mexico.
Shadow Mountain.
I've already called about tickets.
- How soon can we leave?
- The 9:00 plane. We'll get there at dawn.
Doctor, that's their car.
- At last you're here.
- Finally.
- I've only done what she asked me.
- I know. How is she?
In a coma. No change since
you called from the airport.
- Dr Allan, Dr Merrick, Mr Randolph.
- How do you do? This way, Doctor.
Nancy...
She was admitted a month ago.
May I see the history, please?
It's the pneumonococcus now.
When she was admitted,
headaches, nausea,
not connected with her
blindness at all.
It's pressure. Have you
done a spinal puncture?
One. Starting yesterday, she
deteriorated so fast, we had to.
Another odd thing. This apparent paralysis
of the left arm and the respiratory centre.
Couldn't be a stroke.
The onset was so gradual.
No. But it could be a fibroma.
Her old injury.
I know something about it.
It might have caused a clot
which became organised
and fibrotic.
I...
always dance...
with my eyes closed.
Well, Doctor? What do you suggest?
If we could only get Henry
Giraud to fly out here.
There isn't time for that.
Is there?
No, there's no time for that.
I agree. We should operate
as soon as possible.
Let's have a look at Surgery.
- Doctor...
- This way?
Doctor, I couldn't do it.
I've never used a Hudson Burr.
- Isn't there anyone else?
- Here? This is just a private sanatorium.
Four of us on the staff. Not one of
us could take that responsibility.
- Do you want it?
- I?
I don't have enough experience.
- You can't expect me to...
- Bob.
A chance in a thousand.
A chance in a million.
You've got to give it to her.
Edward, I can't.
You're not gonna let everything you've
lived for all these years slip away?
You've gone so far, Bob. So far.
I'd give my life to save her.
You just give your skill.
You're ready for it.
Now you're gonna repay that old, old
debt in a way that you never imagined.
Nancy, will you help scrub?
I'll be glad to, Doctor.
Remove the dressing.
2cc of Pentothal sodium.
We're almost ready, Doctor.
Dr Merrick?
- What's the trouble?
- Doctor, you begin. I'll stand by.
Just a moment, please, Doctor.
You can't let that girl down.
You just can't!
Nancy, I'm not up to it.
I just won't be able to...
Nancy, let's start.
- Ready?
- Go ahead.
All right, Doctor.
It was the longest and
roughest operation I ever saw.
Pretty feathery there
for a while, wasn't it?
It's going to be feathery
until she comes to.
- You'd better get some rest now.
- No.
Thank you, Nancy,
but I couldn't sleep.
- I'll make some coffee for you.
- All right.
Doctor.
Nancy?
Nancy's here. I'm here.
- Doctor?
- Yes.
You must be quiet.
It doesn't hurt so much.
You're going to get better.
Who is it?
Who's here?
It's Bob.
Bob?
Oh, Bob, I'm so glad you're here.
Hold me.
Hold me close.
I didn't know.
You didn't tell me.
Lie still. Please.
What is that?
Helen, you've got to be quiet.
But I think I see some light.
Are you sure?
You mustn't talk. Just rest.
But I'm going to see! I know I am!
Am I?
Yes, my darling.
You are going to see.
I can see you.
Please lie still. You must.
Don't get excited. Not today.
May I... May I get excited tomorrow?
Yes.
And you'll be with me?
Yes, darling. I'll be
with you tomorrow.
Starting tomorrow,
we'll never be apart.
Tomorrow.
Oh, tomorrow.
Once you find the
way, you'll be bound.
It'll obsess you.
But, believe me, it'll be
a magnificent obsession.