Now you take it from here, slugger.
Joey?
Joe Doyle!
All right. What do you want?
Hey, I got one of your birds.
I recognized him by the band.
Yeah, must be Danny-boy.
I lost him in the last race.
Yeah, he flew into my coop.
Do ya want him?
Well, I gotta watch myself these days.
You know what I mean?
Well, listen, don't worry.
I'll take him up to your loft.
Okay, I'll see you on the roof.
That a boy. That a boy.
Come on, fella. Come on.
That a boy. Come on. Come on.
- Hey.
- Hiya.
How goes?
He's up on the roof.
The pigeon?
Uh, yeah. It worked.
I think somebody fell off the roof.
He thought he was gonna sing
to the crime commission. He won't.
- I thought they was gonna talk to him.
- That's the idea.
I thought they was gonna talk to him
and get him to dummy up.
Maybe he gave 'em an argument.
No, I figured the worst they were gonna do
was lean on him a little bit.
Like I said, maybe he gave 'em an argument.
He's been giving Johnny, the boss,
a lot of arguments lately.
- He wasn't a bad kid, that Joey.
- A canary.
Maybe he could sing, but he couldn't fly.
Hey, come on.
I'll buy you a drink.
Well, I'll be in there later, and-
Father Barry is here.
Same thing happened to my Andy
five years ago.
- You're Pop Doyle, the boy's father?
- That's right.
Looks like he fell off the roof,
or maybe he was pushed.
- Got any ideas?
- No.
He was the only longshoreman that had the guts
to talk to them crime investigators.
- Who asked you?
- Everybody knows that.
Shut up. If Joey took my advice,
he wouldn't be-
- Everybody knows that.
- I said shut up!
Look, I know how you feel about cops...
but maybe if you could give me
some leads, I could-
I kept telling him,
"Don't say nothing.
Keep quiet. You'll live longer."
I've been on the docks all my life, boy...
and there's one thing I learned:
You don't ask no questions,
you don't answer no questions...
unless you want to wind up like that.
Edie. Edie, come here.
I want to talk to you.
Come with me.
Father, who'd wanna kill Joey?
Who'd wanna kill Joey?
Stay away from him. Stay away from him!
Stay away from him! Stay away from him!
Edie, Edie listen. Edie, Edie!
Edie, time and faith. Remember,
time and faith are great healers.
- Father, my brother's dead, and you talk about time and faith!
- I know.
- My brother was the best kid in the neighborhood, and everybody said so.
- Edie, listen.
I'm in the church if you need me.
You're in the church if I need you?
Did you ever hear of a saint
hiding in a church?
I wanna know who killed my brother!
What's the matter with you, punk?
Hey, boss, Packy wants another drink on the cuff.
- Give it to him!
- All right.
Here's your cut on the shape-up.
Eight hundred and ninety-one men,
three bucks a head, that's, uh...
$2,673.
Charley, you count them.
Got a banana boat in 46 tomorrow.
If we pull a walkout,
might mean a few bucks from the shippers.
- Them bananas go bad in a hurry.
- Ask two Gs.
$2,673.
These clowns can't fight.
There's nobody tough anymore.
- Hiya, slugger.
- Hi there, Johnny.
Hi, kid.
Look out, now!
Don't hit me. Don't hit me!
Where's Morgan?
Where's that big banker of mine?
- Right here, Mr. Friendly.
- Hiya, J.P. How's business?
Having trouble with Kelly again, boss.
He won't take no loans,
and Big Mac puts him to work anyway.
- He's my wife's nephew.
- But he won't take no loans!
I gotta put him to work!
She'd murder me!
That's why I never got married.
Here's the interest on the day, boss: $532.
Here, you count it.
Countin' makes me sleepy.
Hey, Skins, you handle
that sheet metal all right?
Yeah, it was easy. The new checker
faked the receipt. Here it is.
When you talk to me,
take the cigar out of your mouth.
- Stow the receipt. I'll take the cash.
- Yeah, sure. Yeah.
Here you are- 45 bills.
Hey, Terry, you count this.
Go on. It's good for you.
It develops your mind.
- What mind?
- Shut up. I like the kid.
Remember the night he took Farella
at St. Nick's, Charley, huh?
We won a bundle.
Real tough. Big try.
I lost the count.
Okay. Forget it, Einstein.
How come you never got an education
like your brother Charley here?
The only arithmetic he ever got
was hearing the referee count up to ten.
You know, you're not too funny today, fat man.
Hey!
What gives with our boy tonight, Charley?
He ain't himself.
It's just the Joey Doyle thing
and how he exaggerates the thing.
Just too much Marquis of Queensbury.
- It softens him up.
- Listen, kid, I'm a soft touch too.
Ask any rummy on the dock
if I ain't good for a fin...
anytime they put the arm on me.
But my old lady raised us ten kids...
on a stinkin' watchman's pension.
When I was 16,
I had to beg for work in the hold.
I didn't work my way up outta there for nothin'.
Look, I know that, Johnny.
I know it.
Takin' over this local took a little doin'.
There was some pretty rough fellas in the way.
They give me this to remember 'em by.
He had to keep his hand over his throat...
to stay alive, and he still went after them.
- I know it.
- I know what's eatin' you.
Well, I got 2,000 dues-payin' members in this local.
That's $72,000 a year legitimate.
And when each one puts in
a couple of bucks a day...
just to make sure the work's steady...
well, figure it out.
And that's just for openers.
We got the fattest piers...
in the fattest harbor in the world.
Everything moves in and out,
we take our cut.
Why shouldn't we?
If we can get it, we're entitled to it.
You don't suppose I can afford to be boxed
out of a deal like this, do you...
a deal I sweated and bled for,
on account of one lousy little cheese-eater-
that Doyle bum- who thinks he can go
squealin' to the crime commission, do ya?
Well, do ya?
Well, no, Johnny.
I just figured I shoulda been told.
I make it $2,623.
You're $50 short, Skins.
Gimme.
I must've miscounted.
Gimme!
You come from Greenpoint- go back to Greenpoint.
You don't work here no more.
Here, kid. Here's half a bill.
Go get your load on.
- No, I'm okay, Johnny. Thanks.
- Go on. A present from your Uncle Johnny.
And Mac...
tomorrow mornin' when you shape the men,
put Terry up in the loft- number one.
- Sure, why not?
- Every day.
It's nice, easy work, see?
You check in and you goof off
on a coffee bag. Okay?
Okay.
Hey.
You got a real friend here.
Now, don't forget it.
Why should he forget it?
Yeah. Thanks, Johnny.
All right. Payday.
Barney.
Mac.
Truck.
Hi, Terry.
- Hiya, kid.
- I was just gonna feed 'em.
I already fed 'em.
You must've been up early, huh?
I was up anyhow,
so I figured I might as well.
Boy, they sure got it made, huh?
Eatin', sleepin', flyin' around like crazy...
raisin' gobs of squabs.
Well, I better get over there.
Be careful. Don't spill no water on the floor,
'cause I don't want 'em to catch cold.
I'll see you around, huh?
Come on, Tony. Give me them tabs.
He was a good boy, that Doyle kid.
Sure he was.
That's why he got it in the head.
He couldn't learn to keep his mouth shut.
Pop?
Hey, Pop, why don't you go home?
- The boys who work today'll be chippin' in gladly.
- That's right, Pop.
No thanks, fellas. I'm gonna shape.
Who do you think'll pay for the funeral?
- Johnny Friendly, that great labor leader.
- That's a good one.
Why don't you keep that big mouth of yours shut?
What are you, a wise guy?
If I was wise,
I wouldn't be no longshoreman for 30 years.
I'm poorer now than when I started.
- Wise guy.
- Big mouth.
- Don't mess with those guys.
- Oh, here.
I brought you Joey's windbreaker.
Might come in handy.
- Go ahead. Wear it, Kayo.
- Thanks, Pop.
Mine's more full of holes
than the Pittsburgh infield.
- Hey, Joe.
- Yeah, yeah.
I got a coat for you.
Say, do you know Terry Malloy?
- No, I don't know him.
- Never heard of him.
Say, you're Terry Malloy, aren't you?
So what?
Didn't I see you fight a couple of years ago?
Without the birdseed- whadda ya want?
Oh, uh, our identification.
"Waterfront Crime Commission."
What's that?
I just want to ask you a few questions.
See, we're getting ready to hold
public hearings on waterfront crime...
and underworld infiltration of longshore unions.
- I don't know nothin'.
- You haven't heard the questions yet.
- What did you say?
- You heard me.
There's a rumor that you're one of the last people
to see Joey Doyle alive.
Well, I don't know nothin'.
- Nobody's accusing you of anything, Mr. Malloy.
- I hope you understand that.
Just want to ask you some questions
about some people you may know.
- People I may know?
- That's right.
- You better get outta here, buster.
- Now, slow down, boy, huh?
I don't know nothin', I ain't seen nothin',
and I'm not sayin' nothin'.
So why don't you and your girlfriend
just take off?
All right, Mr. Malloy.
You have every right not to talk...
if that's what you choose to do.
- The public has a right to know the facts too.
- Yeah. All right.
- We'll be seeing you again.
- Never is gonna be too much soon for me, shorty.
Take it easy.
How do you like them mugs,
takin' me for a pigeon?
- Who was it?
- I don't know who they are.
You're three weeks behind on the last $25,
but I'm willing to take a chance.
Some chance at ten percent a week.
And if we don't borrow, we don't work.
May you rot in hell, J.P.
When I'm dead and gone,
you'll know what a friend I was.
Why don't you drop dead now
so we can test your theory?
Condolences.
Hey, Pop, look.
All right. Let her go, Tony.
I guess I spoke out of turn last night.
You think I'm just a gravy-train rider
with a turned-around collar.
Don't you?
I see the sisters taught you not to lie.
All right. Loften, Malloy...
Hendricks, Prochowski...
- Westerfield, McGryer.
- Three forty-one.
- Three forty-eight.
- Seventy-one.
I've been thinking about your question, and, uh...
you're right, Edie.
This is my parish.
I don't know how much I can do,
but I'll never find out...
unless I come down here
and take a good look for myself.
All right, I need some extra banana carriers.
Bananas again. I wonder when we're gonna get a boat
from Ireland with some good Irish whiskey on it.
Dugan, my boy, you're dreamin' again.
All right. Kelly.
Richie.
Yeah, you.
What's the matter?
Nobody wanna work today?
Yeah, you.
Hey, who do you see to get
a day's pay around here?
- Meatballs.
- Definitely.
Come here!
Hey, Terry! Grab that one!
Give me that!
- Give it to me!
- What? What?
Give it to me!
- Give me that!
- What makes you so special?
Things are lookin' up on the docks.
Don't you recognize her, dopey?
That's Joey Doyle's sister.
You give me that!
You Joey Doyle's sister?
Yes, I am.
Yeah.
You don't wanna go to work today anyhow.
Well, it's been nice wrestlin' with ya.
Edie.
Pop? Here's your tab. Take it.
All right. Give it to me.
I can use it.
Now get back to the sisters where you belong.
I'm surprised at you, Father,
if you don't mind my saying so...
lettin' her see things ain't fit
for the eyes of a decent girl.
All right, that's all.
Come back tomorrow.
Hey, what do you do now?
Like Big Mac said, come back tomorrow.
Tomorrow? No ship tomorrow.
I've been standin' here
for five straight mornings...
and that bum over there
looks right through you.
You can't be around here.
Come on. Get outta here.
I'm sorry, Father. I didn't mean it.
- What do you wanna do?
- Come on. Let's go get a bowl.
Wait a minute. Is this all you do-
just take it like this?
What about your union?
No other union in the country
would stand for a thing like that.
The waterfront's tougher, Father.
Like it ain't part of America.
- You know how a trigger local works, Father?
- No. How?
You get up in a meetin',
you make a motion...
the lights go out, then you go out.
That's how it's been ever since Johnny
and his cowboys took over the local.
Name one place where it's safe
to even talk without gettin' clobbered.
The church.
What?
The bottom of the church.
You know what you're lettin' yourself in for?
- You got a cigarette on you?
- Yeah.
Right over there.
Hey.
- You working hard?
- Yeah.
You wouldn't mind working once in a while...
just to justify this lofty position, would you?
I finished the work.
I counted all them bags.
We have an extra detail for you-
that's if you don't mind...
being disturbed or anything.
The priest and this Doyle girl are gettin'
a meeting together down at the church...
and we, uh- we want a rundown on it-
you know, the names and the numbers
of all the players.
Wait a minute.
All right. You're nominated.
Well, why me, Charley?
I feel funny goin' down there.
- Besides, I'd just be stoolin' for you.
- Let me tell you what stooling is.
Stooling is when you rat on your friends,
the guys you're with.
- Yeah.
- But if Johnny wants a favor...
don't think about it- do it.
Now, go on. Join the congregation.
Well, I thought there'd be more of you here, but-
The- The Romans found out what a handful could do...
if it's the right handful.
I'm just a potato-eater, but...
isn't it simple as one, two, three?
One: The working conditions are bad.
Two: They're bad because the mob does the hiring.
And three: The only way we can break the mob...
is to stop letting them get away with murder.
Now, if one of you would just answer one question...
we'd have a start, a very good start.
And that question is...
who killed Joey Doyle?
Not one of you has a line
on who killed Joey Doyle?
I have a hunch all of you
could tell us something about it.
All right, then answer this one:
How can we call ourselves Christians...
and protect these murderers with our silence?
Jimmy Collins, you were Joey's best friend.
How can you just sit there
and not say anything?
And I'll always think of him
as my best friend.
- But what do you want me to-
- Who asked him in here?
I'm just trying to find out
what happened to Joey Doyle.
- Maybe you can be helpful.
- "Helpful"?
The brother of Charley the Gent?
They'll help us get to the bottom of the river.
Better leave Charley outta this.
You don't think he'd be "helpful"?
Why don't you ask him yourself?
Maybe I will one of these days.
"One of these days."
Now, listen. You know who the pistols are.
You going to keep still
until they cut you down one by one?
Are you?
Hey, Dugan, how about you?
One thing you gotta understand, Father:
On the dock we've always been D and D.
- "D and D"-- what's that?
- Deaf and dumb.
No matter how much we hate the torpedoes,
we don't rat.
"Rat"? Now, boys, get smart.
I know you're gettin' pushed around, but...
there's one thing we've got in this country,
and that's ways of fightin' back.
Now, getting the facts to the public,
testifying for what you know is right...
against what you know is wrong.
And what's ratting to them
is telling the truth for you.
Can't you see that?
It seems to me we've gone just about
as far as we can at this time.
I think you'll agree with that, Father.
So I'd like to close
with a few words from St. Matthew.
"Come unto me, all ye-"
What did I tell you, sticking your neck out?
This is a police problem, not ours!
- These people need our help, Vince.
- Okay! Okay!
Only don't blame me
when they ship you off to Abyssinia.
I won't.
You'd better go home in pairs.
Two's is two, you know.
Come on!
- Pop! Pop!
- Come here. Don't go out there.
No, no. Come here.
Edie! Edie!
What happened to Pop?
He's an old man. They won't hurt him.
Get out, you!
Here, talk to me.
Are you all right, Dugan?
Yeah, considerin' they were usin' my head
for a baseball.
Are you still D and D?
You still call it ratting?
- Are you on the level?
- What do you think?
If I stick my neck out and they chop it off,
would that be the end of it...
- or are you willing to go all the way?
- Down the line.
They'll put the muscle on you too...
turned-around collar or no turned-around collar.
Here, wipe your face. Listen to me.
You stand up, and I'll stand up with you.
- Right down the wire?
- So help me God.
I think we're okay.
Steel pipes and baseball bats.
Well, they play pretty rough around here.
Well, I can make it home now all right.
Okay.
Which side are you with?
Me? I'm with me. Terry.
Hey, you got a dime for a cup of coffee?
Beat it, will ya?
Just a little dime you don't need?
Hey, I know you.
You're Edie Doyle.
- Come on, beat it.
- Your brother was a saint.
He's the only one who ever tried
to get me compensation.
What are you doin'?
Get outta here, will ya?
You remember, Terry.
You was there that night-
- Get outta here.
- You remember.
Get outta here!
Here's some change.
Go have yourself a ball.
You don't buy me.
You're still a bum.
So long, Edie.
Lord have mercy on Joey.
Who's callin' me a bum?
Everybody loved Joey.
From little kids to the old rummies.
Did you know him very well?
Well, you know, he got around.
- What did that man mean just now?
- Don't pay no attention to him.
He's drunk, he's falling down, everything.
He's just a juicehead
that hangs around the neighborhood.
Don't pay no attention.
I'd better go now.
You don't have to be afraid of me.
I'm not gonna bite ya.
I guess they don't let you walk with fellas
where you've been, huh?
You know how the sisters are.
Yeah. Are you training to be a nun?
It's just a regular college.
Wait a second.
It's run by the Sisters of St. Anne.
Where is that?
It's in Tarrytown.
- Where is that?
- In the country.
I don't like the country.
The crickets make me nervous.
So how often do you get in here?
I guess I haven't been here
since last Christmas.
We were gonna have a Thanksgiving party.
That's nice.
What do you do up there?
Just- What? Study?
I want to be a teacher.
A teacher? That's very good. You know-
Personally, I admire brains.
My brother Charley is a very brainy guy.
He done a couple of years of college.
It isn't just brains.
It's- It's how you use them.
Yeah, I get your thought.
You know, I've seen you
a lot of times before.
Remember parochial school on Pulaski Street?
Seven, eight years ago?
Your hair- Had your hair, uh-
Braids. That's right.
Looked like a hunk of rope.
You had wires on your teeth, and...
glasses, everything.
You was really a mess.
I can get home all right now, thanks.
Hey, listen, don't get sore.
I'm just kiddin' you a little bit.
I just mean to tell you that you...
grew up very nice.
Thanks.
You don't-
You don't remember me, do you?
I remembered you the first moment I saw you.
By the nose, huh?
Well, some people just got faces
that stick in your mind.
I remember you were in trouble all the time.
Now you got me.
Boy, the way those sisters used to whack me,
I don't know what.
They thought they was gonna beat
an education into me, but I foxed 'em.
Maybe they just didn't know
how to handle you.
How would you have done it?
With a little more patience and kindness.
That's what makes people mean and difficult:
People don't care enough about them.
What, are you kiddin' me?
Come on. I'd better get you home.
There's too many guys around here
with only one thing on their mind.
Am I gonna see you again?
What for?
I don't know.
- I really don't know.
- Come on.
Come on.
All right. You're all packed.
Here's your bus ticket,
and you're on your way back to St. Anne's.
- I'm not ready to go back yet, Pop.
- Edie, for years your mom and me...
put quarters into the cookie jar...
to keep you up there with the sisters...
keep you from things
like I just seen outside the window.
A daughter of mine walkin' arm in arm
with Terry Malloy.
- You know who Terry Malloy is?
- Who is he, Pop?
He's the kid brother of Charley the Gent...
who is Johnny Friendly's right hand,
and a butcher in a camel-hair coat.
You tryin' to tell me Terry is too?
He tries to act tough...
but there's a look in his eye.
Yeah, a look in his eye.
Hold your hats, brothers.
Here we go again.
Do you think he's one of them cases you're always...
draggin' into the house
and feelin' sorry for...
like that litter of kittens
you brought in?
The only one you wanted to keep...
had six toes and was cockeyed to boot.
Look at him, the little bum.
He said he wants to see me again.
Look.
See this arm?
Two inches longer than the other.
That's from years of workin'...
and sweatin' and liftin'...
and swingin' a hook.
Every time I hoist a box or a coffee bag...
I says to meself, "That's for Edie...
so she can be a teacher
or somethin' decent."
Oh, Pop!
I promised your mom, Edie.
Don't let her down.
Pop...
I don't want you to think that I'm not grateful
for everything you've done-
for giving me the education,
for keeping me away from all of this.
But Pop, I've seen things
that I know are so wrong.
How can I got back to school and keep my mind
on things that are just in books?
That- That aren't people living?
I'm gonna stay, Pop...
and I'm gonna keep on trying to find out
who is guilty for Joey.
Heads up!
Hi.
What are you doin' up here on the roof?
Just looking.
Take a look at the champion flock
of the neighborhood.
Fly pretty nice, huh?
"Golden Warriors"?
Yeah. I started the Golden Warriors.
You might say that I was
the original Golden Warrior.
Hey. This bum here is my shadow.
He thinks I'm a tough man
'cause I boxed pro for a while.
Think you're a tough guy, huh?
- Joey used to raise pigeons.
- Get outta here.
Joey used to raise pigeons.
Yeah, he had a few birds.
I've been takin' care of 'em.
I wouldn't have thought
you'd be so interested in pigeons.
I just go for it.
You know this city is full of hawks?
That's a fact.
They hang around on top of the big hotels...
and they spot a pigeon in the park-
Right down on 'em.
You got a second? One second?
I wanna show you something.
Here you are.
What do you think of that fella?
She's a beauty.
She's a he. His name is Swifty.
Oh, look what he went and did.
He's my lead bird.
He's always on top of the perch.
If another bum tries to come along
and take his place, he really lets him have it.
Even pigeons aren't peaceful.
Well, one thing about 'em, though:
They're very faithful.
- They get married just like people.
- Better.
And they stay that way
till one of 'em dies.
That's nice.
Hey, go ahead. Fix the roof.
Here. You want that egg?
Thanks.
Do you like beer?
I don't know.
I'll bet you never had a glass of beer.
- You ever have a glass of beer?
- No.
Wanna have one with me?
In a saloon?
Well, yeah.
I mean, I know a nice little dump down there that...
got a special entrance for ladies,
and all like that.
Come on. It won't hurt.
Come on.
Yeah? Good.
- Hey, Mac?
- Yeah.
Two Glockenheimers and two for chasers.
Yeah. See the fight last night?
- No.
- Kid named Riley. Both hands.
Like you used to do.
I hope he got better dice than me.
Comedian.
Are you really a prizefighter?
I used to be.
How did you get interested in that?
Well, I don't know.
I had to scrap all my life.
I might as well get paid for it.
When I was a kid,
my old man got bumped off, and-
and, uh- never mind how.
And they stuck Charley and me in a-
a dump they call a children's home.
Oh, boy, that was some home.
Well, anyhow, I ran away from there...
and I fought in the club smokers
and peddled papers...
and Johnny Friendly bought a piece of me.
Bought a piece of you?
Yes.
Then, uh, I was goin' pretty good there
for a while.
And after that, uh-
Well, I don't know.
What do you really care?
Am I right?
Shouldn't everybody care about everybody else?
Oh, what a fruitcake you are.
I mean, isn't everybody
a part of everybody else?
And you really believe that drool?
Yes, I do.
Well, here we are.
One for the lady and for the gent.
Here's to the first one.
I hope it ain't the last.
Tink.
Go ahead.
Good?
No, not like that. One hump.
Hey, you wanna hear my philosophy of life?
Do it to him before he does it to you.
I never met anyone like you.
There's not a- a spark...
of sentiment or romance...
or human kindness in your whole body.
What good does it do you
besides get you in trouble?
And when things and people
get in your way...
you just knock them aside,
get rid of them- is that your idea?
Listen, don't look at me
when you say that.
It wasn't my fault what happened to Joey.
Fixin' him wasn't my idea.
Who said it was?
Well, everybody's puttin' the needle on me-
you and them mugs in the church
and Father Barry.
I didn't like the way he was lookin' at me.
He was looking at everybody the same way.
Oh, yeah?
Anyhow, what's with this Father Barry?
What's his racket?
- His racket?
- Yeah, his racket. Everybody's got a racket.
But he's a priest.
Are you kiddin'? So what?
That don't make no difference.
You don't believe anybody, do you?
Listen, down here it's every man for himself.
It's keepin' alive.
It's standin' in with the right people so you get
a little bit of change jinglin' in your pocket.
- And if you don't?
- If you don't-
right down.
It's living like an animal.
All right, then. I'd rather live
like an animal than end up like-
Like Joey?
Are you afraid to mention his name?
No.
Well, what do you keep harpin' on that for?
Come on, drink up.
You gotta get a little fun outta life.
Come on. I'll stick some music on.
What's the matter?
What's the matter with you?
Help me if you can, for God sakes.
Edie, I'd like to help.
I'd like to help,
but there's nothing I can do.
All right.
I shouldn't have asked you.
Here, come on. Have a little beer.
Come on, come on.
I don't want it.
You just stay here and finish your drink.
Oh, no, no. Listen, don't go.
I got my whole life to drink.
Are you sore at me?
What for?
Well, I don't know.
For not-
For not bein' no help to you.
You would if you could.
Here I come!
Pick a winner.
Wait a minute.
First I gotta kiss the bride.
Come on, you kissed her before.
You can get out that way.
You want me to take you?
- What's goin' on here?
- Gimme a cigarette.
You gotta stop smokin' so much.
Come on. We can get out through here.
What's the matter with you?
- Come on.
- That's a pretty tune.
Here's a stick of gum.
It'll do you good.
- Thank you.
- Do you like that music?
If I had my tuxedo,
I'd ask you to dance, but-
Come on. You wanna- you wanna spin?
Come on. Don't be afraid.
You dance divinely.
Say, we're doing pretty good.
The sisters ought to see you now.
Wait a minute.
I feel like I'm just floating.
Just floating.
Hey!
I been lookin' all over for you, Terry.
The boss wants you.
Right now?
Yeah, he just got a call from Mr. Upstairs.
Something's gone wrong.
He's plenty hot.
- I wanna take her home first.
- I wouldn't. I'll see the little lady home.
Just tell him I'll come over there
when I'm ready.
Hey, Ed, wait up!
Who was that?
I don't know. Some mug.
Who was he?
Edie, you gotta quit tryin'
to find out about Joey. It ain't safe.
Now, I'm telling you, it ain't safe.
Mr. Malloy, I was hoping
I might find you here.
Excuse me, miss. You're being served
with a subpoena, Mr. Malloy.
- A what?
- Be at the statehouse, courtroom nine...
10:00 Friday morning.
What's the matter? I told you,
I don't know nothin' about that.
You can bring a lawyer if you wish.
You're privileged under the Constitution...
to protect yourself against questions
which might implicate you in any crimes.
Listen, you know what they're askin' me to do?
All we want you to do, Mr. Malloy,
is tell the truth.
Good night, kid.
Nice wedding.
What are you gonna do?
I ain't gonna eat cheese for no cops,
and that's for sure!
It was Johnny Friendly
who had Joey killed, wasn't it?
Or he had him killed.
He had something to do with it, didn't he?
He and your big brother, Charley?
You can't tell me, can you,
because you're a part of it.
Because you're just as bad as the worst of them.
Tell me the truth, Terry.
You'd better go back to that school
out in daisyland.
You're drivin' yourself nuts.
You're drivin' me nuts.
Quit worryin' about the truth all the time.
Worry about yourself.
I should have known you wouldn't tell me.
Pop said Johnny Friendly used to own you.
Well, I think he still owns you.
No wonder everybody calls you a bum.
Don't say that to me, Edie.
Don't say that to me now.
No wonder. No wonder.
I'm only tryin' to help you out.
I'm tryin' to keep you from gettin' hurt.
What more do you want me to do?
- Much more.
- Wait a minute.
Much, much, much more.
Where are you goin'?
- Hi there, Johnny. I was just-
- Genius!
I was just comin' over there.
- Where were you? Chicago?
- No, I was on my way over there.
How many times you been knocked out, Terry?
- Knocked out? Uh, two times.
- That's once too often.
Your brains must be rattling.
What do you got up there? Chinese bells?
- What's the matter?
- I thought you were gonna keep your eye on that church meeting.
I was there. There was nothin' happenin'.
"Nothin' happenin'," he says.
Some operator you got yourself there.
One more like him,
we'll all be wearing striped pajamas.
I'm tellin' you, it was a big nothin'.
The priest did all the talkin'.
- He did?
- Yeah.
Half an hour later, a certain Timothy J. Dugan...
had a secret session with the crime commission,
and he done all the talkin'.
Well, Dugan- what does he know?
Just 39 pages of our operation, that's all!
- Where'd you get that?
- I got it.
He got it. It's the complete works
of Timothy J. Dugan.
- I knew he had the guts, but I never-
- "Guts"?
Why, that crummy pigeon!
He oughta have his neck wrung.
That's what we get for getting mixed up
with this punch-drunk brother of yours.
He was all right hangin' around for laughs,
but this is business.
- I don't like anyone goofin' off on my business.
- I wasn't goofin', Johnny.
What are you goin' around with his sister for?
- I'm not goin'--
- Just shut up!
Look, Johnny, it's just that...
the Doyle broad, she's got him so he
doesn't know where his feet is anymore.
- It's an unhealthy relationship!
- Definitely.
Get rid of her,
unless you're both tired of living.
- You got her address?
- Yeah.
Look, we gotta do something to muzzle this Dugan,
or he'll raise...
the biggest stink this town has ever seen.
We got the best muscle on the waterfront.
The time to use it is now...
pronto, if not sooner.
You know where you're goin'?
Back in the hold.
No more cushy job in the loft.
It's down in the hold with the sweat gang...
till you learn your lesson, see?
You!
Let's go.
Wise up!
At last, an Irish shipment.
And loaded to the gunnels with fine Irish whiskey.
- See, Kayo? The good Lord takes care of his own in time.
- That he does.
Come on there, Kayo! Get it up!
- All right. Take it up.
- Take it up.
Take it away.
And don't go walkin' off
with any of that!
You know how the boss feels
about individual pilferage!
All right, all right.
Now you see the advantage
of a little man in a big coat.
Kayo, let me see you a minute afterwards.
What are you down here for? To see we don't steal
any of Mr. Friendly's precious cargo?
- I want to talk-
- Get away from me, will ya?
- All right. Take it up.
- Take it up.
Take it away.
Okay.
Kayo, you're a walkin' distillery!
Watch it!
Get a doctor!
He don't need a doctor.
He needs a priest.
I came down here to keep a promise.
I gave Kayo my word that
if he stood up to the mob...
I'd stand up with him... all the way.
And now Kayo Dugan is dead.
He was one of those fellows
who had the gift for standin' up.
But this time they fixed him.
Oh, they fixed him for good this time.
Unless it was an accident,
like Big Mac says.
Some people think the crucifixion
only took place on Calvary.
Well, they'd better wise up.
Takin' Joey Doyle's life to stop him
from testifying is a crucifixion.
And droppin' a sling on Kayo Dugan...
because he was ready to spill his guts tomorrow-
that's a crucifixion!
And every time the mob puts the pressure
on a good man...
tries to stop him from doing
his duty as a citizen...
it's a crucifixion!
And anybody who sits around
and lets it happen...
keeps silent about something
he knows has happened...
shares the guilt of it
just as much as the Roman soldier...
who pierced the flesh of our Lord
to see if he was dead.
Go back to your church, Father!
Boys, this is my church!
And if you don't think Christ is down here on the
waterfront, you've got another guess comin'!
Get off the dock, Father!
Tillio, don't do that.
- Whose side you on, boy?
- Let him finish.
Every morning...
when the hiring boss blows his whistle...
Jesus stands alongside you in the shape-up.
He sees why some of you get picked
and some of you get passed over.
He sees the family men
worryin' about gettin' the rent...
and gettin' food in the house
for the wife and the kids.
He sees you sellin' your souls
to the mob for a day's pay!
The next bum that throws somethin'
deals with me!
I don't care if he's twice my size!
Now, what does Christ think
of the easy-money boys...
who do none of the work
and take all of the gravy?
And how does he feel
about the fellas who wear $150 suits...
and diamond rings on your union dues...
and your kickback money?
And how does he...
who spoke up without fear
against every evil...
feel about your silence?
Shut up about that!
Just watch this.
Did you see that?
You want to know what's wrong
with our waterfront?
It's the love of a lousy buck.
It's makin' love of a buck, the cushy job...
more important than the love of man.
It's forgettin' that every fella down here
is your brother in Christ.
But remember: Christ is always with you.
Christ is in the shape-up,
he's in the hatch, he's in the union.
He's kneelin' right here beside Dugan...
and he's sayin' with all of you...
"If you do it to the least of mine,
you do it to me."
And what they did to Joey and what
they did to Dugan, they're doing to you.
And you, you. All of you!
And only you- only you,
with God's help-
have the power to knock 'em out for good.
Okay, Kayo?
Amen.
All right, come on! Come on, let's go!
Break it up. Lets go to work.
Edie, Joey's jacket.
I'm sure Kayo would wish you
to have it back.
Terry?
I brought you Joey's jacket.
Yours is coming apart.
Pigeons.
Yeah, they're nervous.
There was a hawk around here before.
Edie-
Father, I wanna speak to you a minute.
Remember what you said about Kayo Dugan...
about keeping your mouth shut
when you know the score?
I don't want to hear your confession.
I'll dig it out for myself...
and I'll use it where it'll do
the most good.
Now, you take your turn.
Father Gregory will hear you.
I don't wanna talk-
Wait a second, will ya?
Wait a minute.
I just wanna talk to you one second.
Listen to me. You gotta listen to me.
Wait a minute.
I'm the one that set Joey Doyle up
for the knock-off.
Come on. Take a walk with me, kid,
and give it to me straight.
There's nothing I haven't heard.
Come on.
It started out as a favor.
"A favor"-- who am I kidding?
It's "do it or else."
But believe me when I tell you I just thought
they was gonna lean on him a little bit.
I never figured they was gonna knock him off.
And I tried to tell Edie the other night.
I really tried to.
I wanted to tell her. She's the first
nice thing that ever happened to me.
What are you gonna do about it?
- What do you mean? About telling her?
- Yes, about telling her...
the commission, your subpoena.
- I know you got a subpoena.
- Well, I don't know.
It's like carrying a monkey
around on your back.
It's a question of who rides who.
But, you know, if I spill,
my life ain't worth a nickel.
And how much is your soul worth
if you don't?
They're askin' me to put the finger
on my own brother.
Johnny Friendly used to take me to ball games
when I was a kid.
"Ball games." Don't break my heart.
I wouldn't care if he gave you
a life pass to the Polo Grounds.
So you've got a brother?
Let me tell you something:
You've got some other brothers.
And they're gettin' the short end...
while your Johnny's getting mustard
on his face at the Polo Grounds.
Ball games! Listen.
If I were you, I would walk right-
Never mind.
I'm not asking you to do anything.
It's your own conscience
that's got to do the asking.
"Conscience."
That stuff- That stuff can drive you nuts.
Good luck.
Hey, is that all you got to say?
Come here.
Edie called me this morning.
She's coming here to talk to me.
Come on. Why don't you tell her?
No curves.
Okay.
Thanks.
- You?
- Honest to God, Edie-
You gotta believe me. I swear to God, Edie.
Hey, Terry, guess who's here.
That joker from the crime commissioner's office.
Suppose I knew a guy that knocked somebody off.
Think I oughta turn him in?
You mean call a cop?
Are you kiddin'?
You don't think I oughta turn him in?
You was a Golden Warrior once.
That's right.
You started the gang.
You lookin' for me?
No, not exactly.
I was just resting my dogs a minute.
On the next investigation we get into,
I hope it's got buildings with elevators.
So far this one's just been climbing stairs.
What are you climbin' 'em for?
Well, it's worth it
if we can tell the waterfront story...
the way the people have a right to hear it.
Don't you think?
Say, uh, didn't I see you in the Garden...
three or four years ago
with a fellow named Wilson?
Yeah.
Thought you were gonna take him that night.
Man, he really dumped you.
He dumped me, huh?
What would you say if I told you
I held that bum up for half a round?
Yeah. Yeah, I could see he was hurt.
Hey, what do you think I was doin'
with them combinations? Pettin' him?
You just couldn't finish him off, huh?
Hey, don't monkey around there.
- Why didn't you finish him off?
- What do you talk about, "finish him off"?
I was doin' a favor for a couple of pals of mine.
"Favor"?
- That's the way it was.
If I'd have put him down,
I'd have had a title shot.
- I was ready that night.
- You sure looked it.
That's when I figured it was all over.
It was all over, except for the lousy bet.
- My own-
- Yeah?
Well, I guess I better get going.
Hit those stairs again.
Say, was that a hook or an uppercut
you caught him with that first time?
I didn't use no hooks.
I was strictly a short puncher.
- Looked like a hook to me.
- I had that bum all figured out.
He had a good left hand.
You know what I mean?
So I let him tag me with the left hand
for a couple of rounds.
So just when he starts-
he thinks he's getting cute...
I step inside and jab him with a left,
with a right, with a left.
I had him in my arms, and from there on in,
we were just dancin'.
- I see.
- And that's a fact!
When those guys wanna win a bet,
there's nothin' they won't stop at.
I didn't hear 'em, boss, but I sure seen 'em
nose to nose like a pair of lovers.
The flatfoot was eatin' it up.
Look, so they been seen together
nose to nose, and he smiled at her.
That doesn't mean he's gonna talk.
There is no evidence
until he gives public testimony.
Thanks for the legal advice, Charley.
That's what we always kept you around here for.
How do we keep him from giving this testimony?
Ain't that what you call
the main order of business?
He's a good kid. And you know that.
He's a bum. After all the days I gave him in the loft,
he's got no gratitude.
- You shut up!
- Mac...
I'm conducting this investigation.
Look...
this girl and the father,
they got their hooks in the kid so deep...
he doesn't even know
which end is up anymore.
I ain't interested in his mental condition.
All I wanna know is,
is he D and D or is he a canary?
I wish I knew.
So do I, Charley. For your sake.
What do you want me to do?
Look, it's simple.
Drive him out to this place we've been usin'.
Try to straighten him out on the way.
If you don't, give him to Gerry G.
Johnny, you can't do that.
I mean, maybe the boy is out of line,
but he's just a confused kid.
"Confused kid"?
First he crosses me in public
and gets away with it, then the next joker.
Pretty soon I'm just another fellow around here!
Johnny, I can't do that.
Then don't.
- Who do you like in the third?
- Gotta be New Hope.
Definitely.
Johnny...
he's my kid brother.
That's for you to figure out.
You can have it your way,
or you can have it his way.
But you can't have it both ways.
Am I right, Truck?
Definitely.
Okay, on your horse...
deep thinker.
- Hi, Charley.
- Hello.
I'm glad you stopped by for me.
I been wantin' to talk to you.
- Yeah, sure, kid.
- Where to?
Just go to River Street,
and I'll tell you where to stop.
- I thought we was goin' to the Garden.
- We are...
but I want to cover a bet
on the way over.
Besides, this'll give us a chance to talk.
Well, nobody ever stopped you from talkin', Charley.
Listen, I, uh- The-
The grapevine says that you got a subpoena.
Yeah.
The guys would know you well enough to know
that you're not a cheese-eater...
but they think maybe you should not be
on the outside so much.
A little on the inside. Have a few little things
workin' for you down at the docks.
A steady job, a couple extra potatoes-
that's all I want.
Oh, sure, that's great when you're a kid,
but you're gettin' on.
You're pushin' 30, slugger.
It's time to think about gettin' some ambition.
Well, I always figured I'd live
a little bit longer without it.
Maybe.
Look...
there's a boss loader slot that's open...
on the new pier we're openin' up.
You see, now, it pays six cents...
on every hundred pounds that goes in
and every hundred pounds that goes out...
and you don't have to lift a finger.
That's two, three,
four hundred dollars a week.
Four hundred dollars a week
just for the openers.
I get all that dough for not doin' nothin'?
You don't do anything,
and you don't say anything.
You understand?
There's more to this than I thought, Charley.
I'm tellin' you, there's a lot more.
You don't mean you're thinkin' of testifyin'
against some people that we might know?
I don't know, Charley.
I'm tellin' you I don't know, Charley.
That's what I wanna talk to you about.
Listen, you know how much those piers are worth
that we control through the local?
- I know that.
- All right. You think Johnny's gonna jeopardize the whole setup...
- for one rubber-lipped ex-tanker who's walking on his heels?
- Don't say that.
- What the-
- I coulda been better.
- That's not the point.
- I coulda been a lot better.
The point is we don't have much time.
I'm tellin' you,
I haven't made up my mind yet.
Well, make up your mind
before we get to 437 River Street!
Before we get to where, Charley?
- Before we get to where?
- Listen to me.
Take the job. Just take it.
No questions. Take it.
Charley.
Terry, take this job, please.
Please take it.
Charley.
Oh, Charley.
Look, kid, I-
How much you weigh, slugger?
When you weighed 168 pounds...
you were beautiful.
You coulda been another Billy Conn.
And that skunk we got you for a manager...
he brought you along too fast.
It wasn't him, Charley. It was you.
You remember that night in the Garden
you came down to my dressin' room...
and said, "Kid, this ain't your night.
We're goin' for the price on Wilson"?
You remember that?
"This ain't your night."
My night! I coulda taken Wilson apart.
So what happens?
He gets the title shot outdoors in a ballpark...
and what do I get?
A one-way ticket to Palookaville.
You was my brother, Charley.
You shoulda looked out for me a little bit.
You shoulda taken care of me
just a little bit...
so I wouldn't have to take dives
for the short-end money.
I had some bets down for you.
You saw some money.
You don't understand. I coulda had class.
I coulda been a contender.
I coulda been somebody...
instead of a bum...
which is what I am, let's face it.
It was you, Charley.
Okay.
I'll tell him...
I couldn't find you.
Ten to one he won't believe it.
Here.
You take this.
You're gonna need it.
You, you pull over.
Take me to the Garden.
Edie?
Stay away from me!
Come on. Pease open the door. Please.
Stop it!
I want you to stay away from me!
I know what you want me to do,
but I ain't gonna do it, so forget it!
I don't want you to do anything.
You let your conscience
tell you what to do.
Shut up about that conscience.
That's all I been hearin'!
- I never mentioned the word before. You just stay away from me!
- Edie!
Edie, you love me.
- I want you-
- I didn't say I didn't love you. I said stay away from me!
- I want you to say it to me.
- Stay away from me!
Terry.
Hey, Terry!
Hey, Terry, your brother's down here!
He wants to see ya!
Charley.
Hey, Terry.
Hey, Terry!
Your brother's down here.
Come on down here.
He wants to see ya.
Terry! Come on down!
- What is it, Terry?
- Charley- I think he's in trouble.
Be careful!
Charley.
Terry?
Come on, Terry.
Your brother's down here!
Do you hear what I hear?
Terry! Terry!
Terry!
That's the same way they called Andy
the night I lost him.
Edie, be careful! Edie, be careful!
Terry!
Edie! Watch out for the truck!
Terry.
They got Charley.
Terry, I'm frightened.
Let's get out of here, please.
First Joey, and then Dugan,
and now Charley, and then-
Please, Terry, someplace
where we can live in peace.
I'm gonna take it out of their skulls.
Charley...
Please, Terry. They'll kill you too.
Go get the Father.
Tell him to take care of Charley.
And then come on back here
and stay with him till he gets here.
Terry, please don't do anything.
Please! Terry!
And for God sakes,
don't leave him alone here long.
- Please, Terry.
- Do what I tell you.
Terry!
Where's John Friendly?
He's not here now.
Oh, yeah?
Gimme a shot.
- Take it easy, Terry.
- Don't give me no advice.
Give me the shot.
Look, kid, why don't you go home
before Big John gets here?
Just gimme the whiskey.
- Go away.
- Stick around, Tillio.
Go ahead, sit down.
Get outta that phone booth!
Stay where you are, Tillio!
- I want to see ya, Terry.
- I'm right in front of ya.
Now, don't give me a hard time, Terry.
What do you want?
- Your gun.
- Go and chase yourself.
- Come on. Give me the gun.
- You go to hell.
- What did you say?
- Go to hell.
- Sorry. Let me help you up there.
- Get your hands off of me!
- Now what am I gonna do?
- You want to be brave?
Firing lead into another man
isn't being brave!
Why don't you mind your own business?
- Firing lead into another man's flesh isn't being brave!
- It's none of your business!
You want to hurt Johnny Friendly?
You want to hurt him?
You want to fix him?
Do you? Do you really want to finish him?
- What do you think?
- For what he did to Charley and a dozen other men better than Charley?
Then don't fight him like a hoodlum
down here in the jungle...
because that's just what he wants!
He'll hit you in the head
and plead self-defense.
You'll fight him in the courtroom tomorrow
with the truth...
as you know the truth.
Now, you get rid of that gun,
unless you haven't got the guts.
And if you haven't,
then you better hold on to it.
Gimme a beer.
Want a beer? Make it two.
You mean to sit there
and tell me that your local takes in...
$65,500 every year...
and keeps no financial records?
- Oh, sure. We got records.
- Well, where are they?
Well, you see, we was robbed last night,
and we can't find no books.
You know you're under oath.
Oh, sure.
Doesn't it seem odd to you
that five different waterfront locals...
were broken into last night...
and the only item missing from all of them
was the financial records?
What do you mean, "odd"?
Like I told you, we was robbed.
That's all for now.
Call the next witness.
Before you call the next witness...
are all the officers of Local 374
present this morning?
Call the roll.
Will the following please rise
as the names are called?
Mr. Michael J. Skelly, also known
as Johnny Friendly, president.
Mr. Louis O. Janotta, vice president.
Daniel D. Coogan, financial secretary.
Mr. Vladin Sokolivitch, delegate.
Mr. Tillio A. Rodelli, delegate-
Recordin' secretary.
- Yeah, recordin' secretary.
- Thank you, gentlemen.
- Next witness.
- Mr. Malloy.
Raise your right hand.
- Name, please.
- Terry Malloy.
Swear to tell the truth, the whole truth,
and nothing but the truth, so help you God?
- Right.
- "I do."
- I do.
- Be seated, please.
Mr. Malloy, is it true that the night
Joey Doyle was found dead...
you were the last one to see him
before he was pushed from the roof?
- Yes, that's right.
- And is it true that you went immediately-
Wait. Except for the guys that pushed him off.
And is it true that you went immediately
to the Friendly bar...
and there expressed your feelings
about the murder to Mr. Johnny Friendly?
John Friendly. Right.
And now, Mr. Malloy, can you tell me...
whether Mr. Friendly-
or I should say Mr. Skelly-
said anything to you to indicate his responsibility...
in getting rid of Joey Doyle?
- Right.
- And would you say, Mr. Malloy...
that Mr. Friendly made it very clear to you...
that it was absolutely necessary
that he murder Joey Doyle...
- in order to maintain his control...
- Turn that thing off.
of the docks and the waterfront locals?
Is that correct?
Would there be anything else, sir?
Yes, Sidney. If Mr. Friendly calls, I'm out.
- Anytime today?
- If he calls ever, I'm out!
Very well, sir.
Thank you, Mr. Malloy.
You've done more than break
the Joey Doyle case.
You've begun to make it possible
for honest men to work the docks...
with job security and peace of mind.
You may step down now.
That's all for now.
Mr. Michael J. Skelly, please.
You just dug your own grave.
Go fall in it.
You're dead on this waterfront
and every waterfront from Boston to New Orleans.
You don't drive a truck or a cab.
You don't push a baggage rack.
You don't work no place.
You're done!
Get your hands off me!
Let go!
Come on, will you quit followin' me?
Why don't you get off my tail?
- Orders.
- You're hot. You oughta be glad we're followin' you.
You're makin' me feel like a canary.
- Well?
- Lay off.
Hiya, Chickie.
Who's your friend?
I made some hot coffee.
I thought you might want some.
No.
Well, anyway, it's all over.
My friends don't wanna talk to me.
Are you sure they're your friends?
Terry-
I'll see you later.
Hiya, champ. How's the kid?
A pigeon for a pigeon!
Terry?
The kid.
Tommy?
What'd he have to do that for?
Every one of 'em.
Terry, there's no place that's safe
for you now on the waterfront.
Maybe inland, out west someplace.
A farm.
- "A farm"?
- You could do lots of things...
anything, as long as you're away
from Johnny Friendly.
And even the longshoremen-
You try to help them, and they just turn their backs...
and stick to their stupid D and D.
Are they taking chances for you?
Why should you?
You're not even listening to me, are you?
You're going down there.
Just because John Friendly warned you not to,
you're going down there.
You think you've got to prove something to them,
that you're not afraid of them or something.
Well, go ahead! Get it over with!
Go down to the shape-up
and get yourself killed!
You stupid, pigheaded-
What are you trying to prove?
They always said I was a bum.
Well, I ain't a bum, Edie.
Don't worry. I'm not gonna hurt nobody.
I'm just gonna go down there...
and get my rights.
Okay.
All right! Everybody works today!
Lofgang...
Hendricks...
Prochowski...
Horton...
Dalton, Flaherty, Kaufman-
- What do you think, boys?
- That ain't such a bad picture of you, boss.
Stop breathin' that clam sauce on me.
What's doin'?
I wish you'd let me go to work on that cheese-eater.
I'd top the bum off lovely.
Wait till we get off this front page.
Then he's mine.
I want him.
You hear that? He's mine.
Where're them cops of yours, stoolie?
You're gonna need 'em.
You're still short in the hatch, Mac.
Hey, Speck, bring me the first man you see.
Hey, you.
Here's your man, Mac.
You want more of the same?
Come back tomorrow.
All right. That's it.
I hope that bum comes down here.
I love if he comes down here.
Did you ever hear of the Sullivan law?
They'll be down on us for the slightest infraction- anything!
I'm gonna be indicted any minute!
Come on, now. Gimme, gimme, gimme!
Will you get it through your heads?
They're dustin' off a hot seat for me!
We're a law-abidin' union.
Understand?
He'll kill him.
Hey, Friendly!
John Friendly, come outta there!
Friendly!
Come on outta there!
You wanna know the trouble with you?
You think it makes you a big man
if you give the answers.
At the right time, I'll catch up with you.
Be thinkin' about that.
- Now, go on, beat it. Don't push your luck.
- Wait a minute, you!
You take them heaters away from you,
and you're nothin'! You know that?
You'll talk yourself in the river!
You take the good goods away,
and the kickbacks...
and the shake-down cabbage,
and them pistoleros, and you're nothin'!
Your guts is all in your wallet
and your trigger finger, you know that?
- You ratted on us, Terry!
- From where you stand, maybe...
but I'm standin' over here now!
- I was rattin' on myself all them years- I didn't even know it.
- Come on!
You give it to Joey,
you give it to Dugan...
you give it to Charley,
who was one of your own.
- You think you're God Almighty, but you know what you are?
- Come on.
You're a cheap, lousy...
dirty, stinkin' mug...
and I'm glad what I done to you!
You hear that? I'm glad what I done!
- And I'm gonna keep on doin' it till I get-
- Come on! Come on!
Come on!
That boy fights like he used to.
Truck!
- They'll kill him.
- It's a massacre.
He's one of theirs anyway.
Get him! Get him!
What are we waitin' for? Let's go.
That's enough.
Just let him lay there.
What happened?
Jimmy, what happened?
Where ya goin'?
Let me by.
You want him?
You can have him!
The little rat's yours.
- Get some fresh water!
- Terry?
Terry.
Terry, listen.
Who's in charge here?
Yours truly's in charge here. Look out.
We gotta get this ship outta here.
It's costing us money.
Blow your whistle.
All right, you guys! Get to work!
Come on!
- What goes?
- I'll have 'em workin' in two minutes.
- Come on, you guys! Get goin'!
- He'd better get these men to work.
Go on down!
Come on, you guys. On the double.
Get to work. You heard me.
Come on. Get in there.
Get in there!
- How about Terry?
- He don't work, we don't work!
Work? He can't even walk!
You wanna know who works?
The ones I pick to work! Now, get goin'.
Come on. All of you, get in there.
Come on, get to work. All of you.
Come on, get up here!
Come on, Pop. On the double.
You work today.
All my life ya pushed me around.
Oh, come on!
How do ya like it?
Come on! You walk in, and we'll-
If Terry walks in, we walk in with him.
- They're waitin' for him to walk in!
- Jimmy-
Water.
Did you hear that, Terry? Terry?
- Terry, did you hear that?
- Yeah.
You lost the battle, but...
you have a chance to win the war.
- What do I have to do?
- Walk.
- Father-
- Can you walk?
- Walk?
- Yes, walk.
To the pier, I mean.
- And we'll walk in with you.
- So the shippers can see...
we'll take no more orders from Johnny Friendly.
Then it'll give us back our union,
so we can run it on the up-and-up.
Johnny Friendly's layin' odds
that you won't get up.
What are you standin' around for?
Come on and help me!
Come on, you guys!
Put me on my feet.
Come on.
Take your hands off.
How you doin', pal?
Am I on my feet?
You're on your feet.
- I don't think I'm gonna make it.
- Terry?
You can.
Just finish what you started.
Okay.
Gimme my hook.
- What are you trying to do?
- He's got to.
Take your hands off. Keep 'em off.
Leave him alone.
Leave him alone!
All right, let's go to work!
- Let's go!
Come back here!
Come on, you guys!
Where you guys goin'?
Wait a minute! I'll remember this!
I'll remember every one of ya!
I'll be back!
Don't you forget that!