[Dog barking]
Whoa.
[Door bells jangle]
That's a little over 10 pounds.
How much is beaver
worth this year?
$6.00 a pound.
Well, I'll trade you
for a new plow,
two tubs of lard, a
barrel of molasses,
25 pounds of chewing tobacco...
And you wouldn't have a wife
under the counter there?
I'm looking for a wife.
Any special brand?
Well, yes. I'd like best
a widow woman
that ain't afraid to work.
There's 7 of us men,
me and my 6 brothers.
The place is like a pigsty.
The food tastes worse.
So I made up my mind
next time I'm in town trade,
I'm gonna bring me back a wife.
That's a fine thing I must say,
thinking you can trade for a
wife like she was a bag of meal.
No, I wouldn't say that.
Let me tell you,
none of our gals is gonna go off
to bear country with you
to cook and wash and slave
for 7 slumocky backwoodsmen.
There's 10 men
for every woman out here.
If you want a wife,
go back east and get one.
There's no unmarried
females in this town?
[Door bells jangle]
Good morning, Mrs. Bixby.
Having a quilting bee. Thought
you have some odds and ends.
Mrs. Bixby: I'll see.
How about these?
Now, just a minute.
What's the matter? They married?
They're spoken for.
Oh, just spoken for.
You had me scared.
I tell you, they're promised.
A lady can change
her mind, can't she?
Pay him no mind, girls.
Fred, put his things in the
wagon. Don't keep him waiting.
I'm in no hurry.
I got all afternoon.
You're wasting your time.
You won't find a girl
in this town to marry you.
Never set my mind to something
yet I haven't got.
Whether it's plowing
20 acres in a day
or dropping a tree
where I want it.
I'm here today to get me a wife.
I don't mean to go home
empty-handed.
You're all pretty,
fresh, and young.
I'll keep you in mind.
But I ain't deciding on nothing
until I look them all over.
[Whistling]
♪ Bless your beautiful hide,
wherever you may be ♪
♪ We ain't met yet,
but I'm a-willin' to bet ♪
♪ You're the gal for me
good morning, ma'am.
Mamma, mamma, papa wants you.
♪ Bless your beautiful hide,
you're just as good as lost ♪
♪ I don't know your name,
but I'm a-stakin' my claim ♪
♪ Lest your eyes is crossed
ha ha ha!
♪ Oh, I'd swap my gun,
and I'd swap my mule ♪
♪ Though whoever took it
would be one big fool ♪
Thanks, Adam.
♪ Or pay your way
through cookin' school ♪
♪ If you would say, "I do"
good morning, ma'am.
Good morning, backwoodsman.
Nice day for marrying.
That's a right good idea.
Oh, Lem, I thought
you'd never ask me.
♪ Bless your beautiful hide,
prepare to bend your knee ♪
♪ And take that vow
'cause I'm a-tellin' you now ♪
♪ You're the gal for me
♪ pretty and trim,
but kind of slim ♪
♪ Heavenly eyes,
but, oh, that size ♪
♪ She's got to be right
to be the bride for me ♪
♪ Bless your beautiful hide,
wherever you may be ♪
[dog barking]
Milly, a dozen men in here
are bellering for vittles
and you're chopping wood!
I'm coming!
♪ Pretty and trim,
but not too slim ♪
♪ Heavenly eyes
and just the right size ♪
♪ Simple and sweet ♪
and sassy as can be
♪ bless her beautiful hide
♪ yes, she's the girl for me
milly, milly, let's eat.
Come on. I'm dying of hunger.
You'll all eat.
Just give me time.
Ah, nobody can cook like milly.
When you gonna marry me?
Oh, next week, Sam.
She's gonna marry me,
ain't ya, milly?
What would your wife say?
Anything you'd like?
Could be, but first,
I'd better sample that cooking.
Oh, oh, oh!
Oh, Harry!
Oh, I am sorry.
That's all right, milly.
Awfully sorry.
That smells good enough to eat.
Tastes good, too,
so they tell me.
Got any ketchup handy?
My stew can stand
on its own feet.
Good?
Good.
[Moo]
My name's Adam Pontipee.
Odd name, I must say.
I live up the mountain.
Got a farm there.
Have you?
Good farm and a house on it.
There's timberland,
high grazing meadows,
sheep, milk cows,
50 acres of wheat.
Only thing it ain't
got is a woman.
How about it?
How about what?
I just told you.
How about marrying me?
[Continues milking cow]
Oh, I know it's kind
of short notice.
Back east, we would have met
of a Sunday leaving church.
Six months later,
I would have asked you,
could I walk you home?
Next 2, 3 years,
I would have set
in your front parlor
every Wednesday night.
I would have asked your
father to marry you.
But here, there's not time.
I've got to be home tonight
to tend to my stock.
It'll be another 5 months before
I get down again with my grain.
You going to keep me
waiting 5 months
just for your pride?
I'd have to finish my chores.
I knew it the minute
I set eyes on you.
You're the gal for me.
I'll go get cleaned up
and root out the preacher.
♪ Bless her beautiful hide,
wherever she may be ♪
Uh, where's
the preacher's house?
Down the street,
next to the church.
Thanks, pop.
♪ She's the gal for me
I'll say it plain, milly,
and to your face.
I don't like this marriage.
I don't know you or
anything about you,
and I feel responsible.
Milly's like a daughter to us.
We're her only family.
Reverend, since I came here,
you've been after me to marry.
"A girl had no right
to stay single," you said.
The country needed
to be settled.
We meant for you to marry
one of our young men.
You had your pick with them.
I tried.
Again and again, I tried.
I'd say yes to one of them,
but an awful sinking feeling
would strike me right here,
and I couldn't do it.
When I said yes to him,
I waited for that feeling,
but it didn't come.
I feel just fine.
I feel so good I could cry.
I think it's wonderful...
Love at first sight.
Alice, what kind
of talk is that?
You're determined, milly?
Yes, reverend.
Then step forward.
Take her hand in yours.
Repeat after me...
I, Adam Pontipee.
Take this woman to be
my lawfully wedded wife.
[Dog barking]
Where's she going?
Never did like them Pontipees.
Now I know why.
Maw, maw, he done it!
He got a wife!
[Gasp]
It's milly. It's indecent,
if you ask me...
One lone woman with
7 scroungy backwoodsmen.
♪ Bless your beautiful hide ♪
♪ Wherever you
I'm not much of a bride,
with only this for an outfit.
You'll find a trunk in the attic
belonging to my mother.
There's things,
if you're handy with a needle.
I'd like that.
I'd like to wear something
that belonged to your mother.
My mother left me these...
They're packets of seed
for a flower garden
she meant to plant.
My father left me these...
Plutarch's lives and the Bible.
He taught me to read by them.
Hope maybe someday
I can teach our...
How far is it up to the farm?
Oh, about 12 miles.
Imagine... on my way
to my own home.
I feel so wonderful
I could yell.
Then go ahead.
Hooray!
[Echoing]
Ha ha ha! That's echo pass.
It ain't safe to raise
your voice in the winter.
It might start an avalanche.
I cussed my horse too loud
one February.
We got snowed in till spring.
Most people think that
would be pretty lonely,
but I can stand some loneliness
after the inn.
Yeah.
I'd better water the horses.
Whoa!
My wedding bouquet.
Sorrel?
It makes real nourishing soup.
Ha ha ha ha.
Always back at the inn,
when I'd hear all the men
yellin for their dinners,
I'd think how wonderful
it would be
to cook and care for one man.
Just one man.
Now that it's happened,
I can't hardly
believe it's true.
Ahem.
♪ Ding, dong, ding-a-ling dong ♪
♪ Were the steeple bells ♪
♪ Ever quite as gay? ♪
♪ Wonderful, wonderful day ♪
♪ Bluebirds in the bluebells ♪
♪ Sing a song ♪ to
send me along my way ♪
♪ Wonderful, wonderful day ♪
♪ Though I've got to own up ♪
♪ I'm as grown-up as can be ♪
♪ Seems I've gone and flown up ♪
♪ To a bright, merry,
airy fairyland ♪
♪ And so you'll forgive me
♪ if I simply throw out
my chest and say ♪
♪ Beautiful, glorious
♪ heavenly, marvelous
♪ wonderful, wonderful day
♪ big clouds floatin' lazy
♪ like a Daisy in the sky
♪ big things to be doin'
by and by ♪
♪ Goin', slowin',
growin' things ♪
♪ Big love for my darlin' ♪
♪ As we share ♪ whatever
may come our way ♪
♪ Beautiful, glorious ♪
♪ Heavenly, marvelous ♪
♪ Wonderful, wonderful day ♪
[dog barking]
Whoa!
[Cow lows]
Oh, uh, this is
my brother Caleb.
How are you, brother Caleb?
This is my wife milly.
Your wife?
Well, I'll be a monkey's uncle.
Hey, eph, Dan, he done it!
He got married!
This is my brothers
Ephraim and Daniel.
Hiya, brother Ephraim,
brother Daniel.
Which one is Ephraim,
and which is Daniel?
Me. Me.
And this here is Benjamin.
How are you, brother Benjamin?
You didn't tell me
you had brothers.
It must have been
the wedding threw it
out of my mind.
You all live around here?
Not round... here.
Oh.
I guess I should have picked
some more sorrel.
Uh, this is the house.
[Cluck cluck]
[Squawking]
My, what a nice big room.
Well, it might need readying up
a bit. Now that you're here.
Come on.
Wake up and meet
your sister-in-law.
This is frank.
How are you, brother frank?
This here is Gideon.
You can drop that spoon.
We'll have some human cooking,
for a change.
Are there any more?
No. Gideon's the last born.
It'll take me a while
to put the right name
with the right brother.
Just remember your abc's...
Adam, Benjamin, Caleb, Daniel,
Ephraim, frank, and Gideon.
They're fine-sounding names.
Bible names.
That was maw's idea.
The abc's, that was pa's,
so he could keep track of us.
He was figuring on using
the whole 26 letters,
right down to Zachariah,
but when he got a look
at Gideon,
he chopped a tree
down on himself.
There's one of the names
in the Bible
I don't seem to remember...
Frank.
Is frank a Bible name?
That ain't his real name.
We just call him that for short.
His real name is... Aah!
Pay 'em no mind. I'll show you
around.
Up here's the bedroom.
Can't you stop them?
You'll get used to that.
Like I was saying...
Was it something I said?
No. Frank's touchy
about his name.
There was no "f" names
in the Bible,
so maw named him frankincense
because he smelled so sweet.
Like I was telling ya,
up there's the bedroom.
Down there's where
the boys bunk.
Follow me. I'll
show you the rest.
Uh, this is the washroom.
Me and the boys are
kinda hard on clothes
so there will be lots
of washing and mending, but...
Now that I'm here.
This is the kitchen.
You'll find flour on that shelf,
salt pork over there.
Get out of here! All of ya!
How do you expect her to get
supper with you underfoot?
Get out.
You, too, Gideon. Come on.
You'll find wood
down the path there,
but the water's right
outside the front door.
There's the dinner bell.
Ring it loud when you
get supper ready.
[Clanging]
Ow!
What'd you do that for?
You... all of you falling
on the food that way!
Haven't you any decency
to wait for grace?
Huh? No!
You don't even know
what I'm talking about!
Look at your brothers!
The vittles must be good.
All right.
If you're going
to act like hogs,
you can eat like hogs!
Oh!
Ha ha ha!
"Neither cast ye your pearls
before swine,
"lest they trample them
under their feet
and turn again and rend you."
[Ticking]
[Clock strikes]
It's about time
for you boys to
turn in, ain't it?
Got a big day of
plowing ahead tomorrow.
It's 9:00 already...
An hour past your bedtime.
Yours, too.
[Snickers]
Well, uh...
I guess I am getting
a mite sleepy, at that.
Milly: Who is it?
It's Adam, your husband.
Come in, Adam.
Good night, boys.
I, uh, thought you'd be in bed.
Did you?
It's been a right busy day.
You must be kind of
tuckered out.
That's right.
Shall I, uh, turn
down the covers?
You can if you like...
But I'm not going to bed.
You don't want a wife, Adam.
You want a cook,
a washerwoman... a hired girl.
Well, a hired girl's got a right
to her own sleeping place.
I reckon that's so.
In the wagon, you let me talk...
Make a fool of myself
talking about you and me.
You should have stopped me!
Maybe I should have,
but it sounded real pretty.
Besides, if I'd have
told you beforehand,
you might not have married me.
I wanted you
to marry me real bad.
Sure you did,
because you knew
I was young and strong
and there was
lots of work in me.
That's partly true.
It's a hard life out here
in the wilderness.
There's trees to be felled,
land to be plowed and fenced,
and stock to be fed.
A man wants a wife
who can work alongside of him.
Of course, if...
If she's got eyes
that are bluer than cornflowers
and hair the color
of wheat in the sunshine,
he counts himself
real fortunate.
I'll work alongside you, Adam...
But I'm not sleeping
alongside you.
She wants a drink of water.
She's thirsty.
[Gasp]
Have a drink.
What are you doing?
Bedding down for the night.
Don't know what
the birds see in it.
Somehow it just
don't seem fitting
for a bridegroom to spend his
wedding night in a tree.
It was your idea, not mine.
I guess I was pretty
mad, Adam, but...
I built up such
a store of dreams,
dreams about love
and... And marriage and such.
♪ When you're in love
♪ when you're in love
♪ there is no way on earth ♪
♪ To hide it
♪ when you're in love
♪ really in love
♪ you simply let
your heart decide it ♪
♪ With every sigh ♪
with every glance
♪ with every heartbeat,
you confide it ♪
♪ You'll want the world
to know it, too ♪
♪ When you're in love
♪ as I'm in love with you ♪
I know how it is
with your brothers,
you being the head
of the house and all.
I wouldn't want you
to lose face.
And, well,
all things considered,
maybe you'd better come back in.
[Rooster crows]
[Dog barking]
Bacon!
Fresh-made coffee!
Hot bread! It's milly cooking!
[Takes deep breath]
Adam must have told
her what was what.
It sure smells good.
I feel like I haven't
ate for years.
Where's my pants?
Where's my shirt and pants?
I'm looking for my own.
Who hid them on me?
All I've got is my boots.
Milly: Good morning,
my brothers.
If you're looking
for your outside clothes,
they're drying on the line.
I came in before and got them.
I couldn't get your inside
clothes, so I'll take them now.
Our underwear?
Your winter underwear
that you're sleeping in.
You might as well hand them over
'cause you're not gonna get
your clothes or food
until you're all
cleaned up and shaved.
Where's Adam?
We want to talk to Adam!
He's out plowing.
He had breakfast earlier.
I got hot muffins waiting,
crisp bacon, hot cakes, steak,
fired potatoes,
fresh-ground coffee.
Do I get that underwear,
or do I have to
come take it off you?
Don't listen to her.
She wouldn't dare.
Milly: Oh, wouldn't I?
All right, you'll get it.
I didn't know last night I'd
married
into such a handsome family.
You're mighty good-looking boys.
Well, you are,
every last one of you.
What have you been doing
hiding behind those whiskers?
Afraid some girl will see you
and run off with you?
Why haven't I seen you
at dances or cornhuskings
or at harvest time?
Don't you like girls?
We ain't never hardly seen one.
You've got a big sister now
that will see that you do.
You want to eat?
Well, then...
O lord, thou hast brought us
through desert,
mountain, and wilderness
to a good land of wheat and game
where we need never hunger.
We thank thee, o lord,
for thy loving care
and thy bounty. Amen.
Amen.
After you.
Thank you.
Frank.
Where you going, milly?
To town, Gideon.
The flour barrel's getting low,
and I've worn out
a broom and scrub brush.
I'll help you tote them.
What's going on?
We're going to town.
I'll help drive the horses.
I'll drive.
Hey, milly's going to town!
Let's go with them!
Whoa!
You boys set here and wait.
Gideon will help me.
And don't forget...
Mind your manners.
Hey, look... girls!
Quick. Say something.
Care for a chaw of tobacco?
Well, I never!
That oaf insulted us.
No such thing.
He just offered them a chaw.
It's darn good tobacco.
It is, huh?
Hey, it's us!
My window!
Stop it, Benjamin!
Stop it this minute!
Don't just stand there.
Do something.
What fer? There's only
3 little ones.
Stop it! Do you hear?
All right, milly.
It's stopped.
You get in that wagon.
Get!
What did I do wrong, milly?
Well, if you want to get a girl,
you got to learn
how to talk to her.
I'll show you.
I'm a girl.
You meet me at church.
You raise your hat.
What's the matter, Caleb?
My hair ain't combed.
Well, next, you got
to say something nice.
Gideon, say something nice.
Nice night for a coon hunt.
Ha ha ha!
You get out of here.
You're beating your head
against a stone wall.
You'll never make
Jack-a-dandies of them.
Pay him no mind.
You'll all be just fine.
It's a month before
the barn-raising and picnic.
Remember one thing.
You're going to have
a lot of competition
because every girl
has 5 or 10 fellas
buzzing round her.
We'll clean them
out first thing.
The whole lot of 'em.
No. That's one thing
you mustn't do.
If they want to act
like hyenas, let them.
You've got to be
above such things.
You gotta act gentlemanly
and well-spoken.
Show the girls
you have some etiquette.
Eti... what?
Like I showed you at the table.
When you meet a girl,
don't grab her like
she was a flapjack.
Hold off. Offer her your arm.
When you're alone,
steal your arm around her.
You got to court
a girl to get her.
You got to call her
my darling, my dear,
my precious, my pet.
♪ Going courting,
going courting ♪
♪ Oh, it sets your senses
in a whirl ♪
♪ Going courting,
going courting ♪
♪ Dudin' up
to go and see a girl ♪
♪ Oh, it's fun
to hunt and shoot a gun ♪
♪ Or to catch
a rabbit on the run ♪
♪ But you'll find
it's twice as sporting ♪
♪ Going courting is
this what you mean?
That's what I mean.
♪ Now, there's lots of things
you got to know ♪
♪ Be sure the parlor light
is low ♪
♪ You sidle up
and squeeze her hand ♪
♪ Let me tell you fellas
that it's grand ♪
♪ You hem and haw
a little while ♪
♪ She gives you
kind of half a smile ♪
♪ You cuddle up,
she moves away ♪
♪ Then the strategy
comes into play ♪
Ow!
Ha ha ha! See what I mean?
♪ Going courting,
going courting ♪
♪ If you find it hard
to break the ice ♪
♪ Going courting,
going courting ♪
♪ Here's a little
feminine advice ♪
♪ Roll your eyes
and heave a little sigh ♪
[sigh]
♪ Grunt and groan
like you're about to die ♪
Uh!
♪ That is what's known
as emoting ♪
♪ Going courting how
about sparking?
Parlor's darkened? Yeah.
And you're longing
for a fond embrace?
What about petting?
And sofa setting?
Suppose she slaps your face?
♪ Just remember
blessed are the meek ♪
♪ Don't forget
to turn the other cheek ♪
♪ Pretty soon,
you'll both be larking ♪
♪ Going sparking ♪ going dancing
brothers: Going dancing?
♪ At a fancy ball or minuet ♪
May I?
♪ Going dancing
♪ you'll impress them
with your etiquette ♪
Now you two try. Come on.
You mean men are
learning how to dance?
♪ Yes, it came direct
from Paris, France ♪
♪ It will help
with your romancing ♪
♪ Going dancing now
you follow us.
Turn. Down, up.
Come on. This way.
Step to the right
and then the left.
Make a turn.
Now weave in and out.
Hey, this is great!
I love dancing!
Ha ha!
I'm dancing!
I'm next.
Now, boys!
Yippee!
Oh!
Oh, boy!
Yee hee hee!
♪ Keep your dancing
♪ and hunting
♪ and shooting
♪ and fighting and trapping ♪
♪ 'Cause we're going courting
well, the cleanest
fingernails I ever saw.
What happened
to your thumb, Gideon?
I soaked it in lye. Took offen
the dirt all right.
Dang near took off
the nail with it.
Oh, I'm so proud of all of you.
Just remember...
Mind your manners
and be real gentlefolk.
And no fighting,
no matter what happens.
What's holding you up?
If we're going to
a barn-raising, let's go.
Come on.
Whoa.
Who are they?
I don't recall
seeing them before.
They're strangers to me.
7 of them!
All as tall as church steeples.
It's milly! Milly!
Where are you going?
To see milly.
I just love milly.
Looks like them
Pontipee brothers.
Milly!
Alice!
Mil, I've missed you so!
Milly, it's been months
since I've seen you.
I missed you all so much.
I baked some pies and such.
We'll take them over.
I'd be pleasured
if you'd allow me.
Why, thanks.
We'll all help.
I couldn't let a little
lady like you heft that.
Can we help?
Please, allow me.
If you'll just follow me.
To the ends of the earth.
Afraid that's all.
Sorry. That's all.
May I escort you back?
You know, you're the prettiest
girl I ever acquainted.
May I escort you
to the ball, ma'am?
It wouldn't hurt you
to learn some manners, too.
What do I need manners for?
I already got me a wife.
[Clanging]
Come on, everybody,
get your partners!
There's going to be dancing.
[Music starts]
Ha ha ha!
Hey!
[Girls squeal]
Faster.
Hey, attaboy, Carl!
[Cheers]
Woman: What happened?
Woman: I don't know.
Man: Take him, Dan.
Come on, Dan!
Get him.
Come on, Caleb!
All right, frank.
Come on, frank. Come on, frank.
You got it now.
[Cheers]
Ha ha ha!
Neighbors,
may I have your attention?
All you folk that came
from far and wide,
Henry wants me
to thank you men for
helping him raise his barn.
Thanks, folks.
And he thanks the ladies
for all the fancy vittles.
[Applause]
Since the barn's got four sides,
there will be four teams.
Whoever gets done first
wins the little heifer.
Henry, show them Annabel.
[Moo]
[Laughter]
Now get your teams set up,
and let's see who wins
the little lady.
Adam, we could
use her on the farm.
How about it, boys?
Mr. Perkins, put the 7 of us
brothers down for one team.
Milly says she's taken
a fancy to Annabel.
You hear, boys?
That was Adam Pontipee.
Last time he came to town he
bragged he always got
what he set out to get.
Danged if he didn't.
He's a hard one to beat,
I'm warning you.
Don't worry.
We'll handle him.
We got a team set up, Pete.
Here's your fourth, Pete.
Got your hammers?
Then take your positions.
The sooner you raise the barn,
the sooner you get the vittles.
[Shouting]
Pete: Are you ready?
Men: Yeah!
Let's go!
[Shouting]
[Dog barking]
Come on, Adam! Come on!
Ow!
Sorry. I shouldn't have
had my hand there.
What happened?
Nothing.
Caleb, get that board up there.
Ow!
Now what happened?
I stubbed my big toe.
Come on. Let's get going.
Frank, get those
sideboards up here.
Hurt yourself, frankincense?
Come on. Let's go.
What's the matter
with you boys today?
Just a little dizzy spell.
Hold it! Hold it!
He didn't drop that
hammer. He threw it.
We don't want no fights.
We promised milly.
Come on. We're behind now.
She's made you into mama's boys.
They're out to murder you,
and you apologize for living.
You're a disgrace
to the Pontipee name.
You're a bunch of Lily-livered,
chicken-hearted lickspittles.
Serves you right.
I hope they break your necks.
Come on, Gideon, let's go.
What are you doing that for?
He ain't done nothing!
Ha ha ha!
[Women screaming]
Oh!
Aah!
No!
Boys, boys, stop the fight!
Agh!
[Creaking]
[Laughing]
Witch Hazel.
Split lip.
Don't smile for a few days.
Next.
Two beefsteak. Frank.
A kick in the pants.
Next.
A loose tooth and swelled-up
knuckles.
It's a wonder you have
any teeth left at all.
Witch Hazel, please.
I'm sorry, milly,
but when that feller
took out after Adam...
I understand, Gideon.
You all did your best.
Good night, boys.
Good night, milly.
I... I feel
awful strange-like, milly. Here.
If it's what I think,
witch Hazel's not going to help.
Alice is sweet, isn't she?
Good night.
Well... What's the
matter with you?
Did somebody butt you
in the breadbasket?
No. I felt this way
even before the fight...
Ever since I seen Alice.
Adam... Yeah?
Do... Do you reckon I...
I could be in love?
Well, pa used to say
love is like the measles.
You only get it once.
The older you are, the tougher
it goes.
You ought to get it
kind of light.
Oh, I guess not.
Well, I don't know as I can
answer your question, Gideon,
but according to milly...
And she's had a heap
of book learning...
♪ when you're in love,
when you're in love ♪
♪ There is no way
on earth to hide it ♪
♪ When you're in love
♪ really in love
♪ you simply let
your heart decide it ♪
♪ How can you tell ♪
what's in its spell?
♪ How can you tell
until you've tried it? ♪
♪ Wait for that kiss
you're certain of ♪
♪ And let your heart decide ♪
♪ When you're in love ♪
Wow. I guess
I got the beginnings.
Them townspeople
will never let us
court them gals now...
Not after today.
If you don't get this one,
another one will come along.
One woman is pretty
much like the next.
Come on.
Let's go feed the stock.
[Nicker]
[Sheep bleating]
♪ I'm a lonesome polecat
♪ lonesome, sad, and blue
♪ 'cause I ain't got
no feminine polecat ♪
♪ Vowing to be true
♪ ooh ooh ooh ooh
♪ ooh ooh ooh ooh ooh ooh
ooh ooh ooh ♪
♪ Can't make no vows
to a herd of cows ♪
♪ Ooh ooh ooh ooh
♪ ooh ooh ooh ooh ooh ooh
ooh ooh ooh ♪
♪ I'm a mean old hound dog ♪
♪ Baying at the moon
♪ 'cause I ain't got no ♪
♪ lady friend hound dog ♪
♪ Here to hear my tune ♪
♪ Ooh ooh ooh ooh
♪ ooh ooh ooh ooh ooh ooh
ooh ooh ooh ♪
♪ A man can't sleep
when he sleeps with sheep ♪
♪ Ooh ooh ooh ooh
♪ ooh ooh ooh ooh ooh ooh
ooh ooh ooh ♪
♪ I'm a little old hoot owl ♪
♪ Hooting in the trees ♪
♪ 'Cause I ain't got no ♪
♪ Little gal owl fowl ♪
♪ Here to shoot the breeze ♪
♪ Ooh ooh ooh ooh
♪ ooh ooh ooh ooh ooh ooh
ooh ooh ooh ♪
♪ Can't shoot no breeze
with a bunch of trees ♪
♪ Ooh ooh ooh ooh
♪ ooh ooh ooh ooh ooh ooh
ooh ooh ooh ♪
♪ Ooh ooh ooh ooh
♪ ooh ooh ooh ooh
whew.
It is beautiful, isn't it?
Not to me.
I've seen too much of it.
I'm getting out.
Why, Benjamin!
I'm not gonna spend
another winter here,
snowed in for 3, 4 months.
What will we do without you?
I'd miss you so.
There's plenty here to take
care of the farm without me.
Adam!
Whoa. Yeah?
Benjamin says he's leaving.
What?
He says it's the winter,
but I know it's not that.
He's grieving for his girl.
They're all grieving.
Why should they grieve
for them girls?
They hardly saw them
more than once.
Once is all it takes,
if it's the right one.
And I had such dreams
about all of them living around,
dozens of babies and children,
visiting at christmastime
and birthdays.
If Benjamin goes,
another will go
and another.
I'll talk to them.
Whoa.
If you could just get
a look at yourselves...
You look like a bunch of
lovesick bull calves.
If you're so sweet on those
girls, do something about it.
Go marry them.
Sure, go marry them
as easy as that.
They'd never let us marry them.
Do like the romans did
with the sobbin' women.
Or sabine women.
Those romans were in
the same fix you're in.
They was opening up
new territory,
and women were scarce like here.
There was these sobbin' women.
What did the romans do?
They carried them off.
If you can't do as good as a
bunch of old romans.
You're no brothers of mine.
This being Oregon
and god-fearing territory,
you'd have to capture
a parson with them.
Did romans settle north of here?
No. This was in olden days.
Read about it here
in milly's book.
Oh, a book.
This is history.
This really happened.
♪ Tell you
about them sobbin' women ♪
♪ Who lived in the Roman days ♪
♪ It seems that they all
went swimming ♪
♪ While their men
was off to graze ♪
♪ Well, a Roman troop
was riding by ♪
♪ And saw them
in their me-oh-my ♪
♪ So they took them all ♪
♪ Back home to dry
♪ least that's
what Plutarch says ♪
♪ Oh, yes, them a-woman
was sobbin', sobbin', sobbin' ♪
♪ Fit to be tied
♪ every muscle
was throbbin', throbbin' ♪
♪ From that riotous ride
♪ seems they cried and kissed
and kissed and cried ♪
♪ All over
that Roman countryside ♪
♪ So don't forget that
when you're taking a bride ♪
♪ Sobbin', fit to be tied ♪
♪ From that riotous ride ♪
So then what happened?
Gather 'round. I'll tell you.
♪ They never did
return their plunder ♪
♪ The Victor gets all the loot
♪ they carried them home
by thunder ♪
♪ To rotundas small but cute ♪
♪ And you've never seen,
so they tell me ♪
♪ Such downright domesticity
♪ with a Roman baby
on each knee ♪
♪ Named Claudius and Brute
♪ oh, yes, them a-women
was sobbin', sobbin', sobbin' ♪
♪ Passing them nights
♪ while the romans
was going out hobnobbin' ♪
♪ Starting up fights is that so?
♪ They kept occupied
by sewing lots ♪
♪ Of little old togas
for them tots ♪
♪ And saying, "someday
womenfolk will have rights" ♪
♪ Passing all of their nights ♪
Just sewing.
♪ While the romans had fights ♪
Hey, listen to this.
♪ Now, when the menfolk
went to fetch them ♪
♪ The women
would not be fetched ♪
♪ It seems when
the romans catch them ♪
♪ Their lady friends
stay ketched ♪
♪ Now, let this be,
because it's true ♪
♪ A lesson to the likes of you ♪
♪ Rough them up like
them there romans do ♪
♪ Or else they'll think
you're tetched ♪
♪ Oh, yes, them a-women was
sobbin', sobbin', sobbin' ♪
♪ Buckets of tears mighty sad.
♪ Account of old dobbin'dobbin'
really rattled their ears ♪
And that ain't all.
♪ Oh, they acted
angry and annoyed ♪
♪ But secretly
they was overjoyed ♪
♪ You might recall that ♪
♪ When corralling your steer ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh,
them poor little dears ♪
Why are you sitting there?
Why don't we get them?
♪ Oh, yes, them a-women
was sobbin', sobbin', sobbin' ♪
♪ Weeping a ton
♪ just remember
what Robin, Robin, Robin hood ♪
♪ Would have done
♪ we'll be just like
them there merry men ♪
♪ And make them all merry
once again ♪
♪ And though they'll be
a-sobbin' for a while ♪
Oh, yes.
♪ We're gonna make
them sobbin' women smile ♪
Yeah!
Yee-ha! Ha ha!
Adam: Whoa, there.
Go get them. Be quiet about it.
I'll wait for you here.
[Sotto voce] Dan! Eph!
Your two's in here.
They're coming out.
Liza: Good night.
Aah!
You got mine!
Carl: How about my
good-night kiss, Sarah?
Sarah: Carl, you're
so persistent.
Be a sport. Just one kiss.
Maybe just a little one.
Close your eyes.
Why, Carl.
Frank!
Frank, what are you doing?
Whoa.
That-a boy. Get them in.
Come on, frank.
Hey, where's Gideon?
Meow. Meow.
I hear the cat outside.
I'll go, Mrs. Elcott.
Poor pansy, out on
a night like this.
Meow.
Meow. Meow.
M... Meow.
Hurry up, will you?
Meow. Meow. Meow. Meow. Meow.
Gideon: Meow. Meow. Meow. Meow.
Sounds like pansy has the croup.
I'll look out in back.
Meow. Meow. Meow. Meow.
It's all right, Alice.
She's here.
Oh! No! Aah!
Dorcas: Aah! Aah!
Jenny: Dorcas! Dorcas!
Pa! Pa, come quick!
That-a boy, Gideon.
Aah!
[Clanging]
What's keeping Benjamin?
I don't know.
[Clanging]
Quiet. Stay down.
Let's get out of here.
Let's go.
Adam: Hah! Hah! Come on!
Hah! Hah! Hah! Hah! Hah!
Hah! Hah! Hyah! Come on!
[Clanging]
Sarah kines... she's gone!
So is Alice.
Ruth Jensen, too.
Where's dorcas?
It was them pontipees.
The whole 7 of 'em jumped me.
Come on. We'll get them.
Hah! Giddy-up!
Hyah!
Stop that yelling!
We're coming to the pass.
Keep them quiet,
or we'll have an avalanche.
All right, whoa.
Slow down.
All right, here we go.
Hold your breath.
Aah!
Keep her quiet.
Hah!
Hurry up, Adam.
I hear them coming.
[Horse whinnies]
Adam: Whoa. Whoa.
Let them go.
Aah! Aah!
[Gunshots]
There she goes!
[Women crying]
[Men laughing]
♪ On account of those
dobbin', dobbin' ♪
♪ Really rattled their ears ♪
Whoa.
All right, boys. Line them up.
Oh, milly! Milly!
What have you done?
Oh, milly, help us.
Milly, we've been kidnapped.
Oh, milly.
Take these girls back at once.
We can't. There was
an avalanche.
They'll have to wait
till spring.
It was your idea, wasn't it?
I'd say it was more yours.
It came out of that book
about them sobbin' women.
What kind of men are you?
Are you animals?
Swooping down like hawks,
carrying off poor innocents.
They're just young boys in love.
Didn't you tell me today
you wanted them all married?
I want my mother.
Please don't cry, Alice.
I'm sorry, honest.
It was the only way I could
get to marry you. Adam!
We forgot to get the parson!
Don't worry, now.
Go on in the kitchen.
Nothing's gonna happen.
Cheer up. You got 'em,
haven't you?
Everything will be
all right. Milly.
This house is for the girls.
You won't set foot in it
as long as they're here.
You'll eat and sleep in the barn
with the rest of the livestock.
Now get out of here.
I'm ashamed of you.
Go ahead, boys, go on.
You, too.
You're taking this too hard.
Everything will work out fine.
We'll get a parson up here.
Do you think those girls
would marry them now?
You think because you
got a wife so easily,
'cause I didn't make
you court me,
that that's all there is to it?
I said yes because
I fell in love
the first time I saw you.
I thought it was the same with you.
Milly...
Think a wife's just to
cook and clean.
You got no understandings.
You got no feelings.
How could you do
a thing like this?
When I think of these girls
sick with fright
and their families
crazed with worry,
oh, I can't abide
to look at you.
[Door slams]
This isn't where we'd planned
on spending the night...
In a barn.
What do you think you're doing?
I'm getting out of here.
Going to the trapping cabin
for the winter.
You can't, Adam.
You can't stay up there alone.
The cabin's got enough
supplies for six months.
Don't go. It's us she's mad at.
Nah. Nah, it's more than that.
It's something
that goes a lot deeper.
Suppose you get sick
or break a leg,
up there alone?
The wolves are bad this year.
The wolves are like good company
after what I've been through.
[Crying]
There's nothing like
a nice hot cup of tea
when you're all tuckered out.
[Knock on door]
It's Gideon.
I got to speak to you.
No, milly! Don't!
Shh!
What is it?
It's about Adam. He's going away
up to the mountains,
up to the trapping cabin.
Can you hear me?
I hear.
Just ask him not to go.
Please, milly.
He's gotta learn that he can't
treat people this way.
Now, eph, let's start here.
Oh!
Ha ha ha!
Aah!
Ow!
What's the matter,
afraid of a little snowball?
Snowballs with rocks in them!
"Them poor little dears,
sobbin' buckets of tears."
"When the sign was given,
"drawing their swords
"and following
with a great shout,
they ravished away
the daughters of the sabine."
[Knock on door] Who is it?
It's me... Caleb.
What do you want?
It's a mighty cold night, milly.
I, uh, I need an extra blanket.
Go and get one.
"The custom continues today
"for the bride not of herself
to pass her husband's threshold,
"but to be lifted over
"in memory that the sabine women
were carried in by violence."
[Knock on door]
Who is it?
Benjamin.
What do you want?
My leg is feeling poorly.
I, uh... I need some liniment.
Go ahead, but be quick about it.
Yes, milly.
"Some say, too
the custom of parting,"
"the bride's hair with the head
of a spear was..."
[knock on door]
I got me a stiff neck.
That's enough of this nonsense!
We just wanted to...
Go to the barn and go to sleep,
or I'll bolt the door on you.
"Was... Was in token
of their marriages.
"It began at first by wars
and acts of hostility,
"and then," uh...
Doesn't it do anything
but snow up here?
We've had a blizzard every day
for the past 2 months!
I'm going crazy, shut
up in this house.
Alice, why don't you
read out loud?
No.
We've heard that book
3 times already.
Go on, read about
the sobbin' women!
Please, Alice?
I can't stand it again.
Then go get the dress
milly promised you,
and I'll fit it to you.
What's the use when there's
no one to see it.
No one!
I like that... we're no one!
Where's milly?
In the barn, hunting eggs.
I wish I could hunt eggs.
I love to hunt eggs.
Which boy slept in this bed,
do you suppose?
[Gasp]
Dorcas galen!
What's the matter?
Didn't you ever think of that...
That you're sleeping
in one of their beds?
[Gasps]
I never thought any such thing!
Liza, Alice!
Come away from that
window this minute.
I think it's disgusting,
standing where they can see you.
I notice you peek out
often enough
when you think no one's looking.
I never!
I saw you!
So did I.
You take that back!
[Shouting]
Don't you dare say
that about Martha!
What were you doing last night
out at the woodpile?
Oh, you!
Girls! Now, stop!
Girls! Girls!
Stop it this minute!
[Shouting]
Girls, please don't squabble,
not now. Not when I
need you so much.
I'm counting on all
of you to help me,
'cause I'm going to have a baby.
Milly!
Sit down! Get comfortable.
Are you all right?
I feel just fine.
You won't lift a finger.
We'll take over everything.
We'll do your chores,
cleaning, cooking, everything!
That'd be silly.
Where are you going?
I have a few things to do.
When's the baby coming?
Well, you have to be patient.
But when?
In the spring.
Oh!
I wish it was me.
Dorcas!
I always wanted to
be a June bride
and have a baby right off.
In the spring, maybe.
♪ Oh, they say
when you marry in June ♪
♪ You're a bride all your life ♪
♪ And the bridegroom
who marries in June ♪
♪ Gets a sweetheart for a wife ♪
♪ Winter weddings can be gay ♪
♪ Like a Christmas holiday ♪
♪ But the June bride
hears the song ♪
♪ Of a spring that lasts ♪
♪ All summer long ♪
♪ By the light
of the silvery moon ♪
♪ Home you ride ♪ side by side
♪ with the echo ♪ of
mendelssohn's tune ♪
♪ In your hearts as you ride ♪
♪ For they say
when you marry in June ♪
♪ You will always be a bride
♪ the day a maiden marries ♪
♪ Is the day she carries
through the years ♪
♪ The church
is full of flowers ♪
♪ Bridal showers are passé
♪ the groom's waiting
at the altar ♪
♪ Here comes the bride
♪ they're each promising
to love and obey ♪
♪ Best man is celebrating
♪ every bridesmaid's waiting
just to see ♪
♪ Which one of them will catch
the wedding bouquet ♪
♪ For they say
when you marry in June ♪
♪ You will always
♪ always be a bride
♪ in November,
the snow starts to fly ♪
♪ Piling up ankle-high
♪ come December,
it's up to your knee ♪
♪ Still the bride's
a bride-to-be ♪
♪ January, higher still
♪ to the parlor windowsill ♪
♪ February finds a drift
♪ and a storm that seems
never to lift ♪
♪ March comes in
like a lion, what else? ♪
♪ Still the snow never melts
♪ April showers will come,
so they say ♪
♪ But they don't ♪ and it's may
♪ you're about to forget
the whole thing ♪
♪ All at once ♪ one
day, it's spring
[sheep bleats]
♪ Oh, the barnyard is busy ♪
♪ In a regular tizzy ♪
♪ And the obvious reason ♪
♪ Is because of the season ♪
♪ Ma nature's lyrical ♪
♪ With her yearly miracle ♪
♪ Spring, spring, spring ♪
♪ All the henfolk are hatchin' ♪
♪ While their menfolk
are scratchin' ♪
♪ To ensure the survival ♪
♪ Of each brand-new arrival ♪
♪ Each nest is twittering ♪
♪ They're all baby-sittering ♪
♪ Spring, spring, spring ♪
♪ It's a beehive of budding
son and daughter lives ♪
♪ Every family
has plans in view ♪
♪ Even down in the brook,
the underwater life ♪
♪ Is forever
blowing bubbles, too ♪
♪ Every field wears a bonnet ♪
♪ With some
spring daisies on it ♪
♪ Even birds of a feather ♪
♪ Show their clothes off
together ♪
♪ Sun's gettin' shinery ♪
♪ To spotlight the finery ♪
♪ Spring ♪ spring, spring
♪ from his aerie,
the eagle with his eagle eye ♪
♪ Gazes down across
his eagle beak ♪
♪ And affixin' his lady
with a legal eye ♪
♪ Screams, "suppose we set
the date this week" ♪
♪ Yes, sirree, spring discloses
that it's all one supposes ♪
♪ It's a real bed of roses,
waggin' tails, rubbin' noses ♪
♪ Each day is mother's day,
the next is some other's day ♪
♪ When love is king...
Frank, Dan, Ben,
Caleb, everybody!
Milly's having
her baby! Come on!
Oh!
Oh, Liza, Martha,
Ruth, hurry! Hurry!
[Footsteps]
[Slapping]
[Baby crying]
I'm an uncle.
[Crying]
[Baby talking]
Ooh, ooh, ooh.
Adam! Adam!
Hey, hey! Gideon!
Couldn't stand the barn
any longer, huh?
I've come to get you, Adam,
to take you back with me.
Yeah... Well, milly has a baby.
It come day before yesterday.
Uh... I don't believe it.
Well, it's as true
as I'm standing here.
I don't believe it! Just one
of her tricks to get me back.
Tricks? Why, you lived
with milly as man and wife
and you don't know nothing about her.
She's got pride and she's spunky!
Why, she'd never bring
herself to ask you back.
She'd be wasting her breath.
I don't figure to go.
Not even to see the baby?
Your own kin?
Your own little girl?
A girl?
I might have known
she'd have a girl.
I'll be back
when the pass is open.
I'll stay away
till the shooting's over.
Adam...
You're my eldest brother.
And I've always looked up
to you, tried to ape you,
but today I'm ashamed for you.
Now I know you can lick me,
lick the tar out of me,
but I wouldn't
hold myself no kind of man
unless I showed you how I felt.
Why, you...
Now get!
The pass is open!
All able-bodied men gather
at the meeting house!
Bring your rifles, your sides, your
guns, axes, any kind of weapon!
The pass is open!
Are you ready, men?
[Cheering]
Let's go!
♪ Na, na, num, num,
na, na, num, num ♪
♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na, num
♪ na, na, num, num... [laughing]
Oh, Gideon!
Well, what are you staring at?
I told you I'd be back
when the pass was open.
The pass?
Oh, milly. Carl's there.
He'll kill...
Go upstairs, girls.
Go on. Quickly!
Let's get the guns.
Tell them to hitch up the wagon.
Wagon?
Put plenty of blankets
and straw in it. Go ahead.
Um, what do you call her?
Well, I was thinking
of some name like.
Hannah or hagar or hephzibah,
picking up where
your mother left off.
Hannah.
I got to thinking
up there in the mountains
thinking about the baby
about how I'd feel if
somebody came sneaking in
and carried her off.
I'd string him up
the nearest tree
shoot him down like I would
a thieving fox.
I thought about you too
while I was up there.
It seemed like I couldn't
get you off my mind.
Milly, when you're in love...
When you're really in love...
[Footsteps approaching]
The wagon's ready, Adam.
All right.
Now get the girls.
I want to take 'em back,
back to their families.
Oh, Adam...
Adam, you will be careful?
We're not letting you
you take 'em back, Adam.
We talked it over amongst us
and we're all agreed.
They ain't going.
They're our girls now.
I say I'm taking 'em back.
I'm still head of this family.
Then I reckon
you'll have to show me.
Likewise.
What do I have to do,
beat some sense
into your dumb heads?
Don't you know taking 'em
back's the only way
you're ever gonna get 'em?
The whole town's coming up here.
Let 'em come.
We'll fight 'em all.
Sure you will.
And who will you be fighting?
The girls' kinfolk.
Someone's bound to get hurt.
A father, a brother maybe.
Think the girls gonna
marry you after that?
Adam's right.
I stand with Adam.
Well, don't stand too close.
Adam. Adam, the girls have gone.
They've run away!
Go get them. Get them back.
Go on! Go on!
Come back here!
[Crosstalk]
Hiyah!
[Whistles]
Dorcas, come back.
You'll get hurt.
Let's keep it quiet.
They can hear us from here.
We'll creep up on 'em.
Alice! Please, Alice!
Daniel: Martha, where are you?
Come back, Martha.
Don't run away.
[Alice yells]
I'm not going back!
I want to stay here with you!
You've got to.
It's the only way.
Whoa! Whoa!
It's Alice!
Come on, Ruth.
Aah! Aah!
[Women screaming]
Hey, there they are!
Aah! Aah!
Stop! Let me go!
No! No! No!
Don't! You'll hit dorcas.
[Hannah crying]
Oh, no... Not that!
[Hollering, yelling]
Grab her dress, Ben!
Man: Get a ladder!
Man: Ruth! Ruth!
Please! No, please!
Why, pa!
Alice.
Oh!
Hey, get up! Get up!
What are you going to do to him?
We're gonna hang him
with the rest of 'em
from the nearest tree.
Oh, no...
Just a minute! Just a minute!
Before we go, there's one thing
we've got to know
from our girls.
Girls! Girls!
Now, reverend, what is it
you want to know?
We're all fathers here,
and we love you,
so don't be afraid to answer.
A while back I heard a wee babe
crying in the house.
Whose is it?
Don't be afraid to tell.
All: Mine!
Do you, Alice, Ruth, Martha,
Liza, Sarah, dorcas
take these men to be
your lawfully wedded husbands?
Women: We do.
And do you, Benjamin,
Caleb, Daniel, Ephraim,
frankincense, Gideon
take these girls
to be your lawfully
wedded wives?
Men: We do.
I now pronounce you
men and wives.
synced by
~ cotangent ~