There are more people alive now
than have died in all of human history.
But the number of dead people
is increasing.
One day, there isn't going to be
any room to bury anyone any more.
So, what about skyscrapers
for dead people that were built down?
They could be underneath the skyscrapers
for living people that are built up.
You could bury people
100 foors down...
...and a whole dead world
could be underneath the living one.
...father of our Lord, Jesus Christ,
who has blessed us all with the gift of...
Doesn't anybody know
there isn't anybody in the coffin?
We should've filled it with his shoes
or something.
It's like a pretend funeral.
For a goldfish or something.
This is just what it is, Oskar.
It doesn't make sense.
What if you could ride an elevator
down to visit your dead relatives...
...just like you take the bridge
to see your friends in Brooklyn...
...or the ferry to Staten Island?
Dad once told me that New York
used to have a Sixth Borough...
...right next to Manhattan.
But you can't visit that any more...
...because it floated away
and no one knows where it is.
Okay, you think you're so smart?
Let's find the Sixth Borough.
Okay.
And? What?
"And what" what?
What am I supposed to find?
What are the clues?
Mm.
He shrugged his shoulders like he had
no idea what I was talking about.
I loved that.
This was my favorite game
Dad and I would play.
We called it
"Reconnaissance Expedition. "
I found something from every decade
in the 20th Century.
You rack.
He racks!
The search for the Sixth Borough
was the greatest expedition ever.
All right, I've got
amateur entomologist, Francophile...
...amateur archeologist,
computer consultant.
Why "amateur" everything?
It's a compliment.
Amateur pacifist?
"Pacifist."
- Amateur inventor.
Inventor. Goad one.
Okay, you're all set.
Dad designed my expeditions
so I would have to talk to people...
...which he knew
I had a hard time doing.
What do you want?
What do you think?
Could be useful.
Can't you even tell me
if I'm an the right track?
But if you don't tell me,
haw can I ever be right?
Well, another way of lacking at it is...
...haw can you ever be wrung?
Mm?
There you go. Thank you very much.
Central Park didn't use to be
where it is now.
Dad said it used to rest
in the center of the Sixth Borough.
Enormous hooks were driven
deep into the ground...
...and the park was pulled by
all the people of New York...
...like a rug across the flour,
from the Sixth Borough into Manhattan.
I found something. Over!
What area, Oskar? Over!
Zane E-3. Over!
Dad said it's only because
of the clues in Central Park...
...that we know
the Sixth Borough existed at all.
Where's this from?
Oh, that was my father's.
Grandma gave it to me when I was little.
Never had much use for it.
What's this?
Oh. Grandma's old home movies.
Haven't seen these in years.
Do you know what your father
lacked like?
Nope, not a clue.
Here's what I do know:
He was from Dresden,
which was in Germany...
...went through some really bad stuff...
...and decided he wasn't up
to having a family.
That's it?
- That's it.
Did you always want to be a jeweler?
I might have liked
to have been a scientist.
I'll never know.
Why is that?
Because I'm a jeweler
Strawberry Fields.
Belvedere Castle.
What's he lacking far?
Well, when he finds it, let him tell you.
Gonna send him all aver the park...
...and he'll have to talk to
every single person he meets.
It'll be the greatest
Reconnaissance Expedition.
Don't make it so hard an him.
If it was easy,
this wouldn't be worth finding.
And what kind of adult
is he gonna turn into?
I don't know.
That's what I have you far.
He'll be one of those guys who falls
in love with the very first bassy...
- Watch it.
- I mean, beautiful...
...flaxen-haired lady
who tells him what to do.
- Like write the check?
- Oh...
- Haw much?
- It's the last one. It's 71.40.
- $11.40.
- Where are you going?
Bedtime!
Was there really a Sixth Borough?
Well, as with anything, if you want
to believe, you can find reasons ta.
What reasons?
The clues, of course.
What clues?
What clues? The clues!
The peculiar fossil record
of Central Park.
The incongruous pH balance
of that reservoir.
And that brings us to the swings.
According to the paper of record, ahem
...a note was found beneath
one of those swings in Central Park.
And because of many scientific tests
...which you are tan young
and I am tan simple to understand...
...they were able to determine
that the note must have been written...
...in the Sixth Borough.
What did it say?
What a fantastic question.
Let's find cut.
Ah... It doesn't say.
It ought ta, but it doesn't.
- Can I see that?
- You want to see what?
Wanna see this? Na?
That was the last conversation
we ever had.
- Give it!
- It's behind you, behind you! Hold an.
The next time I heard
my dad's voice...
...was when I got home from school
that morning on the worst day.
Spaz!
Because of what was going on,
they let us out of school early.
Again, that's the incident,
that's what we are hearing.
This is terrible.
You're not supposed to smoke in the lobby.
You'll get in trouble.
There's no such thing as trouble today.
Where are your parents?
Is anybody downtown?
My mom's at work.
My dad's at a meeting somewhere.
Anyway, it's none of your business,
dip shiitake.
Eff you, Oskar.
Succotash my ball sack.
Oh, Gad.
Message one, September 11th, 8:56 a.m.
Are you there? Hello?
If you're there, darling, pick up.
Ugh. I just tried the office,
but no one was picking up
Uh, listen, uh, something's happened.
I'm okay.
They're telling us to stay where we are
and wait for the fireman.
I'm sure it's fine.
I'll give you another call
when I have a better idea
of what's going on.
I wanted to let you know that I'm okay
and not to worry...
...and I'll call again soon.
All right, bye-bye.
Message two, September 11th, 9:12 a.m
Are you there? Are you there?
It's me again.
Hello?
I was hoping you would be home.
I don't know if you heard about what happened...
...but I wanted you to
know that I'm okay.
Everything is fine. We're still waiting
to find out what we're supposed to do.
It's pretty chaotic. Firemen
are supposed to be coming. What...
If the sun were to explode...
you wouldn't even know
about it for eight minutes...
...because that's how long it takes
for light to travel to us.
For eight minutes,
the world would still be bright...
...and it would still feel warm.
It was a year since my dad died...
...and I could feel
my eight minutes with him...
...were running out.
Democrats argued
that Estrada is too conservative...
...and not answering all
of their questions.
Estrada was first nominated
for the position in May, 2001.
The Bush administration has asked for a 4.2
percent increase in military spending...
...from 365 billion dollars
to 380 billion dollars.
That figure does not include...
I hadn't gone into
my dads closet since the worst day.
Mom hadn't touched his stuff.
It was all there.
Oskar! You okay?
This is Oskar Schell.
Grandma? Grandma, are you awake?
Over.
Grandma?
It's Grandma. Uh, what is it, sweetheart?
Can't you sleep?
Do you want me to come over? Over.
Did Dad ever mention a special key
to you, Grandma? Over.
A special key?
I don't think so, no.
A special key? What for?
What was this special key for?
Over.
Is the Renter home? Over.
The Renter? No, no,
he's never home this early. Over.
Grandma had rented a room to a man...
...three weeks after the worst day.
Why is the Renter's dour always
closed? And why can I never meet him?
He likes quiet.
Why can't you tell me
anything about him?
He's someone I knew in the old country.
Now play.
Haw long will he be here?
He never stays any place for lung.
Is he dangerous?
If you ever see him, don't say anything.
He can get very angry. New play.
What have you found, Oskar? Over.
Oskar, are you still there?
Oskar?
It's for some kind of lockbox
It's not like any of these.
It's thicker, harder to break.
But it's not for a fixed
safe, I don't think.
Could be a safe deposit box,
post office box.
It's old. Maybe 20, 30 years old.
Haw can I find the company
that made it?
Anyone could've made it
Then haw do I find the lack that it fits?
I'm afraid I can't help you there, unless you
wanna try it in anything you come across.
You never know what a key's gonna fit.
There are a million different possibilities.
That's what I love about keys.
They all open something.
Just one.
Shouldn't you be in school?
It's Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. Day.
Lie number two
I started counting my lies earlier that
morning when I told Mom I had a fever.
I don't wanna potentially infect
a multitude of people at school.
I could be a walking pathogen
I thought Martin Luther King's birthday
was in January.
It used to be. They changed it.
That was lie number three.
Hold an, Oskar.
Who's "Black"?
On the envelope?
Anybody you know?
Could be somebody who knows
something about the key.
Thanks for being
such a great locksmith.
What do you need these far?
A project an the census.
Lie number four.
Why aren't you in school?
- They said I know tan much already.
- Ah.
Black, Black, Black.
Well, "Black" was definitely a person.
Probably.
If "Black" was a person, he or she
must have known Dad somehow.
Faur-hundred-seventy-two.
But how?
And how was I going to find him/her?
Was this a Reconnaissance
Expedition?
Lagos, Nigeria. And it drifted...
Dad's expeditions
always included a journey.
...2278.3 nautical miles.
Brazil!
And he always planned them,
down to the smallest details.
Five miles an hour.
Seven hundred.
What else could it be?
If there was a key,
there was a lock.
If there was a name,
there was a person.
I'm home.
There had to be a lock.
I would find it because
he wanted me to find it.
Q-56. Q-56. Q-56.
And I would find it because it was the only
way I could stretch my 8 minutes with him.
Maybe I could stretch them forever.
I put together a backpack of vita!
Things I would need for my survival.
An Israeli gas mask Grandma bought me
two weeks after the worst day.
My tambourine to help keep me calm.
Binoculars, obviously.
I had to travel light
to be as quick as possible.
My expedition journal.
My father's father's camera.
A Brief History Of Time, by Stephen
Hawking, that my dad used to read to me.
Cell phone.
Fig Newtons, which I love.
The key, obviously.
And my father's message
to not stop looking.
And I wouldn't, not ever.
Hey.
Where you going?
Out.
Where?
I told you, to the comic book
convention with Minch. Be back later.
Lie number five.
Except for the "be back later" part.
Well, leave your cell phone on.
Check in with me every hour, okay?
I mean it.
I didn't know what
was waiting for me.
Although my stomach hurt
and my eyes were watering...
...I made up my mind that nothing,
nothing was going to stop me.
Not even me.
First up, Abby Black,
Fort Greene, Brooklyn.
Because public transportation
makes me panicky, I walked.
I've always had a hard time
doing certain things.
The elevator works, genius.
I know, retard.
But the worst day
made the list of things a lot longer.
- Old people...
- Ah!
...Running people...
...airplanes...
...tall things...
...things you can get stuck in.
Loud things.
- Screaming, crying.
- Aah!
- People with bad teeth...
- Ha-ha-ha!
...Bags without owners, shoes without
owners, children without parents...
...ringing things, smoking things,
people eating meat...
...people looking up.
Towers, tunnels, speeding things...
...loud things, things with lights,
things with wings.
Bridges make me especially panicky.
- Come on, try.
- I can't try.
If you don't try, you'll never know.
- So try.
- Don't be disappointed with me!
Come on. Take your juice
You know, Grandma brought me
to these swings.
My favorite...
...was one, two...
...the third from the right...
...because I thought it would go higher
than any other one.
So when everyone had gone home...
...I'd swing.
It was just me and the swings.
I'd do a lot of thinking up here,
especially when I learned how to pump
I would go as high as I could go...
...until I couldn't go any higher...
and then I would jump
Ah! And for a moment,
I would feel as free as a bird.
You should give it a whirl, Oskar.
It might change the way
you lack at things.
It's not safe.
You don't have to jump.
Can we go home now?
Fort Greene.
Fart Greene!
Fart Greene! Fart Greene!
What are you doing?
- Hello. My name is Oskar Schell.
Did you know my father,
Thomas Schell?
- You are Abby Black?
- Uh, yeah.
I'm sure people
tell you this constantly...
...but if you lack under
"incredibly beautiful" in the dictionary...
...there's a picture of you.
Abby, I'm trying to say something here.
- What are you doing?
- Would it be okay if I came in?
- New is really not a good time.
- Why not?
I'm in the middle of something.
I'm going upstairs to get this dune.
- Me tan.
- And you can do whatever...
What kind of something?
- Is that any of your business?
- Is that a rhetorical question?
I had to get in there.
I'm extremely thirsty!
Lie number seven.
What do you want to drink?
Iced coffee with half-and-half, please.
You coming?
I love this.
- So did I.
- Haw much do you know about elephants?
Hardly anything.
I know quite a lot
Loxodonta Africana
There's this woman who spent
the past 10 years in the Conga...
...making recordings of elephant calls
to learn haw they communicate.
Abby! Where is everything?
This past year, she started to play them
back to the elephants.
What's fascinating
is that she played back...
...the call of a dead elephant to family
members, and they remembered.
They approached the Jeep,
the speaker.
I wander what they were feeling
when they heard those calls.
I don't know.
I'm walking out of here. I will
call you back in 15 minutes, all right?
Did they cry?
Only humans can cry tears,
did you know that?
Even the elephant
in the picture is crying.
It looks like it, but it was probably
manipulated in Photoshop.
Don't cry.
Hey, Bab, haw are you?
I'm great, I'm great.
How's the family? Awesome.
We're awesome, we're doing great.
So listen. Meet me at the office
at 3:00, okay?
- Who's that?
- My husband.
You must think this is very add.
Oh, I think a lot of things are odd
People tell me I'm very add all the time.
I gut tested once to see
if I had Asperger's disease.
Dad said it's for people who are smarter
than everybody else but can't run straight.
Tests weren't definitive.
Are you sure you didn't know him?
Thomas Schell?
He was in the building.
In 9/11.
I'm trying to find a lack for this key
that was in the envelope...
...that once belonged to my father.
I'm sorry, I don't know anything
about the key or your father.
Can I barrow that?
You're welcome to it.
I thought you really liked it
Lats of things will be different
around here.
Can I kiss you?
You're a sweet bay, but I don't think
that would be a good idea.
Can I take your picture
so I can remember you?
Haw was the comic convention?
Were you there the whale day?
Can you unlock the dour, please?
Oskar, can you open the dour, please?
Oskar?
Do you hear me, Oskar?
Let me in, please.
Oskar, please, let me in.
Why do you wanna came in?
Ta tell you that I love you.
Look, I was hoping you would be home.
I don't know if you
heard about what happened...
...but I wanted you to know
I'm okay.
Everything is fine. We're still waiting
to find out what we're supposed to do.
It's pretty chaotic. Firemen are
supposed to be coming. What...
Message three,
September 11th, 9:58 a.m.
Having survived
what is an extraordinary event...
...the collapse of two towers
As we said earlier in our report,
110 stories each.
I will tell you that what fell...
Oskar?
Oskar!
Are you all right?
Yeah.
They let you out of school early.
Do you know what happened?
Yeah.
Your mother will be home scan.
You want to just wait here
until she comes?
I guess so.
Do you want me to wait here with you?
It's okay.
You're sure?
Positive.
Oskar. Oskar!
Did your fa... Did your father call?
Are there any messages
an the machine?
Thank you.
All circuits-
- Oh!
All circuits are busy now.
Will you please...
Will you pl...
Please, please.
Sorry, your call did not go through.
Will you please try your call again?
All circuits are busy now.
Will you please...
Okay. Okay.
Sorry, due to heavy calling, we cannot
complete your call at this time.
Mam, I don't know,
I've already told you everything I know.
Hospitals, the police,
and any number I can find.
I only missed one of the calls.
Na, I don't want you to came aver.
I don't want to make any of this any bigger
for Oskar than it already is.
Uh, I'll call you if I need you, okay?
Recording.
Hi, you've reached the Schell residence.
Today is Tuesday, September 11th.
Here's today's fact of the day:
It is so cold in Yakutia,
that breath instantly freezes...
...with a crackling sound they call
"the whispering of the stars".
Hi, you've reached the Schell resid...
Now no one will
ever have to listen to them like I did.
Just like nothing ever happened.
Every time I left our apartment,
I became a little lighter...
...because I was getting
closer to Dad.
But I also got a little heavier,
because I was further from Mom.
Why are you lacking at me like that?
- Like haw?
- Like I did something wrung.
- Do you have your cell phone?
- Right here.
I love you.
Maybe she was waiting
there until I left.
Or maybe she'd already walked away.
Maybe she was just talking too quietly
for me to hear.
Hazelle Black
lived in Hamilton Heights.
Gonna worry about
Came an, came an.
If you know the Lord is keepin' you
Why don't you sing and shout?
Hey!
Dear Gad, I just ask that
you would watch aver little Oskar...
...and I pray, ah, Gad,
for a miracle for him.
And that you keep him safe and in
your loving arms as he goes an his way.
Amen.
Remember, every day is a miracle.
I don't believe in miracles.
Finding what this key fits...
would be a miracle
I started with
a key with no lock
And I designed a system
I thought fit the problem.
I broke everything down
into the smallest parts...
...and tried to think of each person
as a number in a gigantic equation.
It could be for a safe deposit box
or a lockbox.
It's old. Can I try it to see
if it fits something?
But it wasn't working.
Because people aren't like numbers.
They're more like letters.
And those letters
want to become stories.
And Dad said that stories
need to be shared.
That's it, leg, leg, leg, leg!
I had anticipated a six-minute visit
with each person named Black...
...but they were never just six minutes.
Everyone took more time
than I had planned for...
...to try and comfort me
and make me feel better about my dad.
And to tell me their stories.
But I didn't want to feel better
and I didn't want friends.
Tae Kwon Do, museum,
comic back convention.
I just wanted the lock.
Paint two five divided by 65...
...156 days divided by 52
equals three years.
I wasn't getting any
closer to my dad.
I was losing him.
What are you, some kind of asshole?
Dickass!
Shiitake! All of you
in this stupid fukozowa building!
It must be a very confusing day.
I'll call you right back.
Message four, Septem...
Oskar, what's wrung?
Do you promise not to bury me
when I die?
It's the middle of the night, Oskar.
Do you promise not to bury me
when I die?
You are not going to die.
You are going to live a lung, long life.
You sure you love me?
Completely sure.
Then put me in one of those
mausoleum thingies above the ground.
Oh.
Okay, we need to talk.
About my mausoleum?
Na.
About what's been going an.
Why do you find it so hard
to talk to me?
In case you haven't noticed,
half the time, you're asleep.
And the other half the time,
you forget the first half.
You're what they call in the law
"in abstentia". An absent parent.
- That was mean.
- Which part?
All of it.
Dad used to say,
"The truth will set you free."
Well, Dad's not here.
- It's just the two of us.
- More like one and a quarter of us...
- ...to be mathematically accurate.
- Don't walk out of this roam, Oskar!
- What if I die tomorrow?
- You're not going to die tomorrow.
Dad didn't think he was
gonna die tomorrow either.
- It's not gonna happen to you.
- How do you know what's going to happen?
You know nothing.
You buried an empty box!
That's not the paint!
His memory is there!
It's exactly the point. Dad was just cells.
Now they're on rooftops, and the rivers...
Oskar!
...And the lungs of millions of people
who breathe him every time they breathe!
- That's not haw it works!
- Haw do you know haw it works?
You don't know anything
about atoms or molecules.
He might even be part of the
dag shit in Central Park!
That is enough. Stop it.
Excuse me, dag feces.
- Stop it!
- But it's the truth!
Why can't I say the truth? Just because
Dad died doesn't mean you can be illogical.
- It has to make sense!
- Nat everything makes sense, Oskar!
There's not an answer for everything!
You're just stupid!
It's completely nonsensical!
It's just a box! An empty box!
I know it's an empty box! I know this.
But I did it for me, and I did it for you
so we could at least try...
...and say goodbye to him...
...because he's gone, Oskar,
he's gone and he's not coming back.
Never.
I don't know why a man flew a plane
into a building.
I don't know why my husband is dead.
But no matter haw you try, Oskar,
it's never gonna make sense...
...because it doesn't,
it doesn't make sense!
Fukozowa you!
You don't know anything!
Why did you lie to me?
What are you talking about?
Where were you?
Where was I when?
That day, the worst day.
You know I was at work.
There was no one here.
I wish I had been.
But it wasn't possible.
You should've made it possible!
I can't make the impossible possible.
I wish it were you.
I wish it were you in the building
instead of him.
So do I.
I didn't really mean that.
Yes, you did.
Ga back to bed.
- Hey.
- Linda?
Yeah, I've been trying to reach you.
I'm an my way home. I'm coming home.
Thomas, can you hear me?
Yeah, I can hear you.
Ugh, this is unbelievable.
Are you watching this?
Listen to me, other people want to use the
phone, so I don't have too much time.
Listen to me, I'm gonna be home
in about 20 minutes.
No, you listen to me.
I'm in the World Trade Center.
What do you... What do you mean,
you're in the World Trade Center?
I had a meeting.
But I'm gonna be okay.
They're telling us to stay where we are.
We broke a window to let in some air.
Where are you?
I'm on the 106th? oor.
There's about 50 of us up here.
You... You listen to me,
you come home right now
It's gonna be fine.
You're gonna be fine.
- No..
- Where is Oskar?
Oskar's an his way home, but you listen
to me, you came home right now.
I will.
I will call and I will tell him.
Tell him what?
I'll... I'll tell him,
ahem, what's happening.
I'll tell him what's happening.
We've been told to wait where we are.
The firemen are on their way.
And we're all fine. We've been told to wait.
Thomas?
- That's what we got to do.
- Thomas...
Okay?
Na, it's not okay. Listen to me.
- Yeah.
- Thomas.
You need to listen to me.
Here's what you're gonna do.
You need to find a stairwell.
Do you hear me?
- Yes.
- Find the stairs and you came home.
Linda, honey, I've gotta go.
Other people need to use the phone.
I'm gonna be fine.
You're gonna be fine.
Stop saying that. Just find the stairs.
Linda, listen to me.
You do everything to make my life better.
I want you to know that
I absolutely love you.
I absolutely love you
Don't stop talking to me.
Just stay talking to me.
I'm gonna try to call you again
in a few min...
Please, just stay talking to me...
This is unconfirmed,
but we are getting information...
...from an employee
of United Airlines.
Again, we want to emphasize this is
unconfirmed, but there is speculation...
Grandma, are you awake?
Over.
Grandma, please wake up. Over.
Please.
Over.
Grandma?
I know someone is in there.
I won't hurt you. I'm only 4 years old.
Lie number 64.
Who are you?
I'm Oskar Schell, Grandma's grandson.
Do you know where my grandma is?
Out this time of night?
Do you know where?
It's kind of a matter of life and death.
Are you a stranger?
Technically?
I wouldn't go into a stranger's bedroom.
Haw came you don't speak?
Are your vocal cards
damaged or something?
Or did something scare you to death?
Coal.
When was the last time you spake?
Do you ever try to talk?
Why don't you try to say
something to me?
Ga an.
"My name is the Renter."
Do you have a criminal record?
Mm. Maybe you hurt people for a living?
Well, what's your story then?
I had to tell someone.
I couldn't keep it a secret any more.
Can I tell you my story?
My father died at 9/11.
After he died, I wouldn't go
into his roam for a year...
...because it was tan hard
and it always made me wanna cry.
But one day, I had completely heavy
boots and I went into his room anyway.
I miss doing Tae Kwon Do with him
because it made me laugh.
When I went into his closet
where his clothes and stuff were...
...I reached up to get his old camera
with the brawn case...
-and I broke a blue vase.
Inside was an envelope
with "Black" written on it.
And I knew that Dad had left something...
...somewhere for me
that the key opened and I had to find
So I take it to Walt the locksmith-
- I get from Stan the doorman...
Some kind of lockbox
-for all the five boroughs.
I count there are 472 people
with the last name "Black."
There are 215 different addresses.
Some of the Blacks live together, obviously.
I calculate if I go to two
every Saturday plus holidays...
...minus my Hamlet school play rehearsals,
it'll take me about three years...
...ta go through all of them. But that's what I'll do.
Ga to every person named Black...
...and find out what the key fits
and what Dad needed me to find.
The very best possible plan.
I divided the people by zones and
I really had to tell my mother another lie.
She wouldn't understand
haw I need to find what the key fit...
...that would help me
make sense of things...
...like him being killed by people
who didn't even know him at all!
And I see some people
who don't speak English...
Hazelle Black, who's all prayered up
and spake to Gad.
If she spoke to God, how come she
didn't tell him not to kill her son...
...not to let people
fly planes into buildings
Maybe she spake to a different Gad
than them!
I meet a man, who is a woman who
is a man, a woman all at the same time
I didn't wanna get near him/her,
because she/he scared me...
...because she/he was so different.
I still wandered if she had a VJ
or penicillin, but what does it matter?
What would this place be like
if everybody had the same haircut?
I see Mr. Black, who hasn't heard
a sound in 24 years.
Which I can understand,
because I miss Dad's voice that much.
Like when he would say
"Are you up yet?" or...
Let's go do something.
I see the twin brothers
who paint together.
And there's a shed that just has
to be a clue, but it's just a shed!
And Astrid Black,
who has the same drawing...
...of the same person
over and over and over again!
Boris Black, the doorman, who was once
a schoolteacher in Russia...
...but now says his brain is dying.
Ramos Black, who has a coin collection...
...but doesn't have enough money
to eat every day!
Alan Black has a view of Gramercy Park
but not a key to it...
...which he says is worse
than looking at a brick wall.
I feel like I'm looking
at a brick wall...
...because I tried the key
in 148 different places...
...but the key didn't fit
and open anything Dad needed me to find.
So that I'd know without him
everything is all right.
Then let's leave it there.
I still feel scared every time
I go into a strange place.
I'm so scared I have to hold myself around
my waist or I think I'll just break apart!
But I never forget what I heard him
tell Mam about the Sixth Borough:
That if things were easy to find...
They wouldn't be worth finding.
But I'm still scared every time I leave
home, every time I hear a door open.
And I don't know a single thing
that I didn't know when I started...
...except I miss my dad
more than ever...
...even though the whale paint
was to stop missing him at all!
It hurts tan much.
Sometimes I think I might do
something really bad.
Like you to what?
No way. Absolutely not. No, no, no.
Sure. Next Saturday, 1 a.m.
I got there 23 minutes,
37 seconds early just in case.
I didn't know if I
wanted him to be there.
I didn't even know
if! didn't want him to be there.
I'd give it the day to find out.
If you're coming with me,
there are rules.
You are allotted two bathroom breaks,
one 19-minute stop for eating.
And sightseeing is strictly prohibited...
although sites of historical merit
may be noted.
Also, there's a list of 15 simple questions
about yourself I'd like you to answer.
Came an.
Rule number four is keep up.
I can't stop and wait every two minutes.
Jean Black is in Zane H,
map grid AQ-16.
It's in the Rockaways, 11.3 miles
This way.
I don't take the train. It's not safe.
It's an obvious target.
All public transportation is.
You can get blown to pieces
by people who don't even know you.
Oh, nu.
He said: "I can't walk that far."
He said if I wanted him to go with me, it
would have to be on the bus or a train.
- And the train was a lot faster.
- Anyway, there's nothing to be.
It's easy for you to say!
Which actually... it wasn't.
"Think about nothing."
That's an oxymoron, like, "now, then."
An oxymoron is when two words
contradict each other.
My father and I used to have
oxymoron wars.