My friends on the mainland...
...think just because I live in Hawai'i...
...I live in paradise.
Like a permanent vacation.
We're all just out here
siping Mai Tais...
...shaking our hips, catching waves.
Are they insane?
Do they think we are
immune to life?
How can they possibly think
our families are less screwed up...
Our cancers less fatal...
Our heartache less painful.
Hell, I haven't been on
a surfboard in 15 years.
For the last 23 days...
...I've been living in a paradise of IVs...
...and urine bags and
endotracheal tubes.
Paradise.
Paradise can go fuck itself.
This is Elizabeth Thorson King.
My wife.
23 days ago she was launched from
a powerboat during a race and hit her head.
Almost drowned.
When I heard about the accident
and about the coma...
...I wasn't even in town.
I was on Maui on business.
We hadn't spoken in 3 days.
In a way, we hadn't
really spoken in months.
If you're doing this to get
my attention, Liz, It's working.
I'm ready now...
I am ready to talk,
I am ready to change...
I'm ready to be your
real husband and a real father.
Just wake up...
Please, Liz, just wake up.
Hi, Noe, what's up?
Matt, Scottie's teacher's on the phone.
She says it's urgent.
Okay, Put her on.
We don't think
these photographs are appropriate...
...for Scottie to be sharing
with her classmates.
Some of them
went home quite disturbed...
...and we've got some
angry calls from parents.
Yeah, she's kind of
been going to town...
...on this whole
picture-taking thing, I had no idea-
Mr. King.
We see this every day.
Children acting out at school
when something's wrong at home.
And your family is
facing a devastating crisis.
Have you been engaging Scottie
in really talking about what's going on?
Yes. Yes. Absolutely.
Encouraging her
to express her feelings?
- That's crucial.
- I understand.
What's the matter with you?
Showing those pictures of Mom
for your art project?
I'm a photographer, Dad,
a real photographer.
No, you're not.
You're overdoing it is what you're doing.
I saw it in a book.
Some famous photographer lady
took pictures of her mom in the hospital...
...While she was dying,
and they're considered art.
That's what I'm doing.
First of all, your mother's very sick,
but she's not dying.
And second of all, we don't share
personal stuff with strangers.
What's going on
with Mom is private.
- I'm hungry. Can we get burgers?
- No.
The last time I took care of Scottie
by myself was when she was one 30.
Now she's 10.
And I have no idea
what to do with her.
I want to eat now,
not in an hour.
And with Elizabeth in the hospital,
she's testing me.
I'm the backup parent.
The understudy.
This's Matt King, I'm returning your call.
How can I help you?
It's your daughter, Scottie.
She's been texting some
awful things to My daughter, Lani...
...and I'd like her to stop.
Huh.
Here's the latest one. "We all know
you grew pubes over the summer."
I mean, my daughter can't help that
she's developing a little early for her age.
Do you think that's nice?
Oh, That's not like her at all.
She's usually very sweet.
As you may know, her mother isn't well,
maybe this is how she's dealing with it.
I'm very sorry about
your family situation, Mr. King...
...But my daughter comes home
from school in tears.
Yeah, no, I get it. I'm sorry.
Scottie's the one who should be sorry.
I want her to come over
and apologize...
...and I don't ever want her
to text my daughter again.
If she doesn't apologize,
I'll take it up with the dean.
You can't buy
your way out of this.
Can you give me an address?
Thank you for coming by.
Hi.
I forgot to mention
the time Scottie said...
...she didn't want to be
Lani's partner at the rock wall...
...because she didn't want to
fall into my daughter's butt crack.
That doesn't even make sense.
Scottie...
Do you have something
you want to say to Lani?
Sorry.
It's okay.
Great.
Well, nice meeting you both.
Lani, you should come over
to our house sometime.
For a swim or a hike or something.
I don't think she's sorry at all.
She's going to keep on
doing it. I can tell.
No, she won't.
Look... Scottie,
you're gonna stop, right?
And you're really really sorry, right?
- Oh, and Mr. King?
- Yes?
Good luck with the sale.
They say your decision
will have a major impact...
...on Hawai'i's real estate world.
Not to mention the whole
landscape of Kaua'i.
Hundreds of millions of dollars, yeah?
Yeah, it's a big decision.
My husband's family is from Kaua'i.
Hanapepe, born and bred.
They hope you don't sell.
You don't say.
All the traffic it's gonna make.
As if Liz's coma weren't enough already...
The whole goddamned state
is following my decision...
...on who's gonna buy
25,000 acres on Kaua'i...
...that my family has
owned since the 1860s.
A lot of my cousins are broke and
the sale will make us all very very rich.
My family meets in 6 days
to approve a buyer.
But ever since my father died,
I'm the sole trustee.
Which means I alone
hold all the cards.
My great-great-grandmother was
Princess Margaret Ke'alohilani,
One of the last direct descendants
of King Kamehameha.
She was originally
supposed to marry her cousin...
...but she fell in love with
Edward King, her haole banker...
...whose parents were missionaries.
Between his land deals
and her huge inheritance...
...generations of their
descendants, all of us...
...have watched the past unfurl millions
into our laps through leases and sales.
Now something called
the Rule Against Perpetuities...
...is forcing us to dissolve the trust.
We're selling our last huge parcel of
virgin Hawaiian land.
Unlike a lot of of my cousins,
I havn't blown my share of the trust money.
Just like my father before me...
I live only on the income
from my law practice.
I don't want my daughters
growing up spoiled and entitled.
Liz always accuses me of being stinginess,
but I agree with my father:
You give your children
enough money to do something...
...but not enough to do nothing.
Matt, your cousins are here.
Not only am I the sole trustee...
...but I specialize in real
estate transactional low.
So a few of the more involved cousins...
...have been meeting with me
regularly to analyze the bids.
- Hey.
- Hey, guys.
Cousin Hal...
Cousin Milo...
Cousin Stan...
Cousin Six...
Cousin Wink...
Cousin Connie.
Okay.
And Cousin Dave, both of whom
oppose the sale entirely.
Good to see you.
Don't be fooled by appearances.
In Hawai'i some of the most powerful people
look like bums and stuntmen.
Alright, so, where are we?
The proposals are virtually the same.
Hotels, shopping centers,
condos and golf courses.
I have some major concerns...
A Chicago group is offering
half a billion dollars...
But we're leaning toward a lower bid
from a guy named Don Holitzer.
He's actually from Kaua'i...
...made a fortune in Silicon Valley.
Old cousin Hugh is pushing us
in that direction, and I say why not?
The money will come from
Hawaii and stay in Hawaii.
Elizabeth's gonna
make it out okay. I know it.
It's not her time yet.
She'll wake up, Scottie and Alexandra
will have their mother back...
...and we'll talk about our marriage.
I know I can make things right.
I'll sell the land and quit my practice
and buy her whatever she wants:
A big boat,
a house in France...
We'll take a trip around the world,
just the two of us.
We'll get close again...
...like the early days.
I wish I had better news, Matthew.
But Dr. Chun and Dr. Mueller
and I agree that her condition...
...is deteriorating.
She has no eye movements,
She has no pupillary responses...
She has no brainstem reflexes whatsoever.
The machines can keep her alive.
But the quality of her life
would be so poor...
Basically the way it is now.
She'll never be the way
she was, Matt. Never.
We know that now.
Look...
I can't tell you how sorry
I am to tell you this.
And you do have your daughters.
There's just nothing
more that we can do.
So if we do go ahead and
take her off the machines -
There is no if.
It's When. I have a legal
obligation, You know that.
How long will she last?
That's hard to say.
Could be a few days,
Could be a couple of weeks.
For planning purposes, I think you should
work off the shortest possible scenario.
I know I've got to get the ball rolling
on the organ donations right away.
Matt...
Elizabeth has many friends...
She has a big life.
If you're gonna let everybody
know to say goodbye which is...
...the typical protocol for these
situations, you start now.
Then when the last day comes...
...they feel more ready.
As ready as they
can feel for something like this.
I'm so sorry, Matt.
- Hey!
There he is!
How's it going?
What's going on?
Oh, she's been looking a little pale
lately all cooped up in here and...
...I just know she'd be mortified if nobody
helped her out with some lipstick and blush.
I know she'll grill me.
And of course Kai's getting her
all caught up on all the latest gossip.
Well, I don't want to
start from scratch later.
Oh, and Matt,
on the way here we stopped by...
...and putted some meals
in your fridge, all ready to nuke.
- Thanks.
- Mmhmm.
So what's the latest anyway, Matt?
Any updates?
Just more of the same.
just keeping her kidneys...
...and other vital organs working,
And hoping for the best.
ocean outrigger club
The food at the club is so good.
Yeah, they do a good job here.
Why is it called a jellyfish?
It's not a fish,
it's not jelly.
I have no idea.
You ask good questions, Scottie.
You're getting too smart for me.
I'm gonna ask Mom
when she wakes up.
Do you think she's gonna
know everything she used to?
I don't know.
I'll be right back.
Hi, Matt.
Hi, Scottie.
Troy.
So, what's going on?
I mean, how's Elizabeth doing?
The same.
Well, you know, I went and
visited her last week and...
I thought she looked pretty good.
Then why'd you ask?
I don't know, I guess I just
wanted to know what the latest is.
And I've been praying for her every day...
...you guys. Really hard. Seriously.
What I meant to say was, when
I was there, I talked to her and she...
...She moved her hand and...
Then I was like... I was encouraged.
I thought that was an encouraging sign.
That's enough.
I really think she heard me.
Look, Troy...
Go to your friends.
There's no hard feelings.
Let's just leave it alone.
I told you, Matt.
The water that day was so choppy.
I told you a hundred times.
What happened to her
could have happened to me.
I mean the ocean was brutal that day.
You can ask anybody.
You weren't supposed to be driving,
She was supposed to be driving.
She wanted me to drive.
She's the one who told me to
pass the other boat before the turn.
You know, it's just your
whole attitude toward me.
I feel terrible about it.
Plus I almost drowned
myself when the boat caps -
Hey.
Scottie!
Hey! Scottie! Scottie!
Hey!
Listen.
Don't pay any attention to that guy.
That guy's a dope.
- I hate him.
- Yeah.
I know.
Hey. Let's do something crazy.
Alright?
let's drive over the airport...
We'll hop over to the Big Island
and we'll surprise your sister.
What do you say?
Right now?
Yes, it'll be fun.
She's not expecting us.
And... we can bring her home.
I think she should be
here with us, don't you?
Don't you miss her?
I miss her.
Yeah, I mean I'm out of school.
She should be too!
Okay. Let's go. Com on.
Hey, Troy.
Somehow it feels natural to find a
daughter of mine on a different island.
A family seems
exactly like an archipelago.
All part of the same whole,
but still separate and alone.
And always drifting slowly apart.
That's the wrong door.
Go back to sleep, Rylan.
It's ok.
Wake up to your roommate, please.
Um... Alex isn't here.
Where is she?
I think she's somewhere outside.
Where outside?
Hey, girls! What you guys
think you're doing out here?
Run!
- Fuck!
- Hi, Alex!
It's me, Scottie!
I pay $35,000 a year for this
kind of crap not to happen.
Alex!
Dad?
- My fucking dad is here!
- You need to watch your language.
This is unacceptable behavior.
What's up, Dad?
What's happening?
You need to come home
and see your Mom.
Fuck Mom!
Really? What did I just say
about the language?
You could get expelled for all of this.
What is it that makes the women
in my life wanna destroy themselves?
Elizabeth with her
motorcycles and speedboats...
...and drinking.
Alexandra with her
drugs and older guys.
And Scottie...
...with Elizabeth gone...
What kind of a chance
will she have with just me?
Go to bed.
All right.
Here we go.
I don't like eggs.
Why didn't you tell me
before I made them?
I thought they were for you.
Good morning.
How're you feeling?
Hungover?
Why am I not surprised?
I thought you were supposed to be
getting your act together.
I have gotten my act together.
I was just drinking.
I've been doing really well, actually.
Nobody ever seems to notice that.
My grades are better...
How I was in that stupid play
that you guys didn't even bother to see.
Do you even
remember the name of it?
That's what I thought.
So what? Wht if I got drunk on the
one night you happened to stop by?
So fucking what?
Hey, hey. Watch your
language around Scottie.
I don't care.
Anyway.
Listen.
it's nice to see you.
Welcome home.
Want some eggs?
I can't believe that.
What?
Oh, my God!
Aha...
Alex?
What did she say?
Can I talk to you for a minute?
The pool's really dirty.
Aha...
Wait... what?
- Hey.
- No.
I really need to talk to you.
She didn't say anything to me.
Aha...
Oh my God, I can't believe...
Hey, yeah... I gotta go.
Okay, I'll see you later.
What day does
the pool guy come?
He comes...
You know, I don't know when he comes.
Awesome.
Sid's coming over.
Who's Sid?
A really good friend from Punahou.
We were in school together for years.
Oh. Okay.
He wants to be there for me
with all this shit happening.
Do I know his parents?
No.
He might stay over too.
Is that cool?
Guys, over here.
What the fuck? Get out of my
underwear, you freak.
Okay, no, no, no, no!
Back inside put on the swimsuit.
Why?
Now.
A real good job you're doing.
That's part of why
I brought you here.
You have to help me with her.
I don't know what to do with her.
Maybe if you spent
more time with her...
...she wouldn't act like
such a complete spaz.
Get her out of town -
Go camp on Kaua'i.
That's what mom used to do with me
whenever I was losing it.
Hey.
Listen.
No, listen, listen to me.
Your mother is not well.
Well, obviously.
No.
They just told me
she isn't gonna wake up.
We know for sure now.
The doctors are gonna
stop caring for her.
Your mother wanted it this way.
She has this...
She has this will, see...
...that says that
we have to do it this way.
We both do.
Do you understand
what I'm saying?
That's why I got you.
Honey, we're letting her go.
Why'd you have to tell me
in the goddamned pool?
Alex...
Alex!
What?
What do you want?
I just found out yesterday.
We have to go through
this thing together...
...you and Scottie and me.
And I have to go around
and tell people what's happening.
Family and a few close friends.
Sometimes I'll really
need you to come with me.
Sometimes I need you to watch Scottie.
You want me to go around with you and
tell people that Mom's gonna die?
What's the point of that?
Breaking the news, watching them cry,
dealing with their emotions.
How depressing is that
gonna be? Just call them.
Alex, nobody
wants to do any of this.
But we have to tell your Grandpa
and Tutu, and a few friends.
They have the right to know,
They have the right to say goodbye.
I don't wanna talk
about Mom with anyone.
Look, whatever you two fought about
over Christmas, you have to drop it.
Grow up.
You love your mother.
Your mother loves you.
I can't drop it.
You have to.
You really don't have a clue, do you?
Dad...
Dad, mom was cheating on you.
That's what we fought about.
When I was over at Christmas,
I caught her with the guy.
It made me sick
to see her near you.
I went back to school
thinking that that was it...
...that I was just done with her.
I was gonna call and
tell you everything, and...
...and then the accident
happened, and...
...I was waiting until
she woke up, I guess.
You didn't even suspect. Right?
Right?
You disgusted me too.
You're always so busy.
Caught her with a guy?
What does that mean?
I was on my way to swim in
the Black Point pool with Brandy...
...and suddenly I see Mom and
some douchebag walking into a house.
His house, I guess.
Just some guy?
It could be anybody.
Yeah, he had his hand on her ass.
It was gross.
Then what?
Then nothing.
Then they went into the house.
A few days later I told her
I knew what she was doing.
And?
And first she acted like she
had no idea what I was talking about.
Like I'm fucking blind.
Then she got like super-mad
and yelled and denied it.
That is when I decided I didn't want
anything more to do with her.
Who is he?
I don't know. Some guy.
What did he look like?
Dark hair.
Watch your sister.
Hello?
Kai?
Mark?
It's me, Matt!
Hey!
Hello!
Wait... Hello?
It's me, it's Matt!
Oh, hey, Matt.
It's a bad time?
No, no, we were just fighting.
Come on in. You want some coffee?
You want something to drink?
No, thanks.
- Fighting about something stupid.
- It is not stupid.
He wants us to throw parties and
have people over, which we do, of course...
...but who winds up doing
all the work? Me.
You don't have to do anything.
- That's the whole point!
- Yes, I do.
It's doesn't have to be work.
You don't have to...
...clean and buy a new outfit.
- Oh, I'm supposed to leave...
- ...and think of the...
...goddamn theme cocktail
for every party.
We can just invite people over
to hang out and drink whatever we have.
Let's talk about it later.
Oh, shit, Matt, is everything okay?
Is there any news?
In fact there is.
I'll tell you about it in a moment.
Who is he?
Does she love him?
Matt...
I'm sorry to put you in that position.
But I'm not really the one
who put you there, am I?
I'd like to know who the guy is
that my wife was... seeing.
Matt, you're angry.
You have very keen
powers of observation.
Wow. Okay, You know what I think?
We should just talk about this later.
I think maybe you need to cool it.
Is it Troy?
That fucking Neanderthal?
You don't know him.
Mark, don't you even.
Shame on you.
You're supposed to be her friend.
Well, guess what?
I'm Matt's friend too.
Okay? And this is a unique
and dramatic situation...
...and I'd wanna know.
Yeah, But don't betray her
when she can't even defend herself.
Matt...
Look, you might not be able
to hear this right now...
...but it's not her fault.
Your marriage was not... just...
She was lonely.
So you're going to talk to me
in clichés about women?
Nothing is ever a woman's fault.
Was it still going on
when she had the accident?
But I stayed out of it.
Anytime Kai would bring it up, I walked away.
And you What?
You probably eggeed her on.
Add some drama to you'r life without any actual risk.
Whom do you think you are protecting Kai?
She doesn't need you'r protection...
it's over. she's gonna die.
- Don't say that.
- It's true, I was gonna tell you yesterday.
She is never gonna wake up.
You hear me? Do you understand what I'm saying?
She is gone!
We are pulling the plug.
You were putting lipstick on a corpse!
Come on, Matt.
That's a little intense.
Does she love him?
How can you ask about him when shes
going to die? who cares?
Yes, she loves him...
...loved him, whatever. She was crazy about him.
She was going to...
...She was going to ask you for a divorce.
You still haven't told me who he is.
I guess it doesnt matter.
Matt?
Matt!
Brian Speer.
His name is Brian Speer.
Two es.
Hi, Daddy.
Hello, Sid.
What's up bro?
Dont ever do that to me again.
Get ready, Were going to see your
Grandparents...
Auntie Esther will come over to watch
you.
Dad, Sid's coming with us, okay?
Yeah, listen Sid, whats going on this weekend, is
realy family matter. You understand.
Sids not going to be interested in meeting your grandparents.
He's gonna be bored stiff.
Dad, I told you that he was going to be with me.
Ill be a lot more civil with him
around.
What can I say?
This is like reading Korean.
Scott, if you want, I can walk you through it.
Jibber-jabber.
Its an advanced directive...
It's basically her instructions on what
procedures she wants or...
I know goddamn well what it says.
she doesnt want us sit around
watching her spoiling like milk.
if there is nothing of doctors can do,
shed just get on with it.
Elizabeth had the good sense
to write this thing here.
She always was a thoughtful
girl.
A Strong girl.
A hell of a lot stronger than her brother.
Barry whines his way through life.
Might even be a homosexual, for all I know.
Scott, I do not think.
And shes stronger than you, Matt.
She lived more in a year
than you did in a decade,
sitting in your office, hoarding all your cash.
All that money you refuse to use...
what the hell good is it?
And now you and your family
get ready cashing in your chips, what the hell for?
Maybe if youd let my baby have
her own boat and bought her...
some safe equipment or...
let her go on those shopping sprees women like.
maybe she wouldnt have gone in
for those shrill sports.
Maybe if youd provided more thrills at home.
And you, Alexandra...
Putting your poor mother through hell...
when all she was trying to do was instill
some sense and drive in you.
Shame on you.
Shame on you!
You should try to be more like her.
Shes a good girl.
Shes a...
Good girl.
Hi, Alice
Its me, Matt.
It's good to see you.
Good to see you too.
Hi, Tutu.
Thats Alexandra.
Shes your grand daughter.
And this is your son-in-law Matt.
This is your family.
Well, except this kid.
I dont know who the hell he is.
Who are you?
What are you doing here?
He's my friend.
Good afternoon.
Alice...
Alice, were going to go to Queens
Hospital this afternoon and see Elizabeth.
We are?
Yes.
She needs us,
just like when she was a little girl.
We need to see her in the hospital.
So think about what she might want in her room.
...We'll take it to her and put it next to
her bed.
Queen Elizabeth?
That's wonderful!
I have to put on a nice dress.
Is she serious?
Shut up, kid.
I have never met Queen before.
Im sorry, man.
I was just laughing.
Its funny I mean.
I think she knows shes being funny.
Im going to hit you.
That was unreal.
I mean...
how often do old people just haul off
and fucking cold-cock you in like that?
Hes hit me a couple times over the years.
And watch your tongue.
can I see it?
Holly shit!
- Ow!
- could you two just cool it...
when you around me?
stop... touching each other.
Whoa man!
Maybe thats why your wife cheated on
you, if you are so against touching.
You little fuck. Do you get hit a lot?
I do not know.
Ive had my share.
Your friend is completely retarded.
You know that?
Hey man, my little brothers retarded.
Dont use that word in a derogatory fashion.
Oh.
- Psych! I dont have a retarded brother!
- Sid, You suck.
Speaking of retarded...
...do you ever wish that retarded
people or old people could just hurry up?
like sometimes...
I'm waiting for them to cross the
street, and Im like, come on already!
But then I feel bad.
Dad?
What?
Dont forget that I know where he lives.
Get in the front seat
Do you know anything about him? Like
what he does or if hes married or anything else?
just his name. Brian Speer.
Why didn't you ask Kai and Mark?
I just didnt.
Why not?
I didnt want to get into it.
Well google him later.
Okay...
That's it, That's it, That's on
stop right there.
- right there?
- yeah, yeah.
There?
He lives there?
Well, I cant say for sure he lives
there. Thats just where I saw them.
Should I go ring the bell?
No, this is stupid... it's just
stalking, or something that, okay, it's...
We came, we saw, that's enough enough.
Let's go.
Its not like were stalking him
exactly.
What would you do if you saw him, anyway?
Talk to him or punch him or
what?
I guess I just want to see him.
Dad, dad. Stop,
stop, stop, stop!
What?
Go back, go back!
Just go back.
- Look, look!
- What?
Look! There he is!
GOLD COAST REAL ESTATE
926-7525 SALE
Now we know what he looks like.
Brian speer 923-7723 GOLD
COAST REAL ESTATE
Hi, this is Brian from GOLD
COAST REAL ESTATE.
Sorry I missed your call.
Leave a message with your name, number
and time of callt...
...and Ill get back to
you just as soon as I can.
Mahalo.
Hi, Brian.
My names Herb Fitzmorris and Im interested in
your house on Koloa Street
the one with the cool fence and gate.
I'm at 6-4-5-2-7-9-6.
Thank you.
Girls, let me go in for just a quick moment
alone first.
Ill be right out.
You were going to ask me for a divorce?
So you could be with some fucking fuckhead Brian Speer?
Are you kidding me?
Who are you?
the only thing I know for sure is that youre a
goddamned liar.
So what do you have to say for yourself?
Go ahead, make a little joke and...
...tell me that Ive got it all wrong.
Tell me again Im too out of touch with
my feelings
and I need to go to therapy.
Isnt the idea of marriage to make your
partners way in life a little easier?
For me it was always harder...
with you and youre still making it harder.
Lying there on a ventilator and
fucking up my life.
You're relentless.
You know what? I was going to ask you
for a divorce some day.
Daddys little girl.
Im bringing your daughters in now.
Alex is home from school
Try to be nice, okay?
Okay?
Hi, Mom! Look whos here.
Say something Alex. Tell her how
you were drunk the other night.
Tell her maybe youre an alcoholic.
Girls, be serious.
Hi, Mom.
Sorry for being bad.
sorry for wasting your money on expensive private schools.
Money you could have used on facials
and massages and...
...sports equipment.
- Sorry for everything.
- Okay.
Sorry we werent good enough for you...
especially Dad.
Stop it. Thats out of line.
Or what? You going to ground me?
Or ship me off to another boarding school?
You going to give me a time out?
Goddammit!
You got served!
Scottie, out in the hall.
- Shes the one out of line.
- Go find Sid.
- Hes smoking. I shouldnt be around
second-hand smoke.
Go! Now! Now! Now!
Did you just spank me?
You have no right to talk to your
mother that way. Shes going to die in a few days.
- What if those were your last words?
- I have every right to speak her that way.
Im mad at her. How can you be so
forgiving?
Ill be angry later. Right now lets just think about the good parts.
and dont say that stuff in front of your sister.
Dont spoil her for Scottie.
Say something different.
Look, Mom, I know we fought a lot...
I just I always wanted to be like you.
I am like you. Im exactly like you.
You are like her.
mostly in good ways.
Maybe some bad ways.
Remains to be seen.
Yeah.
Dad, this is Reina.
Reina, thiss my sister and Sid, and
thats my mom on the bed.
Hi every body.
Hello.
Hi.
So this is your mother?
I guess its true.
Should I shake her hand?
If you want.
No, thanks.
So, Reina, I understand your grandmothers
not feeling well.
Yeah. Its pretty bad. She got her stomach
operated on
and then got some stupid
infection or something.
Its pretty gross.
Well, Reina, thank you for stopping by...
...Scottie, let me give you some money, and
you two can go get ice cream...
Too many carbs.
Too many carbs?
Well, you could go to the cafeteria
and get some lettuce.
Thats okay. Im done.
you arent a liar after all.
Don't you want to hang out?
No, I should go. Ill see you at the
club. Hope your mom gets better.
Bye everybody.
Scottie, whatd she mean by
You arent a liar after all?
What did she think you were lying about?
she didnt believe Mom was sleeping.
So you had to prove to that twat that
Moms in a coma?
What the fuck is in
your skull, a bunch of stupid pills?
shut up, you motherless whore!
Whoa, whoa, easy there, half-pipe.
Whered you learn how to talk like that?
Incoming Call
GOLD Coast Real Estate
- No, no, no.
- Hello?
No, this is the right number.
No, I'm his assistant Sharon.
How may I help you?
Who is it?
Aha.
Oh, All right, all right. So one or the other.
Okay, I'll tell him. Mahalo!
That was Bonnie Tanaka, a realtor.
She says that Mr. Speer is going to be
on Kauai for the next week but...
...shed be happy to show you the house or...
...you can stop by the open house on Sunday.
Hi Mr. King.
Hello, Buzz.
Sorry about Mrs. King. hope she gets better real soon.
Thanks.
It really blows.
I know.
Youve all ask questions about of Elizabeth.
and Ive given vague answers.
But I ask you all here today
to tell you that...
...her coma is permanent.
Shes not going to make it.
So, this week...
...Tomorrow, infact...
as for her her wishes, were going to unhook
her from life-support.
You all know Elizabeth...
...she is doing things on her own.
I wanted to tell you all in person...
...Because Youre all our dear friends
our best friends.
The girls and I are so much appreciate
severything youve done for us in the last few weeks...
bringing food, calling...
Can we go see her?
Yes, for Gods sake, yes. Thats the
whole point.
Go see her as soon as possible.
Thats what I wanted to tell you.
All of you.
It should be now, not after.
Everyone who loves her deserves a
chance to say goodbye.
Youve lost your mind.
You mean him? Tell him to come say goodbye?
Ill only be gone a day or so. Ill leave in the
morning, and be back tomorrow night.
If it takes anothe rday,
fine... I'll give it two days
tops. If I dont find him, at least I tried.
Just Drop it, Dad.
Youve got way bigger
fish to fry than confronting fucking Brian Speer.
Are you recording this?
Im summarizine a deposition.
How can you work in a time like this?
How can you go to a movie?
To get Scottie out of the house.
And youre going to tell him to come back
and see Mom.
I think... I just think she would want
him to know.
Just call his office and say it's an
emergency.
On the phone he can escape.
In person he got nowhere to go.
I want to see his face.
Then I want to go too.
No, you are gonna stay here with Scottie.
Fuck that. Lets all get out of town.
Yo, Matt King!
- Hey, Ralph!
- Hey!
Yeah, how is it?
- Glad to see you.
- Kids, this is cousin Ralph
- Oh, yeah, Hi!
- Good to see you!
Glad to see you.
Well, what you guys doing here?
Just came over for a day or two.
Yeah, I just got back from Kahului. A
little business over there.
- Yes?
- Business is over there.
- Ahan.
- yeah.
So you here to talk to some
of the cousins?
Make sure everybodys
happy with your choice?
Pay your respects to Cousin Hugh?
No, no, nothing like that. Just
a little holoholo. Get the kids out of town.
But it is Holitzer, right?
We all know its Holitzer.
Cousin Hugh wants him, they go way back.
I got my misgivings, somehow.
Theres an argument to be made for
maxing it out. We only do this once in a lifetime.
yeah, no, I want to work with
you guys, Ralph, I really do.
Whatever the majority decides after
the Poll, Ill go along with it.
Lets just get it over with.
- All right.
- okay.
Hows Elizabeth doing? She going to be
okay?
The same.
Well, shes a tough gal. Shell be
okay, yeah?
Yeah.
Say, where you guys going, Hanalei?
Princeville.
Come on. Ill give you a ride.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Come on, kids.
cousin Ralph give us a ride.
- Hey, Ralph!
- yeah.
Turn off over here. Lets go see the
land.
Take a last look, huh?
You got time?
I got nothing but time.
I think this is where a golf course is
going to be.
They want the golf course to rival
Pebble Beach.
you know, bring in the big boys.
subtitle by
"amir_t6262" & "Hossein Gh" & "SUNNY_II"
Scotty, come on sweetie.
Watch out, Scotty, watch out.
are you shitting me?
You guys own all this land?
Not personally. It belongs to a trust.
But yeah, its ours for a few more days.
Big resort there on that point.
Commercial area over there...
houses all through there.
ther's part of me agrees with the
cousins who dont want to sell.
Theyre going to make a pretty big
stink at the meeting.
But we have to.
The trust dissolves in seven years, and if
we don't selld, it's just gonna be a train rack.
it is a shame, yeah?
On the other hand...
...it's just sitting there.
No one's using it.
At least this way the whole world
will be able to enjoy it.
Take a good look, girls.
This is part of your great-great-great
grandmothers inheritance...
...going all way back to Kamehameha I.
Down there is where Mom and I would camp.
We all did, all our lives.
lots of memories.
Everything has it's time.
What about me?
I want to camp.
By the way. Im supposed to meet a friend of
mine, I think he is staying here.
And his name is Brian Speer.
S- P-E-E-R.
sorry Mr King, I'm not
showing anybody that name.
Okay, thanks.
Hey, Scottie.
whats in your suit?
They are my beach boobs.
Take them out of there. Right now.
Jesus Alex, whyd you let her do that? You too, Sid.
I do not know. Take them out, stupid!
Yeah, Scottie. Big boobs
look kind of fatty.
Any luck?
The hotels was a dead end, but I took
another shot with his office.
Hes definitely renting a house in Hanalei.
probably one of that cottages around the bay.
I think we should
go for a walk.
Yeah, let's go.
Scottie?
Can we swim with the sharks?
I read in the hotel magazine how they like put
you in the cage in the water...
...and they throw shark...
...feed in the water and sharks swim right
up to you.
Can we do that?
Scottie, were not really here to do
stuff like that.
What are we gonna do then?
How would you and mom meet?
I was with a law school buddy from the
mainland,
...and I took him to the club.
We were just coming in from paddling,
and your mom was on her way out, and she looked at me and said,
Do you think its going to snow today?
Did it realy snow?
stayed dry.
I like her stories.
Like how she streaked in wedding.
Oh my God!
There are so many.
As when...
your mom
get chased by a shark...
What?
When that was happened?
We were on Molokai with Mark and Kai,
and your mom was out surfing and saw a
shark right beneath her on a wave...
Lets watch one of these!
No, Were not watching porn.
- Give me that.
- No.
Reinas dad watches pornes.
Reina calls them masturbation movies.
She plays them when her parents arent home
and one time invited boys over to see if they grew down there.
One did.
Reina sounds awesome.
Were you there? Did you watch
one of those movies?
No.
Hey! Scottie!
Reina is a fucked-up ho-bag, and you
need to stay away from her.
and she is going to be a meth-head,
and shes going to get used by stupid guys.
She's a twat. Say it.
Shes a twat.
Okay.
- Shes a twat, twat, twat!
- Okay, okay. Stop it!
twat, twat, twat, twat.
...twat, twat, twat, twat...
I dont get it. I dont know what to
do...
...these things she does. What goes
on in her head?
You werent like that.
Itll go away.
Im not so sure. I mean, look how you
kids talk in front of me...
...It's like you dont respect authority.
Hey.
Hi.
Checking on me or something?
I havent been sleeping
very much lately.
Understandable.
Im worried about my daughters.
I think there's something wrong with them.
I used to do some messed-up shit
when I was a kid.
I still do.
It's going to
get worse after your wife dies.
What does Alex really think about this
stuff thats going on? What does she say?
She doesn't.
What do you mean? I thought she
talks to you all the time.
We dont really talk about our like
issues.
We just, I dont know, we deal with our shit by talking about
other stuff and having a good time.
What would you do if you were me?
How would you handle my daughters?
How would you handle... the situation of
this guy were trying to find?
I told you, man.
Would I put the nuts on a dresser
and will be hitting with the spiked bat.
With the daughters, I dont know.
Exchange them for sons, I guess.
Then I might wind up with something
like you.
Im not so bad.
Im smart.
Youre about a hundred miles away from
Smartville. No offense.
Youre mistaken, counselor.
Im smart.
I have good hygiene.
Im an decent
guitarist,
a good cook. I cook food
all the time.
Im vice-president of
the Punahou chess club.
And I always
have weed.
Your mom must
be very proud.
Its possible.
My moms sort of busy
right now.
Yes. What does she do, your mom?
Shes a receptionist at a pet clinic.
But mostly shes been getting the house
together after my dad died.
My dad died a few months ago
November 24th.
Drunk driver.
Actually
both drivers were drunk. Yeah.
Yes.
Good night, Sid.
Good night, boss.
Ill see you in the morning.
Stay in the zone, please! That means
you, Skylar. And you too, Colt.
Watch your sister,
Ill be right back.
Looks like you got yourself a handful
with those two.
Yes.
Must keep you pretty busy.
Theyre pretty non-stop, but theyre at
a really fun age.
How old are they?
Eight and ten.
I have two girls.
Ten and seventeen.
That whole non-stop thing. That never
changes.
You guys live here?
- Oahu.
- Oh, so do we.
Yeah, Im just getting my girls out of
town for a couple days.
their mother is in the hospital, so I
thought Id give them a little break.
Oh, no.
Whats wrong? If you dont mind my
asking.
Just a little boating accident. Hit
her head a little too hard.
A sailboat?
Or one with a motor?
One with a motor.
Well, good luck with that.
I wish her well.
Not so long Skailer.
You guys staying in one of the cottages
here?
Yes, my husband had to come here for
work, so we thought wed all make a little vacation of it.
He knows the owner, so...
- Hugh King.
- Thats right.
Hes my cousin.
Oh. Then you probably know my husband.
Brian Speer?
No, cant say as I do.
Oh, I just assumed, since hes been...
Dad!
Something bit me!
Nice talking to you.
You too. Take care.
Theres Cousin Hugh.
Get us a table.
Order me something.
What do you want?
Anything.
Hey, Hugh?
Heeey! Mattie-boy!
What are you doing
here?
I didnt expect to see you until the meeting.
Just getting the girls out of the
hospital for a couple days,
- Oh, these are...
- Scottie and Alex.
Big girls now!
Yes, just needed
a change of scenery.
Yeah, boy, what youve been going
through. Thats a tough deal.
Yes.
But Elizabeth, hey, shes, shes a
tough gal, Ill tell you that.
A fighter. Shell make it.
Get you a drink?
Yes, whatre you have
- Julia?
- Hey.
- an old-fashioned for my cousin here.
- all right.
- Glad to see you, Matt.
- Me too.
How you been otherwise?
Not much otherwise.
Between our business and the hospital, you know,
trying to keep my head above water.
listen, I see you have some
people staying in the cottage.
Oh, hey, Mattie, if Id known you were
coming, I coulda...
No, no, no, not that at all.
Im just wondering about
the guy youre renting to.
I think his
name is Brian Speer.
Yeah, yeah, real determined son-of-a-bitch.
Hes Lous sisters...
No, wait. Lou has a sister, and the
sisters husband
Lous brother-in-law is cousins with that guy.
Whos Lou?
No, wait. You mean the cottages on the
bay or the cottage back by the trail?
The bay. The guy with the wife and two
boys.
Yeah, thats right. Determined son-of-
a- bitch.
Anyway, the point is the guy were doing
business with is that guys brother-in-law.
Works for him.
What do you mean, the guy were doing
business with?
Who do you think? Don!
Who else? Holitzer.
Holitzer.
Thats what Im saying. Thats Dons
brother-in-law in the cottage.
Brian Speer.
You dont know him? I would have thought
youd know him. Hes a realtor over by you.
So if we sell to Don
and thats what were going to do, right?
Thats what you want too.
Nice guy, Don. Hell do right by us.
Then when Don develops and re-sells and
leases and all that...
Hes letting this brother-in-law in the
cottage handle the transactions.
A lot of them, anyway.
Big score for that guy.
This afternoon will be
us a good voice, my nephew.
From here the Ke'ola.
Hugh, what's he like?
Who?
Brian Speer
what else do you know
about him?
Not much. Hes lucky. Son-of-a-bitch is going
to make a shitload of money on commissions.
Not if we dont go with that bid.
We all want Don.
You do too, Matt.
Youve said as much.
Yes. i'm just... You're right.
Hugh, Good to see you, Hugh.
You too.
- See you at the meeting.
- Ill be there.
This place rocks.
Totally.
We ordered you mahi.
Great.
Well, guess what. That
woman on the beach today...
That was his wife.
- Whose wife?
- Brian Speer
What?
The hottie with the hat?
Yes.
- Are you sure?
So hes married.
- Why didnt you say anything?
- Its him I want to talk to, not her.
I know where their cottage is.
You do?
So lets do it right now.
Lets go knock on his door.
Thats what Im saying.
Dont do that. Dont be excited. This
isnt fun.
Well, its what we came here to do.
Right.
So you to talk to his wife while I talk
to him.
And figure out some way to
distract Scottie and their kids.
Got it.
Sid, come here.
Give em hell, boss.
Come on, Sid.
Ok
Im sorry for sucking you into this.
should be doing this alone.
- Its selfish of me.
- Im the one who sucked you in.
Im the one who knew.
Dont be a pussy.
Hi there!
Its the guy from the beach today.
Oh, hello.
Yeah, hey, Im such an idiot.
I just figured out I do know your husband.
My daughter and I were on our way back to the hotel from dinner,
and we thought wed drop by and say howdy.
- Great. Come on up.
Yes.
Im Matt King. This is Alexandra.
- Im Julie Speer.
- Hi.
Yeah, I thought that was you.
Youve been in the paper so much lately.
I figured you had to know
Brian. Hes been pretty involved.
Yeah, no, I know, yeah, super-involved.
Maybe Ive met him in passing.
I dont know.
So, I guess you guys are deciding really soon.
A couple of days, right right... you and your family meet?
Im sorry. Thats probably a conflict
of interest or something.
No, its okay. Youre right
itll all be over in a couple of days.
You guys want a lasagna?
No, thanks We just ate,
A drink then.
sure
Red wine, iced tea?
- Perfect.
Yes.
Hello!
- Hi.
- Hey.
Hi, Im Brian.
Brian, we may have met before.
Matt King.
My wife is Elizabeth King.
I think you may have met her too.
And this is her daughter, Alexandra.
I was just going to get drinks.
Good, good. Good.
- Do you need help?
No, no, I got it.
Elizabeth is dying.
Oh, wait. Fuck
you
And shes dying.
We unhooked her from the machines this morning.
Shell be dead in a few days.
- This is him?
- Mmchmm.
- How would she go for him?
- Beats me.
Well, hes very articulate.
Im sorry. I never thought
it would come to this.
Youre sorry my moms going to die?
Youre sorry you fucked her?
Youre sorry you fucked over my dad?
Im sorry for all of it.
Look, pal, like she said, Im not here to wreck your life. I just came to
give you a chance to go to the hospital.
I dont know how long youre planning on being
here, but Im sure you can think of an excuse to leave.
You must be good at that.
You can be alone with her to say
goodbye or whatever
Do you hear what Im saying?
Okay, look, I cant have you here. You
understand.
Here we go.
Thank you.
Everyones so serious. Please dont
tell me youre talking about business.
Were talking about love.
This is nice.
Brian, call the boys in for dinner.
Theyre fine. Let them play a while
longer.
Awesome cottage youre renting.
Yeah, say, prime Hanalei location.
I used to come here as a kid before it
was a vacation property.
Alex, your great-uncle Warren and Aunt Lillian
built it back in the 20s.
Havent been
inside in years.
Come on. Well give you a tour.
Or, Brian, maybe you could give my dad a little
walk down memory lane, and Julie and I can chat out here.
Yeah, Id like that, if you dont mind.
Just a quick look.
Yes. But its not like I live here anything.
but OK
Can you keep it?
Go from here.
Here it is.
How did you meet? Im curious
I cant do this.
Neither can I. How did you meet?
I thought you said you came here just
to tell me.
I changed my mind. And I cant very
well ask her the details. can I
Howd you meet?
At a party.
- What party?
Super Bowl party
At the Mitchells
Does that help? Does that make it
better?
Hey, Im doing you a favor here. I
could go out there right now and fuck you up,
so get a better attitude.
Then what?
Howd you get the nerve to ask
her out?
Was it about the deal?
Is that when you decided she was for you?
No.
Its not what you think.
It just happened.
Nothing just happens.
Everything just happens.
Was she going to leave me?
She would have.
But I, I, uh... I
didnt want that happened.
I love Julie.
Please dont tell her.
Please.
I dont know what Ive done. Im sorry.
Did she say she loved you?
Do you love her?
You dont love her.
You dont love
her. You just used her to get to me.
No, I told you. I wasnt trying to get
to you.
It was an affair,
an attraction. Sex. And she got sort of... carried away
with the whole thing, and I guess I went with it.
I mean, I didnt exactly
say no to things. I should have. I love my family.
Then I guess its all working out. Her lips are sealed,
and you dont have to go through the trouble of dumping her.
Hey, hey, thats really unfair. I had..
have... a lot of respect for her.
Shes a wonderful woman.
One more question fot you
Yes?
Have you ever been inside my bedroom?
Once.
You could have had the decency to lie
about that one.
Okay, two.
Well, shes in Queens
Hospital if you want to say goodbye.
That really is all I came to say.
that's great, all remodeled, new
appliances.
Nice.
Alex, I think we should go.
Well, hey, thanks for stopping by.
Really nice to meet you both. Maybe
well see you at the beach tomorrow.
Yes, maybe.
Nice to meet you.
Hey.
So when do you think hell show up?
I have no idea.
Was he sorry?
I hope he was sorry, man.
You could have told his wife, and
you didnt.
I would say everything. I mean..
I hope he knows how lucky he is.
She deserves to know.
Or else shes going to be a dumb bitch the
rest of her life.
Sid.
Im just saying.
No need to get creepy about it
Anyway, doesnt
matter. Thats all behind us.
Yeah, the one we have to worry about
telling things to now is Scottie.
Ive asked Dr. Johnston to help us
break the news tomorrow.
Here we are.
Hey.
- Hey, Barry.
- Hey.
- Hi, Alice.
- Hey, Barry.
- Hi, Alex.
- Glad to see you.
Scott.
Hi, Tutu.
Alex, we will... e.. bring some
chairs for Tutu, right?
There you are again.
so...
what did you decide?
Theres not much left to decide.
Were just sort of playing it by ear and
making sure shes comfortable.
I mean what did you decide about the
buyer?
Whos your buyer?
How much are you getting?
Dad...
Im sure youll be able to read
about it in the paper.
I dont need to read about it. I can
hear about it right now.
Scott, lets not talk about that here.
Its not the time for that.
All the same to you, I guess. A
million here, a million there.
Just ironic, thats all
Elizabeth coming into this misfortune just as youre
coming into a fortune.
She gave you
everything, Matt.
A good, happy home,
two beautiful daughters.
Scott, whats your point?
She wanted her own boat. She should
have had her own boat,
- one she would have been familiar with.
- She wasnt even driving!
Her boat,
someone elses boat... it wouldnt matter
Youre not going
to blame me for this.
quibble about the details.
She was a faithful, devoted wife. She
deserved more.
Youre right. She deserved more.
For Christs sake,
take it easy on the man.
You know, My father has been doing a really
amazing job under the circumstances.
Are we leaving?
No, Mom, not yet.
Man, that guys a prick.
Was he always
like that?
Yes.
Well, no surprise. Other than the
hold outs who dont want to sell at all,
its Don Holitzer.
Chicago group a distant second.
Feels good.
Were doing the right thing, Mattie.
At least there aint going to be any
Wal-Mart.
All right.
Now its your call, and
were all behind you,
most of us anyway.
Go ahead, Captain. Make it official.
Its strange, thats all.
Whats strange?
We didnt do anything to own that land.
It was entrusted to us.
And now were just...
I cant do it.
I wont do it.
- What do you mean?
- Im not going to sign.
Whatre you doing, Matt?
I mean, we know you have a lot on your plate right now,
but youre not going to fuck this up for us.
Its over.
I dont want it to go to Holitzer.
I dont want it to go to anyone.
I want to keep it.
Your heads not right, Mattie.
Your heads not right.
You want a couple
days to think it over? Take a couple days.
dont need a couple days. I have the
authority, and this is what I want.
We have other businesses were
converting to corporations. We can figure it out.
Youre the trustee.
You know better than anyone we
only have seven years left.
Then I have seven years to figure out
how to keep it.
Well come after you.
Just because youre a lawyer doesnt mean the rest
of us would be afraid to come after you.
But nobody wants to do that.
Were family.
People will be relieved, Hugh, the
whole state.
I sign that document, Something
that was ours to protect will be gone.
were haole as shit
and go to private schools and clubs and cant
even speak pidgin, let alone Hawaiian,
But we have Hawaiian blood.
and were still tied to this land.
And our children are tied to this land.
Its a miracle that for whatever bullshit
reason 150 years ago, we own this much of... paradise, but we do.
And for whatever bullshit reason now,
Im the trustee.
And Im not signing.
And if you sue me, itll only make us closer.
All right.
everybody, listen up.
Cousin Mattie has an announcement.
Get ready.
come in
Julie?
I know we just met, but I was thinking
about you guys these past few days,
I knew your mom was here. I dont
know. I just felt I should stop by.
You remember Alex.
- Hi.
This is Scottie.
Sid. This is Mrs. Speer.
Julie.
Were you friends with my mom?
No, we never met. But I know a lot
about her.
Look, Julie, we appreciate your coming by.
The flowers are lovely.
- Scottie, Alex. Lets go to the cafeteria.
- Okay. Yes.
Come get up Scotty.
- I come.
- Come on, Scotty.
I wanted two more seconds.
- Scotty.
- comeing!
I, uh, Im not sure how much you know
about my wifes condition,
but shes
going to die very soon.
Basically for this reason we are here.
I know.
Thats why I came. Because I
know.
I came because Brian wouldnt.
And that just didnt seem right. I thought someone from my
family should come.
So he told you, huh?
he was acting really weird. that night,
After you left Then I started smelling it all over him.
Id already smelled it.
I finally got it out of him. Weve
been going crazy ever since.
Not easy
with the kids around.
Its all
something I never could have imagined.
And then your familys decision about
the land. I think youre doing the right thing,
but Brian is... well, its
all so complicated and confusing.
I know.
Im angry,
but Im just so sorry.
I cant imagine what youre going
through.
Do you mind if I say
something to her?
Ok
Elizabeth, Im Julie.
Brians wife.
I just wanted to tell you...
I just want to tell you I forgive you.
I forgive you for trying to take Brian away
I forgive you for almost destroying my
family.
Why should I forgive you...
I have to forgive you.
Even though I want to hate you.
Okay. Thats enough,
I have to forgive you.
Frankly, I think that is enough.
Okay? Come, go.
Thank you, Julie.
He didnt love her. Just so you know.
He didnt really love her.
That's why I came.
All right.
Goodbye, Elizabeth.
Goodbye, my love.
my friend,
my pain,
my joy.
Goodbye.
I guess that is
are very few places that are difficult
can go in this world...
...but there are others
be more difficult to live.
The average temperature here in the bottom
of the earth is about 50 degrees below.
With strawberry.
one scoop mocha chip.
Great.
Antarctica used to be tropical place.
With dense forests and bustling.
But then the continents
began to move south.
And to finish the move forests
were replaced by a new territory.
Ice
As for the old residents, all
died or moved long ago.
Basically, almost all of them.
The royal penguin
is essentially a bird.
Only he makes
the home of the sea.
And if you wonder what
done here on the ice, then...
This is another story.
is here around the same time
who wants to leave the ocean's house
and begin a memorable trip.
They traveled a long distance...