♪ After seven years Of
life upon the ocean ♪
♪ It is time to bid The
seven seas farewell ♪
♪ And the city I've pinned
Seven years of hopes on ♪
♪ Lies just over the horizon
♪ I can hear the harbor bell
Land ahoy!
♪ Got a tattered overcoat
And battered suitcase ♪
Au revoir, Chef.
♪ Got a pair of
leaky boots Upon my ♪
-♪ Feet -Sorry, Cook!
♪ Gotta drag myself up
♪ By my one good bootlace
♪ Gotta work My
rotten socks off ♪
♪ If I want to make ends meet
♪ I've poured everything
I've got into my chocolate ♪
♪ Now it's time To show
the world my recipes ♪
Good luck, Willy!
♪ I've got 12
silver sovereigns ♪
♪ In my pocket
Goodbye, Cook!
♪ And a hatful of dreams
♪ There's a famous restaurant
On every street here ♪
♪ There's Brandino's
And the bar Parisienne ♪
- Restaurant map, sir?
- Thank you.
♪ Got a little map to tell
me Where to eat here ♪
♪ Had a dozen
Silver sovereigns ♪
♪ Now I'm somehow down to ten ♪
♪ Want the finest produce? ♪
- ♪ This is where
They stock it ♪
That's three sovereigns, mate.
♪ Though the prices Are
suspiciously extreme ♪
Break my pumpkin,
you pay for it.
♪ I've got... ♪
Five, six, seven...
♪ Six silver sovereigns
In my pocket ♪
♪ And a hatful of dreams ♪
- Brush your coat, sir?
- No, thank you.
- Cologne?
- No. Leave me alone.
♪ At last ♪
♪ The Galeries Gourmet ♪
♪ I knew that We'd
see it one day ♪
It's everything you said, Mamma.
♪ And oh, so much more ♪
♪ Each way that you turn,
Another famous Chocolate store ♪
♪ Here's my destiny ♪
♪ I just need to unlock it ♪
♪ Will I crash and burn ♪
♪ Or go up like a rocket? ♪
♪ I got nothing to offer ♪
♪ But my chocolate ♪
♪ And a hatful ♪
♪ Of dreams ♪
Yeah!
No daydreaming.
♪ In this city, Anyone
can be successful ♪
♪ If they've talent And
work hard, or so they say ♪
♪ But they didn't mention
It would be so stressful ♪
♪ Just to make A dozen
silver sovereigns ♪
♪ Last more than a day ♪
Could you spare a sovereign
for a place to sleep, love?
Of course.
Here. Take all you need.
Thank you.
♪ I've got one silver
sovereign In my pocket ♪
♪ And a hatful of dreams ♪
Hmm.
There we go.
Time for a little nightcap.
Mm.
Okay.
Hello there. No,
stop. Hey, shoo.
Go away, stop!
Go away, shoo! Shoo!
Stop!
Sit.
Sorry about Tiddles.
Seems to have an
unusual interest
in your legs.
Must be these pants.
I got them from a
mailman in Minsk.
That would be it.
Tiddles would spend all day
pursuing postal
workers if he could.
Wouldn't you, boy?
You're not planning on
sleeping there, are you, son?
Oh, it's just for a night.
By this time tomorrow, I
plan to have made my fortune.
By this time tomorrow,
you'll be frozen solid.
Oh, don't be ridiculous.
Ooh.
Perhaps it is a little
cold for camping.
But unfortunately, I'm not in a
position to pay for a room, sir.
- Oh, I'm sorry to hear that.
- Mmm.
But as luck would have it,
I know someone who might
be able to help you out.
Really?
Here we are, Mr. Wonka.
Home sweet home.
Get your filthy paws
off my front door,
you mangy mutt.
- If that's you, Bleacher,
you'd better have my gin.
Oh, I have something better
than gin, Mrs. Scrubitt.
A guest.
Hmm.
Oh! Well, why didn't you say?
Come on in, sir.
Welcome to Scrubitt and Bleacher's
Guest House and Laundry.
Make yourself at home, warm
your cockles by the fire.
- Gin?
- Oh.
Noodle!
Yes, Mrs. Scrubitt?
Put that book down and get
our guest a glass o' gin.
Poor man's frozen half to death.
Thank you, Mrs. Scrubitt.
You and your husband
have been so kind to me.
Husband?
Him?
Husband.
Oh, you'd love
that, wouldn't ya?
- No.
- Oh, I'm holding out for someone
far superior to
that idle peasant.
Chin-chin.
That is extremely strong stuff.
Yeah, you can run cars on that.
So, what is it I can do
for you? Room, is it?
Well, yes, but, uh...
Mr. Wonka is
temporarily embarrassed.
Oh, no. You don't say.
I'm afraid that's
true, Mrs. Scrubitt.
But...
- all that's about to change.
- Oh, yeah?
You see, I'm something
of a magician,
inventor and chocolate maker.
And first thing tomorrow
at the Galeries Gourmet,
I plan to unveil my most
astonishing creation yet.
- Oh?
- Prepare to be amazed
as I present to you...
A teapot?
No, that's just for making tea.
One second.
That's for my stew.
It's in here somewhere.
Don't you worry, Mr. Wonka. I can
see you're a man of great ingenuity.
And we've got just
the thing for ya.
The entrepreneurial package.
Now, the room is one
sovereign a night,
but you don't have to
pay till 6:00 tomorrow.
Does that give you enough
time to earn a few pennies?
More than enough,
Mrs. Scrubitt.
Thank you.
Oh, it's the least I can
do for a stranger in need.
Now, sign here and
we're all done.
All righty.
Read the small print.
What?
- Thank you,
Noodle. That'll do.
Ooh. What'd she say?
- Who's that, then?
- The girl.
-What girl?
-That girl. It sounded like,
"Read the small print." And
there does seem to be a lot of...
Oh. Oh. Oh.
Oh. Oh.
Oh. Just keeps on coming.
Yeah, you don't wanna
listen to Noodle, Mr. Wonka.
- She's damaged.
- Damaged?
Orphan Syndrome.
Orphan Syndrome?
She was dropped down the laundry
chute as a bab, and I took her in
out the goodness of my heart,
and I've done my best,
Mr. Wonka, honest, I have,
but she's been left with
a suspicious nature.
She sees conspiracy everywhere.
- Poor girl.
- I know.
These are just your
standard Ts and Cs,
but you're welcome to
take a look if you want.
I'll just give it a once-over.
Well, that all seems
to be in order.
- Really?
- Uh-huh.
- Hello.
- Ah!
Then welcome to Scrubitt's.
There you are, Mr. Wonka.
The entrepreneurial suite.
There's your four-poster,
and your sink plus soap,
and there's a little
mint on your pillow.
Fantastic.
What kind people.
Noodle!
Oh, Noodle!
Yes, Mrs. Scrubitt?
I've been lookin' for you.
What do you want?
I wanna teach you a lesson,
you miserable little bookworm.
What did I do wrong?
You know what you did, you brat.
- Stop squirming!
- What? No, please.
You ever interfere
in my business again,
and you'll be in this coop
all week. Do you understand?
Yes, Mrs. Scrubitt.
Sorry, Mrs. Scrubitt.
I should think so, too.
Here we go, Mamma.
Ladies and gentlemen of
the Galeries Gourmet,
my name is Willy Wonka,
and I have come to show
you a marvelous morsel,
an incredible edible,
an unbeatable eatable,
the likes of which this
world has never seen.
So quiet up and listen down.
No, scratch that, reverse it.
I give to you
the Hoverchoc.
♪ In a ♪
♪ Jungle near Mumbai
♪ There's a little hoverfly
♪ Whose wings go At a
thousand flaps a sec ♪
♪ And that's no lie ♪
♪ These microscopic fleas ♪
♪ Like chocolate
More than leaves ♪
♪ And when asked
nicely, Lay precisely ♪
♪ One little egg
In each of these ♪
♪ When it hatches
From its shell ♪
♪ It gives a happy
yell Whoo-hoo! ♪
♪ How thrilling to be living
In a chocolate hotel ♪
♪ It beats its wings with glee
And then, as you will see ♪
♪ The chocolate will levitate ♪
♪ And float most gracefully
♪ Well, there's chocolate
♪ And there's chocolate ♪
♪ But only Wonka's
Makes your eyes ♪
♪ Pop out their socke-lets ♪
♪ Put your hand Into
your pocke-let ♪
♪ Get yourself Some
Wonka chocolate ♪
♪ Come now I insist ♪
♪ You've never Had
chocolate like this ♪
♪ No, you've never Had
Bravo!
Thank you.
- Miss Bon-Bon?
- Yes, Mr. Slugworth.
Call the police.
Very good, sir.
Well, who wants to try one?
- Me, please!
- I will.
- Mr. Slugworth, sir.
- 'Scuse me.
Mr. Fickelgruber.
And Mr. Prodnose.
What an honor.
Ever since I was a little boy...
That is quite a handshake.
It's a business
handshake, Mr. Wonka.
Lets people know
I mean business.
- Huh...
- Now, come along.
Let's try one of these
so-called Hoverchocs.
Ooh.
It's not just chocolate, is it?
There's...
- marshmallow.
- That's right.
Harvested from the
mallow marshes of Peru.
And caramel.
- But... but it's...
- Salted.
With the bittersweet
tears of a Russian clown.
And is that...
Surely not?
Cherry?
Cherry-picked by the pick
of the cherry pickers
from the Imperial
Gardens in Japan.
Well, Mr. Wonka.
I've been in this
business a very long time,
and I can safely say
that of all the chocolate
I have ever tasted,
this is without doubt
the absolute 100% worst.
Whoo!
There we have it,
ladies and gentlemen.
An endorsement from Mr...
Wait. The worst?
We three are the
fiercest of rivals,
and yet we agree on one thing.
A good chocolate
should be simple.
Plain. Uncomplicated.
Whereas this, with all
its bells and whistles...
Well, it's just...
Weird.
That's a shame.
- If you thought the
chocolate was weird,
you're gonna hate
what happens next.
Hmm?
What's happening?
Whoa, what's going on?
That's the hoverfly.
It's broken out of its cocoon.
It's flapping its
wings like billy-oh.
My hair! You mean a
fly is doing this?
Yes. But don't worry.
- It'll be completely unharmed.
- Oh, thank you.
In about 20 minutes,
it'll get tired
and exit through your rear.
You what?
He means we're going to fart
them out of our botties!
Yes, I know what he meant.
You're off your rocker, Wonka!
Who in their right mind
wants a chocolate
that makes you fly?
Well, let's find out, shall we?
Who's for a Hoverchoc?
I want one!
One sovereign,
please. Thank you.
Thank you very much.
One sovereign.
Thank you, madam.
Enjoy your flight.
Look, I'm flying! I'm flying!
How's the view up there?
Not too high, darling!
Beat it, kid.
All right, folks.
Nothin' to see here.
Just a small group of people
defyin' the laws of gravity.
- Yeah.
- Hook 'em, boys.
That's the Hoverchoc,
sir. That's the point.
I'm afraid we've had some
complaints about you, sir.
Complaints?
That you're disrupting the
trade of other businesses.
I'm regrettably
obliged to move you on
and to confiscate
your earnings.
- Hey! What are you doing?
- No!
Don't worry, it's
going to a good cause.
- Get off.
- Sick kids, or something.
Sorry, sir. Rules is rules.
Cheeky devil, you! Come here!
Could you at least
leave me a sovereign?
I need to pay for my room.
Here.
Thank you.
Evening, Mr. Wonka.
How'd it go?
Not quite as well as I'd hoped.
Oh, shame. Well, I'm afraid
we do have to settle up now.
Well, thankfully, the
room's taken care of.
Believe we said a sovereign.
For the room, yes.
But you have
incurred a few extras
during the course of your
residency with ourselves.
- Have I?
- Yes, you have.
There was that glass of
gin you had on arrival,
and if I remember rightly,
you warmed your
cockles by the fire.
He did indeed, Mrs. Scrubitt.
Cockle-warming is extra, see?
Used the stairs to get
to his room, and all.
Oh, then you've got
your stair charge,
and that is per step,
I'm afraid. Up and down.
Now, tell me, Mr. Wonka,
did you happen to
use the mini bar?
There's a minibar?
Mini bar of soap.
By the sink.
- Uh... I might have, briefly.
- Oh-ho!
See? Even Bleacher knows you
never touch the mini bar,
and he was raised in a ditch.
Add in your mattress hire,
your linen lease, and
your pillow penalty,
and you are looking at...
Ten thousand sovereigns.
You gotta be kidding me?
It's all in the
small print, dearie.
I don't have 10,000 sovereigns.
Then we have a
problem, Mr. Wonka.
You're gonna have to work it off
in the Wash House, ain't ya?
At a sovereign a day.
Ten thousand days is...
Twenty-seven years.
- Hey!
- Four months.
And 16 days.
Ah.
- You must be Mr. Wonka.
- Who are you?
Abacus Crunch,
chartered accountant.
At least, I was.
- Now, uh...
- He runs the place.
And you best do as he says,
or you'll answer to me.
Piper Benz. Plumber by trade.
This is Miss Lottie Bell.
Hi.
She don't talk much.
And I'm Larry Chucklesworth!
Comedian.
Hmm.
So they got all of
you, too, did they?
I'm afraid so.
We each of us found ourselves
in need of a cheap
place to stay,
and neglected to
read the small print.
One moment of stupidity,
followed by endless regret.
Sounds like my third marriage.
I'm sorry, I do that a lot.
- He does.
- A lot.
I've only been married once,
and it didn't work out.
There's gotta be
some way outta here.
You don't think we've tried?
There are bars on the window
and there's a dog on the door.
And even if you could get out,
that contract is watertight.
If you're not here at roll call,
Mrs. Scrubitt will call the police,
they'll bring you right back,
and she'll charge you a
thousand for the inconvenience.
All right, everybody.
Back to work.
Come along, Mr. Wonka.
You come with me.
You're in here. On suds.
Whoa.
♪ First, you pick
up The apparel ♪
♪ And you stick
it In a barrel ♪
♪ Scrub, scrub ♪
♪ Then you take It to the mangle
And you turn a giant handle ♪
♪ Scrub, scrub ♪
♪ Then it's hung up really
high Until it's nearly dry ♪
♪ Scrub, scrub ♪
♪ But when we sing this song
The day don't seem so long ♪
♪ Scrub, scrub ♪
It's still long, though.
♪ Gotta press out
All the creases ♪
♪ From the dresses
And chemises ♪
♪ Rub, rub ♪
♪ Gotta fold 'em
Like they told us ♪
♪ Or they'll scold us ♪
♪ And withhold our grub, grub ♪
♪ We all signed the dotted
line So we gotta do our time ♪
♪ Scrub, scrub
♪ Scrub, scrub ♪
And if you don't agree...
See clause five.
- Section 7A.
- Paragraph 22.
Part D.
Which says...
♪ Scrub, scrub ♪
♪ Scrub, scrub
Room service.
Told you to read
the small print.
Slight problem with that.
You can't read, can you?
I focused my studies almost
exclusively on chocolate.
I see.
For everything else, I've relied
on the kindness of strangers.
And look where that's got
you. The staff quarters.
You've got a bed.
You had a bed.
Desk, and a wash basin/toilet.
- Ugh.
- The water comes
in two temperatures. Cold...
and colder.
How much do you owe them?
Ten thousand.
Count yourself
lucky. I owe 30.
What? How do you
owe them money?
I thought they found you
down a laundry chute.
Oh, they did.
Took me in out of the
goodness of their hearts
and charged me
for the privilege.
What a pair of monsters.
The greedy beat the needy
every time, Mr. Wonka.
Guess it's just the
way of the world.
Oh, come on, Noodle.
That's just your Orphan
Syndrome talking.
- My what?
- Your Orphan Syndrome.
And we are not gonna
be eating any slops.
What are you doing?
I'm making chocolate, o' course.
How do you like it? Dark?
White? Nutty?
Absolutely insane?
I don't know.
I've never had any.
You've never had chocolate?
- No.
- What?
You've never had chocolate?
Still no.
Well, this is unbelievable.
I mean, this is outrageous.
Well, lucky for you,
Noodle, I have a selection
of the world's
finest ingredients
right here in my travel factory.
Whoa.
Where to begin?
That's the question.
I know!
Silver Linings.
Made of condensed thunder clouds
and liquid sunlight.
Helps you see that
faint ray o' hope
beyond the shadow of despair.
Just what we need,
wouldn't you say?
Did you always wanna
make chocolate?
No.
Back when I was your age,
I wanted to be a magician.
My mom was a cook.
We lived on the river,
just the two of us.
In a perfect little
world of our own.
The way I remember
it, I used to spend
every waking hour
trying to come up
with some new trick
to impress my mom.
Bravo!
But the real magic
came from her.
We didn't have a lotta
money, but each week,
she brought home one cocoa bean.
And by the time my
birthday came around,
there was enough to make
a single bar o' chocolate.
But it wasn't just
any old chocolate.
Far from it.
This has to be the best
chocolate in the world.
Oh, don't know about that.
They say the very best
comes from a place
called the Galeries Gourmet.
Theirs can't be any
better than yours, Mamma.
It's impossible.
Well, as it so happens,
I do know a little secret
that even those
fancy-pants don't.
What is it?
I'll tell ya.
When you're older.
Now get to sleep.
We should go, Amma.
Where's that, then?
- To the Galeries Gourmet.
- What?
- And start a shop?
- Yeah.
With our name above the
door and everything.
That's a wonderful dream, honey.
Is that all it is?
Just a dream?
Hey now.
Every good thing in this
world started with a dream.
So you hold on to yours.
And when you do share
chocolate with the world,
oh, I'll be right
there beside ya.
Promise?
Do better than that.
I pinkie promise.
Now,
sleep.
So, what was it, Willy?
What was the secret?
I never found out.
Soon after, she fell sick.
And before I knew it, all I had
left was her bar of chocolate.
That's why I'm here, Noodle.
So I can feel the same
way I did back then,
eating chocolate with her.
What do you mean?
My mom once promised that when I
share chocolate with the world,
she'd be right there beside me.
I know it sounds crazy,
but I always hoped
she'd somehow keep that promise.
She might even
tell me her secret.
Here. Try one.
Wish you hadn't done that.
- You don't like it?
- No,
I like it. It's just...
What?
Now each day I don't have
chocolate will be a little harder.
Then how would you like to have all
the chocolate you can eat, every day,
for the rest of your life?
A lifetime supply?
A lifetime supply.
What would I have to do?
Not much. Just get
me out of here.
- Are you crazy?
- Shh!
It's easy. I'll get
someone to cover my shift,
and you could smuggle me
out in your laundry cart.
- But I...
- Just for a few hours, mind.
No one will even
know I was gone.
What's the point of that?
To sell chocolate, o' course!
We'll split the profits
and pay off Mrs.
Scrubitt in no time.
It's a nice idea, Willy.
- It's a great idea.
- But it'll never work.
'Course it will.
Eat your chocolate.
You don't understand.
Mrs. Scrubitt's like a hawk. She
keeps her beady eye on everything
that comes in and out of
the Wash House except...
Huh.
What is it?
No, it's nothing.
Oh, okay.
Huh.
Double-huh! That's
not nothing.
That's the Silver Lining.
It's given you an idea.
Okay. So, the one time
she dropped her guard
was when this aristocrat
came to the laundry.
He was only asking
for directions,
but she was all over
him like a rash.
It was disgusting.
That's it, Noodle.
All we have to do is
find an aristocrat
and slip out while
she's distracted.
Yeah, but...
where are we going to
find an aristocrat?
Huh.
Huh?
A double-huh.
Do you have a pencil and paper?
- Uh-huh.
- I got an idea.
I've come to make a confession.
You sound great,
fellas. Keep it up.
Forgive me, Father,
for I have sinned.
I have had 150 of these
since my last confession.
Temptation is very
hard to resist.
Mmm.
Send me down.
I'll see you later.
Good evening, Chief.
They're all waiting.
Thank you very much.
Good evening, gentlemen.
I've brought my invoice.
One chocolatier moved
on for the usual fee.
Oh.
Here we go, baby.
There's the good stuff. Yeah.
- Tell me, Chief...
- Mm-hmm?
How would you like to
earn a few more of those?
Oh, I am listening.
We think that Mr. Wonka
might require a little
more than simply moving on.
- Oh.
- He's good.
Too good.
And what's more,
he only charges a
sovereign a chocolate.
So anyone can afford
them, even the...
You know, the...
- The poor?
- Oh, dear.
I've just been a little
bit sick in my mouth.
Could you please
refrain from mentioning
that demographic in my presence?
He doesn't like it
when people say "poor."
Sorry, Felix.
We want you to send
Wonka a message.
Backed up by physical force.
That if he attempts to sell
chocolate in this town again,
he is liable to meet
with a little accident.
In which he dies.
Yeah, no, I... I
got that already.
You don't have to
keep saying it.
I'm just making sure we're
all on the same page.
Well, no one's on your page.
What's that supposed to mean?
Well, I know what it means...
Actually, what does it mean?
Gentlemen, please.
So, what do you say, Chief?
Do we have a deal?
Well, listen, fellas, I'm
an officer of the law.
I can't just go around
roughin' up your competition.
I'm sorry.
Well now, Chief.
I can see that you're
a man of integrity.
Thank you.
But ask yourself this...
♪ Have you got a sweet tooth? ♪
♪ I do ♪
♪ A hunger That
you have to feed? ♪
♪ Have you got a sweet tooth? ♪
♪ I do ♪
♪ Well, we've got
Everything you need ♪
Mmm.
♪ Don't give me That
conscience nonsense ♪
♪ It's simply ♪
♪ Quid pro quo ♪
♪ So, a hundred Of
your favorites ♪
♪ Sorry, I'm afraid it's no ♪
Promised the wife I'd
cut down on chocolate.
You know, I gotta get in shape
for the Policeman's Ball, so...
♪ But think about
Your sweet tooth ♪
♪ I do ♪
♪ I've had it
since I was a boy ♪
♪ Your naughty
Little sweet tooth ♪
♪ It's true ♪
♪ The only thing
That brings you joy ♪
♪ Don't look At
your waistline ♪
- ♪ It's fine!
- ♪ Come on!
♪ Who needs To
see their toes? ♪
♪ So ♪
♪ Seven hundred boxes ♪
♪ That's a lot Of
chocolates... ♪
♪ Mm-hmm
No!
Gentlemen, let's
give it the big sell.
♪ Have you got a sweet tooth? ♪
-♪ Me, too -♪ Fellas...
♪ Have you got The
hots for chocs? ♪
I do, really. Yeah.
♪ Do you think that candy's ♪
- ♪ Dandy?
- ♪ Oh, yeah
♪ Well, we've got lots and
lots And lots and lots ♪
-♪ And lots and lots
-♪ Why am I singing?
♪ If the wife's complaining ♪
♪ Body-shaming ♪
♪ It's amazing What a
tailor can conceal ♪
♪ Keep your wretched
Chocolates ♪
♪ Eighteen-hundred boxes? ♪
♪ Oh, deal
Bell.
- Here.
- Benz.
Mm.
Chucklesworth.
Crunch.
- Here.
- Wonka.
Bleacher!
Toilet's blocked again.
Oh, wow.
The unmistakable sound of love.
You what?
Don't tell me you
hadn't noticed.
What?
She's madly in love with you.
Mrs. Scrubitt?
Besotted.
And why not? Look at you.
Fine figure of a man.
You just need to tidy
yourself up a little bit.
Get some new clothes.
Have a bath.
A bath?
You do know what
they say, right?
What do they say?
She'll be thankful for an ankle.
- Yes.
- And pleased to see your knees.
- Right.
- But if you wanna
- make her sigh...
- Tell me.
Show her some thigh.
Bleacher!
It's overflowing now.
- Get in there. Back to work.
- All right.
It's up to me ankles!
Time-waster.
Bleacher!
Curse that idle peasant.
What you got there?
Nothing.
Do you like that coop, Noodle?
All right.
I was collecting laundry from
Professor Monocle the other day.
Yeah.
He's writing a book about
the Bavarian Royal Family.
Boring.
He's got sketches of
noblemen all over his wall.
So?
This one looked rather familiar.
Oh.
Blow me. That looks
exactly like...
Mr. Bleacher.
Are you telling me Bleacher
is a Bavarian aristocrat?
Uh-huh.
Go and get my gin.
♪ First, You pick
up the apparel ♪
♪ Then you stick
it In a barrel ♪
♪ Scrub, scrub ♪
♪ Then you put it
Through the mangle ♪
♪ Making sure You
don't get strangled ♪
♪ Scrub, scrub ♪
Whoa!
♪ Oh, Tiddles,
Here's your chance ♪
♪ To chew my mailman pants!
♪ Something must be going on ♪
♪ 'Cause we never
Change our song ♪
♪ Scrub, scrub ♪
Oh, so you finally managed
to drag your lazy...
Have you done something
with your hair?
Maybe.
Maybe not.
Where'd you get them dungarees?
Lost property.
Why,
do they suit me?
Yeah.
Not bad, I suppose.
What're you doing all
the way over there?
Keeping my knees warm.
Well, why don't
you come over here
and have a glass o' gin?
Why don't you come over here,
where it's all hot?
Whoa!
Oh! Oh, my Lord.
Ladies and gentlemen,
may I present to you
a brand-new contraption
of my creation,
an innovation in
laundrification.
♪ Scrub, scrub
Let me ask you a question, how does
Tiddles wanna spend all his time?
Chasing after mailmen.
And what do I have to do all
day, fellow scrubbers, please?
♪ Scrub, scrub ♪
But now, with Willy Wonka's Wild and
Wonderful Wishy-washy Wonka Walker,
please don't make
me say that again,
Tiddles gets to run
and I can have fun.
♪ Scrub, scrub ♪
Just popping out for a bit.
I'll be back before roll call.
Until then, Tiddles
has agreed to...
♪ Scrub, scrub
So, tell me all about Bavaria.
- Where?
- Where you're from.
Oh, yes. It's very...
- Bavarian.
- Oh, whoo.
All clear.
- Really?
- Yeah.
We did it! Well done, Noodle.
I can't believe it worked.
Wait till you see how much
chocolate I made last night.
We sell this, and
we're gonna be...
Oh, no.
What's going on, Willy?
Not again.
Where are the chocolates?
I don't know how to tell
you this, Noodle, but...
they've been stolen.
- Stolen?
- Mm-hmm.
Who by?
The Little Orange Man.
What?
The Little Orange Man. I
didn't tell you about him?
No, ya didn't.
He's my nemesis.
About yea high.
Comes in the dead of the night,
and he steals all my chocolate.
Been happening every few weeks for
the past three, four years now.
Really?
Sometimes I spy him
in that strange realm
'twixt sleep and wake,
green hair glinting
in the moonlight.
Green hair?
One day I shall
catch him, Noodle.
- Willy.
- When I do...
- Willy!
- Hmm?
You don't seriously expect
me to believe this, do you?
Of course I do. What other
explanation is there?
I don't know,
- that you go to sleep...
- Mm-hmm.
Dream 'bout Little Green Man...
Orange man, green hair. Yeah.
And while you're dreaming,
stuff your face with chocolate!
Stuff my...
That makes a lot more sense.
Why'd I ever think
this would work?
I've been eating all
my own chocolate?
- Stupid Silver Linings.
- I don't think I have been.
Hey!
There's nothing stupid
about my chocolate.
If Mrs. Scrubitt
had spotted us,
I'd be in the coop right now.
Look, I'm sorry, okay?
But we can make more chocolate.
Only problem is I'm
all out of milk.
Well, that's not a problem.
Milk.
A, that is stealing.
And C,
Willy Wonka does not
use any old cow's milk.
For this particular creation,
I require the milk of a giraffe.
Okay... fine.
As a matter of fact,
there's one at the zoo.
Bingala!
But A, the zoo is not that way.
Great.
And B,
they're not gonna let you just
walk in there and milk it.
Mm. That, my dear Noodle,
is why we're very lucky
the Little Orange
Man didn't find this.
What is it?
From Zoo Management.
In recognition of
your years of service.
But I've only been here a year.
Which is why there's
only one chocolate.
Huh.
Well, thank you very much.
You're welcome. Good night!
Hey, well done, Noodle.
So, what is it really?
It's called A Big Night Out.
A single chocolate
that perfectly mimics
- a night on the town.
- Mmm.
The outer layer, a
champagne truffle.
That's lovely.
The next is white wine.
Mmm.
Followed by red.
Now we are talking!
That's when the singing
and dancing starts.
♪ We're gonna Have
a party tonight! ♪
It's when he hits the layer o'
whiskey fudge he'll get emotional.
She was the only
woman I ever loved!
He might do something reckless.
I'll give her a call.
What harm could it do?
Hello, Gwennie? It's Basil.
I just wanted to say,
I've always loved you.
I love you so much. What?
It's Basil Bond.
We sat together in
chemistry at school.
No, no, don't hang up!
Finally, some old port from the
back of the cupboard, and...
Hmm.
Let's go.
Noodle, let's go.
Why don't they fly away?
I don't know. Perhaps they
haven't thought of it.
- You're kidding?
- No, I'm serious.
That's the thing
about flamingos.
They need someone
to show 'em the way.
Huh.
Giraffe.
Giraffe. Giraffe.
Ah! Giraffe.
You have got to
learn how to read.
Why?
You were nearly
eaten by a tiger.
"Nearly" is the key
word there, Noodle.
I've nearly been eaten
by a lot of things,
and none of them got
more than a nibble.
Giraffe.
Okay, I'll learn how to read.
Good evening, Miss, um...
- Abigail.
Whoa! Easy, now.
I brought acacia mints.
Oh.
Giraffes are just crazy
about my acacia mints.
Love 'em more than
anything else.
Except being scratched
under the chin, you see?
You wanna give it a go, Noodle?
Me?
Yeah. Why not?
Okay.
- Ugh!
- Oh!
Think she likes you.
Miss Abigail,
if my colleague here
gives you a good scratch,
do you think you could
possibly spare us
a pint or two of your milk?
So, have you done this before?
Once. In Africa.
Magnificent beast.
- Was she wild?
- Wild?
She was absolutely furious.
You sure can be silly, Willy.
I suppose that's
true-dle, Noodle.
True-dle?
That doesn't work, does it?
Nothing rhymes with Noodle.
Where'd you get
that name, anyway?
Doesn't matter.
No, go on.
This.
It's all I have of
my real parents. See?
"N" for Noodle.
Or Nora, or Nina,
or nothing at all.
Can't you trace the owner?
You don't think I've tried?
When I was a kid,
I always hoped that
I'd find my parents.
And they'd live in this beautiful
old building full of books.
My mom, she'd be waiting
there for me at the door,
and I'd run into her arms.
She'd give me this big hug
like she'd never let me go.
But then I realized it
was just a stupid dream.
There's nothing
stupid about that.
Isn't there?
I know things haven't
been easy for you, Noodle.
But they're gonna get better.
I'm not gonna let you rot
in that Wash House forever.
You promise?
I can do better than that.
I pinkie promise.
And that's the most
solemn vow there is.
Get scratchin'.
We don't have long until that
guard comes to-dle, Noodle.
- To-dle!
- It's not even a word!
Oh.
I'm gonna keep working on it.
♪ For a moment ♪
♪ Life doesn't
seem quite So bad ♪
♪ For a moment ♪
♪ I kinda forgot to be sad ♪
♪ He turns night to day ♪
♪ But don't get carried away ♪
♪ Never let down your guard ♪
♪ Let them into your
heart For a moment ♪
♪ Not for a moment ♪
I got it, Noodle!
Listen to this.
♪ Noodle, Noodle,
Apple strudel ♪
♪ Some people don't ♪
♪ And some people doodle ♪
♪ Snakes, flamingos,
Bears, and poodles ♪
♪ Singing this song Will
improve your moodle ♪
♪ Noodle-dee-dee
♪ Noodle-dee-dum ♪
Willy!
♪ We're having oodles
♪ And oodles of fun ♪
Thanks, Abigail!
-♪ For a moment -♪ Noodle,
Noodle, Apple strudel ♪
♪ My life has
turned Upside down ♪
♪ Some people don't And
some people doodle ♪
-♪ For a moment -♪
Snakes, flamingos
-♪ Bears and poodles
-♪ I can't keep my feet
♪ On the ground ♪
♪ Singing this song Will
improve your moodle ♪
-♪ He's the one good
thing -♪ Noodle-dee-dee
♪ Noodle-dee-dum ♪
-♪ That's ever happened to
me -♪ We're having oodles
♪ And oodles of fun ♪
Chief,
you know that fella
you wanted a word with?
♪ For a moment ♪
♪ Life doesn't
seem Quite so bad ♪
♪ And for a moment ♪
♪ I kinda forgot to be sad
Mr. Wonka! A word in
private, if I may.
Certainly, Officer.
- Be on your way, Affable.
- Are you sure, sir?
Oh, yeah. This is
between me and Mr. Wonka.
You better get
outta here, Noodle.
- But Willy...
- Don't worry about me.
I've talked my way out of
tighter spots than this.
I'll meet you back at the cart.
Now, Officer, if this
is about Abigail...
I got a message for you, pal.
Whoa! No.
Do not sell chocolate
in this town!
You got it?
Not really, I'm afraid.
Oh, so you got a mouth
on you, huh, Candy Man?
I said...
Don't sell chocolate!
You hear me that time?
I have water in my ears.
Oh.
Yeah, that... You've...
Okay, that makes sense. Yeah.
Listen, I'm sorry.
I'm all outta whack.
Truth is, I don't
wanna be doin' this.
I don't want you
to be doing this.
But I still gotta
give ya a message.
Sell chocolate in
this town again,
you're gonna get more
than a bonk on the head.
I don't have a bonk on the head.
What is with me today? I...
- Can you give me just a second?
- Sure.
Lord Bleachowitz.
Mrs. Scrubitt. Your eyes are
like two rabbit droppings
in a couple of bowls
- of custard.
- Oh!
You really do have
a way with words.
See you downstairs.
Geronimo!
Ah, Mr. Wonka.
Good of you to join us.
- Not late, am I?
- Well, no.
Cutting it a bit fine, but...
Has Tiddles been
pulling his weight?
As a matter of fact,
Tiddles has been
a very good boy,
and productivity is up 30%.
We took the afternoon off.
But that's not the point.
This is the point.
- Not now, Larry.
- Sorry.
The point is...
Where have you been?
And why do you smell of giraffe?
Guess I owe you
guys an explanation.
- Mm.
- The truth is,
I'm a chocolate maker.
Not just any chocolate.
The best in the world.
Ah, well, Noodle's flattering
me, but she's right.
They're exquisite.
Plan is to sell chocolate
and pay off Mrs. Scrubitt.
At least, that was
the plan, until...
Oh, let me guess.
You had a little run-in
with the Chief of Police?
How do you know that?
Because I was
Slugworth's accountant.
For a week, at least.
His regular bookkeeper
was off sick.
- Station, please.
- And I was called
halfway across the
country to take his place.
Good evening, Mr. Slugworth.
I just need your signature on...
Seemed a straightforward job.
Oh.
Until I realized
there were two sets of books.
One for the authorities,
and one which told the truth.
Slugworth, Fickelgruber,
and Prodnose
have been in cahoots for years.
A sort of chocolate
cartel, if you will.
They've been watering
down their chocolate
and storing the excess
in a secret vault
deep beneath the cathedral,
guarded round the clock
by a corrupt cleric
and 500 chocoholic monks.
The only way in is down a
secret elevator, and past
the Mistress of the Keys.
A subterranean sentinel...
who hasn't seen
sunlight in years.
Good evening.
There's thousands of
gallons of chocolate
down there, and the
Cartel use it to bribe,
blackmail, and bludgeon
the competition.
- I do not care that they
were school children...
they were in our way. Next
time, put your foot down.
Miss Bon-Bon?
Good morning, Mr. Slugworth.
From now on, I'll be keeping
the ledger in the vault.
Very good, sir.
Oh, and Mr. Crunch?
Yes?
You're fired.
Very good, sir.
I'm sorry, Mr. Wonka,
but they've got you right
where they want you.
You can't get a shop
without selling chocolate,
and you can't sell
chocolate without a shop.
Hey, Noodle!
Noodle! Psst!
What is it, Willy?
Watch out.
Whoa!
What's this for?
Your wages. A lifetime
supply, remember?
You didn't have to do that.
Of course I did. I
gave you my word.
Well, thanks.
- I've got something for you, too.
- For me?
What's this?
- Glass half full?
- Other way up.
Glass half empty.
It's an "A." Your
first letter.
I'm teaching you to read.
Oh, Noodle.
Well, I can't have my business
partner eaten by a tiger.
Or nearly eaten.
So we're still partners?
Sure, but I don't know how
we're gonna sell any chocolate.
Every time the police show up,
you'd have to vanish into thin air.
Like a magician.
Right!
Yeah, but it's one thing
when you're onstage.
You have ropes and
pulleys and trapdoors.
There's none of
those on the street.
As a matter of fact, there are.
There are trapdoors
all over the city.
They're called storm drains.
I'd be happy to show you around
if you cut me in on the action.
If you're recruiting,
I'd do anything
to get out of here
and make up with my wife.
I don't have any
practical skills, but,
I can talk like I'm under water.
And if you need someone
to handle communications,
I'm your woman.
Lottie?
What? Why you all
staring at me?
I did not know she could speak.
- I thought you were a mime.
- No,
I actually used to work
at the telephone exchange.
But back then, I was
quite the chatterbox.
But since I came here,
I haven't had much
to chat about.
Far be it from me
to pour cold water
on all your fun,
but if Mrs. Scrubitt catches
you trying to escape,
you'll all get six
months in the coop.
So just think about that
before getting involved in
this harebrained scheme.
But it's not
harebrained, Abacus.
Willy's chocolates
are incredible.
Try one.
That's very kind of you, Noodle.
I don't care how good
his chocolates are.
When do we start?
I guess what I'm trying
to say, Barbara, is, um,
- will you marry me?
- Oh.
I dunno, Colin.
You're a lovely man, but
I'm looking for someone
to sweep me off
my feet. You know,
whisk me off to a
life of adventure.
Could that be you?
- No.
- Oh.
Not with my chronic
lack of self-confidence.
- Uh, I best be off.
- Oh, but Colin...
Sorry to have wasted
your time, Barbara.
Uh, taxi!
Uh, monsieur, can I help you?
Oh, waiter.
Do you have anything
for a broken heart?
♪ So the taxis never stop ♪
♪ The girls think
You're a flop ♪
♪ You're wet and cold,
You're getting old ♪
♪ Your confidence is shot ♪
It's true.
♪ When people look at you ♪
♪ They seem to look
Straight through ♪
♪ Or like you're something
Brown they found ♪
♪ Upon the bottom
Of their shoe ♪
Have you been following me?
♪ But this should lift The
gloom My Giraffe Milk Macaroon ♪
♪ Just take a chance
And you'll be dancing ♪
♪ To a different tune ♪
♪ Goodbye to feeling small
And frightened of it all ♪
♪ Just eat a few of these ♪
♪ And you'll be
feeling ten feet tall ♪
♪ Well, there's ♪
♪ Chocolate
♪ And there's chocolate ♪
♪ Only Wonka's makes Your
confidence skyrocke-let ♪
He doesn't even work here.
♪ Put your hand ♪
♪ Into your pocke-let
♪ Get yourself Some
Wonka chocolate ♪
♪ Madam, just one kiss ♪
♪ Yes, please! ♪
♪ You've never had chocolate
♪ Like this
♪ No, we've never Had
chocolate like this ♪
- ♪ Have you tried
His new one? ♪ - ♪ No
♪ Oh, you've got to have a go ♪
♪ Just pop one in And everything
becomes A Broadway show ♪
♪ The news that
Makes you gasp ♪
♪ The jokes that
Make you laugh ♪
♪ All that you say
And do all day ♪
♪ Will be choreographed ♪
♪ Lost your hair,
Can't think where ♪
♪ Feeling fairly
bare Up there ♪
♪ Don't despair,
I come prepared ♪
♪ Behold My Hair
Repair Eclair ♪
♪ It's made from ground vanilla
From the markets of Manila ♪
♪ Take heed, Eat
more than three ♪
♪ And you'll end
up Like a gorilla ♪
♪ Well, there's chocolate ♪
♪ And there's chocolate ♪
♪ Only Wonka's makes you
Rock around the clock-elet ♪
♪ Put your hand Into
your pocke-let ♪
-♪ Get yourself -♪
Oh, put a sock in it!
- ♪ Make sure
They're all frisked ♪
♪ Have you ever Had
chocolate like this? ♪
♪ I've never Had
chocolate like this ♪
♪ Put your hands
Into your pocke-let ♪
♪ Get yourself Some
Wonka chocolate ♪
♪ Put your hands
Into your pocke-let ♪
♪ Get yourself Some
Wonka chocolate ♪
♪ Put your hands
Into your pocke-let ♪
♪ Get yourself Some
Wonka chocolate ♪
♪ Put your hands
Into your pocke-let ♪
♪ Get yourself some choc ♪
♪ Well, there's literate
♪ And illiterate ♪
♪ Can you tell me
What this word is? ♪
♪ Not a bit of it ♪
♪ Well, that's a vowel
And that's a consonant ♪
♪ What's that now? You're
talking nonse-nence ♪
♪ I should call it quits ♪
♪ But you've never Sold
chocolate like this ♪
- ♪ Well, there's chocolate ♪
- I understand that, yeah.
-♪ And there's
chocolate -Totally true.
♪ Only Wonka drives a hole
Right through our profi-lets ♪
Yes, but what I'm trying
to tell you is that...
♪ If we don't get
on top Of this ♪
-♪ We'll go bust
-♪ Choc-apocalypse!
♪ We'll cease to exist ♪
But, fellas...
♪ You've never Had
chocolate like this ♪
♪ No, we've never Had
-♪ Well, there's chocolate
-♪ And there's chocolate
♪ Only mine will find you
Buying wedding frocke-lets ♪
♪ We have just tied the knot ♪
♪ And it's all because
Of Wonka's chocolate ♪
♪ Off to a life Of bliss ♪
♪ You've never Had
chocolate like this ♪
♪ No, we've never had ♪
♪ Chocolate like this ♪
♪ Have you ever Had
chocolate like this? ♪
♪ No, we've never
had Chocolate ♪
♪ No, we've never Had
chocolate like this ♪
All right, where is he?
Where'd he go?
So that's how you're doin' it.
Affable,
I want a man on every
storm drain in the city.
Are you sure, sir?
Shouldn't we be focusing on
all those unsolved murders?
No, no, no, no, this
is the priority.
Okay.
Okay, you know what? I'm
gonna need your help up.
Yep, there we go.
Pretty sure I've
gained about 150 pounds
in the last two weeks.
Ooh!
Gotcha!
What the devil?
Let me out of here. I
demand to be released.
Incredible. It can speak.
Well, of course I can speak.
Now let me out of here,
or I shall shriek.
- Wow.
- Let me out!
Not until I take a
good look at you.
Wow.
Good evening.
So you're the funny little
man who's been following me.
"Funny little
man"? How dare you.
I will have you know
that I am a perfectly
respectable size
for an Oompa Loompa.
An Oompa-what-now?
In fact, in Loompaland, I am
regarded as something of a whopper.
They call me Lofty.
So, I will thank you
to stop gawping at me
as though I was
something unpleasant
you'd found in
your handkerchief.
I find it uncomfortable
and, frankly, rude.
Um...
- Sorry.
- Now let me out of here.
You have absolutely no right
to go around embottling
innocent strangers.
Innocent?
Hold on, you've been
stealing from me. For years.
Well, you started it.
Me?
You stole our cocoa beans.
What are you talking about?
Do you mean that you
don't even remember?
Remember what?
The day you...
destroyed my life.
No, I don't remember that.
Well then, young man.
Allow me to refresh your memory
in the form of a song
so ruinously catchy
that it may never
leave your mind.
Oh, I don't think
I wanna hear that.
Too late.
I've started dancing now.
Once we've started, we
can't stop, you see.
♪ Oompa Loompa doompety-doo ♪
♪ I've got a tragic
tale For you ♪
♪ Oompa Loompa doompety-dee ♪
♪ If you are wise,
You'll listen to me ♪
- ♪ Dear Loompaland Is
both luscious and green ♪
♪ But not conducive
To growing the bean ♪
♪ My job was guarding
What little we'd got ♪
♪ You came along ♪
♪ And pinched the lot ♪
Hey, why didn't
you say something?
Well, perhaps I drifted off.
♪ Oompa Loompa doompety-day ♪
♪ When I awoke,
They sent me away ♪
♪ I'm disgraced, Cast
out in the cold ♪
♪ Till I've paid my friends
Back a thousandfold ♪
A thousandfold? You
gotta be kidding me!
I repeat...
♪ A thousandfold
Hah. Wow.
Um... Mr. Loompa,
if you really think that's
a reasonable penalty
for taking three beans...
Four beans.
Four beans,
then I'm sure we can come to
some sort of understanding.
But I can't give you
my entire supply.
I got people counting on me.
Hmm.
Very well.
I tell you what.
You let me out of here,
and we can discuss it,
like gentlemen. Hmm?
All right.
Ah, thank you. Now,
would you be so very kind
as to pass me that
miniature frying pan?
Hmm. This one?
No, no. The heavier
one, please.
All right.
Thank you. Thank you very...
Ooh, I say, that is
quite a beast, isn't it?
Now, come a little closer.
That's it, closer,
closer, closer,
- come on, cozy on up.
- Okay.
- There we are.
- What?
Ow!
Oompa Loompas do not negotiate.
Good day, sir.
But that's my last jar!
I said good day.
He came back?
Yes, Noodle, but this
time I set a trap.
And he walked right into it.
So, where is he?
Ah, well, we had a
fight, you see. He won.
Hit me on the head
with a frying pan
and jumped out of the window.
Of course he did.
You don't believe me, do you?
Honestly? No.
No!
No.
- No.
- Definitely not.
But,
as it so happens,
we don't need to
sell chocolate today.
And why is that?
You know that shop?
The one you've been dreaming of?
Now, I know what
you're thinking.
It may need a little work.
Looks like someone
left the water running
twenty years ago and the
ceiling fell through.
And the ceiling above that,
and the ceiling above that.
But that means we can afford it.
For a week, anyway.
And we'd finally be legitimate.
The police wouldn't
have any excuse
to keep bothering us.
So, what do you think, Willy?
Do you like it?
Do I like it?
Noodle, it's just as
I always imagined.
No, scratch that, it's
better than I imagined.
I mean, look at this place.
I mean, yeah, it's a wreck,
but... the potential!
The bones!
You mark my words, this is
gonna be the best chocolate shop
- the world has ever seen.
- Whoo!
You won't be scrub-scrubbin'
much longer, Noodle.
We'll all be free.
As free as flamingos!
There's six of them in total.
Including the little girl.
She seems to be the
brains of the operation.
They're based out of a laundry
called Scrubitt and Bleacher.
Scrubitt's?
That's right. Why, you know it?
Yes, as a matter of fact, I do.
They just rented a shop.
So, legally, I can't
touch them. But illegally,
I'm happy to do
whatever you guys want.
You want 'em all to
have a little accident?
In which they die?
Not a problem.
But it's gonna cost you
a lot more chocolate.
It's all right, Chief.
And also, I'd, uh, be
grateful for an advance.
'Cause the last
boxes you gave me...
they're gone.
All of them?
I've been eating these
little paper cases
for the... for the
past three days.
You know, you think they're
gonna give you the same hit.
They don't.
Oh.
There you go, Chief.
There's plenty more
where that came from.
You stand down for now.
We'll give you a call
when the time is right.
What is it, Arthur?
The girl.
You don't really think
it could be her, do you?
I do.
You always assured us she
wouldn't be a problem.
He's right. You did assure us.
And she won't be.
Nor will Wonka.
I'll see to it, personally.
Who is it? What d'you want?
Mr. Slugworth.
Just a minute, sir.
Good evening.
- Good evening.
- -Who is it, puffy-wu...
Stone me.
It's Mr. Slugworth.
To what do we owe the honor?
You have a guest. A Mr. Wonka?
He's been sneaking
out to sell chocolate
with the help of
your serving girl.
Why, that little brat.
Well, quite.
I wondered if you might help
me put an end to their...
business.
Here we go, Mamma.
Ladies and gentlemen,
greetings to you all,
and welcome to Wonka's.
Tremendous things are in store,
both literally and
metaphorically.
What?
In there?
Humor me.
♪ Close your eyes
And count to ten ♪
♪ Make a wish ♪
♪ Now ♪
♪ Open them ♪
♪ Here's a store
That's like no other ♪
♪ If it were, I
wouldn't bother ♪
♪ Chocolate bushes
♪ Chocolate trees ♪
♪ Chocolate flowers
And chocolate bees ♪
♪ Chocolate memories
♪ That a boy once saved ♪
♪ Before they melted away ♪
♪ A world of your own ♪
♪ A place to escape to ♪
♪ Where you can be free ♪
♪ Wherever you go ♪
♪ Wherever life takes you ♪
♪ This is your home ♪
♪ A world of your own ♪
♪ Here is the child ♪
♪ That you left behind ♪
♪ Here is the kid ♪
♪ With the curious mind ♪
♪ Here is the wonder
We used to feel ♪
♪ Back when the
magic Was real ♪
♪ A world of your own ♪
♪ A place to go when you're ♪
♪ Feeling alone ♪
♪ Feeling unsure ♪
Mmm!
♪ Embrace the unknown ♪
♪ Enjoy the adventure ♪
♪ Let's go strolling
In the clouds ♪
♪ Grab a handful ♪
♪ It's allowed ♪
♪ Clouds are made
Of cotton candy ♪
♪ Just keep Your
umbrella handy ♪
♪ 'Cause there's A
hard rain gonna fall ♪
♪ Humbugs, gumdrops ♪
♪ And aniseed balls ♪
♪ Fireworks bring
♪ Sugar string to chew ♪
♪ All the colors
Of the rainbow ♪
♪ And some others, too ♪
♪ A world of our own ♪
-♪ A place to escape to
-♪ A world of our own
♪ Where we can be free ♪
♪ That's where we can be free ♪
♪ Wherever you go ♪
♪ Wherever life takes you ♪
♪ This is our home ♪
♪ A world of our own ♪
So, mushrooms, pears,
assorted flowers.
That comes to 89 sovereigns.
A bargain at twice the price.
Thank you, sir.
And how would you
like your change?
Spendable or edible?
Oh, edible, please.
Enjoy.
And, uh, don't forget
to eat your basket.
Oh.
Abacus, that man just
gave us 100 sovereigns.
I know, Noodle!
Who's next?
- That'll be me.
- Me!
Uh...
Mr. Wonka?
Yes?
What's going on here?
Oh, my goodness.
That's impossible.
Unless...
Yeti sweat?
The most powerful hair
potion in the world.
But I didn't put it in there.
Ladies and gentlemen!
Your attention, please!
There appears to be a
manufacturing error.
Nobody eat the flowers!
Uh, why not?
What's wrong with them?
What's the matter
with this toadstool?
My daughter took one bite,
and just look at her!
There's nothing wrong
with the chocolate milk,
is there?
I'm terribly sorry, everyone,
and I don't know how
to explain this, but...
it appears that the
chocolates have been poisoned!
Poisoned?
- Poisoned?
- He poisoned my child!
I didn't... I
didn't poison them.
I want my money back.
I want compensation.
I want revenge.
Whoa!
No, no! Please!
This is what you get for
mustach-ing my daughter!
I'll wait for you. Help! I have
to get away from this place.
And that, I believe,
is the end of Wonka's
Chocolate Shop.
I don't understand. What...
What...
What happened?
Isn't it obvious?
The Chocolate Cartel.
It's okay, Willy.
We can rebuild.
We can start again.
There's no point, Noodle.
It didn't work.
What do you mean?
She promised she would be here.
She wasn't.
You didn't actually
think that...
No, I did.
Stupid dream.
Don't say that, Willy.
Please don't ever...
Come on, Noodle.
I think Mr. Wonka
needs to be alone.
Every good thing in this
world started with a dream.
So you hold on to yours.
And when you do share
chocolate with the world, oh...
I'll be right there beside ya.
Terrible shame,
what happened here.
Take it you're responsible?
Us? Oh, no. Well,
not personally.
We may have encouraged
Mrs. Scrubitt
to enhance your creations.
We paid her to poison them.
- Yes, thank you, Gerald.
- You're welcome.
So why have you come?
- To gloat?
- Oh, no, Mr. Wonka,
I don't waste my time
with that sort of thing.
We've come to offer you a deal.
This is the precise amount
you owe Mrs. Scrubitt.
This is for the number cruncher,
the plumber,
the telephonist,
the so-called funny-man,
and this...
is for the girl.
Now, we put in a
bit extra for her.
So that she can get
a place to live,
clothes, toys...
books.
Oh, yes, Mr. Wonka.
You could change her life.
Change all their lives.
And what would I have to do?
Leave town.
Oh, and, um,
never make chocolate again.
There's a boat
sailing at midnight.
And for their sake,
as much as your own,
I hope you're onboard.
♪ Sorry, Noodle ♪
♪ I guess I got carried away ♪
♪ I hope you'll
forgive me One day ♪
- Checking out, are we?
- Yeah.
♪ I just wanted it ♪
♪ To feel the way that it did ♪
♪ When I was a kid ♪
♪ Sorry, Noodle ♪
Ah, Mr. Wonka.
Your ticket. Uh, one-way.
To the North Pole.
It's premium economy.
Yeah, it's basically economy.
I mean, yeah, you get
a little more legroom.
A complimentary
packet of peanuts.
Is it worth the extra?
- I don't know.
- But these guys...
We don't need to go into detail.
Goodbye,
Mr. Wonka.
Thank you.
♪ Oompa Loompa doompety-dee ♪
♪ I'm not in premium economy ♪
♪ I'd go first class
If I were you ♪
♪ That's what Oompa Loompas ♪
♪ Doompety-do! ♪
So glad you're here.
Oh, I'm not going to let you
out of my sight, Willy Wonka.
Not till you've paid your debt.
But I bring glad
tidings on that score.
What's that?
I've been doing my sums.
One more jar, and we're even.
Or, if you prefer, I
will accept half a jar
of those rather
amusing Hoverchocs.
You're outta luck.
I don't make chocolate anymore.
Oh, dear, please don't tell me you're going
to go through with this ridiculous deal?
I have to.
For Noodle.
I promised her a better life.
I pinkie promised.
You should stand up
to those bullies.
Give 'em the old one-two.
That's what an Oompa
Loompa would do.
But if you are determined
to just sit there feeling
sorry for yourself,
I am going flat.
Good night, sir.
Huh.
What is it?
No, nothing.
Well, it's obviously something
because you said, "Huh."
I'm sorry. Forget it.
Very well.
Huh.
Oh, you did it again.
Tell me what it is,
or I shall poke you
quite viciously with
a cocktail stick.
Look. Where Slugworth
shook my hand.
His ring left a mark. See?
It's an "A," surrounded by "S"s.
So what? His name
is Arthur Slugworth.
It's probably a family ring.
Yes, but Noodle has
one just like it.
- Noodle?
- Uh-huh.
Why would Noodle the orphan
have a Slugworth family ring?
There's only one
reason I can think of.
Which is?
And if I'm correct, Noodle
could be in grave danger.
Well, come on,
Wonka. Spit it out.
Produce your owl
pellet of wisdom.
There's no time.
I gotta get back.
- Captain!
- Wonka?
Come back here. Wonka!
I demand an explanation.
Captain?
On second thoughts, the
explanation can wait.
Good day to you.
Well, gentlemen,
one dead chocolatier,
as requested.
Miss Bon-Bon?
Yes, Mr. Slugworth?
Give the chief his chocolate.
My, my.
What a lot o' long
faces this morning.
It's almost as though you lot
had a sneaky little scheme
to try and wriggle
out of your contracts.
Which spectacularly misfired.
But I've got some
good news for you lot,
not that you deserve it.
Your friend, Mr. Wonka, done
a deal with Mr. Slugworth.
What?
Gave up on his dream to
settle your accounts.
- Mr. Crunch.
- Present.
You're free to go.
Scram, bookworm.
- Bell.
- Hello.
Sling yer hook.
Benz.
You ain't gotta tell me twice.
Chucklesworth.
You've been a terrible audience.
Good night!
Yeah, well, you ain't been
much of a comedian, mate.
- I know.
- Hey, Larry.
Keep going. You've
got something.
You scare me.
And finally, Noodle.
Biggest pile o' the lot.
But this isn't to pay your bill.
This is to keep you here.
What do you mean?
My friend, Mr. Slugworth,
doesn't think nasty
little urchins like you
should be out on the streets,
lowering the tone.
So, he gave me this money
to keep you down in the
Wash House for good.
And I'm only too
happy to oblige.
- I hate you!
- Hey!
Hey, hey, hey.
Look at her go,
Lord Bleachowitz.
Lord Bleachowitz?
You don't still think
he's a lord, do you?
What?
We made it up, you
stupid old hag.
She's... she's lying.
Right, that's it, you
horrible little brat.
You're goin' in
the coop, my girl.
And you! Take them
dungarees off,
you... you peasant.
But Puffy-wuffy.
I wuv you.
Hello, Noodle.
Willy. I thought you'd gone.
I did.
Slugworth promised
you a better life,
but he didn't exactly keep
his side of the bargain.
So I came back. We all did.
- Hey, Noodle.
- How do?
Hey. Surprise!
He wants me locked up forever.
Yeah, well, that figures.
Why? What's he got against me?
I don't know,
Noodle. Not for sure.
All I know for certain is that
you won't be safe until Slugworth
is behind bars.
And how exactly is that
supposed to happen?
Abacus. You said
the Cartel keep
a record of all
their dirty deeds.
In the green ledger, yes.
So if we can get hold o' that,
we can prove that they
poisoned our chocolate.
Scrubitt and Bleacher
would go to jail,
and we'll all be free.
Uh, yes, but may I remind you,
they keep that
ledger in a vault.
Guarded by a corrupt cleric.
And 500 chocoholic monks.
- Mm-hmm.
- That's all true.
But I went for a long,
cold swim this morning.
Cold water is very
good for the brain.
Stimulates the neural pathways.
And after just four
miles, it came to me.
How an ingenious orphan,
an accountant, a plumber,
a telephone exchange operator,
and a man who can
speak underwater,
could combine those talents,
and pull off the
heist of the century.
But even if we do get
our hands on that ledger,
the Cartel will simply bribe
their way out of trouble.
It's what they do.
The greedy beat
the needy, Willy.
It's just the way of the world.
You're right, Noodle.
I guess that's why there's
one other thing to do.
- What's that?
- Change the world.
Whoa!
Where do we start?
'Scuse me, sir.
Could you spare a piece of
chocolate for a starvin' orphan?
I'm sorry, my child. I
don't have any on me.
Oh.
Then have some acacia mints.
Yes!
"To Basil Bond,
employee of the week."
Oh, that's lovely...
Everything all right back there?
Everything's fine.
Isn't it, Abigail?
Tell her she might want to duck.
Tell her she might wanna what?
Duck!
Good morning, brethren.
Good morning, Father.
Now, as you all know,
it's Baron von
Schmeichelhammer's funeral today.
And his widow is...
- a bit of a pious type.
- Ugh!
So, I don't want to see anyone
eating chocolate
during the service.
Yes, Father.
We all know that one day,
we shall be judged for our sins,
but it's not going to be today.
Amen.
There, there.
Nice giraffe.
- Run! Everybody out!
- ♪ Giraffe ♪
- Run!
- The beast!
Save yourselves!
- ♪ Giraffe ♪
- Get out!
- ♪ It's a giraffe ♪
- Judgement has come!
- ♪ Giraffe's a giraffe ♪
Run off! Quickly!
- In a most unexpected form.
- ♪ Got a giraffe ♪
♪ You're having a
laugh - Run away!
♪ I know it's a giraffe,
Giraffe, giraffe ♪
What have I done
to deserve this?
You know what
you've done, Julius.
You've sold your soul for
30 pieces of chocolate.
Hello, operator. How
may I direct your call?
I need the Zoo.
It's an emergency.
Putting you through to the
Escaped Animal Department now.
Hello, Zoo.
Quiet down, you animals.
You too, octopus.
There's a giraffe.
- What? Oh, yeah, I think
we did lose a giraffe.
Well, could you come and get it?
Okay, jeez. I'll
send the guys around.
Oh, forgive me!
I'm a sinner!
A weak and wicked chocoholic!
Good morning, everyone.
- Welcome to St. Benedict's.
Baroness, I'm so
sorry for your loss.
We're just having a few
technical difficulties, um,
so you might want to pop
the late baron
down for a minute.
Ah, the cavalry.
Are you the cleric who
called about a giraffe?
All clear.
Huh. "Thanks for
all your hard work."
"Father Julius and
the Chocolate Cartel."
Oh, that's nice.
Mmm.
Here we are, Father.
One giraffe.
- Marvelous.
- Thank you, thank you.
Stand back,
please. Stand back.
♪ Have I got A sweet
tooth? Pow! I do ♪
Wow.
♪ Have I got a sweet tooth... ♪
She can really move.
I could've been happy,
but I threw a pearl away.
I'll give him a
call. No, I can't.
I will give him a call actually.
Hello?
Basil? It's Gwennie.
You were right.
What are the chances?
Those days in chemistry class
were the happiest of my life.
Cool.
Sorry about this, sir.
The seafood truck
spilled its load.
There's so many blasted
flamingos about these days.
Well, hurry it
along now, will you?
The town square was
closed this morning
after a bizarre incident
at the city cathedral.
Delaying the funeral of
noted philanthropist,
Baron von Schmeichelhammer.
In nomine Patris,
et Filii, et Spiritus Sancti.
Amen.
Sorry, I'd best get that.
- Hello, pulpit?
- Father.
Everything all right there?
Oh, yes, Mr. Slugworth.
All tickety-boo.
At least, it is now.
What do you mean by that?
Oh, we had a giraffe
in here earlier.
Had to clear the whole
place for about 20 minutes,
but everything's back to normal.
Hello?
Damn the flamingos,
Donovan! Floor it!
Yes, sir!
Idiot!
- Anything?
- Nothing.
Well, keep looking.
It's not in here, Willy.
But Abacus said
that it was here.
Abacus has been in the Wash
House for the past four years.
Maybe all the scrubbing
has gone to his head.
'Cause all that's down here is just
a bunch of stupid old chocolate.
Willy, look!
We did it, Noodle.
We got 'em.
Naughty, naughty, Mr. Wonka.
You've caused us quite
a bit of trouble.
You and your urchin.
Yeah, but she's
not just an urchin,
is she, Mr. Slugworth?
You're family.
What?
What are you talking
about, Willy?
You know that ring, Noodle?
The one your parents gave you?
Mr. Slugworth has
one just like it.
Don't you, Mr. Slugworth?
As a matter of fact, I do.
That belonged to my
brother. Zebedee.
Was he my father?
A hopeless romantic
is what he was.
Fell in love with a
common little bookworm,
died before they could marry.
Leaving me sole heir
to the family fortune.
Or so I thought.
But nine months later,
your mother turned
up on my doorstep,
begging me to get a doctor
for her sick little newborn.
I said I would help.
But you didn't. Did you?
Oh, no.
Instead, you put me
down a laundry chute.
Bye-bye, baby.
Mrs. Scrubitt found me.
She saw the ring.
Thought it was an "N,"
and called me Noodle.
But it wasn't.
It was "Z." For Zebedee.
Well, quite.
- When your mother returned, I told her you had died.
- Oh, no!
She was heartbroken, of course.
But, uh, I gave her a
handful of sovereigns
and had her escorted
from my property.
What was her name?
Eh?
My mom. What was her name?
Ooh.
Let me see. Um...
No, I don't think I
could remember that.
Sorry. But you
have to understand,
she was very poor.
Sorry, Felix.
Her name was Dorothy.
Dorothy Smith. It
says so right here.
Dorothy?
Well, what do you know?
I guess you did teach
me to read after all.
Well, this is all very touching,
but back to business.
We'll take that, thank you.
How much chocolate do you have at
your factory, Mr. Fickelgruber?
Oh, about 80,000 gallons.
Prodnose?
Seventy-five?
And I've got 150.
That should be enough.
For what?
Death by chocolate.
On you go.
Uh, gentlemen.
Considering the situation,
I wondered if you'd do a
good deed on my behalf.
A what?
"A good deed."
It's a sort of pointless
act of selflessness...
Yes, of course, Mr. Wonka.
What would you like us to do?
I was wondering if you
could give this to someone.
Only if you happen to see him.
And who is it?
- A little orange man.
- Eh?
A little orange man.
About eight inches high,
with orange skin and
bright green hair.
I owe him a jar of chocolates,
you see. And, well,
I think these might be
the best I ever made.
Well, in that case,
I'll make sure he
gets them personally.
Farewell, Mr. Wonka.
Urchin.
Willy...
What are we gonna do, Willy?
I don't know, Noodle.
I'll think of something.
Best chocolate he ever made, eh?
- Whoo-hoo.
- Oh!
I got it!
What is it? Did you
think of something?
Yes, I did.
If we're gonna drown
in chocolate, Noodle,
and let's face it, we're
gonna drown in chocolate,
then it's gonna be
Wonka chocolate.
We're not gonna drown,
Willy. Look, there's a light.
We'll let the
chocolate lift us up,
we'll bang on the glass,
and pray somebody hears us.
That's a much better idea.
Ah, gentlemen.
It was a bit of a close
shave this morning,
and I was wondering if perhaps
we could rethink our
arrangement. Or...
Or... just leave
things as they are.
Father.
Well, Wonka might be as
nutty as a fruitcake,
but he sure knew how
to make chocolate.
- Mmm.
- But do you think
we should have saved some
for the Little Orange Man?
Tell me you're joking.
Uh, yes. Yes, I am.
Sorry, why am I?
Because there's no such thing
as a little orange
man, ya nincompoop.
- Help!
Somebody help, please!
- Please help!
- Help!
Look. Look, somebody's
coming. Look.
Willy, we're saved!
- I'm sorry, Noodle.
- Don't be.
You found my family.
A mom who loved me.
That's all I ever wanted.
Deep breath now.
Mmm! Exquisite.
You mustn't let yourself
get so worked up.
It's just a bit of chocolate.
Correction.
It was actually my chocolate.
You have made a very
grave error, gentlemen.
You steal from an Oompa Loompa,
we take back
a thousandfold.
What's going on, Willy?
It's draining, Noodle.
We've been saved!
- By who?
- I don't know.
By the Little Orange Man!
- Look.
- Wh...
The Little Orange Man!
Thank you, Little
Orange Man! Thank you!
Gentlemen. Thank
goodness you're okay.
I came as fast as I could.
Whew! Car shrunk.
I'm sure it did.
And you've nothing to
worry about, Chief.
All under control.
A couple of thieves
broke in, but I'm afraid
they met with a
little... accident.
In which they died.
That's actually
rather good, Gerald.
I wouldn't be so
sure about that.
Officer, would you kindly
take a look at this?
Wonka!
It details every
single illegal payment
these men have ever made.
Thousands of them.
Affable, don't listen
to her. She's lyin'.
Well, of course she is.
She's not, sir.
She's absolutely right.
It's incredible.
Oh. Well.
Then that sounds like a case
for the Chief of Police.
So you give it to me, Affable, I'll,
uh... I'll take it off your hands.
You know, save
you the paperwork.
I can't do that,
I'm afraid, sir.
Why's that?
Because your name is
written down here.
Huh?
- A lot.
- Gentlemen...
- You're under arrest.
- Run.
We puttin' handcuffs on, here?
That's okay, Noodle.
Give it one second.
What's happening?
Why are we airborne?
You didn't eat any
of those chocolates,
- did you, Mr. Slugworth?
- Why?
Because they're Hoverchocs.
Delayed action,
but extra strong.
You think you're very
clever, don't you, Wonka?
Well, there's a billion sovereigns
of chocolate beneath our feet.
We'll get the best lawyers,
bribe the judge, rig
the jury if we have to.
We'll be fine.
I wish I'd thought of that.
Hey, Noodle!
What is that?
It's our chocolate!
All our chocolate!
We're ruined!
Hey, don't worry, gentlemen.
You'll come down eventually.
Probably. I think.
But until then,
ladies and gentlemen,
Willy Wonka and friends...
invite you to enjoy
our chocolate.
Yay! Magic Wonka!
Gwennie?
Basil!
What did I say, Abacus,
I told you we could fix it all.
Your cup.
Thank you.
- There you are.
- There you go.
Careful, not too much.
Okay.
- Mmm.
- Oh, thank you.
Thank you.
- Mmm.
- Thank you.
- Oh.
Huh.
So... how does it feel, Willy?
Is it as good as you remember?
Every little bit.
I wish it could last forever.
I guess it's time.
Time for what?
Do you know how many people in
this city are named D. Smith?
106.
And luckily, you have a friend who
works at the telephone exchange.
And she spent the
entire afternoon
ringing around.
And guess what?
We found her.
You found my mom?
She works in the library.
That's where she lives.
Come on, Noodle.
♪ Come with me ♪
♪ And you'll be ♪
♪ In a world ♪
♪ Of pure imagination ♪
♪ Reach out, touch ♪
♪ What was once ♪
♪ Just in your imagination ♪
♪ Don't be shy ♪
♪ It's all right ♪
♪ If you feel A
little trepidation ♪
♪ Sometimes These
things don't ♪
♪ Need explanation ♪
♪ If you want To
view paradise ♪
♪ Simply look at
them And view it ♪
♪ Somebody to hold on to ♪
♪ It's all we really need ♪
♪ Nothing else to it ♪
Mom.
So goes a good deed
in a weary world.
I was wondering if
I'd see you again.
I'm not going
anywhere, Willy Wonka.
Not until you've paid your debt.
Now, I know you tried.
Loompa law is very
clear on this subject.
Until such time
as the chocolate is
physically in my hand...
Oh. Thank you.
Thank you. For saving my life.
Well, I suppose that
concludes our business.
I will now return to
my beloved Loompaland.
Where the cocoa beans grow in
disappointingly small numbers,
and my friends look down on me.
What? I thought they
called you Lofty.
The truth is that
I am a quarter-inch
below average.
They call me Shorty-pants.
But there it is.
Good day to you, sir.
Uh, it's a shame you have to go.
I said good day.
If I'm gonna share my
chocolate with the world,
I'm gonna need more than a shop.
I'm sure you will.
I'm gonna need a factory.
Yeah, well, good luck with that.
And someone to head up
the tasting department.
The tasting department?
♪ Come with me ♪
All right.
- ♪ And you'll be ♪
- Where?
♪ In a world Of
pure imagination ♪
It's a ruined castle.
♪ Take a look ♪
♪ And you'll see ♪
♪ Into your imagination ♪
Frankly, I rather doubt it.
♪ We'll begin with a spin ♪
♪ Traveling in the
world Of my creation ♪
♪ What we'll see ♪
♪ Will defy explanation ♪
Well, that does
defy explanation.
♪ If you want To
view paradise ♪
♪ Simply look
around And view it ♪
♪ Anything you
want You do it ♪
♪ Wanna change the world?
There's nothing to it ♪
Not bad.
♪ There is no life I know ♪
♪ To compare With
pure imagination ♪
♪ Living there,
You'll be free ♪
♪ If you truly ♪
♪ Wish to be ♪
♪ Oompa Loompa doompety-do ♪
♪ I've got a little
Bonus for you ♪
♪ Sit back down And
stay in your seat ♪
♪ For a last Oompa
Loompa-ish treat ♪
♪ Abacus Crunch
Returned to his home ♪
♪ Benz to her friends ♪
♪ Lottie Bell to her phones ♪
♪ Brave Larry made A
triumphant comeback ♪
♪ One day his ex-wife ♪
♪ Saw the act ♪
♪ Laughed a lot
And took him back ♪
♪ Oompa Loompa doompety-day ♪
♪ But what of Mrs. Scrubitt
And Bleacher, you say? ♪
♪ Give me Just a
moment or two ♪
♪ And I'll Oompa
Loompa Show it to you ♪
Oh. What is wrong
with this thing?
Infernal machine.
♪ I'll show it to you ♪
There. Much better.
Shoes, facelift,
nose job, Ibiza,
big old house in the
country, lingerie.
It's the Cartel.
They've gone down.
We ain't done nothin'.
Oh, except poison
all them chocolates.
Police. Open up.
Quick! Drink the evidence.
Oh, just a second, Officer.
Police.
I'm on the toilet, Officer.
Open up.
One wipe, and I'm done.
Oh, there's more coming,
hang on a minute.
Right.
Wow.
How can we help you, Officer?
You two are coming with me.
But we ain't done nothin'.
You're going away
for a very long time.
One last kiss, my Lord?
Oh, puffy-wuffy.
♪ Close your eyes ♪
♪ And count to ten ♪
♪ Make a wish ♪
♪ Now
♪ Open them ♪
♪ Here's a store
That's like no other ♪
♪ If it were, I
wouldn't bother ♪
♪ Chocolate bushes ♪
♪ Chocolate trees ♪
♪ Chocolate flowers
And chocolate bees ♪
♪ Chocolate memories ♪
♪ That a boy once saved ♪
♪ Before they melted away ♪
♪ A world of your own ♪
♪ A place to escape to ♪
♪ Where you can be free ♪
♪ Wherever you go ♪
♪ Wherever life takes you ♪
♪ This is your home ♪
♪ A world of your own ♪
♪ Here is the child
That you left behind ♪
♪ Here is the kid With
the curious mind ♪
♪ Here is the wonder
We used to feel ♪
♪ Back when The
magic was real ♪
♪ A world of your own ♪
♪ A place to go when you're ♪
♪ Feeling alone ♪
♪ Feeling unsure ♪
♪ Embrace the unknown ♪
♪ Enjoy the adventure ♪
♪ Let's go strolling
In the clouds ♪
♪ Grab a handful,
It's allowed ♪
♪ Clouds are made
Of cotton candy ♪
♪ Just keep Your
umbrella handy ♪
♪ 'Cause there's A
hard rain gonna fall ♪
♪ Humbugs, gumdrops
And aniseed balls ♪
♪ Fireworks bring ♪
♪ Sugar string to chew ♪
♪ All the colors
Of the rainbow ♪
♪ And some others, too ♪
-♪ A world of our own
-♪ A place to escape to
-♪ Where we can be free -♪
That's where We can be free ♪
-♪ Wherever you go
-♪ Wherever life takes you
♪ This is our home ♪
♪ A world of our own ♪