Ba.
Ba! Ba!
Ba, ba, ba.
- Bye.
- Ba, ba.
A pile of organs without the
spark of self from a brain,
or the pump of
blood from a heart.
Just a butcher's tray
for a Sunday lunch.
Now, who would like to
reconstruct the organs?
And who can tell human from
animal, if there is a difference?
Come, come.
You did puzzles as
children, did you not?
Is it just me, or is it devilishly hard
to concentrate when the monster's talking?
He is an extraordinary surgeon.
His research is groundbreaking.
His father founded this place.
Have you mistaken yourself as included
in this conversation, Max McCandles?
Your physical proximity
to us does not make it so.
Fuck off, old pal.
Get yourself a suit.
You really think that's
where the liver goes, sir?
Can I ask what is the purpose
of putting them back in, sir?
My amusement.
Mr. Max McCandles!
Walk with me at the
end of the lesson.
Your paper.
You liked it, sir?
It showed signs of a conventional mind
straining hard to almost touch mediocrity.
- Thank you.
- I need someone. An assistant on a project.
I would love to.
- Are you a religious man?
- I believe in God.
- Me or the deity?
- Humorous, as you're often known as the...
It is a joke of my own making.
I do not need it
explicated for me.
The very devil's work.
Have you thought of
growing a beard, sir?
I look like a big
dog in a cravat.
Kids like dogs.
This job.
Yes. Come.
God! God.
God.
- Hello.
Bella, this is Mr. McCandles.
Hello, Bella.
- Bud.
- Blood.
- Marvelous.
I'm fine. I'm fine.
What a very pretty retard.
She suffered a brain injury.
I repaired it.
Her mental age and her body
are not quite synchronized.
Language is coming. She is
progressing at an accelerated pace.
She is stunning.
I need to meticulously
note her progression.
You will do this for me?
It would be my honor.
Wee!
Yes. It is exciting, Bella.
"Wee." I believe she's doing...
Mrs. Prim!
Wee.
Do you not like kippers?
I am quite partial
to them, actually.
I find them to be
nice in the morning...
Bella cut, too?
Just dead ones for Bella.
Just dead.
Squish! Squish, squish.
Chog!
Run!
Chog.
She gathers 15 words a day.
Her coordination is
unstable at best.
In the evenings,
there's progress.
Her hair grows one
inch every two days.
- I have a hair diagram here.
- Excellent.
You may go. See you tomorrow.
Sir, where did she come from?
I believe your job
is collecting data.
When I add inane questions
to it, I'll let you know.
"And so, when they
returned from the wood
"she was reunited with
her Mummy and Daddy."
"That night, for dinner, they
ate cake until they were sick."
"They were so happy
to be back together."
You me Daddy, God?
- I...
- Prim say you not be.
Bella nowhere girl.
Where that be? Nowhere?
You are an orphan.
Your parents died.
Then you cut parents up, God?
No.
They were my friends.
They were brave explorers,
and they were killed in a
landslide in South America.
They pushed the boundaries
of what was known,
and they paid the price.
But that is the only
way to live, Bella.
They sent you to
me to care for you.
Dead?
I'm afraid so, my darling.
Poor Bella.
But love God.
Sleep here.
No.
Good night, dear Bella.
This, parents.
Peru, yes.
Why you pen book every nut?
I must note down your
nutritional intake.
How many?
Tell Bella other places.
That's Lisbon, Portugal.
The south of France. The Alps.
Australia.
Far away and dangerous,
in both people and animal.
Bella want look at world.
Just...
Bella.
Bella, I don't think
we're allowed up here.
Let's just...
Bella.
No.
Bella, this is dangerous.
Bella.
No, Bella.
God.
Outside must go.
Outside? No, we work.
Cut fingers?
Candles take me. Candles.
Of course I can. If...
No.
Yes. Out!
Has she ever been outside?
No.
I have created a perfectly
entertaining and safe world for Bella.
Now.
- Bella.
- Now!
Now!
Bella.
You know, so many things
outside can kill you, Bella.
Kill dead?
Snakes, carriages,
sharp-faced birds, earthquakes
inhalation of toxic grass seeds.
Bella.
Bella. Look.
- Kill it.
- What?
Why you funny thumbs, God?
Once when I was very small
my father pinned my thumbs
into a small iron case
to see whether he could retard
the growth cycle of bones.
Now, the pain was so great
to stop myself from weeping...
I would stare deeply
into my other fingers,
and simply by observation
begin to parse out the
epidemiological elements.
When he came back
to his surprise, I was smiling.
Good God.
He was a man of
unconventional mind.
Time to go.
A storm approaches.
Why must you scare her so?
She's an experiment,
and I must control
the conditions,
or our results will not be pure.
Stop! God, we go!
No, Bella.
Bella want walk in ice cream.
No.
Bella wants!
My face. People scared of God.
Laugh at God.
God lovely.
Like dog face.
Quite.
- Stop! Me walk.
- No!
No now? No never?
Just no.
- Bella!
- No!
- No! No! No!
- Bella!
No!
- Sorry. Sorry.
- No!
No! No!
I'm sorry, my darling.
Mother of God.
What did you do to her?
Why are you hiding her?
Tell me what all this means,
or I'll go to the police.
I shall. For it is a happy tale.
It is rare to get a body, albeit
dead, but so close to life.
Rigor had not set in.
The body had hardly cooled.
No pulse.
But some electric currents, so
I could have kept her alive.
But you didn't.
I knew nothing of the
life she had abandoned
except she hated it so much
that she had chosen not to be,
and forever.
What would she feel
on being dragged from her
carefully chosen blank eternity,
and forced to be put in
one of our understaffed
poorly-equipped madhouses,
reformatories or jails?
For in this Christian nation, suicide
is treated as lunacy or crime.
Who was I to decide her fate?
But then there was also,
on my part, a recognition.
All my research had
come to this moment.
Fate had brought me a dead body,
and a live infant.
It was obvious.
It was?
Take the infant's brain out,
and put it in the full-grown
woman, reanimate her, and watch.
Jesus!
She knows?
No.
Who was she?
No idea.
But would you rather the
world did not have Bella?
Mrs. Prim?
Bella discover
happy when she want.
You are a sour
face, but I fix you.
Close eyes.
- No!
- Just wait. It takes a moment.
She grabbed my hairy business.
She's sick!
Bella.
Bella have discover
something I must share.
Watch.
- What if put cucumber in me?
- No.
Bella! Bella!
Cease working
yourself immediately.
What?
In polite society,
that is not done.
Just do not.
What... is that?
My father took out my
oxyntic and pyloric glands,
so I must make my
own gastric juices.
Why in God's name
would he do that?
To discover what no one knew.
Turns out we need them. Ideally.
Bella
you have not eaten.
Do not.
Good night.
'Night.
You know, I'm actually
something of a romantic, Max.
What?
I believe I see love
between you and Bella.
I... She is...
Perhaps you should marry her.
What?
I think she loves you.
I've seen people look
at each other with love
as an observer.
Not the subject, of
course. I see it.
You do?
I...
I do have feelings for her.
So, you would?
Take Bella out.
Bella...
I...
Feel funny?
Do Bella.
I was wondering
if perhaps you were raising
her to be your mistress.
A dark thought
unworthy of me, I know.
So, you are not laying with her?
Spermatic ejaculation can
only induce homeostasis in me
if accompanied by prolonged
stimulation of higher nerve centers
whose pressure on the ductless glands
changes the chemistry of my blood
not for a few spasmodic minutes,
but for many days.
What?
I am a eunuch and
can't fuck her.
To get a sexual
response from my body
would take the same amount of
electricity as runs North London.
Besides, my paternal feelings
seem to outweigh
my sexual thoughts.
I apologize for my
own dark thoughts.
Not dark at all.
Men's, indeed all sexuality,
is basically immoral.
Not all, sir.
Do you wish to marry her or not?
I wish to marry you. Be my wife.
Let us touch each
other's genital pieces.
No. No.
I do not wish to take
advantage of you.
You are special.
When we are wed.
One condition.
She must desire it
also, I understand.
Two conditions, then.
That one you said,
and you must live
here with me, always.
I will have a legal
agreement drawn up.
Curious contract.
There are several
spelling errors.
Immaterial to the legal
bindingness of it, I assure you.
Must be quite a woman
to warrant such binding.
If you'll excuse me, I
need to use the facilities.
Are you five years old that
you can't hold your water?
Weak bladder, sir. Like my father
before me and his before him.
You may have prostate
cancer. Look into it.
Will do.
Ms. Bella Baxter, as per
your contract, no doubt.
Good afternoon, visiting man.
Want my hat?
Would it suit me?
Yes.
It is foolish good.
I had to meet this woman
who would inspire such a contract
of marriage that imprisons her.
What you mean?
You shall live here
travel with Mr. Max
McCandles and Baxter abroad,
but not go forth in the city.
I see.
They love me tight.
I understand why.
I have to pinch you,
to see if you are real.
You will not...
Who is you?
Mr. Duncan Wedderburn.
Open.
How you get up here?
I climbed.
You were watch me long?
Not long.
You did not see me working on
myself to get happiness, did you?
It is not polites, I know.
Do not care for polite society.
It's fucking boring.
Destroys one's soul.
God not believe in soul.
I think God's the actual
author of the soul idea.
Godwin Baxter?
That burnt dog.
What is that story?
You are a prisoner
and I aim to free you.
Something in you,
some hungry being
hungry for experience,
freedom, touch.
To see the unknown and know it.
So, why am I here, you ask?
I'm going to Lisbon on
Friday. I'd like you to come.
Lisbon of Portugal?
That is the Lisbon I speak of.
God never allow it.
That's why I'm not asking him.
I'm asking you.
Bella not safe
with you, I think.
You are absolutely... not.
May I have a moment of
value time, dear God?
Of course, Bella.
I wanted to tell you big news.
Bella is dizzy with excite.
What is it?
Tonight, at midnight...
I secretly run away with
one Duncan Wedderburn.
What?
You will wish to stop me.
I shall stop you.
You hold Bella too tight.
I must set forth into waters.
We can travel.
You, me, and Max whom,
I will remind you
you are betrothed to.
I will marry Max
as he seems right for that,
but first, I shall adventure
on Duncan Wedderburn
who, I think, cares
little of damage to me,
but will be interesting as well.
I can't let you go.
Kiss me and set me forth.
If you do not...
Bella's insides shall
turn rotten with hate.
- Hate?
- Hate.
Unpack those bags, Prim.
Godwin has told me your plan.
I do not blame you, Bella.
That man is a cad and a rake.
He has insidious ways of getting
under a naive woman's skin.
It is mostly his eyes on mine.
And his hands when
between Bella's legs,
and whisper words I can't hear,
but heat in my body.
Jesus, Bella.
We are engaged.
I love you.
And when I return, we marriage,
and be happy as two
doves on a branch.
- You think I need travel hat?
- No!
This will not do.
It cannot!
I'll see to this man myself.
I will beat his handsome face into
a porridge of blood and bones!
Max, you are flushed,
and I am too at sight
of different Max.
I apologize,
but I will not let a man that I know
has nothing but ill intent in his mind,
and nothing for you in
his heart trick you.
I will smash his
fucking head in.
Bella? It...
Bella.
Goodbye, later dove.
I will see you after
grand adventure.
God?
She's gone.
I am having port for breakfast.
It is strangely delicious.
Why did you not stop her?
She is a being of free will.
She's now out there. Alone.
She will be fine.
I'm a fool. I should
have stopped her.
We are men of science.
This emotionality is unseemly.
I just hope she's all right.
You are the most beautiful
woman I've ever seen.
I will not lie, I
have been with many.
Mrs. Prim said you were wolf with
scent of hundred women on you.
She undersells it.
Okay. Oysters.
Have you had them before?
I have not.
Shuck, chuck and bubble.
Rollicking.
Wait. Bella.
So, nuns and monks would starch
their clothes with egg whites,
and, with the yolks,
make these tarts.
Now, how to eat them?
I will guess through the mouth.
They must not be eaten
dainty flake by dainty flake,
but inhaled with gusto,
like life itself.
Incredible.
Who made these? We need more.
No more. One's enough.
Any more is too much.
It's siesta time.
What is siesta?
Why do people not just do this
all the time?
Well, at the risk
of being immodest
you've just been thrice
fucked by the very best.
It's probable no other man would ever
bring you to the raptures I have.
I feel bad for you.
Well, then it will just be
you I do furious jumping with.
Furious jumping?
I love that.
I'm rested.
Let us go again.
Again?
Unfortunately
even I have my limits.
Men cannot keep
coming back for more.
It is a physiological problem?
A weakness in men?
Well...
Perhaps so.
You'd be advised,
if it's not too late
not to fall in love with me.
I have very little to offer
in the way of constancy.
Just adventure.
I see.
Let us sleep.
Taxi, madam?
Good evening...
Duncan Wedderburn.
Bella, where were
you? You disappeared.
I did not.
Nobody can just disappear.
What?
Can they? Disappear?
No, of course not. What
the fuck are you talking...
Where were you?
I wanted a tart and then
an adventure befell me.
I did not know how to
return and then I heard it.
The tram.
I will walk to the
noise, and I found it.
Amazement to Bella.
Explorer bloods in me.
Bella, it's dangerous
to go out without me.
I have adventured it and found
nothing but sugar and violence.
It is most charming.
I am fine.
Now, I must lie down and you must lie down
on top of me and do more furious jumping.
Kitty.
Did you see the new
show in London by Wilde?
Marvelously witty.
I loved it.
"A handbag."
Bella.
What?
Why I keep it in my
mouth if it is revolting?
I have said that
before to Gerald.
If you catch my drift.
You are wicked.
Oh. Because you mean his penis.
Duncan's can sometimes be salty.
Good God, Bella.
I must go punch that baby.
Bella.
Your behavior is unconscionable.
Will you behave?
The food was cacking my throat
the baby annoying,
and the woman boring with words.
You will rejoin the table,
and will confine yourself to
the following three phrases...
"How marvelous!", "Delighted",
and "How did they make
the pastry so crisp?" Yes?
You are hurting Bella.
Sorry.
Reason does not penetrate.
Let us go.
Are you enjoying Lisbon, Bella?
Delighted.
Kitty, how is your dear father?
He's very unwell.
I fear he will not
see the year out.
How marvelous.
How did they get
the pastry so crisp?
Good God.
What is it?
From her.
"Me good. Lisbon."
"Sugar tart lick me all day."
At least I hope that's
all one sentence, anyway.
- Do you think they're...
- Fucking?
Yes.
Also
fellating a tram.
Does your head ache
too, Duncan Wedderburn?
And I also am
starving for dinner.
Where the fuck were you?
Victoria Blessington?
I haven't seen you for years.
And you still have not
as I am Bella Baxter
strange feathered lady.
I apologize. I could've
sworn you were she.
Right.
Shall we?
The steak, the fish
little caramel things in pots
that old spotted
people over there have.
I don't want caramel in pots.
Of course not. That
was all for Bella.
Order at your whim.
You are cross at Bella's
outings and adventures.
And yet we must discover by whim
as spoken by Duncan
Wedderburn to Bella Baxter
day one of Lisbon love affair.
Touché.
Understand me never lived
outside God's house.
What?
So, Bella so much to discover,
and your sad face
makes me discover
angry feelings for you.
Right.
I have become the
very thing I hate
a grasping succubus of a lover.
I've pried many of them
off me and now I'm it.
Fuck!
You, like me, are a creature
of freedom in the moments.
What do you keep doing that for?
A man over there
repeated blinks at me.
I blink back.
For polites, I think.
We are going to dance
in town. Please join us.
I have never danced in town.
- Duncan!
- Can't!
You're quite mad.
Stop talking as your
sounds make Bella angry!
I will not stop talking.
If I have something
to say I'll...
Ouch.
All right.
What's this?
A man was teaching me chess,
and he said he thought I would probably
have the softest skin he had ever touched.
And I said, if I did it would
be the inner thighs to test
as that is where the
epidermis is at its most fine.
So we tested,
and it was the softest ever.
I wondered if perhaps they're
not equal in softitude.
Indeed they were not.
So I made sure to note it,
remembering which was which.
What of the tongue play
you were about to perform?
Is that not happening?
You...
You are troubled.
Did he lie with you?
No, we were against a wall.
Did you furious jump him?
No, he just fast-licked
my clitoris.
I had the heat that needed
release, so at my request it was.
You, too, may tongue play me,
so I'm not understanding
this complicated feeling.
Are you now crying?
What a confusing person
you are, Duncan Wedderburn.
A liver.
A small incision
is all that is needed.
I was chloroforming
goats all morning.
I may have ingested too much.
I am going to venture to suggest
you are upset by Bella's absence.
The liters of port
the sobbing I hear at night.
Good God, man! You
prattle like an imbecile.
She is gone!
I am a man of science.
I just need to engage in,
and continue, the project.
That is all. I must go
on to the next thing.
Our feelings must be put aside.
Do you think my father
could have branded me
with hot irons on the
genitals the way he did
if he could not put
science and progress first?
Branded you?
Let us find a body.
A what?
Hello. Good morning.
Good morning, darling.
I haven't been very supportive
of your adventurous spirit.
So I have a surprise for you.
Get in.
- We changed hotels?
- Look out the window, Bella.
- We're on boat?
- Indeed.
- You aim to trap Bella at sea.
- I aim to give you a new adventure.
I suppose it's true
you'll be easier to find.
Come, disrobe me.
Ride me.
And we'll then have
cocktails on foredeck.
Bella.
Bella!
Blue. Blue. Blue.
Shit on me?
Fucker!
Madam.
When do we stop?
Athens. Three days.
That woman's on fire, look.
I know you're upset with me.
Forgive my kidnapping of
you, but it was for love.
A romantic jape. Don't
be such a cunt about it.
- I want a drink.
- Of course, my darling.
The ship is fun, a
whole world to explore.
Do you love me? I love you.
Describe the elements I should be
looking for within myself to be sure.
You just feel it or not.
So it is no evidence
base, as God would say.
- So how judge it empirically?
- What the fuck are you talking about?
Who are you?
You don't know what bananas are,
you've never heard of chess,
and yet you know what
"empirically" means.
Bella wants a drink.
I said twice now.
I've never felt
anything like this.
Is this true for you?
I suppose, empirically it is.
I'm out of ink.
Then ink you shall
have, my love.
Hello, interesting older lady.
I must touch your hair.
I also noticed your hair.
Just like silk on a
translucent, glowing egg.
That is fancy words
that excite me somehow.
I saw you're with
handsome over there.
White teeth and a hard cock.
Duncan Wedderburn.
His teeth are also hard.
His penis is also white.
- Good lay, I hope.
- He is my only.
But I find him to elicit exceptional
sensations throughout my whole body
that leave me yelping happily.
I also wish to dash his body,
form, cadaver, into the sea.
Is this man jumping
on your body?
No, he is not.
I haven't been
bedded in 20 years.
What?
That is terrible.
It doesn't concern me greatly.
As years have passed
what's in between my
ears is my big concern.
What's in between my legs
much less so.
A desperate
rationalization, Martha.
Oh, this is Harry Astley.
Don't take what he
says too much to heart.
He's a cynic.
Madam.
I am Bella Baxter.
I do not know what
this "cynic" is.
Bella.
Ink.
Duncan Wedderburn, I have made
friends, colleagues, comrades.
Harry Astley.
This is Martha.
She is my new friend who has
not been fucked in 20 years.
Is that not astonishment?
I hope you use your hand between
your legs to keep yourself happy.
Good God, Bella, you
cannot speak like this.
Polites of society. I forgot.
Polite society
will destroy you.
- It will?
- Yeah, there's some truth to that.
We all agreed on that.
As to your enquiry on my hand.
Occasionally, yes.
That is much reassuring news.
- We shall all dine together.
- Well, actually...
We are all on a ship
and cannot escape,
and there is a world to enjoy,
traverse, circumnavigate.
Or can she not have
friends, Mr. Wedderburn?
Delighted.
Marry me.
What?
I meant to throw you aside.
A few months and send you
packing, but I cannot.
Say you'll marry me. No one's
ever captured my heart. You have.
It is tricky
as I am engaged to
Mr. Max McCandles.
What?
My hand has taken by another.
It is a saying I heard,
but did not understand.
You do not take just the
hand, but all, do you not?
You ran away with me from him.
A recounting of events, the
point of which is elusive to me.
You chose me over him.
For now.
For fun.
I'll fucking throw
you overboard!
So you wish to
marry me or kill me?
- Is that the proposal?
- No.
Going to the casino.
That's fine.
She is coming along.
Let's try again.
Gross motor skills
will develop slowly,
but you will progress fast.
Felicity.
Not that fast.
I am reading Emerson.
He speaks about the
improvement of men.
I do not know why he does
not give advice to women.
Perhaps he does not know any.
Try and read Goethe.
Philosophy is a
waste of time, Bella.
Really? Say more.
No, no, Harry, you wretch.
It is integral.
People and society
can be improved.
It is the goal of all to
improve, advance, progress, grow.
I know this in me, and I am
sure I am indicative of all.
Trust me, you are definitely
unique, Bella, in all ways.
But this improvement
through philosophy
is people trying to run away from the
fact that we are all cruel beasts.
Born that way, die that way.
It is a dark view
of things, Harry.
Bella
let us take the air
in our cabin.
But these two are fighting,
and ideas are banging around
in Bella's head and heart
like lights in a storm.
You're always
reading now, Bella.
You're losing some of your
adorable way of speaking.
I am a changing able feast
as are all of we.
Apparently according to Emerson,
disagreed with by Harry.
Come, come. Just come.
You are in my sun.
What?
Come.
Busy drinking heavily.
Busy losing heavily.
I must go meet Martha.
Martha.
She is the problem.
I'll throw that perfumed
bag of flesh overboard.
I dare you.
Martha!
Where is she?
Where are you, fuck.
- Where are you going?
- She's going over the side.
Oh, marvelous!
I never imagined being murdered.
How dramatic.
Well, she seems happy to die. I'm
sorry for getting in your way.
Exciting.
I'll be in the bar.
You have made me think, cogitate
perambulate on
ideas that are wrong
erroneous and
nonsensically annoying
that lead me not to sleep.
So...
You say all are cruel.
And I disagree, disavow,
and say no not.
But when with Duncan
the cruel just bubbles up in me.
That shows good judgment.
He is a pretty moron.
No.
I do not wish to be cruel.
I must improve this
aspect of myself.
You don't know the world.
And you fear it.
I do not fear it.
Do you want to see what
the world is really like?
I'll show you.
Yes.
Of course.
Do you hear that?
What is it?
Lot of dead babies.
Must be hot.
We must go help them.
How will we do that?
We go down there
they'll quite rightfully
rope us, rob us, and rape us.
And if they were here
and we were there
we'd do the same to them.
Bella.
We are casting off, ma'am.
But I have to go back.
I must give this money to
the poor near the hotel
in what they call a slum.
We're staying ashore, ma'am.
We could take care
of that for you.
You can?
Of course.
It is generous of you.
They need money.
Everyone does.
Thank you.
You! Get me the captain. Now
we'll find this fucking thief.
Bella!
We've been robbed!
I won.
I won everything
like never before.
And now it's gone.
You've not been robbed.
- I took it.
- For what?
I took it.
I'm so tired.
Or maybe just my spirit is.
My soul has been
buckled, crumpled
flattened, Duncan Wedderburn
by the sights I have seen.
- So, no need for the captain then, sir?
- Fuck off before I break all your teeth.
Indeed, sir.
Where is it?
You hid it for safety.
I was drunk and foolishly left
it everywhere. What a relief.
I did not hide it.
I gave it to those
poor people out there.
Money is its own
form of sickness,
and all the scarcity of it.
And who am I
lying in a feather bed
while dead babies
lie in a ditch?
Duncan.
You what?
I am expecting a hug of solace.
You...
I need to offer
something to the world.
And yet I have nothing.
Except some money.
It is a bad day
for Bella Baxter.
Where is my fucking money?
I just told you.
I gave it away to the poor.
I thought I told
you to fuck off!
The steward informs me
that you may not have sufficient
funds to make good your account, sir.
- Well, I...
- That is probably true.
I gave it all to some nice men
to pass on
to the slum poor.
You'll be put ashore
at the next port,
and confined to crew's
rations until then, sir.
- Good evening.
- How dare you?
"Dead, blind babies"
"bit Harry."
"My mouth"
"was full of blood."
Poor Bella.
She is a ruin.
- How's your hand?
- It's fine.
I'm sorry.
You were trying to
help me understand.
No. I actually
wanted to hurt you.
Couldn't bear to see such dumb,
beautiful happiness in someone.
It was cruel of me.
I am not sorry.
If I know the world,
I can improve it.
You can't.
That is the real point.
Don't accept the lie of religion
socialism
capitalism.
We are a fucked species.
Know it. Hope is smash able.
Realism is not.
Protect yourself with the truth.
I realize what you
are now, Harry.
Just a broken little boy who
cannot bear the pain of the world.
I suppose so.
Goodbye, Harry.
We get thrown off in Marseille.
Why do you stay with him?
I always think it
will be better.
'Course you do.
I have heard great things
of the beauty of Paris.
I'll fucking kick
your dog to death.
Fucking...
Paris with no money.
- What do you suggest we do, Bella?
- I will get us a hotel.
Do not worry.
With what? We have no money.
Is it not an
interesting experiment?
We have nothing.
- How will we live now?
- I don't know!
Exactly, that is the experiment.
We are now the poor.
Also, many adventurers
have faced these odds.
Robinson Crusoe, for example.
Selfish, thoughtless,
careless bitch.
I'm not thoughtless, Duncan.
And while it is true my ability
to think things through to
the logical conclusions is not
strong...
I did help those
suffering people.
I have ruined us
as you pointed out,
but I do believe my actions
come from a good place.
Shut the fuck up.
I will get us a hotel.
Good afternoon, madam.
Good day, my fresh,
darling English Rose.
Is this a hotel?
We have rooms.
Are you looking for work?
How much is a room?
I'll charge you
10 francs an hour.
You charge them 30.
Everyone's happy.
I see.
Monsieur Chapelle.
Fresh from London.
Hello.
So, off you go.
At this point, I am confused.
You're not here to work?
Come on.
Lie with him, let
him cock you a bit,
and make some nice francs.
I see.
He would pay me for this?
Yes.
If you need money
it is the shortest route to it.
I have never been
cocked by another man,
and yet have wondered on that.
And am in need of funds.
It is, I believe, a
confluence of circumstances...
I regard as almost fate-like.
Let us do this.
Room 16.
What is your name?
Mysterious.
Should we warm me up a bit...
Good day, sir.
Éclair au chocolat?
I've come into some money
and some enlightenment.
You stole it?
You've always said you're the
best bed man in the world,
and I have never known another, so
I knew not whether this was true.
But now I do.
And he was terrible,
and made ungodly noises as
he thrust himself into me.
And a mere three thrusts, Duncan
Wedderburn, was all he could manage.
I stifled a laugh
out of polites, of course.
I took his money. I thanked him.
I laughed all the way
to buy us these eclairs,
and I thought so fondly
remembering the fierce
sweaty nights of ours.
You fucked for money?
And as an experiment.
And it is good for our relationship
as it gladdens my heart toward you.
My heart has been a bit dim on
your weepy, sweary person lately.
You are a monster. A
whore and a monster.
A demon sent from hell
to rip my spirit to shreds.
To punish my tiny sins
with a tsunami of destruction.
To take my heart and
pull it like taffy
to ruin me.
I look at you, and I see
nothing but ugliness.
That last bit was uncalled
for and makes no sense
as your odes to my
beauty have been boring,
but constant.
And the simple act
of letting a strange
man ride on me
has erased all that?
Fuck!
You who red yourself.
Which you are now going
to explain to me is bad.
Can I never win with you?
It is the worst
thing women can do.
We should definitely
never marry.
I am a flawed,
experimenting person,
and I will need a husband with
a more forgiving disposition.
Cunt!
I can now see you are not that.
Our adventure is clearly over.
I shall book you a
passage back to London.
You had money
this whole time?
It is God's money.
For emergencies.
It has been a fucking
emergency for weeks now!
I believed in you the whole time
that you would rise
to the occasion.
But now I see that was a mistake, and
there's clearly something broken in you.
You broke that something in me!
I feel this conversation
has become circular.
Cunt!
Madam Swiney, I have
examined my situation.
I need sex and money.
I could take a lover
another Wedderburn
who would keep me,
but may require an
awful lot of attention.
Or else it's 20
minutes at a time,
and the rest of my day is
free to study on the world,
and the improvement of it.
Hence, I seek employment
at your musty-smelling establishment
of good-time fornication.
A woman plotting her
course to freedom.
How delightful.
Come.
Monsieur Saveur.
A fillet mignon.
A prime cut.
Bella.
Say "formidable" at the end.
House rules.
Is that smell you?
Formidable.
For the smell.
And tea. Just
because tea is nice.
It was brutal
in a strangely not
unpleasant way.
Pamphlet.
- Read.
- What is that?
Une personne qui veut... change
the world pour le meilleur.
Make it better. A better world.
Then I am that too.
Madam Swiney
this lineup system
you really expect me to go upstairs with
a man even if I find him distasteful,
and therefore am sad
when I let him furious jump me?
That is the way
it is, my darling.
Gosh, you look pretty.
How it agrees with
you to be ravaged.
I suppose so.
So, would you not prefer
it if the women chose
as it would be a sign of
enthusiasm toward you?
You wouldn't have the vague sense
that they are in a state of horror
when you jump them.
Bella is new and may
have a mental illness.
As God, my father, says
it is only the way it is until
we discover the new way it is,
and then that is the way it is
until we discover the new way it is,
and so it goes until the
world is no longer flat
electricity lights the night, and
shoes are no longer tied with ribbons.
As a socialist,
I agree entirely.
Toinette, you have
such a clever mouth.
Monsieur Mersault will
enjoy it for free.
Go. Now.
Bella, a moment in my office.
You have the most
delicious looking lobes.
Thank you.
I must...
Oh, I am sorry. I drew blood.
Here.
I sometimes give in to myself
when I see beauty, young beauty.
For one day, my dear
you will be a
wrinkled, old husk.
And no one will want you either to
pay you for it or to have it for free.
I still believe everyone would
be happier if we could choose.
An idealist.
Like me.
How delightful you are.
But we must give in to the
demands of the world sometimes.
Grapple with it,
try to defeat it.
- So you believe as me?
- Of course.
But some men enjoy that
you do not like it.
What?
- That is...
- Sick.
But good business.
Come with me.
My grandchild.
Sick and poorly, and
requiring much doctoring.
My choice of giving you choice
will jeopardize the business.
Her health. Her life.
- Do you want that, Bella?
- Of course not.
You don't? You're so lovely.
I thought you were
going for my lobes.
We must work.
We must make money.
But more than that, we
must experience everything
not just the good.
But degradation,
horror, sadness...
This makes us whole, Bella.
Makes us people of substance
not flighty, untouched children.
Then we can know the world.
And when we know the world
the world is ours.
I want that.
Now
go and fuck someone,
and bring me 10 francs.
First, I suggest a short quiz.
A quiz?
You tell me a childhood memory.
Then I tell a joke.
Then a quick sniff,
and if necessary, a quick
douse in lavender oil.
And all of this will enhance the
experience making it formidable.
Non, I tell the joke.
You the memory.
When you were little in Greece,
you fell from your bicycle?
Blood. Down my leg.
Joy?
You watched the blood with joy.
Knock, knock.
Cheese to meet you.
You know it.
You smell okay.
Let us fuck.
God gave you a gift, my friend.
Very inelegant work.
This is what you do
when you're homesick?
You wish what?
My boys are of an age
for education. Sexual.
I will demonstrate.
I see.
At times.
Shall I lay, bend, astride?
Let's start simple, please.
To aid things along
- a finger in the arse.
- No.
Or a slight choking may do it.
Go home!
Bella!
Madam Swiney was right.
I am discovering parts of
myself hitherto unknown.
It is a way to look at it.
The variety of desires being
made manifest is fascinating.
Have you had the man
who puts a wedge of pineapple in
your mouth and covers you in dust?
Bella.
I'm almost ready to forgive you.
I've booked our berths home,
and I've told Mother to
prepare our wedding bed.
Did you fuck that guy
with hooks for hands?
You did. I know!
I beat the tar out of that guy.
Duncan. I thought you left.
Back to the ship, but
started to ache and vomit,
so I'm here to save you.
Hello, Duncan.
Go home, Duncan.
Our time has ended.
I look at you and feel nothing,
but the lingering question
of how did I ever want you?
And we must go to the
meeting of socialists.
You're whores.
We are our own
means of production.
Go away.
Foot.
Paint, foot.
Very good.
Language is slow but improving.
Paint. Foot.
Genius.
Can you not be so cruel to her?
I made a mistake with Bella.
I allowed feelings to develop.
There are none for her. She is
no different to the chicken dog.
Foot.
It is better this way, perhaps,
and gives some insight into
my father's coolness to me.
It was a necessity of science.
Good God, man.
- Foot.
- I do not expect you to understand
village doctor.
By the way, I need
you to operate on me.
Shall I put a beating heart
in your monstrous form?
If you have time
while taking
this out.
I'll remove some cysts
from around the tumor.
No need. You may close me up.
It has spread. I
see tiny polyps.
I am dying.
How to break it to
the patient, eh?
Baxter...
Do not cry into the wound! You'll
kill me faster with sepsis.
Quiet now.
And close me up.
Find her.
I am closed.
Hot chocolate, my dear.
And pain au chocolat.
You are my favorite.
I have heard you say
that to the others.
We are a machine you feed with
compliments and chocolate.
You are my children
I feed with love.
Something terrible
has happened, Swiney.
I feel almost nothing.
My empathy is creeping
toward what I would describe
as contemptuous rage.
This is fabulous.
It is?
You're in the dark period.
Before light and
wisdom come to you.
You must forge through it,
and once on the other side
you will be grateful to this
moment, but you must keep going.
I see.
You've got a baby scar.
Mine is with ma maman.
I don't have one.
It is an accident scar.
But you're not the first
to have made the mistake.
Why lie?
I'm not lying.
My Godwin told me himself.
Wedderburn.
Good day, sir.
You wrote to Mr. Godwin Baxter.
He has sent a demon at
large into the world.
The devil's wrapped in an alluring
body that cannot be satiated,
and a mind that picks people
apart stitch by stitch
like a bloodied and burned rag doll
shat out of an elephant's arse.
Bella.
Where is she?
Who are you?
I'm her fiancé, sir.
Obviously, things did
not end well between you.
Did not?
She destroyed me.
Well, we're all masters
of our own ship, sir.
There's that.
I do not like you or your words.
That Godwin Baxter.
He knew, and he
set her on to me.
He trapped me.
Where is she?
Would not wish her
on my worst enemy.
I shall save you from her, sir.
Forgive my frustration.
Just tell me.
It does not hurt.
I have no insides.
She hollowed me out.
My soul. My bank account!
I am a bug! A shell!
Shall we sing?
Oh, we are sailors...
It doesn't...
Doesn't hurt.
I do not wish it
to be like this.
You force my hand.
"We're all masters
of our own ship."
You cunting
cunt-faced dead shit.
Please.
I ask you as politely as I can.
Where is she?
The whore is back.
God?
Bella!
Max wrote me.
- You are ill?
- I am not. I am dying.
A subtle difference, but one I
take seriously as a physician.
You are a sight and a good one.
You cannot die.
Empirical data says different.
I missed you.
I now have to lie down.
It is not all sunshine I bring.
I also bring beady eyes
and hard questions.
Did I have a baby in me?
And if so, where is it?
I see.
Well, technically,
you are your baby.
And also, I suppose
you are your mother.
And also neither.
No memory survives.
No experiences survive.
What do you mean I am
mother and daughter?
You knew and did not tell.
I did not see good reason to.
And were too cowardly to.
A bit of that as well.
I wanted to be with you,
and I was not sure you
would even understand.
And Baxter kind of makes
one a prisoner to him.
And I am...
I'm sorry.
Bam.
Who is this?
Bell whore.
- Bell whore.
- I see you've introduced me then, Prim.
- I like this one though.
- Bell whore.
- That's enough now, Felicity...
Fucker.
Another one?
We missed you.
Monsters.
Oh, fucking hell.
Bell whore.
It is hard to be in the position
where one wants to hit someone
who is already in obvious pain.
It is a conundrum for sure.
Would you rather be a gray slab of
flesh with a fishhook in your nose?
I will feel good for a second,
but bad for longer, so...
I really had a
fishhook in my nose?
You did.
So, I am your creation
as is the other one.
Neither of you are that.
She wanders the halls
with a hammer and a song,
and that is not my doing.
And I read your cards
and letters home,
and watched you fearlessly
create Bella Baxter with wonder.
I am finding being alive fascinating,
so I'll forgive you the act,
but always hate the lies
and trapping that followed.
Understood.
Good to see you.
You too.
Anger, confusion, and brain
dissonance aside, I missed you.
I arrived home, and I
smelled the formaldehyde,
and I knew what is next.
I will be a doctor.
My surgery is yours.
My father once told me
always carve with compassion.
He was a fucking idiot.
But it's not bad advice.
He does not have long.
I know.
You've not mentioned
our betrothal.
You were much younger.
There is no bind.
I was mesmerized by you,
and Baxter took advantage.
So, you are mesmerized no more?
I am still mesmerized.
I've been a whore,
you understand?
Cocks for money inside me.
You okay with that?
Does the whoring thing
challenge the desire,
for ownership that men have?
Wedderburn became
much weepy and sweary
when he discovered my whoring.
I find myself merely jealous
of the men's time with you
rather than any moral
aspersion against you.
It is your body, Bella Baxter.
Yours to give freely.
I generally charged 30 francs.
Well, that seems low.
Do you believe people
improvable, Max?
I do.
Just as a human body
can be cured of illness,
so can men and women
be cured of aspect.
Will you marry
me, Max McCandles?
I will.
We will need less of your
tongue in the future,
but overall, most agreeable.
I will take that note.
And have you been
checked for disease?
I have not, but I shall.
I'm enjoying this
practical love we have.
But I assure you mine
is also passionate.
You are adorable.
You always were.
God, you are walking.
I have taken five milligrams of
heroin through the toes for pain
amphetamines for energy,
and cocaine because I
am partial to cocaine.
I've come here to walk
you down the aisle.
And so, by the powers vested
in me by the church...
I shall solemnize this union.
Do you, Bella Baxter, take
this man as your husband?
Did we miss the part about
anyone objecting to this?
Or has that been removed in some kind
of faux modernization of the catechism?
Hello, Victoria.
You look well.
Do you refer to me, sir?
A man doesn't normally
introduce himself to his wife.
But if I must...
He is the God of it.
I do not know if he's in
her power or she in his.
'Tis Devil's work at hand. Look!
He coughs not air as a
normal man but blood.
He has cancer,
you fucking idiot.
Duncan.
Do not lay your
eyes on me, demon!
As I was saying, General
Alfred Blessington.
"Alfie" to you.
You really do not know me?
When Mr. Wedderburn put
your photo in the paper...
I remembered that old bird in the
hotel called you Victoria Blessington,
and I pieced this diabolical
fuckfest of a puzzle together.
- You are...
- Your dear Alfie.
You left in a state of some mental
addlement and hysteria over your pregnancy.
On the discovery of your
absence, I felt disemboweled.
I have disemboweled men
on the field of battle,
and I always imagined a
dull, hollow throbbing,
and that is what it was like.
There's also a stench, but that
does not apply as a metaphor here.
But here you are, my darling.
Here you are.
God.
I have no recollection of you.
I am Bella Baxter.
Hurtful.
But perhaps you've
hit your head,
and these men have clearly
taken advantage of you.
Please go, sir.
- You were my husband?
- Your dear Alfie.
Bella, I'm sorry.
Actually, I would like to go.
What?
Bella?
You have a carriage, sir?
Yes.
Let us go then.
Bella!
Let me go, God.
Max, you will not stop me.
It is good to have
you back, Victoria.
The servants and I have
not been getting along.
I fear an uprising.
You remember David, darling?
Allison, look who's back.
You know me?
Tell me about myself.
Was I nice?
Eat.
All your favorites.
Kippers, goose
tongue, champagne.
I've missed you.
What was the root
of the unhappiness?
What drove her to
leap off the bridge?
You hated the baby.
You called it "the monster."
I see.
I have noticed a lack
of maternal instinct.
And yet I'm happy
to have you home.
How did we meet?
At a ball.
Why did we like each other?
We shared a love of good times.
Watch.
Allison, soup!
Rex!
Fuck!
Allison
we'll have some
cheese when you can.
A love of cruelty?
- I was not a kind person, it seems.
- Kind?
You would never be
so dull, Victoria.
Appalling idea.
Wedderburn says
you were a whore.
- I suspect that was part...
- I was.
In Paris.
I tired of it, but
it was fascinating.
- Right.
- These kippers are strangely delicious.
Vinegary or something.
Marriage is a
constant challenge.
Some, we bend to,
some we bend to us.
I will try to forgive
you for the whoring.
Your sexual hysteria
was often out of hand.
And for the killing
of our unborn child.
In fact, when I list the
ways you've wronged me...
Jesus Christ himself would probably
beat your head in with a bat.
You're blessed with
a forgiving husband.
I've not wronged you, Alfie
as I do not know you.
Well, you're in luck as I've had a lot
of experience in the field with amnesia.
Either men who wish to
forget where they were,
or a mortar exploded nearby
ringing their cranium
like a church bell.
I suggest we stick close to
the house for several months
maybe a year.
Until you've made
a full recovery.
I will leave at my leisure, but I am
flattered by your desire to trap me.
You're not the first.
I will have to shoot
you in the fucking head
if you try to leave, darling.
The front or the
back of the head?
The back.
As to be sure you were leaving,
and I was not being rash.
I have missed you.
So, I'm a prisoner?
This conversation has gone
down an unfortunate route.
I am sure you will be as
happy as you were before.
As I was before when I
threw myself from a bridge?
I suspect you fell
while looking for fish.
Why would you want to keep me
here if I do not wish to stay?
If one must drown, let it
be in the river of love.
David
does that pheasant look
stripped to the bone?
It was a misjudgment, sir.
I apologize.
Dessert, darling?
It comes off easy?
Like a button on a suit.
I saw them do it in Africa
with sharpened rocks,
but had my own more
precise device made.
Do you want just clitoral hood,
or glans as well?
The whole infernal packet.
It will calm her no end.
This time we will get it done.
I shall get her sedated and bring
her to your surgery this evening.
Victoria, darling!
Where are you?
Perfect timing.
Martini.
Rather not.
I would, however, like to leave.
I have found our time
together interesting,
but I've ascertained why
I jumped from a bridge.
I wish to go see
my near dead God.
Adorable idea.
Unfortunately, my darling
my life is dedicated to
the taking of territory.
You are mine,
and that is the long
and short of it.
I am not territory.
The root of the problem
is between your legs.
I will have it off,
and it will not distract
and divert you anymore.
You see, a man spends his life
wrangling his sexual compulsions.
It's a curse and yet, in
some ways, his life's work.
A woman's life's
work is children.
I intend to rid you of that
infernal packet between your legs,
and plant a seed in
you straight after.
Let me explain
what has happened.
Victoria, your wife, threw
herself from a bridge and died.
Godwin Baxter found her,
brought her to his surgery.
He then removed the baby,
removed the brain from the baby
transplanted it into my
head and reanimated me.
I'll bring you the file. It's
actually quite fascinating.
However, I will
keep my new life,
and my lovely old
clitoris, thank you.
If you'd call a carriage for me.
They talk and talk,
and yet at some point there's
nothing left but to pull a gun.
'Tis the way with women.
Are you giving in?
I'd rather you shot me
in the fucking heart.
I will oblige if I have to.
Drink the drink, darling.
Chloroform and gin.
In some ways it would be a relief
to be rid of my questing self.
Sip deeply and that
freedom is yours.
Fuck.
Max?
Max. We have to
get him to surgery.
He'll die if we don't.
Bleeding a lot.
You're fucking dead.
Bella, if he lives...
I do not sense he is
a man who will stop.
Well, I won't watch
him bleed to death.
But I agree, he could
do with improvement.
I've removed the bullet
and stopped the bleeding.
I have the notes.
I am never happier
than when I'm in here.
Bella.
You're back.
It was just a story
of someone else
not Bella Baxter.
All my life, people's
eyes looked at me
horror, pity,
but you.
It's all very interesting
what is happening.
Anatomy exam is
making me nervous.
I've tested you many
times. You know it.
No one knows anatomy
better than you.
Ladies, gin?
Please.
Gin?
We should get some
water for the general.
Felicity
water.