Watch it!
More harpoons!
Ready the nets, men!
-I say kill her 'afore she comes aboard!
-Where is she? Let me see!
Wait. Wait. Wait.
She's a fast one.
-Hand me another!
-She's getting away!
I think she's smilin' at you.
I missed her.
-Another one.
-Come on, another one!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Move! Move! Get back!
What are you doing?
-It's a mermaid!
-A mermaid?
Use your eyes!
What were you thinking?
These are dangerous waters.
And this is a dangerous time.
Tonight's the Coral Moon.
They say this is when the Sea King calls
his mermaid daughters together...
to lure men to their deaths.
-Is that what they say?
-Aye.
Not even the strongest
can resist their spell.
It's just an old lore.
Back to work!
-Come on, lads.
-You see there?
See what, Hawkins?
Crosswind gust kicked up the chop,
that's all.
-That's the Sea King's doing.
-Give me a hand, mate.
He'd pull us under himself if he could.
-Sail faster!
-Raising the main!
This line's tight.
Where's Prince Eric?
Up at the bow, Sir Grimsby.
Eric!
What are you doing out there?
Get back here at once!
You ought to stop worrying so much
about me, Grimsby.
Call me selfish...
but I do not want to tell the Queen...
that her son fell overboard on my watch.
And on his birthday, of all days.
Looks like there's a Spanish galleon out
there headed toward the mainland.
We could follow it to port...
see what they've brought to trade.
Our ship is loaded to the gills as it is.
We've risked our necks out here
for seven weeks already.
We're going home tonight.
Eric.
Pay attention.
I need you to be more careful.
Careful, Grimsby!
My Daughters of the Seven Seas...
I welcome news from all of your waters.
Tamika, Perla...
it's so good to see you.
Caspia, Indira...
it fills my heart to have you all here.
Mala...
Karina...
Where is Ariel?
Sebastian?
You were supposed to see to it
that Ariel was here.
I tried, Your Majesty...
but that child, she is impossible.
I reminded her about the gathering
just this mornin'.
What more can one crustacean do?
You can go find her.
-Yes, Your Majesty.
-Yes.
Right away.
"Yes, Your Majesty.
Right away, Your Majesty."
How hard can it be to find a mermaid,
after all?
If I'm lucky, I'll only have to search
one ocean.
Where are you, child?
We aren't supposed to be this far
from the palace, Ariel.
Let's go back.
How does that work?
Come on, Ariel. Please?
Flounder, stop being such a guppy!
I'm not a guppy.
I think we've gone far enough.
Wait.
What is that?
I've never seen that one.
Come on.
Ariel! Wait for me!
You know I can't swim that fast.
Look at all that.
They must have used the ship
for battles or something.
Yeah, great.
Now let's get out of here.
-Getting cold fins?
-Who, me?
-No way.
-Good.
Then you can stay out here
and watch for sharks.
All right, good.
What?
Ariel, wait!
Do you really think there might be sharks
around here?
Flounder.
Look at this.
It's the smallest trident I've ever seen.
I'm King Flounder, Lord of the Seven Seas!
I wonder why a human
would need one that size.
I bet Scuttle will know.
She always does.
Will you relax?
It's just your reflection.
Calm down.
Nothing is going to happen.
Flounder, look out!
Flounder!
You okay, Flounder?
Sure.
I mean, I've seen bigger sharks.
Just, you know, you can't back down.
You gotta show 'em who's in...
Come back, Flounder. It's just Scuttle.
Ariel. Hey, kid, how ya doin'?
Don't mind me, I was just grabbin' a snack.
Scuttle, we found more treasure.
Yeah. We went into this sunken ship...
and it was really creepy.
Human stuff.
All right, all right, let me see.
Let me see.
Any idea what this is?
Wow.
This...
This is... Yeah.
This is very, very unusual.
What? What is it?
It's a...
It's a dinglehopper.
-A dinglehopper.
-Yeah. Yeah.
Humans use these babies to style their hair.
You just give it a little twirl...
a little yank, you might get some pieces
with it...
and you're left with an artistically
pleasing conflagration of hair...
that humans go nuts for.
Really? I would love to see that.
-Can't.
-Flounder.
You know it's true.
Your father still won't let you go
to the surface, huh?
No, it's forbidden.
He thinks all humans are barbarians.
Oh, they're not so bad.
Unless you're a coconut.
They hate coconuts.
I swear, they get a hold of one...
they smash it to pieces, just like that.
It's weird.
-And what's this?
-Ariel!
Swam half across a whole ocean lookin'
for this child.
Ariel!
Sebastian!
-Sorry about that!
-Ariel!
What are you doin' up there?
Wasting your time with this know-nothing bird
that can't tell swimmin' from flyin'?
Hey!
I suppose you've completely forgotten
tonight's the Coral Moon?
Oh, no!
Oh, yes!
The gatherin' of King Triton's daughters...
minus one.
My father's gonna kill me!
-Sorry, Scuttle, gotta go!
-Yeah, yeah.
All right, sweetie. Me too.
Gotta get some air.
Yes, hurry home, Princess.
We wouldn't want to be late
for Daddy's gathering, now, would we?
Perhaps I'll join them.
Oh, wait, what a shame.
It seems that Big Brother forgot
to invite Auntie Ursula to the party.
Again.
I should be the one throwing the parties,
not waiting on an invitation.
Oh, the feasts we had
when I lived in the palace!
And now look at me, the family pariah.
Wasting away to practically nothing.
Banished and exiled,
driven halfway to madness...
in this dim little crevice for 15 long years.
While Daddy and his spoiled little mer-brats
celebrate the Coral Moon.
Well, I'll give them something to celebrate.
I may have finally found Daddy's weakness.
Yes.
Red's fascination with humans
might be just the opening...
I've been waiting for.
It is irresponsible.
Your sisters are only here for one phase
of the Coral Moon.
Can you imagine any one of them missing
the gathering?
No. You're right.
I'm sorry.
It wasn't Ariel's fault.
We were exploring,
and a shark chased us and...
Shark?
So, you went to the shipwrecks again?
Those waters are dangerous.
You don't have to worry about me.
Well, I do worry, my little one.
I do worry.
This obsession with humans has to stop.
I just want to know more about them.
You know all you need to know.
I barely know anything.
You won't even let us go to the surface.
Why do you have to be so strong-minded?
-Just like your mother. It...
-I am her daughter.
Yes, foolish enough to be taken
with the human world.
-If you would just try to understand...
-Well, I have tried.
I have tried to understand you long enough.
But as long as you live in my ocean,
you'll obey my rules.
Do you understand that?
Children, you give them an inch,
they swim all over you.
Was I too hard on her?
Definitely not.
It's like I always say...
"Children got to live
by their parent's rules."
You're absolutely right, Sebastian.
My Ariel needs constant supervision.
Constant.
Someone to watch over her.
All the time, day and night.
And you're just the crab to do it.
I am just the crab to...
No, wait, that's not...
What?
No, see, I serve you, Your Majesty,
as your honored majordomo.
There is no better way you can serve me...
than to make sure my little one
stays out of trouble.
-But I...
-Yes?
Go.
Yes, Your Majesty.
How do I get myself into these situations?
I'm an educated crustacean.
I got options.
I don't need this.
I should be advising the King...
not chasing after some headstrong teenager.
Ariel, are you okay?
He doesn't even hear me.
I'm just not like him.
I don't see things the way he does.
And I...
I don't see how a world that makes...
such wonderful things could be so bad.
Look at this stuff, isn't it neat?
Wouldn't you think my collection's complete?
Wouldn't you think I'm the girl
The girl who has ev'rything?
Look at this trove, treasures untold
How many wonders can one cavern hold?
Looking around here you'd think
Sure, she's got ev'rything
I've got gadgets and gizmos aplenty
I've got "who's its" and "what's its" galore
You want thingamabobs?
I got 20
But who cares?
No big deal
I want more
I wanna be where the people are
I wanna see, wanna see 'em dancing
Walkin' around on those...
What do you call 'em?
Oh! Feet!
Flippin' your fins, you don't get too far
Legs are required for jumpin', dancin'
Strollin' along down a...
What's that word again?
Street
Up where they walk
Up where they run
Up where they stay all day in the sun
Wanderin' free
Wish I could be
Part of that world
What would I give
If I could live out of these waters?
What would I pay
To spend a day warm on the sand?
Bet ya on land they understand
Bet they don't reprimand their daughters
Bright young women sick of swimmin'
Ready to stand
And ready to know what the people know
Ask 'em my questions and get some answers
What's a fire and why does it...
What's the word?
Burn?
When's it my turn?
Wouldn't I love
Love to explore that shore up above
Out of the sea
Wish I could be
Part of that world
Ariel!
Don't!
Oh, no, no, no!
What does she think she doin'?
I'll tell you a tale of the bottomless blue
And it's hey to the starboard
Heave ho! Heave ho!
Look out, lad, a mermaid be waitin' for you
In mysterious fathoms below
Who's an old man?
I'll sing you a song of the King of the Sea!
And it's hey to the starboard
Heave ho! Heave ho!
The ruler of all of the oceans and seas
In mysterious fathoms below
Heave ho!
-Enough!
-Heave ho!
Thank you, gentlemen.
Oh, let's have a dance, aye.
Oh, come on. It's his birthday.
Oh, come on, Grimsby.
What's wrong with me having a little fun?
Everyone else is.
You, sire, are not everyone else.
It's time you separated yourself
from the rest of the crew.
-But I'm one of them.
-And behave in a manner...
more becoming of a future king.
You mean, be more like my father was?
Cut off from the rest of the world.
Eric, you know what I mean.
When you came to us 21 years ago...
the King and Queen took you in
and treated you as one of their own.
-Now that you've come of age...
-Max.
Max!
What are you doing over there?
Come here, boy!
Come on. Come on.
-Go on.
-And now that you have come of age...
your responsibilities are at home.
Your father would have expected that.
Yes, trapped inside that castle
in isolation and fear.
I can't do it.
-I believe a little fear may be advisable, sire.
-Grimsby, you're not listening.
I want to be a different kind of leader.
That's the whole reason we're on this voyage,
don't you see?
We have to stay open to what's out here.
That's the only way our island can grow.
Eric, think what you risk.
I can't explain it, Grims.
It's in my blood.
Even now...
I feel there's something out here
calling to me.
Storm coming in fast.
-Squall coming in!
-Squall!
All hands on deck!
-Batten down the hatches and crates!
-Yes, sir!
Tie 'em down!
Get the ropes in! Tie her down!
Man the pumps! Man the pumps!
Pull the main sail!
Clew up and stow the main course!
We're over-canvassed!
Brail up the foresail!
Stow all of the sails!
Clew that!
Drop it down. Open up!
Oi, lads!
Fire!
Grab the port side!
Lifeboats! Abandon ship!
Abandon ship!
Into the water, boy!
-Go! Now!
-Jump!
Get in. Get in!
Jump!
Give me your hand, boy.
Come on, get up. Hold on!
Boy! In here. All right?
Max.
That's it. That's it, boy.
Come on, boy. That's it.
All right, boy. Go on.
Go on.
Come here, boy!
-Max! Come on!
-Good boy!
Come on.
Come on, Max.
There you go.
-I got ya.
-Eric!
Oh, no.
Get off me, you fool!
Oh, hey. Didn't expect to find you here.
And I really didn't expect to find her here.
Hey. You listen to me, bird.
The King can never hear of this.
We are going to forget this ever happened.
Are you listenin' to me?
Yes.
You won't tell him, I won't tell him...
and I will stay in one piece.
You got it?
Got it.
Sorry, what'd you say again?
I'm a dead crab.
What would I give to live where you are?
What would I pay to stay here beside you?
What would I do to see you smiling at me?
Where would we walk?
Where would we run
If we could stay all day in the sun?
Just you and me
And I could be
Part of your world?
Check the cove, men.
Checking the cove!
Eyes peeled!
On the other side!
Move it, lads. Follow me.
Down on the sand!
Over here!
This way.
Is he breathing?
He's alive.
Alert the Queen!
-You lead, mate.
-Go quickly, lads.
Back to the castle.
Go ahead.
Go, let's go!
Let's go.
I don't know when
I don't know how
But I know something's starting right now
Watch and you'll see
Someday I'll be
Part of your world
No.
No, it's too easy.
She's already in love with the human world...
and now she found her soulmate.
Wait until Daddy finds out.
He's gonna hit the surface.
That little girl's gonna run straight
into my tentacles.
Then I'll use her as a prawn
in my little game...
and finally get to rip the power
away from Triton...
that should've been mine all along.
All right.
Okay.
As long as the King never finds out,
everything will be all right.
He never has to know she used that precious
siren song of hers to save a human.
I just have to find Ariel
and get her back home.
Now...
she was around here somewhere.
Yeah, this must be it.
I just have to be firm with her...
get her to see that this is all just
a passing fad...
and in time, she'll forget all about him.
Ariel!
Sebastian, how did you find me?
What is all of this?
What are you doin' with that...
that thing?
Isn't it beautiful?
Look at the longing in his eyes.
What you know about longin'?
What is he doin' here?
It's from the shipwreck.
I found him at Merman's Reef.
And I'll bet there's so much more.
No, no! Ariel!
Child, get back here.
Ariel!
You have to let go of this obsession
with humans.
I'm not obsessed.
I may be crusty, but I'm not blind.
I saw you the night of the shipwreck.
What?
Your father wants you to stay as far away
from them as possible!
But why?
You know why.
We don't have to be afraid of them,
I know that now.
Sebastian, if you had just seen it up there.
The ship rode on the wind,
and they filled the sky with fire.
Okay, okay. Listen to me.
The human world is a mess.
Life under the sea is better than anything
they got goin' on up there.
The seaweed is always greener
In somebody else's lake
You dream about going up there
But that is a big mistake
Just look at the world around you
Right here on the ocean floor
Such wonderful things surround you
What more is you lookin' for?
Under the sea
Darling, it's better
Down where it's wetter
Take it from me
Up on the shore they work all day
Out in the sun they slave away
While we devotin'
Full time to floatin'
Under the sea
Down here all the fish is happy
As off through the waves they roll
The fish on the land ain't happy
They sad 'cause they in they bowl
But fish in the bowl is lucky
They in for a worser fate
One day when the boss get hungry
Guess who's gon' be on the plate
Oh, no
Under the sea
Nobody beat us
Fry us and eat us
In fricassee
We what the land folks love to cook
Under the sea
We off the hook
We got no troubles
Life is the bubbles
-Under the sea, hey
-Under the sea
-Under the sea, yes child
Since life is sweet here
We got the beat here, naturally
Naturally
Even the sturgeon an' the ray
They get the urge 'n' start to play
We got the spirit
You got to hear it
Under the sea
Watch this.
The newt play the flute
The carp play the harp
The plaice play the bass
And they soundin' sharp
The bass play the brass
The chub play the tub
The fluke is the duke of soul
Yeah! The ray he can play
The lings on the strings
The trout rockin' out
The blackfish she sings
The smelt and the sprat
They know where it's at
And oh, that blowfish blow!
-Yeah! Under the sea
-Under the sea
When the sardine
Begin the beguine
-It's music to me
-Music is to me
-What do they got? A lot of sand
-A lot of sand
We got a hot crustacean band
Yeah!
Each little clam here
Know how to jam here
-Under the sea
Each little slug here
Cutting a rug here
-Under the sea
Each little snail here
Know how to wail here
That's why it's hotter
Under the water
Yeah, we in luck here
Down in the muck here
-Under the sea
-Sea
Yes
Hey, Ariel?
Somebody got to nail that girl's fins
to the floor.
Don't tell me Eric is still going on
about this girl who rescued him.
I'm afraid so.
And the shipwreck. Any casualties?
None, Your Majesty.
Well, thank goodness no lives were lost.
Indeed.
This restless nature of his, it concerns me.
Undertaking these dangerous voyages.
Oh, Eric, sit.
Any sign of that girl yet, Grimsby?
Have some breakfast, please.
We looked, sire.
There was no girl.
You were lucky to have made it to shore
before you passed out.
She was real. She saved my life.
Sit down, Eric.
-I'm not hungry, Mother.
-I'm worried about you.
You've not been yourself since the shipwreck.
Have you checked the neighboring islands?
-Not all of them, but...
-Then I will.
No, you will not.
You're not leaving this castle
until you're feeling better.
I'll feel better when I find her.
Do not think you're using this girl
as an excuse to run off again...
risking your life on some trade ship
for the sheer adventure.
"Sheer adventure"?
I'm trying to reach out to other cultures,
so we don't get left behind.
Did you know on this last trip
we traded our cane for 20 cases of quinine?
They use it in Europe to treat malaria.
And where are those 20 cases now?
At the bottom of the sea.
How many shipwrecks have there been
in our waters this year, Prime Minister?
-Six, Your Majesty.
-Did you hear that, Eric?
-Of course, I did.
-Shipwrecks, hurricanes...
the sea gods are against us.
How many times do I have to...
They are eroding our land from under us...
stealing it back into the ocean.
They would kill us all if they could.
That's ridiculous.
Is it?
May I remind you, that a deadly shipwreck
first brought you to us.
And now, I almost lost you to one
the other day.
We cannot keep tempting fate like this.
It has got to stop.
Well, what does that mean?
It means that...
that your responsibilities are here now.
So, no more voyages...
and no more chasing after girls
who don't exist.
All I ever wanted was the open sea and sky
Freedom from the life I always knew
Now, all I am is haunted
As days and hours roll by
All I ever think about is you
There you are
Over me
Taking me with your song
To wild uncharted waters
Miles beyond the sea
I was darkness bound
I had almost drowned
Till you came around, and you found me
Now I am on the shoreline
But I'm still lost at sea
In these wild uncharted waters, come find me
Again
All I do is wonder
Who you are and where you'll be
In my mind, your melody goes on
Stronger than the undertow
The night you rescued me
Silhouetted by the rising dawn
Over you
I cannot get over you
In wild uncharted waters
Beyond where man can see
When your eyes outshine the horizon line
And you're finally real, here beside me
Now I'm right here on the shoreline
I'm right where you left me
And your voice is like
A siren that guides me
To wild uncharted waters
Alone, just you and me
And I hope you're there, in the open air
There's no map or compass to guide me, no
Time may change the shoreline
But time will not change me
If it takes my life
I will finally find you again
In uncharted waters
Come find me
Again
Ariel, could you give me a hand?
Ariel!
Yes, of course.
How do we untangle this?
Do these humans have any idea
how much damage their shipwrecks do?
I don't think they intended
to have a shipwreck.
They are careless, Ariel.
It will take thousands of years
for this coral to grow back.
And they've killed
nearly all of the sea fern.
They'd kill us too, if they had the chance.
No, no. They're not all like that.
How would you know?
You've never even seen one.
You were just a child when Mother died...
and Father stopped us going to the surface.
I just mean, we're not all the same,
so why should humans be?
What about humans?
-I just meant...
-Look at what their shipwreck did.
They got what they deserved.
They are the most dangerous species of all.
Spoiling our waters...
destroying the reefs...
having no respect
for the balance of the oceans.
They're not the only ones who have no respect
for balance.
Ariel, where are you...
What's going on with her?
Oh, she's just at that age...
when she doesn't want to hang out
with her older sisters anymore.
Exactly. You remember what I was like.
How could we forget?
Well, I wonder who the lucky merman is.
The crab, Your Majesty.
Come over here, Sebastian.
Breathe, Sebastian.
Remember, guilty is as guilty acts.
Don't overreact, remain calm.
Yes?
Yes, Your Majesty?
Sebastian...
have you noticed that Ariel
has been acting peculiar lately?
Peculiar, sir?
Distracted, daydreaming...
disappearing for hours.
You haven't noticed?
Well, I...
I actually haven't, you know...
that is to say, I didn't...
Sebastian...
I know you've been keeping something from me.
Keepin' somethin'?
About Ariel.
Ariel?
Is my little one in love?
Oh, I tried to stop her, sir!
I tried to stop her
from going to the surface!
I told her to stay away from humans!
-Humans?
-When I saw her with that statue I...
Humans? Who said anything about humans?
Let's just drop these things off and go back.
No way!
With all that great stuff still down there?
Don't we have enough already?
Come on, Flounder.
We're just getting started.
So...
You broke the rules?
You went to the above world.
There was a shipwreck.
A man was drowning. I had to save him.
You should have let him drown.
They're savages.
You don't know that.
They killed your mother.
I know.
But...
one man did.
Why blame every human?
-Mother wouldn't.
-No!
Enough. That's enough.
And Eric had nothing to do with it.
Eric?
Have you lost your senses completely?
If you would have just heard him, Father.
He's compassionate and kind and...
He's a human!
-You're a mermaid!
-Yes.
But that doesn't make us enemies.
Promise me you will never look for him again.
-I can't.
-Promise me, Ariel!
I can't lie to you. I won't.
I swear, I will get through to you!
No!
Please!
Father, stop.
This ends now!
Please, stop it!
It's for your own good.
Father, no!
Never leave again.
Ariel.
I'm...
Just go away.
Poor child.
Poor sweet child.
He can be so angry.
He thinks he knows everything.
Who are you?
You must not remember me.
I'm your Auntie Ursula.
The Sea Witch?
The what?
What has your father told you about me?
That you like to stir up trouble
between humans and merpeople.
Is that what he said?
I'm not half the monster he claims I am.
And I'm only here to help.
I don't need your help.
Whatever you say, darling.
-Wait.
-Yes?
How can you help me?
Ariel?
Where is she going
with those slippery good-for-nothin's?
Let's go.
Come in.
Come in, child.
We mustn't lurk in passageways.
It's rude.
Forgive my aggressive garden.
I wouldn't choose to live like this,
believe me.
Daddy's been so unfair to both of us...
controlling everything we say and do.
In a way, we're the same, you and I.
You don't seem at all like
Father described you.
Is that right?
We never did get along.
Squidling rivalry.
He always got what he wanted,
and what did I get? Nothin'.
Zip, nada, squat.
Sound familiar, hon?
Oh, I know what you're going through,
believe me...
and I know why you're here.
I'm not sure I do.
Oh, please.
I've been watching you
for a long time now, dearie.
What you really want is to be up there
in the above world.
It's always had your curiosity...
and now it's got your heart.
What do you mean?
You're so young.
Don't you see?
You're meant for each other.
And I can't bear to see you suffer like this.
As it happens, I can help you.
How?
The problem is simple.
You can't live in that world, unless...
you become a human yourself.
Become human?
Is that even possible?
Oh, my dear.
It's what I do.
It's what I live for.
I admit that in the past I've been a nasty
They weren't kidding when they called me
Well, a witch
But you'll find that nowadays
I've mended all my ways
Repented, seen the light, and made a switch
True? Yes
And I fortunately know a little magic
It's a talent that I always have possessed
And here lately, please don't laugh
I use it on behalf
Of the miserable, lonely, and depressed
Pathetic
Poor unfortunate souls
In pain, in need
This one longing to be thinner
That one wants to get the girl
And do I help them?
Yes, indeed
Those poor unfortunate souls
So sad, so true
They come flocking to my cauldron
Crying, "Spells, Ursula, please!"
And I help them?
Yes, I do
Now, it's happened once or twice
Someone couldn't pay the price
And I'm afraid I had to rake 'em
'cross the coals
Yes, I've had the odd complaint
But on the whole, I've been a saint
To those poor unfortunate souls
-The Sea Witch!
-Shh.
So, here's the deal.
I'll whip up a little potion
to make you human for three days.
Got that?
Three days.
Before the sun sets on the third day,
you and Princey must share a kiss.
And not just any kiss.
The kiss of true love.
If you do, you will remain human permanently.
But if you don't...
you'll turn back into a mermaid...
and you belong to me.
-No, Ariel!
-Shh.
You understand, of course...
that you'll have to give up
your mermaid gifts.
You won't have this tail of yours,
hangin' around, draggin' you down.
You won't be able to breathe underwater,
who needs it?
And you'll no longer have
that siren song of yours...
because that wouldn't be fair, now would it?
Don't worry.
I'll keep it safe and soundless here with me.
We got a deal?
I don't know.
Well...
I mean, I just gave you
the premium package, kid.
Well...
life's full of tough choices, idn't?
No.
This is wrong. I can't do this.
Fine then, forget about the world above.
Go back home to Daddy...
and "Never leave again!"
Come on, you poor unfortunate soul!
Go ahead
Make your choice
I'm a very busy woman
And I haven't got all day
It won't cost much, just your voice
You poor unfortunate soul
It's sad, but true
If you want to cross the bridge, my sweet
You've got to pay the toll
Pluck a scale from off your tail
A drop of blood inside the bowl!
Flotsam, Jetsam, now I've got her, boys
For boss is on a roll!
This poor unfortunate
Soul!
Beluga! Sevruga!
Come winds of the Caspian Sea!
Amnesia, glossitis et max laryngitis
La voce to me!
Now sing!
Keep singing!
Yes!
Look at her stupid little feet!
Oh, Ariel.
Well, come on, gal.
It's either sink or swim.
Don't worry, boys.
She doesn't stand a chance without this.
A mermaid without her voice?
And just in case...
I slipped a little somethin' extra
into that spell of mine.
No matter how hard that girl tries...
she won't remember
she needs to get that kiss.
Now it's just a matter of time.
And then she's mine.
Not so easy without your tail, is it?
Keep going.
You just got to get your sea legs.
We're almost there.
Get away from here!
Lord have mercy.
Are you all right?
Ah, poor girl.
You must be in shock.
I'll go find something to cover you up.
Another shipwreck.
Santa Maria.
Say, what's goin' on, kid?
I thought you weren't supposed to be up here,
now you're taking boat rides?
That rotten Sea Witch,
she stole Ariel's voice.
Hey, Flounder.
What are you talkin' about?
So, Sebastian told Triton
that Ariel saved a human...
-and Triton got so mad.
-Okay, okay, okay.
-And then... Wait!
-Explanations later, man.
-We've gotta get you out of here.
-Wait!
-I didn't tell you about the Sea Witch!
-Bye-bye.
And don't tell anyone about the Sea Witch!
Something about you seems different.
Don't tell me.
It's your hairdo, right?
'Cause you've been using the dinglehopper?
No?
I can't quite figure it out...
but I know that if I stand here
for long enough...
She got legs, ya idiot!
You know, we've discussed this.
I don't like it when you call me an idiot.
Why don't you tell me somethin' nice?
-"Hey, Scuttle. Your feathers look good."
-Shoo!
Here you are.
It'll have to do for now.
I'll take you to the castle.
They'll know what to do with you there.
Come on, in ya go.
Good catch today.
It looks good, though.
It looks raw.
You're not done yet?
His looks so good!
I must say a parrie fish.
Got plenty of fish for two weeks.
Hey!
Look at the sun and the sky
And the sand and the sea behind me
Look at me, suddenly I am on land
And I'm free
Don't mind me as I climb for the first time
Jump for the first time
Trying to stand
But this gravity's pulling me down
Walk on, Emile.
Trot on!
Get Lashana, quick!
Right-o!
What is all this?
What on Earth?
The girl got tangled in the net.
-She all right?
-She'll survive.
But she's been through it, though.
Won't say a word.
I wonder what happened to her out there.
Look, it's a fire, it's warm and it glows
And it lights this chamber
Let me admire it
Ow!
Get too close and it bites
I came too close for the first time
Burned for the first time
Everything's clearer and brighter and hotter
But now that I'm here
Like a fish out of water
I'm trying to stand
But this gravity's pulling me down
Oh, my! Heavens.
Here, let me take you upstairs...
get you cleaned up,
find you some clothes.
Okay, up we go...
one step at a time.
She can't speak at all?
Can you blame her, Rosa?
After all she's been through...
it's a blessing she's not worse off.
Such a faraway look in her eye.
Bit of a soap and a scrub,
she'll be good as new.
Are we only
Food for slaughter?
Is this life on land?
Child, the blue dress that's in your room.
Well, you were lonely under water
Come on, Ariel, time to stand
There you go. Smells nice, doesn't it?
Oh, no, you poor girl.
You must be starvin'.
Rosa, get this poor child some food.
And quick, before she tries to
eat the scrub brush.
-Yes, ma'am.
-Right.
Let's get that seaweed stink off you, girl.
Yes.
Squeeze in the shoes
And the corset, it's tight
And the seams are busting
Some women choose this
I guess it's all right
Are my dreams adjusting
Hard to believe...
two shipwrecks in one week.
Prince Eric's still looking for
that girl who saved him.
Said he won't rest until he finds her.
Stay right there. I'll get the Prince.
As I wait for the first time
Here for the first time
Now, for the first time
He's coming through those doors
Up the stairs
From the shore
From that moment
And he'll smile
Like he knows
When I say
I'm so sorry to hear what happened.
What's your name?
She doesn't speak, sire.
She...
Well, we're glad you've made it to us.
Do you have a place to stay?
Family?
Well, then you're welcome to stay here.
For as long as you like.
Make sure she has anything she needs.
Yes, Your Highness.
We should let you get some rest.
Realize the price that you paid
With your voice
As he turns from you
Those sacrifices you made
Were a choice that you can't undo
Lost
For the first time
Scared
Gravity feels like an undertow
Pulling me
Down
This has got to be, without a doubt...
the single most humiliating day of my life!
I could have been fricasseed...
and then, having to climb
all the way up here.
They couldn't give you a room
on the ground floor?
I hope you appreciate what I go through
for you, young lady.
No.
Don't ya turn your back on me.
What were you thinkin',
choosin' to give up your mermaid gifts?
Now, if we could just get that witch
to give them back...
then you could go home and just be...
well, and just be...
just be miserable for the rest of your life.
Oh, my, what a soft shell
I am turnin' out to be.
All right. All right.
I'll try to help you.
But we've got to be bold, act quickly.
Don't forget about the kiss.
No, no, not me, the Prince!
You gotta kiss the Prince.
Don't you remember?
You only have three days to...
Hello?
Oh, no!
She's put a spell on you.
You can't remember, can you?
Now, what are we gonna do?
Well, we got no time to lose.
We just got to find a way
to get the two of you together.
You are hopeless, child.
You know that?
Completely hopeless.
A buffet.
What? No nuts?
What are you doin' here?
Oh, there you are.
I've been lookin' for you.
Flounder told me the whole story.
Has Ariel killed the Prince yet?
No, not killed.
Kissed, ya bird brain.
And it's worse than we thought.
The witch has placed a spell on her.
Soon as I tell her she's got to kiss him...
the thought jumps clear
right out of her head.
So, now it's up to us.
To kiss the Prince?
Forget it.
Where's Ariel now?
What do ya mean? She's right...
What are you doin' in here, child?
You can't just go wanderin' around
wherever you please.
Hide!
Who's in here?
Oh, it's you.
Nobody usually comes in here.
My little mermaid.
It's all right, it's all right.
You can look at it.
I found her on the coast of Cartagena.
Isn't she beautiful?
Oh, that's right. You...
Well, it really doesn't matter.
Most people around here use too many words
and have nothing to say.
You know...
I never believed all that lore about
mermaids luring sailors to their deaths.
Here, take her.
No, really. I want you to have her.
I'm running out of space as it is.
Nearly all of these things
come from my voyages.
I know it must seem silly,
collecting all this stuff...
but just look at this fossilized sea stone.
Can you believe that such amazing things
exist down there?
No, wait!
How did you know that was in there...
all this time?
That's incredible.
-Well, that.
-Hey, girl.
That I just picked up from the beach
here on the island.
There's loads of them at this time of year.
I had no idea you could do that.
Oh, me?
Really?
All right, hand...
How do I...
Yeah, that's it.
That's it, girl.
Go get it, go get it.
I see ya.
Go on, come now...
Sorry.
Yeah, well...
I'll work on that.
I love the people there.
Their culture, their custom.
This whole region is known
as the Brazilian Empire.
Then there's Venezuela...
Colombia...
the area up here is called Mosquito Coast.
Those waters are all uncharted.
Wouldn't it be amazing to discover
someplace no one's ever seen before?
Well, this...
this was one of my favorite voyages.
I bought that Peruvian rug there...
along with six of the looms
they used to make it.
Another one. All right.
This is our island.
We're in that very castle right now.
Over here's our main village.
Now, our port there was once
the busiest in the region.
I'm hoping it will be again one day.
And there's a beautiful lagoon
with a little waterfall right here.
And then all of that is rainforest.
I could show you around, if you like.
All right.
We'll go tomorrow.
But, sire...
Grimsby, good.
We'll need a horse and carriage
ready for us in the morning.
May I have a quiet word, sire?
Of course.
He's a special one, isn't he?
And that moonlight.
We were going to send out all the carriages
tomorrow to look for the girl.
The girl!
I wasn't thinking.
Of course, yes, we must do that.
-Absolutely.
-And I must remind you, Eric...
what your mother said yesterday
about you not leaving the castle...
-until you're feeling better.
-Grimsby, I feel fine.
I feel better than ever.
Yes.
Yes, I can see that.
I suppose we could spare one carriage.
Looks like you made a friend there.
Come on, Max.
We'll see you later.
Oh, no. You're not goin' without me.
I only got two days left.
I'm a crab on a mission.
Trot on, King.
I'm getting too old for this.
Oh, no, no, no! Down, beast!
I still got it.
Who is that ridin' out with Prince Eric?
Is that the girl who washed up the other day?
Yes, it is, Lashana.
Didn't the Queen tell him to
stay in the castle?
Yes, she did, Lashana.
Aren't you going to get into trouble
for fetching him a carriage?
What carriage, Lashana?
Do you wanna try?
Here.
Look out! Look out!
Come on! Move, move, move!
Sorry about that!
That was close.
Whoa!
Hey, guys! Get out the way!
-Turn!
-Quickly!
Wait, wait, wait!
Hey, hey, hey. Watch yourself!
Careful!
That was...
fun.
Here, I'll...
Let me give you a hand.
Move, move 'em.
Here we go. This way.
Come on. This way.
Here we go.
Go on. That's it.
Thank you, lad.
Island berry?
How is it? Pretty?
-Coconut!
-Breadfruit!
Coconut!
Fresh coconut?
No? You don't want it?
Get some water in ya.
Thank you, Miss.
Young lady, would you like to try some?
I think you'll be needing this.
Hey, can I have some salt?
Good day, sire.
How ripe the mango?
Hat for the lady?
Oh. There you are.
No, no. Too big.
Try this.
Tropical flowers?
Hey! Everybody, everybody!
-Hey, hey, hey!
-Hey!
Say, any kissing yet?
No. When it comes to romance,
these two are slow as snails.
Hey, go find Flounder.
We got to move this thing along, and quick.
Okay, bossy.
Hey!
Bring it here, bring it here,
bring it here now!
Back it up, back it up, back it up!
Come on, now!
I love this time of night.
Sometimes you'll see the eyes
of a screech owl, up in the tree...
Hey! Hey!
Hey, come back with that!
Come on.
Watch out.
I think it went this way.
You all right?
Hey!
Give me my hat back!
All right then.
I didn't want to lose this.
Move your big fat feathers, bird.
I can't see a thing.
Well, that worked pretty good, didn't it?
But nothing's happening.
We're running out of time,
and no one's puckered up once.
I think it's time for a little...
vocal romantic stimulation.
Please, no.
-Scuttle? You got to be...
-Me, me, me
Womp chicka womp womp
Chicka womp womp
Chicka womp
Womp womp
-All right. Gosh.
-Womp
-I was off. I was off on that one.
-No.
Womp
Let me find it. Let me find it.
Ya finish?
Womp
All right, all right. Listen.
Ariel cannot know we're helpin'.
If she sees or hears us, she'll shut us down.
Nah, man. We got to be sneaky about this.
We got to work on the Prince...
-using the power of suggestion.
-Good.
How are we gonna do that?
We got to blend in with the sounds of nature,
so she doesn't hear us.
Percussion.
Strings.
Winds.
Words.
There you see her
Sitting there across the way
She don't got a lot to say
But there's something about her
And you don't know why
But you're dying to try
You wanna kiss the girl
Yes, you want her
Look at her, you know you do
Possible she wants you, too
Use your words, boy, and ask her
Do you want to try?
If the time is right
Then the time is tonight
Go on and kiss the girl
Sha la la la la la, my oh, my
Look like the boy too shy
Ain't gonna kiss the girl
Sha la la la la la
Ain't that sad
Ain't it a shame, too bad
He's gonna miss the girl
Hey, pull it back. Scuttle, pull it back.
What a clear night.
You can see Orion.
The sailors use the constellations
to navigate.
That one's Orion, the hunter.
There's Aries, the ram.
That's Cassiopeia.
That's funny.
I still don't know your name.
Let's see. Is it...
Diana?
No?
Or...
Katherine?
No, definitely not Katherine.
How...
Sky...
Aries?
Aries.
Arie...
Ari-el.
Ariel?
Ari-el?
Ariel.
That's a beautiful name.
Written in the stars.
Now's your moment
Floating in a blue lagoon
-Boy, do it soon
-Boy, you better do it soon
No time will be better
She don't say a word
And she won't say a word until you
Kiss the girl
Sha la la la la
Don't be scared
You got the mood prepared
-Go on and kiss the girl
-Kiss the girl
Wow, wow
Sha la la la la la
Don't stop now
Don't try to hide it
How you wanna
Kiss the girl
Sha la la la la la
Float along
And listen to the song
The song say
"Kiss the girl"
Sha la la la la la
The music play
Do what the music say
You gotta
Kiss the girl
Why don't you
Come on and
Kiss the girl
Go on and
What was that?
That was close.
Too close.
I don't get it.
I didn't think that little barracuda
stood a chance...
luring him in without her voice.
How's that even possible?
Well, we're not gonna let that happen again.
It's time Ursula took matters
into her own tentacles.
Where is it?
Come on, come on.
It's gotta be here somewhere.
No! No!
Nobody ever puts my things back!
No! Where is it?
No, no, no!
No!
Oh, there it is.
I got it.
That Prince won't know what hit him.
Only one more sunset...
and then I'll make Triton writhe.
I'll see him wriggle like a worm on a hook.
So where is she?
-We don't know, Father.
-She's gone.
What do you mean, she's gone?
We've been looking and looking.
There's no sign of her anywhere.
She's not in these waters.
Then look again.
Search all of the Seven Seas if you have to.
-Ariel wouldn't dare go above again.
-Don't even think such a thing.
Doesn't make sense. Why would she leave?
I have no idea.
Never mind that. Just find her.
What have I done?
Everyone's asleep.
We should probably be quiet.
-In his room, all day?
-Wait.
-Go. Oh, no. Go, go. Go in there. Go.
-I haven't seen him once.
-Careful.
-I imagine he's just resting.
Has he been avoiding me?
No, Your Majesty.
-No?
-No.
You seem awfully certain.
Avoiding you?
Doesn't seem like Eric, does it?
Then where is he?
Oh, he's not searching for
that fantasy girl, I hope.
No, Your Majesty.
That I can say with certainty.
Thank heavens for small blessings.
It's wet.
I will look into it.
You really must get some rest yourself.
Yes, I suppose I should.
Thank you, Grimsby. Good night.
Ma'am.
Sorry about that.
I wasn't supposed to leave the castle today.
But I'm glad I did.
All these rules...
The truth is, I wasn't born to all this...
and it all makes me feel a little uneasy...
-Welcome back, sire.
-Oh, Grimsby.
I trust you two had a pleasant outing.
Yes, we did.
Didn't we?
Yes. Very nice.
You've had a long day, Miss.
I imagine we should let you get some sleep.
And perhaps dried off as well.
Yes. We took a rowboat out onto the lagoon...
and I'm afraid we ended up in it.
Anyway, good night.
Good night...
Ariel.
About the carriages, sire...
I'm afraid they...
didn't find the mystery girl.
They didn't?
May I then ask...
should we continue the search?
Grimsby...
I just...
I feel a little...
Well, if you want the advice
of an old man, sire...
don't be held back
by what you think should be.
Think only of what is.
Good night, sire.
Hey! Wake up! Wake up! Wake up!
What?
Hey, have you not heard the scuttlebutt?
Your butt?
No, the gossip, the buzz
The who-said-what-who-does-that
Yeah, the scuttlebutt
Well, I was flying over land and sea
An ear to the ground
Then I came flying here for you to see
And hear what I found
Remember the swamp?
Remember my song in the swamp
When I was like
"Womp chicka womp womp chicka womp womp"
I remember.
Well, ever since
The what's his name?
The guy with the hair and the shirt
-The Prince.
-Yeah, the Prince
Has been dropping hints
He wants to
You know when humans
Dress all nice like they're penguins?
Throw rice for the pigeons?
They're trying to blow up the pigeons
But those are just urban legends
I know a lot of really fat pigeons
-Scuttle...
-Will you just listen, Sebastian?
I got the scuttlebutt
Hurry up.
You'll be like, "What?"
When I drop that scuttlebutt
Okay, now, huddle up, buttercup
From the women who wash all the clothes
To the hunter who arrows the bows
The chatter all over the palace
Is that your Prince Eric is gonna propose
-What?
-To somebody nobody knows
They're saying he suddenly chose
-Who?
-Who? You sound like an owl
-I'll bet it's the kid with the new set of toes
-No!
Oh, yes, anything goes
Who'd ever guess
Our little Ariel's marriage material?
Time for the rice and the dress
And the what do you call it?
The thing with the lips, when they press
I don't have lips, I have a beak
So I guess I could give you
A peck on the cheek
I don't believe it.
Say, you're awfully quiet.
Oh, yeah. So, what now?
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
Can you believe the scuttlebutt?
Get dressed, child.
You're welcome for the scuttlebutt
We got a lot of work to do before sundown.
The scuttlebutt, scuttlebutt, hey!
Oh, please let this be the day.
-Let's go, let's go, let's go
-Let's go
We got it, the gossip, the buzz
The who-said-what-who-does-that
Yeah, I told you so
Let's go, let's go, let's go
We gotta go before the sun goes down
What? Got to get her ready
For the big showdown
-Right
-Go ahead and get her out of bed
And get her ready for the wedding
Sun is setting so we can't slow down
The scuttlebutt
Scuttle, you're too close.
My goodness, it is wonderful news.
-Isn't it, Grimsby?
-Oh, yes.
I must admit, I was mistaken.
It seems you really have found the girl
of your dreams after all.
Yes. Quite the surprise, Eric.
What?
I know.
I know it must seem fast...
but I do owe her my life.
We will celebrate.
This evening.
You shall introduce your intended
to the court.
We can make that happen, can't we, Grimsby?
Yes. If it's really what you want, Eric.
What I... want?
It's what we both want.
Lovely.
Well, we've got our work cut out for us.
Indeed.
Then let's begin preparations. Grimsby...
Oh, Ariel, girl.
Where have you gone?
-Yeah. Any sign of her?
-No luck.
I flew over the village three times.
Well, check the castle again!
It's almost sunset. We got to find her.
Copy that.
What's wrong with that fool Prince?
Something fishy going on here.
-I don't like the smell of it...
-Sebastian!
-Over here.
-Yeah, what?
I coming, I coming. Hold on.
Yes, what?
I think I know where Ariel is.
Well, what are we waiting for?
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
Ariel?
So long, Red.
Oh, no!
Risking it all
Only to fall
Back where I started
Back near the shore
Back to before
You took my hand
Bet ya on land
They understand
And they don't strand you brokenhearted
What did I give to live where you are?
Where do I go with nowhere to turn to?
Hey, what are you doin', child?
You can't give up so easily.
This all has to be
some sort of misunderstanding.
I watched both of you.
You're meant to be together.
There you are.
I've been lookin'.
And I thought I found you, 'cause I heard.
But then I saw it wasn't you.
It was her!
But it wasn't...
In the mirror, except she had...
She had your voice!
What are you talkin' about?
-Don't you get what I'm tellin' you?
-No!
The Prince has been tricked.
That lady who showed up is actually
the Sea Witch in disguise.
Are you sure about this?
Of course I'm sure!
Have I ever been wrong?
I mean, like, you know, when it counts?
Well, what are we gonna do?
Well, we have to do something...
before Prince Eric ends up
with that slimy squid.
Yes, girl, go!
Flounder, go tell the Sea King
what's happened.
He has to know everything.
Okay.
What do I do?
You give me a lift to the castle.
We got to find a way
to stall that engagement.
Really is very special.
Heroism's too strong a word for it...
but I suppose I did save Eric.
-That's what anyone would do.
-Of course.
-Grimsby.
-Sire.
Have you seen Ariel?
According to the servants,
she left the castle early this morning.
Left?
Can you blame her, Eric?
I don't understand. This is not like you.
I'm not sure I understand it myself.
I just wanted to...
-I thought if...
-Eric.
Thank you.
I don't really know what I wanted.
Almost there!
Now, when I give the signal, you drop me!
-Got it?
-Got it.
No, you idiot...
Guess I'm on my own.
My darling...
this belonged to my mother.
And I'd like you to have it.
Your happiness means everything to me.
You're very sweet.
Would you excuse me?
Enjoy yourself.
Oh, Eric.
It's beautiful.
-What in the...
-The ring.
The ring. I lost...
Has anybody seen the ring?
Have you seen the ring?
Have you seen it?
Get off me, you filthy bird!
Help me! I'm being attacked!
Ariel!
Ariel, I've been looking for you.
Who is that?
What are you doing?
-Grimsby, let me go!
-Sire!
Get her away from me!
She's insane!
What's going on?
Ariel, stop!
Get off!
Ariel.
Yes.
It was you all along.
I should've known.
I don't know what came over me.
She bewitched you.
Get away from her!
Eric, I want you to know I...
Oh, just kiss!
-I want you to know everything.
-Nothing matters now.
No!
Oh, good Lord. She's a sea creature.
You're too late!
Stay back!
Shut up!
Eric!
Eric, no.
This is the work of the sea gods.
I warned you.
Their whole world is evil.
Eric, wait! Eric!
What are you doing? Let go of me!
Not a chance. You made a deal, remember?
Three days, no kiss.
Yeah, is it all comin' back to ya?
I thought so.
Well, now you gotta live with it, toots.
Ursula!
Let her go.
Forget it, Big Brother.
She belongs to me now.
Oh, you see?
We made a deal.
In blood.
It's unbreakable, even for you.
I'm sorry, Father. This is all my fault.
What do you want with my daughter?
Nothing.
It's you I want.
I want to see you suffer,
like I've suffered all these years.
And the daughter of the great Sea King...
is a very precious commodity.
Poor, unfortunate soul.
Hey!
Get her, boys!
I wouldn't.
Shocking, isn't it?
Of course, I always was
a gal with an eye for a bargain.
What do you say to a trade, hmm?
What's your precious little Ariel
worth to ya?
It's mine now.
No!
Father!
You monster!
Don't be a fool, you little brat!
You are powerless against...
You're gonna pay for that.
Get him!
Say goodbye to your human heartthrob.
Don't!
My babies!
Eric!
Get to shore. She'll kill you!
I'm not leaving you!
Yes!
Give me your hand!
Now!
Look out!
Now I rule the seas...
and all will be helpless under my power!
No!
So much for true love.
So long, lover boy.
You gave your life for me.
And you fought to get my life back.
I didn't fight alone, Father.
Eric was with me.
All that matters now is
that you're safe and home.
Where you belong.
Sire, please!
We need a boat.
Grimsby, we have to find her!
And then what?
And then what, Eric?
Darling.
You were right.
-I was chasing after a fantasy girl.
-No.
No, I was wrong.
She was very real.
And so were your feelings for her,
I see that now.
It's just that...
our worlds were never meant to be together.
Sebastian!
You gotta be kidding me.
Yes, Your Majesty.
I have always tried to do
what's best for our people.
Yes, Your Majesty.
And what's best for my daughters.
Indeed, Your Majesty.
And I've done everything in my power
to make her happy.
Well, not quite.
She wants a different life
than I had planned for her.
She did try to tell you, Your Majesty.
But I won't be able to protect her anymore.
Well, it's like I always say...
children got to be free
to lead their own lives.
Oh, is that what you always say?
Somethin' like that. Yeah.
Then there's just one problem left.
And what's that, Your Majesty?
How much I'm going to miss my little one.
Good boy. Go on.
Again?
Max?
Blessings to you both.
Magical news, yeah.
Oh, what's all this, Grims?
Oh, the Queen wanted the two of you
to have a proper send-off, sire.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
No. Thank you.
Much as I hate farewells,
we still have cause to celebrate.
Our worlds have misunderstood one another
for far too long.
Your marriage marks a new beginning for us.
Yes. A beginning.
Now...
get out there...
and change the world...
or whatever it is you have to do,
so we don't get left behind.
That doesn't sound like my mother.
What have you done with her?
Off you go.
Have you decided where you're headed first?
Uncharted waters.
Okay!
A mermaid and a man.
Whoever would have imagined?
Well, look who's here.
-We got you something, Ariel.
-Sure did.
Something you almost lost.
Where is it?
You're sittin' on it, bird.
My little mermaid.
Keep her for me.
I hope she causes you less trouble
than I did.
I was right about the dinglehopper, wasn't I?
Yes, you were, Scuttle. You were.
You won't be gone too long...
-will you, Ariel?
-Of course not.
I'll be back by the next Coral Moon.
Yeah, don't be late this time.
You ready?
Yes.
Yes, I'm ready.
My child.
Eric.
Thank you for hearing me.
You shouldn't have had to give up your voice
to be heard.
But now I am listening.
And I will always be here for you.
We all will.
I love you, Father.
The seaweed is always greener
In somebody else's lake
You dream about going up there
But that is a big mistake
Just look at the world around you
Right here on the ocean floor
Such wonderful things surround you
What more is you lookin' for?
Under the sea
Darling, it's better
Down where it's wetter
Take it from me
Up on the shore they work all day
Out in the sun they slave away
While we devotin'
Full time to floatin'
Under the sea
Down here all the fish is happy
As off through the waves they roll
The fish on the land ain't happy
They sad 'cause they in they bowl
But fish in the bowl is lucky
They in for a worser fate
One day when the boss get hungry
Guess who gon' be on the plate?
Oh, no
Under the sea
Nobody beat us
Fry us and eat us
In fricassee
We what the land folks love to cook
Under the sea we off the hook
We got no troubles
Life is the bubbles
-Under the sea
Under the sea
-Yes, child.
Since life is sweet here
We got the beat here
-Naturally
Even the sturgeon an' the ray
They get the urge 'n' start to play
We got the spirit
You got to hear it
Under the sea
Watch this.
The newt play the flute
The carp play the harp
The plaice play the bass
And they soundin' sharp
The bass play the brass
The chub play the tub
The fluke is the duke of soul
Yeah! The ray he can play
The lings on the strings
The trout rockin' out
The blackfish she sings
The smelt and the sprat
They know where it's at
And oh, that blowfish blow!
-Yeah! Under the sea
-Under the sea
When the sardine
Begin the beguine
-It's music to me
-Music is to me
What do they got?
A lot of sand
We got a hot crustacean band
Yeah!
Each little clam here
Know how to jam here
Under the sea
Each little slug here
Cutting a rug here
Under the sea
Each little snail here
Know how to wail here
That's why it's hotter
Under the water
Yeah, we in luck here
Down in the muck here
Under the sea
Yes