Go past me children.
There are some to my left
and some ahead here.
Yes.
Sleep child sleep.
Don't sit on me.
I didn't sit on you.
That's what happens when you stamp on my foot.
You'd better not throw a
bucket of water over me.
No, we'd never do that.
It better not make me late.
This way... and out.
Watch out for the steps.
Feel for it... and down. Perfect.
Last step, and now turn around.
...
Where you go. Wait. Stand here.
Surprise.
Is this for me?
Yes.
Thank you.
Happy birthday.
Where did you get it?
I have my sources.
One, two, three passengers.
Who wants the first ride?
Me.
You.
You can have the first ride.
The paint is still fresh.
Annagret will have a green bottom.
Coats, hags, off to school.
Thank you, children.
Goodbye.
Inge, pull your socks up.
Bye bye Daddy.
Phlox.
Would you like to smell a rose?
Smell a rose. Yes. This one.
This one is beautiful.
Look, what a big dahlia.
And a ladybird. Yes.
Bronek.
Marta.
Upstairs please.
Then come and see me.
Sophie.
Aniela, come.
Choose something you like.
Only one each.
Take something.
This one needs to be cleaned
and the lining has to be mended.
Be careful with it.
Of course.
Go back downstairs.
The bees are flying.
It is hot, isn't it?
How was your journey?
...
Long. But we're here now.
Yes indeed. So, not too bad?
No, not too bad.
Easier than last time actually.
Excellent. Well then, welcome back.
Absolutely. We're glad to be here.
Should we take our shoes off as well?
No.
Did you travel via Prague or Vienna?
Prague. It is 56 minutes faster.
She asked me where I got
one of my jackets from.
I said, "Canada."
And she asked, "How did you get to Canada?"
She thought you meant the country?
Yes, of course.
An understandable mistake.
The same thing happened when Helga Pattisch
came for the first time.
Out of all of the clothes, she chose a dress
that belonged to some little
Jewess half her size.
I could only pull the zipper up to here
and the dress came apart.
And ! pulled and pulled at it.
She just looked down at herself and said
"I love this dress."
In the end she took it.
And she said, "I'll go on a diet."
Would you like more coffee?
Yes please. Thank you.
You take it black?
Black is good, thank you.
Helga's husband only adopted
that little Polish bay to keep her at home
That's what she told me.
And he hits her as well.
I didn't know that.
How do you know that?
Haven't you noticed the bruises on her arms?
I forgot to tell you something.
Guess where I found this diamond?
In the toothpaste
No. Really?
How clever you must have to be.
Yes, they are very.
I've ordered more toothpaste
because you never know.
I think I told you above
the Schilling concert.
About Brigitte Frank's ermine fur coat.
Did I tell you about it?
I don't think so.
Look.
She looks like an empress.
The other side of it is the next chamber
with the next load ready to burn
once the pieces here
have been completely incinerated.
How long does it take?
7 hours, 400 to 500 at a time.
Closer to 500.
So, once that has happened,
you close this chimney,
then simultaneously open the next.
The fire will follow the air,
through this baffle of course,
into this chamber and then burn this load.
The chamber directly opposite
the combustion zone,
which burns at roughly 1,000 degrees,
has by now cooled to around 40 degrees.
Cool enough to unload the ash
and then reload the chamber.
So, this chamber is cooling
while this one is heating up?
Correct. The process moves one chamber over,
counterclockwise.
So, burn, cool, unload, reload.
And...
Continuously.
Cheers.
Dilla.
Happy birthday, Commandant.
Itis an honour to serve under you.
Thank you.
Happy birthday, Commandant.
That is a rifle.
And this is also a rifle.
And here is one with a pistol,
and another rifle here.
Do you hear that?
It's a bittern. A heron.
A Eurasian grey heron.
You cried like this too.
You were even louder.
What's going on with her?
She's strong, isn't she?
I'd like to try mine now.
What are you doing?
I'm looking.
At what?
Teeth.
What are you doing?
Nothing.
What are you doing here?
I'm handing out sugar.
Who to?
I'm looking.
Come.
Then, a little white bird flew past
to guide them out of the forest.
Soon they arrived at a huge lake.
They were puzzled as they
did not know how to cross it.
Suddenly, a big beautiful swan
came swimming towards them.
"Oh beautiful swan, please be our boat."
The swan bent its neck and came to the shore.
Bracht phoned the house.
Yes, while you were outside for your toast.
I forgot to tell you.
He said he'd call back tomorrow, midday.
Rudolf.
Will you take me to that spa in ltaly again?
All that pampering.
And the walks. And that nice couple we met.
Is she wandering around again?
No.
And that man
who played the accordion to the cows?
They loved it.
It was so funny.
All looking at him like this.
Will you?
What?
Well, take me back there.
When?
I don't know when.
You smell nice.
It's French.
Oink, oink.
Chocolate. If you see it. Any goodies.
To the head of the Party Chancellery
Reichsleiter Bormann.
Personal.
Dear Reichsleiter
I have learned that the commandant
of the gigantic K.L. Auschwitz
Obersturmbannführer Höss
also well known to you,
is to be transferred.
Comrade Höss has made
unprecedented achievements
over four years of painstaking work.
I witnessed the construction
of this great camp close up
so can attest.
Reichsführer Himmler himself acknowledges
the uniqueness of what he built.
Now it is said that the
task is too big for him
and that someone must take his place.
Höss knows prisoner use inside out
has close contacts with the
Silesian armaments industry
and has brought groundbreaking ideas
to the whole field of KL practice.
He is a model settler farmer
and an exemplary German pioneer of the East.
His particular strength is
turning theory into practice.
I will refrain from listing more qualities
which prove a change in his
command is not possible.
Therefore, could you please speak
to the Reichsführer as soon as possible
to prevent the transfer of Comrade Höss.
I would be very grateful for a brief reply.
Hell Hitler.
Gauleiter Fritz Bracht.
Can I do it now?
In a moment.
Did you know that storks
fly as far as Africa?
How far do you think they fly?
How many kilometers?
300?
More.
All these weeds here.
You are what you say.
Cows find this funny.
The whale farm is roaring,
because you are so boring.
Cows find this funny.
The whole farm is roaring,
because you are so boring.
No, you're boring.
All is well.
I hate you.
Keep your eyes closed, or it'll hurt.
I know.
Once more. All good. Come here.
We have 10 rinse your eyes.
Everything's fine. You'll live.
...with which 60,000 Italian spectators
showered their victorious national team.
We will be able to share in their delight.
How long it's been since Milan saw
their beloved Squadra Azzurra?
And now they have returned with a 4-0 victory
to the arena of their many triumphs.
Can you imagine the celebration?
4-0 against their old rivals Spain,
who are again aspiring to a position of power
in European football,
as we Germans saw with our own eyes
in Berlin last Sunday.
But don't let the result fool you.
4-0 was the final score.
But at half time
this thrilling Italian-Spanish encounter
stood at 0-0.
Hang up.
Fritz.
Go on.
What does it say?
Well.
No, you wrote a very powerful
letter on my behalf.
Their minds were obviously made up.
I'd better tell my wife.
She might.
The train stopped for ages at Krakow.
How frustrating.
And it was so hot.
A lady fainted next to me, it was that hot.
She's moving here with her husband,
who's an engineer. He's a lot older.
Yes.
They've both got jobs at a new factory.
Siemens.
Ah, yes. That's possible.
All the big companies are here, he said.
Yes, yes.
Don't you need to get on?
Yes. I'd better.
I'll show Mum to the girls' room.
Are you ready?
You'll have Heideraud’s bed
and she'll get in with Inge-Brigitt.
You don't mind, do you?
-
Of course not.
The house looks big, but it actually isn't.
The first thing we did
was install central heating.
It gets so cold in winter.
You wouldn't believe it.
Hand-painted.
Really?
Yes.
This is Heideraud's bed here.
This is lovely.
Truly.
Such a lovely room.
The top two drawers are for you.
Yes, that's more than enough.
Such beautiful flowers.
Yes, try it.
But I'm sleeping here?
Yes, but they're both...
...the same.
My girl.
That's spinach strudel, apple strudel,
potato salad.
And your cinnamon rolls.
My recipe?
Very nice.
My god.
Subject:
Lilac bushes by the commandants
guard barracks.
From now on, SS members who pick lilacs
in a thoughtless and blatant manner
so that the bushes bleed
will be punished.
I expect the SS members,
if they wish to take some,
to do it in a way
that does not damage the bushes.
In the interest of our whole community,
I hope you understand
that the lilac bushes
are intended to decorate our entire camp
both now and in the future.
Jews in the house?
The Jews are over the other side of the wall.
They're local girls.
Say hello to grandma.
Hello.
My God.
He's got so big, and you have such nice hair.
I think it's your turn to push, isn't it Hans?
Inge pushed you before
and now it's your turn. Go on.
Let's go.
This is all us.
There's a grape vine.
Obviously, it'll grow.
it's huge.
I'm speechless.
It's all my design.
All the planting and everything.
The greenhouse, the gazebo at the end.
Is that a pool?
Yes.
I have gardeners. I couldn't do it alone.
With a slide?
Oh Heddy.
Do you like it?
Of course I like it. How could I not?
This was a field three years ago.
No.
We just had the lower garden by the street.
And the house had a flat roof.
It's hard to believe.
And that's the camp wall?
Yes, that's the camp wall.
We planted more vines at the back
to grow and cover it.
Maybe Esther Silberman is over there.
Which one was she?
The one I used to clean for.
She was the one who had the book readings.
God knows what they were up to.
Bolshevik stuff.
Jewish stuff.
And I got outbid on her curtains
at the street auction.
Her opposite, she got them.
I loved those curtains.
These flowers are so beautiful.
The azaleas there.
There are also vegetables.
A few herbs. Rosemary.
Beetroot. This is fennel.
Sunflowers.
And here is kohlrabi. The
children love to eat it.
Cabbage. Kale. Runner beans.
Pumpkins.
Potatoes and more.
We have bees over here to provide our honey.
It's a paradise garden.
And Rudolf is okay?
Yes, he's fine.
Working non-stop, even when he's home.
Which he loves.
He's a busy bee.
He is. Non-stop.
And under pressure like you wouldn't believe.
And you're okay?
Do I look okay?
Rudi calls me the Queen of Auschwitz.
Honestly.
To have all this.
You really have landed on your feet, my child.
The linden trees are turning yellow.
It smelled so nice when they were flowering.
This will grow and cover everything.
You'll see next time you visit.
No.
Stop it.
The heartfelt time we spent in the Hoss house
will always be
among our most beautiful holiday memories.
In the East lies our tomorrow.
Thanks for your National Socialist hospitality.
And this was from... Willy... Billy...
Hans says you have his sandals.
We have to leave, Mutzi.
Leave where?
Here. We have to go. We're being transferred.
Sorry, what?
We're being transferred.
To where?
Oranienburg.
What?
They're swapping me for Arthur Liebehenschel.
He comes here.
I take over as Deputy Inspector.
If you've known this for a
while, why tell me now?
There was no good moment to say it.
You've said it now.
Where are you going?
To get the sandals.
When did you find out?
Pohl told me last week.
I tried to make it go away.
Then call, Bormann.
I've tried Bormann.
Should I go to Hitler now?
Well, yes.
Rudolf.
Don't turn your back on me.
Stop.
Calm down. Go back to the party.
You can't do this to me.
What is this? Marta.
Mrs Höss?
What's this, "Mrs Höss? Mrs Höss?"
I'll show you Mrs Höss.
Mop it up.
Don't forget you live well in our house.
Bloody hell.
Now.
Why are they transferring you?
Structural changes.
What does that mean?
They weren't specific.
But I'm not the only one being moved.
There are lots of us.
When?
Soon.
How soon?
I'm waiting to be told.
If it's about the investigation
they should call Himmler.
if it's about the investigation
they should call Himmier.
He encouraged us.
No.
So it's not that?
It's a political matter.
Then go to Hitler.
Don't be ridiculous.
It's not ridiculous.
You're the one who carries out his orders
once you peel away the layers.
We have to face facts. We have to leave.
No.
You have to leave.
Yes.
Your work is in Oranienburg now.
Mine is raising our children,
and I'll do that from here.
I never thought that you wouldn't be with me.
Never crossed my mind.
They'd have to drag me out of here.
You know that.
This is our home.
We're living how we dreamed we would.
Since we were 17. Beyond how we dreamed.
Out of the city finally.
Everything we want. On our doorstep.
And our children are strong,
healthy and happy.
Everything the Fuhrer said
about how to live is how we do.
Go East. Living space.
This is our living space.
I know you agree with me.
Arthur can find somewhere else to live.
He doesn't need to take our home.
You should make it a condition.
It's the least they can do.
He'll want a townhouse, anyway.
Rudolf?
I heard you.
So?
I'll ask.
You'll be working all the time.
Yes.
We'd never see you.
No.
I'll miss you, of course.
But you'll come home when you can.
I‘ll be...
with you. Just like you'll be with me.
Yes?
And after the war
when everything is over, we'll farm.
Like we said.
Do you all understand?
Yes.
So, I'll be missing your birthday.
And maybe even our anniversary.
Depending on how long I'll be gone.
So, those are some of the things
that definitely add to the struggle.
But the life we enjoy
is very much worth the sacrifice.
It's time for bed.
Hans, your plate.
Be calm.
It'll be hard for you too.
I know that.
Don't you think I know that?
I love you.
I love you, my beauty.
Call Walter Dürrfeld first thing and
see if he can join us at selection.
Tell him they're Dutch
and he can have his pick.
Otherwise, I'll see him at the IG lunch.
Letter to Messrs. Prifer and Sander,
Topf and Sons.
Subject: New Crematorium.
I'm glad you were able to
make the journey last week.
SS-Obersturmbannführer
Bischoff and I both agree
the ring crematorium is
definitely the answer.
What a difference it will make.
Bravo.
I welcome your...
I welcome your suggestion
that the design should be patented
in order to secure priority.
I will follow up with a letter of intent.
You should be aware,
I've been promoted to Deputy Inspector
of concentration camps at the IKL.
Come.
And therefore, future communications
will be from Oranienburg-Berlin.
The focus there is now on labour.
Of course, this direction will affect our plans
and though it pains me to leave Auschwitz
I believe I'll be in a better position
to push for funds and materials
from there.
Heil Hitler. Et cetera.
Letter to Gruppenführer Glücks, IKL.
Subject: Transfer.
Dear Gruppenführer Glücks,
I would like my family to remain
at 88 Bielitzstrasse, KL Auschwitz
for the duration of my transfer.
It would be a great favour to me
for this to be permitted.
I must stress what a wonderful environment
Hedwig is making for the
children since settling here.
An inspiration in many ways
for our new German community in the East.
If this is acceptable,
provision of a simple lodging for myself
in Oranienburg will suffice.
I would be very grateful for a speedy answer.
Heil Hitler, et cetera.
Sweaty.
The little snow white bird flew down and sang,
"Be warned, be warned."
Gretel understood what the witch had in mind
and said, "Please show me first,
I don't know how to do that."
The witch sat on the shovel
and Gretel pushed her into the oven,
as deep as she could.
Then she closed the iron door of the oven.
And secured it with a bar.
The witch got cooked alive
as a punishment for her horrible deeds.
Gretel ran straight to Hansel,
unlocked the goose cage and let him out.
He jumped out
and threw his arms around his sister's neck.
They kissed one another,
cried with joy, and thanked God.
The little white bird sang,
"Pearls and gems for bread crumbs.”
(Polish)
Here you are at last.
(Yiddish)
Words by Joseph Wulf.
Written in 1943
(Yiddish)
in Oswiecim, Auschwitz Ill.
Sunbeams
radiant and warm
Human bodies
Young and old
And we
who are imprisoned here
Our hearts
are not yet cold
Souls afire
the blazing sun
Tearing, breaking
through their pain
For soon we'll see
that wawing flag
The flag of freedom
yet to come
Don't forget to stand straight.
I've packed butter bread for you all.
Come on children. Hurry.
Sophie.
Tell her it's getting cold.
She's not here.
What?
She's gone.
What, not upstairs?
No, she's gone.
And her case has gone.
That cannot be.
Mum?
Go and look for her.
Aniela.
Take it away.
Was that here to spite me?
No, Mrs. Höss.
I could have my husband spread your ashes
across the fields of Babice.
Relax, let her find it.
Are you not going to be a commandant anymore?
I'll be head of all commandants.
Inspecting their camps, seeing
where improvements can be made.
Their yield, that kind of thing.
It has a great name.
It's girl's eye, or tickseed.
Girl's eye?
Girl's eye, yes.
I can only guess
that's because of its serrated petals,
because they resemble the long eyelashes
of women and girls.
You there.
Guard.
Bring him here.
What's he done?
Fighting over an apple, Commandant.
Drown him in the river.
Come.
Don't do that again.
Move it.
I don't care.
Get it out.
Are you going to stand there trembling?
Something to say?
Come.
Aren't you lovely?
Yes, you are lovely.
Male or female?
Male.
How old?
4 years old.
What's his name?
Torin.
You don't see many with his colouring...
No, mostly black or salt and pepper.
I had a black one when I was little. Elsa.
Born on the same day I was.
He's lovely.
Thank you.
Come on.
On Sunday at 19h there
will be a benefit concert
at the Marksmen’s Club to raise
money for War Winter Relief.
Junior Squad Leader Johann Thissen
will conduct the orchestra in
a two part programme
featuring a tribute to Herms Niel...
Liebehenschel, Auschwitz I.
Hartjenstein, Auschwitz Il / Birkenau.
Schwarz, Auschwitz III / Monowitz.
Haas, Bergen-Belsen.
Pister, Buchenwald.
Walter, Dachau.
Koegel, Flossenblirg.
Hassebroek, Gross-Rosen.
Grünewald, Herzogenbusch.
Sporrenberg, Hinzert.
Goecke, Kauen.
Weiss, Majdanek.
Ziereis Mauthausen.
Dieter, Moringen.
Hartjenstein, Natzweller-Struthof.
Pauly, Neuengamme.
Goth, Plaszow.
Suhren, Ravensbrick.
Kaindl, Sachsenhausen.
Hoppe, Stutthof.
Schnabel, Vaivara.
Herbert, Warsaw.
Apologies for absence,
Foérschner, Mittelbau-Dora.
Sauer, Riga-Kaiserwald.
The Führer has approved the deportation
of Hungary's 700,000 Jews for extermination
and war production where able-bodied.
An agreement was reached
with the new Hungarian government
to begin the operation immediately.
They are being amassed
for transportation to Auschwitz.
4 trains a day, 3,000 on each.
12,000 daily.
Firstly via the Eastern zones, 1 to 3.
Then via 4 and 5
in the middle of the country,
and finally, Budapest.
Pressburg and Vienna are heavily loaded
with military transports.
Jewish transports will pass through
Kassa and Muszyna instead.
Based on estimates provided
by Obersturmbannfiihrer Hiss,
25% will be retained for
labour after selection.
20% of those will be utilized
in Auschwitz sub-camps,
and the other 80%
will come to your camps in due course.
The scale is many times larger than before.
So prepare yourselves.
Before I hand over to
Obersturmbannfiihrer Höss,
I'd like to announce
the promotion of Colonel Maurer
to the rank of SS-Standartenfiihrer
for consistently hitting his labour targets.
Bravo.
I get fan mail from CEOs for this man.
More famous than me.
Thank you, sir.
Well deserved.
As I've said before,
I'm grateful for your leadership.
Thank you. You have said that.
I appreciate that.
Thank you, Obergruppenführer Pohl.
Good morning, everyone.
Good morning.
Two apologies for absence.
Sturmbannführer Férschner, Mittelbau-Dora.
Sturmbannführer Sauer, Riga-Kaiserwald.
You will appreciate
we have a very busy agenda today.
The Hungarian operation is urgent,
and complex,
and will involve converging challenges
at every operational level.
Please turn to the first page in your files.
You will see five headings.
Item one.
Timings.
Item two.
Re-direction of construction resources.
Item three.
Transportation.
For item four, prisoner workers.
Dr. Meindi from Steyr-Daimler-Puch,
some of you know him, some of you don't,
is joining us today
to discuss pay rates and incentives.
Item five.
and air defence measures.
The girls didn't want to go out.
Yes.
Because it is so cold.
Well, I love the snow.
Stop.
Leave me alone, Claus.
Stop it, Claus.
No.
Leave me alone, you traitor.
Saturday's funeral ceremony for the pupils
of the Air Force School
who died in the bombing raid
of March 6th will start at 11:30.
SS pall bearers should congregate
in the forecourt of the T Building by 10:45.
Transport will leave for Hans Schemm School
promptly at 11am.
Commander of the Guard
Obersturmbannführer Gustav Wegner
will lead the cortege to the cemetery
with a delegation from the
League of German Girls
and Air Force Students.
Obersturmbannfiihrer Höss.
Rudolf. Come on in.
How are you?
Good.
I've just received this.
Obergruppenführer Poht met with
Reichsführer Himmler
to assess the numbers involved
and your name came up.
We're moving Liebehenschel to Majdanek.
He's not energetic enough for this.
Okay.
You'll receive operational
orders from Eichmann.
Perfect.
Tell me what resources you
need when you get there.
I will.
Any problems, come to me or Gerhard directly.
Thank you.
How's Hedwig?
Good.
Pohl told me she sends the boss
flowers from your garden every week.
Yes.
Get the job done.
I will. Thank you.
I appreciate the trust and confidence
you have in me.
And?
I'm not sure yet.
Relax.
He won't put them all up the chimney.
You'll get your workers.
You'll see.
Are you sleeping, okay?
Yes.
How many bowel movements
do you have per day?
Twice per day.
Urinating?
Without issues.
I'll feel around now. On the surface, first.
If there is any pain, then please let me know.
This is Höss.
Long-distance priority call,
KL Auschwitz, Höss private residence.
I'll stay on the line.
Are you there?
Hello?
Can you talk?
Is everything okay?
Yes.
I have news.
I told you I'd heard rumblings
but nothing concrete.
What news?
The Hungary thing.
The old man gave me orders from Heinrich.
It's happening at last.
I'm coming back to run it.
Well, I'm very relieved about that.
I have to admit, I'm pleased as Punch.
Yes.
I don't know, I go to Budapest first.
Things will be clearer after that.
Anyway, my cogs are turning.
I must get on.
I'll call you re party.
No. Wait, please
Tell Eleanor Pohl,
when she receives her parcel,
to look in the compact.
They're inside.
I heard Himmler's calling it Operation Höss.
That's fantastic. I'm so happy for you.
Thank you, Mutzi.
It's your name too.
Who was there?
To tell you the truth
I wasn't really paying attention.
I was too busy thinking
how I'd gas everyone in the room.
Very difficult, logistically,
because of its high ceiling.
It's the middle of the night
and I need to be in bed.
I shouldn't have called so late.
I was just excited to tell you the name.
You can tell me about it when you get back.
You have told them Daddy's coming home?
Yes.
Goodnight.