Captain Tower?
Sorry. You may go. Vamos.
Dejénlo pasar. Dejénlo pasar!
- Where do you live, Tery?
- Why?
So l can take you home.
It's only 30 minutes until curfew.
Just drop us at the Hotel Carrera.
Thanks for the ride.
Listen, if you need anything, call me.
Here's my business card.
My home number's on the back.
OK.
- Thanks again.
- OK.
lt's nearly curfew. They shoot everyone.
The phones don't work here.
Let's get a cab.
Why didn't you let him drive us home?
l didn't want him to know where l lived!
- We'll take a taxi.
- No, ya no, es muy tarde.
Vicuña Mackenna. ;Sí, por favor!
- Blew it.
- You did not.
Look, l have a credit card.
We can stay here.
lt's curfew. Come on, we better go in.
# ..your ding-a-ling
# My ding-a-ling, my ding-a-ling,
# l want you to play with my ding-a-ling
# Oh, your ding-a-ling
your ding-a-ling
# We saw you playing with your...
# Ding-a-ling
# Oh, my ding-a-ling
# Everybody sing
l want to play with my ding
# Everybody, my, oh, my... #
# All or nothing at all... #
You all right?
Never better.
Be positive, OK?
l just keep thinking about
what Patrick said about...
bodies everywhere.
Beth's all right. Nothing can happen to her.
l hope so.
She's probably hiding
in the bath with the duck.
Laugh. It's the best thing l've said all day.
l just wish it was morning.
Er, does the light bother you?
No. No, not at all.
Charlie, you think it's smart
to keep all those notes?
Es aquí.
- Beth?
- She's probably asleep, Charlie.
- Shh, shh, shh.
Beth, it's me.
Oh, shit. You're alive.
Yep.
- Where have you been?
- In Viña.
- You were supposed to be there one day.
- We couldn't get back.
Why didn't you call me?
l've been going nuts.
- There was nothing l could do.
- l thought something terrible had happened.
We got trapped. They cut the roads down
and shut off the telephone wires.
- Come here.
- l love you.
Come here. l missed you.
l didn't know if you were alive.
Everybody's safe.
- Where's Tery?
- There.
- You shit!
- Who?
- You. l was worried about you.
- You were worried?
Cut it out. Wait. Hold it.
You creep! Living out at the beach,
and l'm stuck here with the duck.
This is from Charlie.
l heard it on the radio but there were
bombs going off down the street.
Really?
- Were you scared?
- Yeah, l hid under the bed.
Want some help?
Get-a your tootsie-fruitsie.
Para ti, para mí.
Why a duck? Why no goose?
Hey, hope you guys aren't verry hungy.
- We're starved.
- Hm!
Seriously, is there anything to eat
besides a couple cockroaches?
No. l'm sorry.
l was scared to go out shopping.
Hey, Beth, l got this of Charlie at Viña.
Hey, Beth. How about a little
Long Island ducky?
Stuffed with a little Peruvian tuna fish,
Spanish olives?
lt's OK. l was kidding.
Hey - l was just kidding. OK...
- Old jokes.
- l know.
- l've listened to them for five days.
- Ty five years.
- Señora Núñez...
- Here. l know you can't get these here.
You're looking for Beth Horman?
She's in the bedroom.
Go on. Pase, pase.
''Si, gracias, señor.''
Oh, careful, señora.
''Gracias, señor. Señora...?''
Old jokes.
l want to go home, Charlie. Now.
- Come on, Beth.
- We have to.
l can't stand this place any more.
- OK, we'll go.
- l hate this house.
OK, we're going, we're going.
Let's go with Tery, today.
We can't just leave without my stuff.
We gotta settle things up...
- Just leave it.
- We can't.
We're going. l promise you.
You don't know what it's like
being here without you.
Have you heard from David or Frank?
No.
- l hope they're OK.
- Me too.
- l better go check on 'em.
- Let me go.
You take Tery to the airport.
l gotta get outta here.
- OK.
- You guys want me to take a walk?
- Later.
- Not too much later.
Patrick said there were
search-and-destroy missions.
- Patrick?
- A colonel in Viña.
We saw some verry upsetting things in Viña.
- You gonna let me read it, or tell it to me?
- Whichever you prefer.
End of the line.
- What time you coming home?
- Four o'clock.
l'll be waiting for you. You better watch out.
- l won't be late.
- You better not be.
l'm warning you.
- ;Vía Magna, Plaza Italia!
- That's me.
- You sure you wanna go?
- Yeah.
- Love you.
- Un momentito, por favor.
l'll see you in New York.
Oh, call our parents and tell them
we'll be back in a couple of days.
Say goodbye to David and Frank for me.
A partir de hoy, las mujeres
en este país no usan más pantalones.
What did he say?
He said, ''From now on,
women in this county wear dresses.''
My God, look at this.
A week ago,
this was the quietest place on Earth.
- Come on.
- It was a lot cooler than that.
l think Braniffs over there. Wait a second.
- No quedan más, se acabó.
- Shit.
Al primero que se mueva, métele un balazo.
Se queda en el suelo hasta que yo diga.
l'm with her. Vengo con la señorita.
Adónde vas con eso?
He wants to know where you're going.
l-l'm an American. l was going to New York.
l was going to get my ticket.
Es norteamericana y va a New York.
The airport is closed,
and there is no more planes.
You may go.
Don't look.
Excuse me.
Could we speak to Mrs Tyler, please?
There's nobody here by that name.
Could we speak to whoever's helping
Americans leave the county?
That's not our job.
Talk to somebody at the consulate.
We were told that the consulate
was closed because of gunfire
and that the consul was working here.
Yeah? Well, that's news to me.
Could you call for us and maybe find out?
Lady, if you wanna see
if the consulate is open, then go there.
lt's lunch time. Everybody's gone,
and the phones are dead.
Well, thank you verry much.
Excuse me. l'm Kate Newman,
a freelance reporter out of New York.
No comment.
Just a friendly misunderstanding.
lf you don't mind, if l were you,
l'd come back after lunch.
Demand to see the ambassador.
Don't go to the consulate -
it's a mile away and the streets are murder.
- Thanks. Wait. Miss Newman?
- Yes?
- Would you do me a big favour?
- Sure.
- Can l borrow your paper?
- Certainly.
l don't understand. There's nothing here.
They told us in Viña that the militay were
executing thousands of people here.
- There's nothing.
- When were you in Viña?
We just got back yesterday.
Wanna hear something strange?
Our hotel was full of
American militay officers.
l'd forget about that.
- ;Suélteme, estúpido!
- ;Déjenme ir con él!
- Hey! Hey, wait a minute!
- Do not meddle!
- Jesus!
Déjalos, son americanos.
- Are you OK?
- l'm all right.
- Why did you do that?
- l don't know.
l just...
- Listen, both of you.
Forget this and forget Viña.
Find yourselves a safe place.
A hotel with lots of people around.
Just hole up there
until you can get out of here.
Hey. Hey!
All right? You'll stay here? Gracias.
You'll get a room for Beth and me too?
We'll be back as soon as we can.
- All right?
- Yeah. Got enough money?
- l think so. How about you?
- l got my credit card.
Here. Take it. You never know.
Thanks, pal. Charlie...
- Be careful.
- Don't worry. They can't hurt us.
We're Americans.
l think l felt him kick.
Come on, Maria. You gotta have faith.
Carlos will be OK.
Tienes que ser fuerte. Piensa en el niño.
- She's right.
- Sé que lo van a matar.
No, Maria! He's probably
up in the mountains hiding.
l know they are going to kill him.
They're killing everybody.
- You should go.
- l got a few more minutes.
No, you must go. l will take care of her.
You'll be OK?
Let me know if you get any news.
Take care.
- OK, Frank?
- Yeah.
- How's she doing?
- She's OK. Pia's with her.
Frank, what did happen to Carlos?
What's happening to everrybody?
Maybe he's at an embassy
as a refugee or something.
- Or somebody blew his brains out.
- David.
- What about Silvio?
- He's OK. He's in hiding but, er...
- But Cleo really disappeared.
- Oh, shit.
This place is a free-fire zone.
They shoot you just for being left-handed.
l hope you aren't planning
to stay around too long.
- Party's over.
- They were tying to do something new.
l'm sorry, l've gotta go.
Charlie's gonna kill me.
Promise to call when you get to New York?
Use the phone booth at the corner
of West Broadway.
Frank, l'm sorry things worked out for you
the way they did.
Soon we'll be playing chess
in Washington Square.
- Checkers.
- Checkers. l hope so.
- Where you gonna be?
- His folks' house, Upper East Side.
- Chic!
- That's us. Take care.
lt's my... Oh, my bus!
Taxi!
- Adónde va?
- Vicuña Mackenna por favor.
molf whistle)
Oye, ven con nosotros.
'Atención, atención.
Es la hora del toque de queda.
'Atención. Atención.'
- 'Atención, es la hora del toque de queda.
'Despejad la calle enseguida.
'Vuelvan todos a sus casas.
Despejad la calle.
'Atención, el toque de...'
;Vete a tu casa!
Qué quieres?
Soy americana. El toque de queda,
por favor, necesito ayuda.
Get out. No foreigners here.
- Help me.
- Get out.
Get out!
;Alto, alto!
;Escóndase, escóndase!
Yoo-hoo, Charlie!
Char...
Charlie?
Charlie...
Excuse me, señora.
My husband? Did you see my husband?
Gracias.
You've been in touch
with our embassy there?
Several times, sir.
l spoke to a Mr Shipler.
And?
Senator, all they seem to know
is that my son is missing.
Hm. Have you been
to the State Department?
l have tried, sir, many different people.
You are the first that would see me.
Well, l urge you to get to them, Mr Horman.
l'm tying, sir.
How does your son make a living?
Well, frankly, l...
l guess he's a writer.
Well, he says that he wants to...
The important thing right now is to help him.
Yes, sir.
Here in the State Department, sir,
we've investigated and have been unable
to find any trace of your son.
Neither our embassy nor the militay
government knows where he is.
The New York Times says he was arrested.
That's what your daughter-in-law
told the press.
She...
She's been pestering
those embassy people, so they told me.
Tery Simon is a friend. She was there
on vacation, caught in the coup.
She confirmed everrything Beth told me.
The arrested Americans have all been
released thanks to our embassy's efforts.
The last two, Teruggi and Holloway...
They're friends of your son's.
..were released, and Teruggi left
without even thanking the embassy.
Mr Horman, this is gonna take a little time.
l suggest you go back up to New York
and relax and let us handle it.
l met him in New York
at the Third Church of Christ Scientist.
- Doubt he'd remember.
- You're a Christian Scientist too?
And your son?
- You know how young people are.
- Of course.
Mr Horman, would you mind
waiting here a moment?
No, not at all.
- Mr Horman?
- Yes.
- l think we've met before.
- Yes, Congressman.
New York? This is my assistant, Ann.
- How do you do?
- You know Bob.
Do you mind if we talk while walking?
No. Not at all, sir.
- What did they say?
- They think he's in hiding.
- Why?
- Political reasons.
They think he'll surface
when things calm down.
- What are his politics?
- Liberal, l suppose.
Liberal, or radical?
Congressman, my son
is much too wishy-washy to be a radical.
- Are you sure?
- What difference does it make?
Well, it doesn't but you said
that Percy and Abzug are sending cables?
They promised to,
but so did Kemp and Koch
and Magnuson and Javits and you.
Well, l'm certainly gonna consider it.
Good luck. God bless.
Nice meeting you, Mr Horman.
Mr Horman.
What's that? That.
This?
Those are my books.
One of those is a Bible.
l'm a Christian Scientist.
Pasaporte.
Mr Horman? l'm Phil Putnam.
l'm the US Consul down here.
- Thank heaven.
- Sorry about the confusion.
That's all right. Is there any more news?
Nothing so far, but l think
we're on top of the situation.
Washington cabled us you were coming.
;Déjenme, yo tengo
mi salvoconducto, déjenme!
We're over here in the Ford.
- You'd think there was a war on.
- There is, sort of.
- l thought the coup was over.
- It is, but there are still problems.
The ambassador can see you at 3:30
if that's OK.
- The sooner the better.
- Good.
- Cheerful little county you picked to live in.
Yeah, well...
How long have you been here?
Three years, four months and 19 days.
Counting the days.
lt's not a bad county, really.
l'm just ready for a change.
Where will you go next?
My dream is to be posted to Brazil.
But l'll go wherever they send me.
Al hotel Cabrera.
Ed. Ed.
l'm sorry l didn't meet you.
l've been tying to meet this Major Pieto...
Mrs Horman? Hi. How are ya? You all right?
All right.
Good, good. Listen, we'll be back
to pick you folks up at 2:30.
Yes, 2:30. That's fine.
l've been tying to meet this Major Pieto.
This morning was the only time
that l could meet him.
And the bathroom, sir.
Thank you verry much.
- How was your trip?
- A total delight.
How's Elizabeth?
How do you suppose?
You blame me?
Did you find out anything in Washington?
No, but...
Putnam thinks that things down here
are in good hands.
- You don't agree?
Well, l don't expect
a whole hell of a lot any more.
No?
Why?
He's been gone two weeks.
l don't know. They give me the same
song and dance over and over again.
He could be hurt or...
tortured.
They don't give a goddamn about him.
l don't want to hear
any of your anti-Establishment paranoia!
l certainly get enough of that from my son.
lf he had settled down where he belongs,
this never would have happened.
Please don't cy.
Beth, l'll find him.
Charles wrote that these toilet articles
were hard to get.
Not any more.
His mother sent him fudge.
Why don't you go freshen up?
We only have one hour.
Oh, by the way, where's Tery?
At Braniff, picking up her ticket.
- When does she go?
- Tomorrow.
ls she all right?
Yeah, Ed. So am l.
- Come in.
Ta-daa.
Beth, l have to ask you a question.
l want you to answer me
absolutely honestly.
- OK.
- What did he do?
- What?
- What stupid thing did Charles do
to cause his arrest,
or make him go into hiding?
- Ed, Charlie is not a stupid man.
- He wasn't too smart!
l can tell you, getting in such a mess
that l have to fly 16 hours in order to...
Sometimes l honestly think that that boy
is incapable of doing anything,
except give idealistic speeches
and write novels that'll never be published.
Unless the disappearing act is a stunt
- to publicise his autobiography.
- Why don't you just go home?
l'll find my husband by myself.
- l'll be ready in a few minutes.
- Take your time.
l still want an answer to that question.
- Mr Ambassador, Mr Horman.
- Come right in, sir.
- My pleasure.
- Mine too.
Captain Tower, US Navy,
our senior militay group officer.
Colonel Clay, our defence attaché.
- Mr Horman.
- Thank you.
Mrs Horman, how are you today?
Fine.
- Shall l review?
- Yes. But first...
l want to express our deep concern
over your son's disappearance.
- Thank you.
- l assure you
everry element at our disposal
has been and will continue to be utilised
to facilitate his safe return.
That's exactly what l'd hoped to hear,
Mr Ambassador.
Go ahead, Consul Putnam.
Sir, we've conducted
an extensive investigation.
Captain Tower's staff
have interviewed residents
in the area where Charles was last seen.
Colonel Clay has maintained his contacts
with militay and police authorities.
But after analysing all the data,
we still come to the conclusion
- that he must be in hiding.
- From what?
That's a valid question,
and one we'd like the answer to.
We've been through this a hundred times.
He's not hiding. Our whole neighbourhood
saw him picked up by a goon squad.
The militay swears they haven't got him.
l've been to the carabinero stations,
to the department of investigations,
l even got into the national stadium,
and he's just not in their custody.
So the hiding theoy seems to be
the most viable, at least for the present.
That's dumb. If he were in hiding,
he'd let me know he was all right.
Maybe he can't. There have been
a lot of civilian accidents and injuries.
No shit, Sherlock.
Were you going to say something,
Mr Horman?
Er, yes. Er...
As the colonel suggested,
if Charles was possibly injured,
he could be in a coma,
or suffering from amnesia...
Have you checked the hospitals?
- Some.
- Not all?
lt's pretty difficult to get into some hospitals
right now, and...
Translated, he means you can break a leg
tripping over bodies.
The only thing that we know
for sure right now
is where he isn't.
l may have some further news for you
after tonight.
l'm having dinner with the junta's
chief of staff, Admiral Huidobro.
God. That one again?
Haven't you seen him yet?
These people are verry busy.
l bet they are.
By the way, Beth, do you have that list?
What list?
l asked her for a list of Charles' friends
so l could extend this investigation.
l'll see that you get it.
You said several of Charles' friends
were contacted by the militay
- after he was supposedly arrested.
- They all called the consulate.
- What calls?
- l wasn't aware of any.
You certainly were.
l saw all the notes on the calls the day
Shipler showed me your file cards.
l forgot that, sir. You're right.
Yes, l think l do remember.
Why don't you check that out sometime
in the next couple of days?
We'll meet again
to take stock of the situation.
lf you need anything...
Dave? Driver, please.
lf you need anything, let me or Captain
Tower know, and we'll arrange it.
- l'll see that he gets that list.
- Not from me, he won't.
l'll check the phone logs
and start working on the hospitals.
- Thank you, Consul.
- Call me Phil.
- Mrs Horman.
- Thank you again.
What is the matter?
Why were you so rude?
- Jesus Christ!
- And do you swear all the time?
l'm sorry. l don't mean to offend you.
Why aren't you cooperating with them?
- l am cooperating.
- Oh...
l've been cooperating for two weeks, Ed!
l'm sick and tired of getting fucked around
by these people, that's why!
- To the hotel, sir?
- Yes.
- Want some?
- Uh-uh.
Back.
One more step.
lt's an old joke.
- We better go. Last bus is at six.
- Right.
;Vámonos!
- Catch!
- Right. l'll race ya.
- Oh, no. No, you won't!
- l'll beat ya!
Hay huelga de camioneros
y están bloqueados todos los caminos.
- Sí, gracias. Fucking great.
- What?
The truckers are on strike,
roads are all blocked.
- How do we get back?
- We don't.
Beth is gonna go nuts.
lsn't there another way? Any trains?
Mañana, a las 9.
- What'd he say?
- He said, with luck,
there might be a train tomorrow at nine.
So what do we do till then?
- What is it?
- l don't know.
'That's the morning the coup started?'
The 24-hour curfew
had shut everrything down.
The phones were out. Charlie freaked
because he couldn't reach Beth.
Did you pick that up from Charlie?
Charles picked it up from me.
What happened next?
Well, we stayed at the hotel.
We didn't have much choice.
That's when you met all the Americans?
And they were caught up
by the coup also?
- The others.
- Then you met Babcock?
No. Him we met the next morning.
Wednesday, September 12.
- Here?
- Yeah, sure.
Me permite su periódico, señor.
You would do better to ask in English,
monsieur.
- Tu es français? Pardon.
- English.
l come from Paris, Texas, boy.
- You're American.
- Red, white and blue.
- Well, you fooled me.
- Good, good.
l was just pulling your leg there...
Charlie Horman.
Nice to meet you.
This is my friend, Tery Simon.
- How are you?
- All right.
Yes, you are.
Erm... That's my friend.
- Hello.
- Do you mind?
- No, help yourself.
- What'd you say your name was?
- l didn't.
- My name's Andrew Babcock.
- Nice to meet you.
- Thanks a lot. Are you a tourist?
- No, not exactly.
What are you doing down here?
The navy sent me down here to do a job
and, er...she's done.
Where are you stationed?
Panama's my home base,
if that's what you mean.
You said you're with the navy.
l'm retired. l'm on a special assignment.
Really? What's it like in Panama?
- Panama's nice.
- Is it?
And it's a good place
to keep an eye on everrything.
There's my man from Milgroup.
- What's Milgroup?
- Just a US militay group.
There isn't
much news in there
for someone with such big ears
and such a long nose.
- But enjoy it.
- l will.
- Enjoy.
- Thanks.
Sure enough.
'Charlie said, ''That's incredible.'''
l can't believe he told us all that.
That's when he decided
we should take notes.
- Notes on what?
- Didn't you hear what she said?
Ed, all those American officials
in Viña were probably involved in the coup.
- Do you believe that, Tery?
- Why don't you believe me?
You married Charles.
It colours your perceptions.
- You're his damn father. What about yours?
- Come on.
God! Whose side are you on?
- How did you finally...
How did you finally get home?
'Ray Tower drove us back.
Erm...
That's all right. Listen...
if you need anything, call me.
Here's my business card.
My home number's on the back.
OK.
Guess who's having dinner again tonight?
- Admiral Huidobro?
- Uh-huh.
You gotta be kidding me. Again?
- Again. Can you believe that guy?
- Did he ask for the list? Of course.
ls this Tower?
How do you know him so well?
We don't know him so well.
When Charlie disappeared,
that's who we contacted.
- He invited us for dinner.
- He said Admiral...
- Huidobro.
..Huidobro would be there and we could talk.
- But this admiral never showed up.
Ed, it happened just like this!
You went to Tower's house
to see that admiral, and...
This admiral never showed up.
lt was past curfew, Tower insisted
we spend the night and we had to.
- Tery?
- What do you want?
- Got everrything you need?
Yes.
l appreciate everrything you've done
but would you do me a favour
and get out of here? Please?
You know, if l were you...
l'd quit living in the past.
l think it's about time
you started thinking about your future.
You gotta learn to stay ahead
of the power curve, kid.
- You know what l mean?
- Leave me alone!
- Tery, it's me.
- It's an old aircraft carrier term.
Come on. Hury up.
lf a pilot gets ahead of the power curve
and something happens,
- then he can pull up and away.
- Hury up!
But if he falls behind the power curve
and something happens,
then it's adios. You gotta stay ahead
of the power curve, kid.
And when we woke up
the next morning, Tower was gone.
- When does your plane leave?
- Nine.
Would you take a letter for Elizabeth?
- l'll see you in the morning.
- Good night.
- Night, Ed.
- Want some fudge?
Why did you take a bath in his house?
Ed, l took a bath.
We were stuck there.
Ed?
Ed.
Wait a minute. Where are you going?
Can't you lower your voice? For a walk.
You can't go out for a walk.
It's curfew. You'll get shot.
Did she have an affair with Charles?
Why did you come here?
'Había 4 soldados con un oficial
y dos más trayendo unas cajas.'
'She says it was late afternoon.
'There were four soldiers and an officer,
and two soldiers carried boxes of things.'
Había otros soldados?
Sí, había muchos,
esperando en un camión militar.
There were many other soldiers
waiting in an army truck.
'Qué estás diciendo, mujer?
No fue así, te equivocas.
'Yo no oí más que unos pocos milicos
y era un auto particular.'
'What did he say?'
'lt was a civilian truck,
'and there weren't many soldiers.
No, estoy segura, había muchos soldados
en un camión del ejército, yo los vi.'
'She says there were many soldiers,
and it was definitely an army truck.'
ls she sure it was Charles?
Seguro que el muchacho fue mi marido?
- Estoy segura que sí.
- Huh?
- She's pretty sure.
- She's pretty sure?
With witnesses like this, no wonder
nobody can find him. Buenos... Gracias.
- Gracias.
- Hasta luego.
- Is this the way you found it?
- No. It was a real shambles.
- You were living here?
- Yeah.
Why?
We lived like everrybody else.
l guess it's easy to be poor when you have
a round-trip ticket in your pocket.
Let me explain something, Ed.
We're here because we wanna be here.
We like it.
We have friends here.
We're not playing poor.
lt may sound weird to you but this is
one of the happiest homes l've ever had.
l know Charlie feels the same way.
Doesn't look like it now
but we really had it together here.
Local artist.
Gracias.
Your son's a pretty popular guy around here.
- The Little Prince?
- That's a great book.
When we first got married,
Charlie read me a chapter everry night.
lt's about this little prince
and he meets a wild fox in the desert,
and little by little, by being verry gentle
and kind and thoughtful,
he tames the fox,
so the fox tells him a secret. Let's see.
''lt's only with the heart
that one can see rightly.
''What is essential is invisible to the eye.''
What is essential?
The stuff you can't see.
This is Charles' handwriting, isn't it?
''Once upon a time,
there was a county so far north
''it was further north than the North Pole.''
ls this part of the same book? No.
Charles...wrote this.
''lt was further north than the Big Dipper.
''lt was even further north than the
Milky Way, and that's pretty far north.''
''Nobody knew its name
except the folks who lived there,
''because the ink in the explorers' pen
froze before they could write it down.''
What does this mean -
''The Sunshine Grabber''?
That's the name of an animated film
Charlie's working on.
This is one of the characters.
Recognise the eyes?
But he seems so innocent,
almost deliberately naive.
ls that so bad?
ls that so good?
You raised him.
- Who is it?
- moman) Soy yo, Beth.
Hello.
Señora Duran. Ed Horman.
This is the lady whose mother
lives across the street.
- Hello.
- Buenos dias.
- El coche está esperando.
- Taxi's waiting.
Aquí, a la derecha.
l was leaving my mother,
who lives across the street.
A taxi came for me just when the soldiers
put your husband in the truck.
Ahora a la izquierda, por favor.
My taxi followed
the same road the truck took.
They drove right into that big door
and went inside the stadium.
- How come you followed them?
- She didn't...
Let her answer.
Why did your taxi follow the truck?
Well, l just live beyond the stadium.
l have to go past here when l come
from the house of my mother.
- l don't believe that!
- Ed, don't.
Don't. They could arrest her
just for talking to us.
Hello, Beth. Mr Horman,
my name's Kate Newman. l'm a reporter.
ls it true you are fed up with the way
the embassy's been handling this
and you're planning your own investigation?
- There's Putnam.
- Er...
l'm not interested in challenging them,
l'm concerned with getting back my son.
- Excuse us, please.
- Beth, get him to talk to me.
- OK.
- What happened?
- Shall we sit down?
ls there any news?
We bacMracked
over all our militay leads so far.
They still deny knowledge of his arrest.
We had a fingerprint check made
at all the morgues. Came up negative.
- Do you trust your sources?
- Captain Tower checked them.
- Then l'm sure they're impeccable.
- What we need now
is more background information,
mostly from Beth.
For example, why you were living here.
We were tired of seeing the world
through the New York Times.
- Why this county?
- Of all Latin America,
- this seemed the best.
- Politically?
ln everry way, till your generals took over.
They're not our generals.
Why don't we shift our ground a little here?
- Beth, what was Charles doing?
- Was?
l'm sorry.
What kind of work is Charles doing?
He's working on an animated children's film
and he writes articles.
- Articles for FIN?
- What is FIN?
lt's a left-wing newspaper.
lt is not left-wing.
Besides, he doesn't write for it.
He translates news stories
for such bastions of communism
as the New York Post
and the Wall Street Journal.
- There's another theoy.
- What?
That your son was picked up
by leftists posing as soldiers.
As a matter of fact, there are even people
who think it may have been his idea.
You've gotta be kidding me.
He could've done it to make it look like
the government are arresting Americans.
They are arresting Americans.
Or don't David Holloway
and Frank Teruggi count?!
Shh. Of course they count.
l heard about them
in Washington, Teruggi and...
They're released, right?
We should speak to them.
- We're seeing David tomorrow.
- We are?
ls that my list?
No. These are things
l'd just like you to check on.
Hm.
OK, l'll do my best.
Well, if that's all
l guess we can get back'to work.
Just one moment, please.
To be frank, l know that in these countries,
the embassies have agents
involved with the police
- and militay training...
- This has nothing...
l assume that this case
has something to do with it,
and l don't care how or who runs it,
l just want you to use it
to help find my son.
- l assure you...
- That's all l have to say.
l noticed you were talking
with a reporter before.
lt might be better for the investigation
if you hold off on that for a while.
You know what l mean?
- l'll hold off.
- Good.
Mrs Horman.
- Three, please.
- l can't believe what you said there.
lf you call a spade a spade,
you'll get a favourable response.
- You can also get dead.
- That's your paranoia.
- And, of course, Charles's.
- Ed...
Why didn't you make the list of his friends?
- Are you serious?
- Do l look like l'm joking?
Five minutes after l give that list to Tower,
those friends will probably be arrested.
- Charles knew some dangerous people.
- We're not criminals, Ed!
- Charlie's not a failure.
- l didn't say that.
You always imply it.
lf you'd stayed and paid attention to basics,
this wouldn't have happened.
The basics? God, county and Wall Street?
- You know what l mean.
- God bless our way of life.
A verry good way of life it is, young lady,
no matter how much people like you
ty to tear it down with your sloppy idealism.
l can no longer abide the young people
of our county who live off their parents
and find nothing better to do
than whine and complain!
- Is that your image of Charlie and me?
- Yes.
Ed. How can that be?
We're not freaked out.
We're just two normal,
slightly confused people
tying to be connected
to the whole damn rotten enchilada.
Screw you then, Mr Horman!
Why don't you just go back to New York?
You're just messing things up.
Ed?
l'm sorry, Ed.
Are you all right?
l said l'm sorry.
Shit.
Always me and my big mouth.
Frank, you're not asleep yet?
Stop fucking around. Shit!
- Está bien, no disparen.
- Has visto a Holloway?
- Holloway.
- Dónde está Frank Teruggi?
Frank?
Holy shit. What's going on?
- Be cool.
- What is this?
- Get your hands off me, asshole.
- Stop, they'll kill you.
Bullshit.
We have the right
to call our embassy!
- ;Son americanos!
- Tranquilo, son americanos.
- Lugar donde trabaja.
- El Senado.
- Qué hace ahí?
- Soy senador.
Dónde lo aprendió?
40 años.
Estado civil.
Você tira a roupa dessa gente
e leva eles para cá.
They're not gonna hurt us, OK?
We, erm, never found out what happened.
A lot of rumours going around about...
torture and specialists.
- Brazilians.
- You were tortured?
Oh, no.
Somebody stepped on my hand.
They're gonna shoot us, aren't they, Frank?
No, l don't think so, David.
They're just tying to scare us, that's all.
Well, they sure as hell succeeded.
l can't take you anmhere.
Next time we get arrested, l'm going alone.
You're really full of shit, Frank.
Come on. David, come on.
They can't kill us.
Our embassy'll go bananas.
l can't help it.
They're gonna shoot that guy, aren't they?
l'll bet you dinner at Arturo's
we'll be out of here by morning.
What do you say? Come on.
Teruggi?
Teruggi!
Looks like you lose, turkey.
Now be strong, all right?
As soon as l get out,
l'm going to the embassy.
Remember, you owe me one. Arturo's.
- Vamos.
- Hold your water, scumbag. l'm coming.
That's the last time l ever saw Frank.
They released me the next day.
The State Department said
Frank left when he got out.
l spoke to Frank's dad in Chicago.
Frank never called him or anyone else.
- Maybe he's in hiding too.
- You think Charlie's in hiding?
- l don't.
- You insist upon rejecting that hope!
Because it's just not true.
This newspaper that you all have worked on.
Could that be the reason
why you were arrested?
They never even interrogated me about it.
Was Charles verry active in it?
Just like the rest of us. Sometimes put in
18 hours a day just to get it out.
Charles worked 18 hours a day?
Sometimes, sure.
What did you get paid for those 18 hours?
A little gratitude, some respect.
You don't get verry many hot dogs
with a little gratitude, do you?
Let's don't start.
Have you looked for Frank here?
l looked for him everywhere,
even in the morgue.
He's just gone.
Vanished.
Sometimes l...
l get the feeling we're never gonna
see him again.
l'm ready, Ed.
What?
- What are you doing?
- l fix the telephone.
The telephone works perfectly.
Now is working better.
- They fixed mine yesterday.
- How can he be that brazen about it?
Hello, Ray Tower.
How is everrything over there?
Hello? Yes?
What about?
Thank you. Fine.
Who was it?
The ambassador wants
to see me in the morning.
- Why?
- l don't know.
Yes, sir.
- Mr Horman, you can go in now.
- Thank you.
Good morning. Beth, l'm sorry.
This appointment is only for Mr Horman.
Anything l'm about to hear is for her also.
lt's all right,
send them both in.
Come right in, please.
- Mr Ambassador.
- Good morning. Have a seat.
- What happened?
- Have a seat, please.
- Did you find him?
What? Oh, no, not that at all. l'm sorry.
What is it then?
l hear you'd like to discuss
some political questions.
- What?
- You suggested
that there might be some kind of
American police assistance program here.
l'd like you to know nothing of that sort
exists in this county.
Mr Ambassador,
l'm not interested in the politics.
l just want you to use
everry resource at your command.
l repeat, Mr Horman,
no such operation exists.
l got the clearance for those hospitals
you wanted to visit.
What about the national stadium?
- Well, it's kind of touchy.
- Handle it!
What do you mean, ''it's touchy''?
Look, gentlemen...
l know these are bad times,
it's not fun for you people.
lt's certainly not fun for Beth or me.
Or Charles.
You're doing your best,
l have to believe that. That's our only hope.
But you have all the machiney on your side.
Don't you see?
You have all the connections.
l'm a middle-aged businessman
from New York.
l don't speak one word of Spanish.
Here l am.
My son may have been shot.
Maybe he was tortured.
Maybe he was - oh, Lord -
beaten so badly
that they're keeping him until he's well.
l don't know. l don't care.
Really, l don't care.
Because what is done is done.
l want you to tell those people
l will take Charles back in any condition.
l'm not gonna make a stink.
l'm not gonna go to the newspapers.
You make out any kind of a release form,
l will sign it.
l will absolve anyone,
everryone of everrything.
l just want my boy back!
He's the only child l have, sir.
Did you hear what l said?
Yes, l did, Mr Horman.
Oh...
Come on, Ed. The meeting's over.
- l made a fool out of myself.
- Ed, you were great.
Mr Horman, don't feel bad, please.
Just ty to understand.
There are so many cases,
this isn't the only one we're working on.
This is the only one that l care about.
You and a lot of other people. l've never
seen so many cables from Washington.
What kind of pull do you have up there?
l'm an American citizen.
Mr Horman.
Sorry. Dave McGeay from the consulate.
l've got Beth outside in the car.
l'll be with you in a moment.
- You all set?
- No, but let's get it over with.
- Gracias.
Where would you like to start?
l've listed the hospitals geographically,
and the first is St Anne's.
- OK. That's on Avenue Ruiz.
- Yes, l know.
Listen, er, if you don't mind my asking,
what's Christian Science about?
Faith. It's about faith.
Faith in what?
ln truth.
There's no one registered
under the name of Horman?
- No, sir.
- Have we seen all of the patients?
Yes, except for los perdidos -
the ones with no names.
- Well, where are they?
- Below, in the basement.
l'm sure we don't have him,
but you can check by yourself.
molf whistle)
l'm verry sorry.
Gracias.
- No está.
- Gracias.
Muchas personas viene aquí todos los días.
Many people come here everry day.
Seguramente algunos de ellos están locos.
Several of them are certainly insane.
Para eso.
;Para eso!
Ahí solamente son los desahuciados.
Mr Horman.
Sir, these are the incurables here.
- Where you going?
- Go ahead. l wanna take a walk.
Ed, you don't know your way around.
Please, l'll catch a cab. l'll be fine.
l-l need the air.
l'm going with ya.
- We're gonna walk.
- Beth, it's too dangerous.
Charles always used to drive me crazy
when he was little.
Cape Cod, running up and down,
throwing everrything into the ocean.
He still likes to do that.
l wonder what they're doing
up on old Cape Cod.
Now it's out of season. The beach is empty,
houses are all boarded up.
That summer, before we were married,
we came to visit you and Elizabeth,
and you made us sleep
in separate bedrooms.
Yes.
One night we snuck out,
went down to the beach to make out.
There was all this sparkly phosphorous
in the water.
There was a guy there listening
to the Red Sox game on the radio.
What else does Charles like to do?
l don't know. He likes to pretend he's
a county-western singer in the shower.
But he's got a terrible voice.
And he likes to cook corned beef hash
with an egg in it.
- And he's a star freak.
- A what?
A star freak. He can point out
everry constellation up there.
- l never knew that.
- Yeah.
And he loves to make love
on Sunday mornings.
ln fact, he's a regular sex maniac.
l really don't want to hear about your...
bedroom antics.
Come on.
'Las papas... Oh.'
- 'Y el queso?'
- 'Aquí.'
That's Frank Teruggi.
- 'Oh, my God.'
- 'You're not bad.'
'lf you have two houses, the state takes one,
gives it to the man who has no house.
'Sí, sí.'
'lf you have two cars, the state takes one,
gives it to the man with no car.
'lf you have two chickens, the state takes
one, gives it to the man with none.
- 'l thought you understood our revolution.'
- 'l have two chickens.'
- 'That's the whole stoy.'
- 'l have two cameras.'
'Women and children first!'
- 'We got diapers in here.'
- 'No!'
'Give it back!'
What is this about? Why did you make this?
Just for fun.
It was a party for Tery.
'Ever been to Viña? These are from Viña.'
'That's an idea.
We should take her to the beach.'
- 'Great beach.'
- 'l'll be in New York.'
- 'We'll go tomorrow.'
- 'l gotta renew my visa. You all go.'
- 'Next day.'
- 'You shouldn't miss it.'
- 'No, go. Go tomorrow.'
- 'Day trip?
'Bring your camera. Bring your cameras.'
- 'l'll stay home.'
- That's all.
Sir, your son is not what they told you.
- How do you know that, Silvio?
- He's a nice guy, sincere.
Hard worker, but he's a political neophyte.
He's terrified of violence.
- What's wrong with that?
- l'm not knocking him.
l like Charlie
and l've got my fingers crossed.
Why did you go into hiding?
- l knew they would pick me up.
- What had you done?
You Americans always assume you must
do something before you can be arrested.
- Isn't that the way it usually works?
- Not here, Mr Horman.
lt's crazy, Charlie being arrested by them,
when some people thought
he was from the CIA.
What?
Charlie was always asking questions,
taking notes on everrything.
- l warned him.
- And?
He just laughed and took a note.
He will come back, Beth, just as Carlos has.
- This is all of them, Colonel?
- Me temo que sí.
One form for each prisoner
who was held and released.
- But none for my son?
- That means that he was not here.
Come and check for yourself.
l thought Frank Teruggi was released.
Who?
Teruggi. The man arrested
with David Holloway.
Very sorry. l don't recall his name.
Shall we?
'Atención, su atención...'
Go ahead, Mr Horman.
l-l can't seem to.
You go ahead. You...you start.
Charlie, this is Beth.
l'm here with your dad, Charlie,
and the American consul.
So, ifyou can hear me,
please come out so we can take you home.
Charles Horman,
this is your father, Edmund.
l'm here in the hope
that you can hear me.
Charles. Charles.
Do you remember when we...
took that trip together across county
from LA to New York?
Just the two of us?
That's him. Oh, my God, that's him!
- No, it's not. It's not him, Ed.
- Charles!
lt's not him. It's not him, Ed.
My father cannot come here,
but how about some ice cream
with my dinner, Colonel Espinoza?
Ambassador,
my friends have talked to refugees
in the Swedish, Mexican
and French embassies.
The man they must see is here
in your embassy.
All these people
are here for protection.
- l am responsible for their lives.
- Oh, come on, look at them.
Do they look like assassins?
Ve y dile que no son problema.
- Beth. Mr Horman.
- OK, Kate. This way.
You must remember,
Mr Paris is a desperate man.
- How many refugees have you got here?
- About 800, 900.
'There were four of them
in Lutz's office.'
The general, of course, the colonel,
my friend, who told me of this,
- and the American.
- The prisoner?
The American officer.
No, the prisoner was in the next room.
- Was he alive?
- More or less.
What do you mean, ''more or less''?
- l'm only telling you what l heard.
- What does ''more or less'' mean?
Well, apparently he had been roughed up
during interrogation.
- How badly?
- l don't know. l wasn't there.
- Your friend was?
- My former friend, Mr Horman.
Nobody in this regime
is my friend any longer.
Who was the American officer in the room?
Who knows? The ministy is full of them.
Their Milgroup office is down the hall
from the general. This is a scoop for you.
Oh, Paris, everryone knows that.
Did they mention the prisoner?
Did they call the prisoner by name?
- Horseman?
- Horman?
Maybe. Horman, sure.
Horman. If l had been there,
l would know for sure.
l am an honour graduate
of your police academy in Washington.
l like America. There it is more democratic
and someday l hope to...
Paris, please. Just tell them what
the General Lutz said about the prisoner.
- Who is Lutz?
- He's the...
He's the head of the local version of the CIA.
He said the man must disappear.
- Oh, my God! Why?
- He knew too much.
- About what?
- l don't know.
But only a few verry important people
have been detained,
most of them were killed after interrogation.
- The others were sent to camps.
- What happened to my son?
They drove him back to the stadium.
How can you order the disappearance
of an American?
- l didn't order his disappearance!
- Ed, he didn't.
l'm a police officer but l'm not a murderer.
- We know you're a good man...
- l have worked for many governments.
Some, their politics l agreed with.
Others, not so much.
l have worked now
for the junta for two weeks,
but these are Nazis.
They are destroying everrything
that was beautiful about this county.
What we need to know is
can they order an American to disappear
without consulting the Americans first?
No, they wouldn't dare.
How can l verify that?
You can't.
What's gonna happen to these people?
Safe for the moment.
Later, they'll be deported.
- What about Paris?
- He's not even close to getting out of here.
- Why does he talk?
- If he gets enough press, they won't kill him.
They won't dare to.
It's like the old switch-hitting game.
Only way to survive.
Do you think that prisoner
in the other room was Charles?
What do you think?
What could Charles know
that's so important?
- Probably what he discovered in Viña.
- Do you still have his notes?
- Yeah, at the hotel.
- Stop it! Stop it!
- Ed, you'll get shot!
- Mr Horman.
- Stop! Stop it!
Good God!
Shut this.
Were you tying to get us all killed?
l'm sorry.
l am just beginning to get amully
sick and tired of all of this...
shit!
l saw your son do almost
the same damn dumb thing.
He did that?
''During the barbecue,
Ray Tower arrived.
''Later he drove us back to Santiago.
''Trip uneventful, aside roadblock incident,
detailed page 12.''
- Ray Tower drove 'em back?
- ''Later he drove us back to Santiago.''
Well, what? Does that mean something?
Go back to where they first meet Babcock.
''Charlie - 'May l borrow
that paper if you're through?'
''Babcock with a French Accent -
'You'd do better to ask in English.'''
You're French?
'Skip ahead to why he was there.'
- What are you doing down here?
- The navy sent me to do a job. She's done.
Any idea how long we'll be stuck in Viña?
About a week. Everything's all right.
The coup went verry smoothly.
- You're completely safe.
- Was it planned verry far in advance?
Tery, does a bear shit in the woods?
- Will the US recognise the government?
- That's up to the politicians.
''Red-haired woman appeared edgy.
Babcock stopped talking.''
Did Babcock introduce them to Patrick?
No, Charlie introduced himself.
''The next day in the lobby...''
Excuse me, Colonel.
''Colonel - 'Hello. What are you doing
in this neck of the woods?'
'''l'm Charles Horman.
This is my friend, Tery Simon.'
''l explained that we'd come for one day
and got stuck by the coup.''
Oh. You'll be here a while.
The roads are closed.
What's happening in the capital?
The militay's doing search-and-destroy
missions, just like in Vietnam.
There are bodies everywhere.
It's a royal mess.
How long before you think
the roads are open?
l don't know - but give me
your room number, l'll keep you posted.
l'd appreciate it.
''l'm terribly anxious about Beth.''
''Next morning Babcock was in lobby
with carton of Kents and without lady.''
- How's it going?
- Can't complain. Yourself?
l complain.
Uh-oh.
Where are you going when you leave?
Probably Bolivia.
- Bolivia is beautiful. You'll love it.
- That's what l hear.
So are you.
Of course, they have
their problems too, but...
lf they've got problems,
you'll probably go there next.
l know l'll go there next.
Sherlock, tell me something.
What would a naval engineer
be doing in Bolivia,
one of two landlocked countries
in Latin America?
Sir, any news?
lf l were you, l wouldn't be so anxious
to be there. It is a battlefield.
But sir...
Look, l have to meet somebody,
l'll be back in a couple of minutes.
l can take you to a place where you can
radio your parents and tell them you're safe.
- Couple of minutes.
- l know l'm safe.
lt's my wife l'm worried about.
You mind if l ask you a question?
Certainly. Go ahead.
- How do you feel about the coup?
- Verry good.
l've been in a lot of...
frustrating situations before this.
l was in Key West
waiting for the Bay of Pigs.
l even took an advanced scuba course
for that invasion.
lf Kennedy had provided decent air cover,
proper militay support there,
we wouldn't be having these problems here.
'''We arrived
at the home of Paul Baker,
'''where Naval Mission radio was installed.'''
Yeah, we received a cable
through Panama on September 14th.
''After radioing Dad,
Patrick offered to arrange a ride to Santiago
''with Captain Ray Tower, USN,
''who's returning there
with Herbert Porterfield.''
And the next day they came back?
Yeah. ''Checked out of hotel,
and Patrick drove us to his house
''for 'going away' barbecue.''
You're welcome to stay. We have a room,
if the hotel's too expensive.
That's verry nice of you, but thanks anmay.
- We have a Ping-Pong table too.
- Ping-Pong?
- Yes.
- No, thanks.
So are you guys friendly
with the local militay?
Some. l took Admiral Huidobro
to the United States to buy arms last July.
Militay's all right but the truck drivers
are the real heroes of this thing.
They wanna talk to Babcock again.
'''They considered us automatic allies
in anything the US might do.'''
He had to be a hamburger
to miss with a rocket.
- Charlie, you determined to go back?
- Mm-hm.
You know about the rebels?
Ray Tower is number two on their hit list.
l wouldn't ride with him.
l wanna see my wife. Thanks, anmay.
- Hello, Ray.
- Hi, Pat.
Well, here's your chauffeur.
Ray Tower, Charlie Horman.
- Pleased to meet you.
- And you.
So the boss of Milgroup
and the senior political officer
both happened to be in Viña
when the coup started.
''We came to do a job and it's done.''
What did Babcock mean by that?
Most people think the coup
was prepared in Viña.
Now, if we weren't involved in the coup
whatever Charlie saw or heard down there
is meaningless.
But if we were, it still doesn't mean much
but it could be significant.
At least enough for somebody
to take a look at his jacket.
- His what?
- His record.
They keep a file on everry American national
living down here.
Somebody decided to review that file
and found that Charlie worked for FIN.
They might conclude
that he was well worth watching.
Do you think that's what happened?
lt seems possible.
Doesn't look so good, does it?
OK, this gentleman
is gonna take us through.
Por acá.
- Hace mucho frío ahí abajo.
- Sí.
He says it's quite cold down here.
You better put on your sweater.
l think you should wait upstairs.
Todos ellos han sido identificados.
These have all been identified.
Vengan por acá.
Vengan, vengan.
Esos también han sido identificados.
These have all been identified as well.
Estos también han sido identificados.
These too, all identified.
Estos no han sido identificados.
The identities of these
have yet to be determined.
Ed?
Who is he?
Frank Teruggi.
Jesus Christ almighty!
Come on. Let's get her outta here.
Get off me. l'm not leaving here
until l've looked for my husband.
- Ed, give me a hand.
- You heard what she said.
Señores, por favor, quiero respuestas.
Por qué el cuerpo...?
Why wasn't the body discovered until now?
What took so long?
Por qué tardaron tanto
en descubrir el cadáver?
What kind of world is this?
You sound just like Charlie.
OK.
lt appears that Mr Teruggi was picked up
for a curfew violation
and detained at the stadium
and then released.
Then the carabineros found him
Iater that night, dead on the street.
Why did the State Department
tell me that he'd left the county?
l... Most likely some screw-up
at local immigration.
Phil, l'm not gonna leave this county
until l find my son, alive or dead.
What? No, it's just that...
everry new turn seems to lead us right back
to the beginning, you know?
Like we're going in circles.
We're going in circles!
Elizabeth! Can you...? Oh, yeah. OK.
That's better, dear.
What? No! l'm fine.
l'm just pooped, that's all.
Beth? Yeah, she's all right.
What?
Yes. Yes, dear, l will. And you too.
God bless you, Liz.
Earthquake.
Ed, not the elevator!
Don't stay in the windows.
It's dangerous!
Señores, no se queden
en las ventanas, es peligroso.
- Don't stay in the window. It's dangerous.
Be calm. The hotel is earthquake-proof.
No need for alarm!
You can't go outside. It's curfew!
Hey, you! Don't go out!
Curfew! Please, don't.
- Go back to your...
Ladies and gentlemen,
please, go back to your rooms.
There is no more danger.
Vuelvan a las habitaciones,
no hay peligro ya.
- l'm sorry.
- It's all right. l don't mind.
You wanna go up?
l'm still tying to come down.
Beth, how about a drink, hm?
- Help you sleep.
- But not in the bar.
Thank you.
- A la vida.
- A la v...
To life. Charlie and l always say that.
Now...
- l owe you an apology.
- No, you don't.
For a long time now, l've sold you short,
both of you.
l don't really know why,
unless it's because l'm getting old.
And l'm verry stubborn.
Why don't you sit over here?
This past week, l've felt like...
my heart has just been torn out of me.
lt's OK.
l feel verry guilty.
Charlie always says guilt is like fear,
it's given to us for survival,
not destruction.
Beth, you're one of the most courageous
people l have ever met.
l mean it.
Thank you.
You think he's dead?
l don't know.
No. No, l don't...
think he's dead.
But that's not how you really feel, is it?
- l spoke to Elizabeth tonight.
- And?
She was speaking again with some people
from the Ford Foundation.
They think we should contact Peter Cooke.
He runs their office here.
Do you mind if l skip that one?
No.
You kids love each other
verry much, don't you?
l'm verry sorry, sir, but Mr Cooke
is out of the county until Monday.
- Oh...
- Can l be of some help?
Well, l was just paying a courtesy call
on Mr Cooke.
You're Mr Horman, aren't you?
Erm, why don't you come inside
and we can talk for a while?
- Well, l...
- Mr Horman, please come in.
Hi, l'm Peter Chernin.
l'm an economic advisor with the foundation.
Would you come with me for a moment?
Please, take a seat.
l have a friend l play golf with.
l won't identify him, but he works
for an English-speaking embassy here,
and he's close to someone who has
good contacts with the militay.
He thinks your son was executed
in the national stadium on September 19th.
That was nearly a month ago.
Yes, sir.
Could l...
speak to your friend or his contact?
No, l'm afraid not.
These are verry dangerous times.
l'll go anmhere, in any way.
You can tie my hands.
You can blindfold me. You can...
l'm sorry. l am sorry, but l can't do that.
l probably shouldn't even have told you.
This is a terrible, terrible tragedy.
Just give me a name.
Please.
Just...
That's all right. l understand.
Thank you for telling me.
Ed. Ed. The ambassador is waiting for you
in the ballroom.
We've been tying to reach you.
We may have some good news.
What would that be?
That my son was executed in the stadium
three days after his arrest?
Wait. Who told you that? Ed, wait.
Ah, good, Consul, you found him.
Mr Horman, this is Mr Samuel Cross.
Gentlemen, perhaps we'd be
more comfortable over here.
Mr Cross is a journalist with good access
to left-wing circles down here
and he's dug up some
interesting information about your son.
l believe that your son's alive and well,
Mr Horman.
Captain Tower asked me to make inquiries
about Charles's whereabouts.
l spoke with a guy who's helping
political refugees escape.
His organisation has secured credentials
for three Americans to leave Santiago.
One of them was your son.
- Where is he?
- He's in the north.
He should be out of the county
sometime next week.
Can l contact him?
l'm afraid you can't. But l'll lay odds
he's home in New York before...
Will you please get him out of here?
Now, l said ''please''.
l wanna speak to the two of you alone.
Mr Cross, thank you.
Mr Horman has new information
and l'll check it out right away.
Yes, you do that. You call General Lutz.
l believe my son was killed by the militay.
- Where'd you hear that?
- l do not think they would dare do that
unless an American official
co-signed a kill order.
That's a hell of a statement considering
we're here to protect American citizens.
This mission has done everrything
humanly possible to locate your son.
l think you knew
he was dead from the start.
lf we knew, why wouldn't we tell you?
- l don't know but l'll find out.
- Why would we want him dead?
Because he knew
of our involvement in the coup.
We're not involved.
Our position has been completely neutral.
That is a bald-faced lie!
How can you say a thing like that
when you have army colonels,
- naval engineers, all over Viña del Mar?
- Please, sit down.
lt's obvious you're harbouring
some misconception
- regarding our role here.
- What is your role here...
besides endorsing a regime
that murders thousands of human beings?
Let's level with each other.
lf you hadn't been involved
in this unfortunate incident
you'd be sitting at home complacent
and more or less oblivious to all of this.
This mission is pledged
to protect American interests.
Well, they're not mine.
There are over 3,OOO US firms
doing business down here,
and those are American interests.
ln other words, your interests.
l'm concerned with the preservation
of a way of life.
And a damn good one.
Maybe that's why there's nobody out there.
You can't have it both ways.
l don't know what happened to your kid, Ed,
but l understand he was a bit of a snoop.
He poked his nose in dangerous places
where he really didn't belong.
Now, suppose...
l went up to your town, New York,
and l started messing
around with the Mafia.
l wind up dead in the East River.
And my wife, or my father,
complains to the police
because they didn't protect me.
They really wouldn't have much of a case,
would they?
You play with fire, you get burned.
Just a minute. What's going on?
They wanna ask questions about Charlie.
- Who are you?
- l'm Inspector Rojas.
l am taking Mrs Horman to headquarters.
- For what?
- Interrogation.
She's not going anmhere.
- Ed?
- Wait a minute.
Get me the American consulate, please.
ls everrything all right?
- Ed, what's wrong?
- Nothing. Nothing, dear.
l'd like to speak to Consul Putnam.
This is Ed Horman calling.
What'd they say at the Ford Foundation?
- Consul, there's a... What's your name?
- Inspector Rojas.
An Inspector Rojas here, and he...
Oh, just a minute. He wants to speak to you.
Yes, Consul Putnam?
Oh, l understand.
Certainly.
l will do as you say.
Fine, sir. Thank you.
Yes?
Why?
Yes, all right. But if l have any trouble with...
l said, ''All right''. l'm going with you.
- Name of missing person?
- l've answered this a thousand times.
- Name of missing person, please.
- Charles Horman.
Date of disappearance?
September 16th.
- Time of disappearance?
- l'm not sure.
He was arrested that afternoon.
l don't know when.
- Time unknown.
- Hay una Ilamada para el señor Horman.
You have a call, sir.
l'll be right back.
Place of birth?
New York.
ln this room.
Hello?
l looked into that, Ed,
and it appears that you were right.
We've been informed that the body
has been identified
through a recheck of morgue fingerprints.
Positive identification?
'Yes, absolutely...
'positive. They found him.
'He was...buried in a wall.'
ln a wall? l don't understand.
They do that. It's quite common down here.
W-Was he killed in the stadium?
- 'lt looks that way.'
- l see.
Goodbye.
His political affiliation?
Please, Mrs Horman.
We're going home.
l love you, Ed.
l want you to contact the militay.
l want you to demand all Charles'
personal effects stolen from this house.
- That's not verry realistic.
- Every drawing, everry notebook,
everry article my son wrote or had.
- Ed, l can't go to the...
- Do it!
l don't care whether it's a cinch
or difficult as hell.
- l want it done.
- l'll ty.
Right here, please.
- Good. That takes care of it.
- That's it?
- Yes.
- OK.
When will he be sent home?
Erm, l'd say a few days.
We've got to get some other clearances.
Nothing important.
We should ship him home by Friday.
- You're sure?
- You've got my word on it.
Wait, there's just one more thing. Just one.
Did you mention the shipping charges?
No, l didn't. There's going to be
some sort of a fee
in addition to the air freight duty.
How much?
- Do you have the exact...?
- It comes to $931 .1 4.
That includes the freight
and the taxes as well, of course.
You mean you want it now?
No, l don't think that's necessay.
- When the body arrives...
- We'll take care of it.
- Good. Let me get this.
- l wanna get rid of the money.
OK.
- 'Departure to New York...'
- Beth! Mr Horman!
Hello. We called your room this morning.
You'd already checked out.
l tried to leave you a message.
l'm on my way to La Paz.
Bolivia. That's where Babcock said
he was going next.
Now that you mention it, yes.
Miss Newman, thank you for your help.
l'm terribly sorry. Beth...
- You have a good flight.
- Take care, both of you.
- Beth.
- Beth, no more special privileges.
l wish there was something
we could say or do here.
There's something l'm gonna do.
l'm gonna sue you, Phil,
and Tower and the ambassador,
everybody who let him die.
We'll make it verry hot for you.
- l guess that's your privilege.
- No, that's my right.
l just thank God that we live in a county
where we can put people like you in jail.
'Ed Horman filed suit
charging 1 1 government officials,
'including Heny A Kissinger,
'with complicity and negligence
in the death of his son.
'The body was not returned home
until seven months later,
'making an accurate autopsy impossible.
'After years of litigation,
'the information necessay
to prove or disprove complicity
'remained classified as secrets of state.
'The suit was dismissed.'