♪ Tumble out of bed
and I stumble to the kitchen ♪
♪ Pour myself
a cup of ambition ♪
♪ And yawn and stretch
and try to come to life ♪
♪ Jump in the shower
and the blood starts pumpin ' ♪
♪ Out on the streets,
the traffic starts jumpin ' ♪
♪ With folks like me
on the job from nine to five ♪
♪ Workin ' nine to five ♪
♪ What a way to make a livin ' ♪
♪ Barely gettin ' by ♪
♪ It's all takin ' and no givin ' ♪
♪ They just use your mind ♪
♪ And they never give you credit ♪
♪ It's enough to drive you
crazy if you let it ♪
♪ Nine to five ♪
♪ For service and devotion ♪
♪ You would think that I ♪
♪ Would deserve a fair promotion ♪
♪ Want to move ahead ♪
♪ But the boss
won't seem to let me ♪
♪ I swear sometimes that man
is out to get me ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ohh ♪
♪ They let you dream
just to watch them shatter ♪
♪ You're just a step
on the boss-man's ladder ♪
♪ But you've got dreams
he'll never take away ♪
♪ You're in the same boat
with a lot of your friends ♪
♪ Waitin ' for the day
your ship will come in ♪
♪ And the tide's gonna turn ♪
♪ And it's all gonna roll your way ♪
♪ Workin ' nine to five ♪
♪ What a way to make a livin ' ♪
♪ Barely gettin ' by ♪
♪ It's all takin ' and no givin ' ♪
♪ They just use your mind ♪
♪ And you never get the credit ♪
♪ It's enough to drive you
crazy if you let it ♪
♪ Nine to five ♪
♪ Yeah, they've got you
where they want you ♪
♪ There's a better life ♪
♪ And you think about it, don't you? ♪
♪ It's a rich man's game ♪
♪ No matter what they call it ♪
♪ And you spend your life ♪
♪ Puttin ' money in his wallet ♪
♪ Nine to five ♪
♪ What a way to make a livin ' ♪
♪ Barely gettin ' by ♪
♪ It's all takin ' and no givin ' ♪
♪ They just use your mind ♪
♪ And they never give you credit ♪
♪ It's enough to drive you
crazy if you let it ♪
♪ Nine to five ♪
♪ Yeah ♪♪
But, Norman, she has never
worked in her life before.
I thought you'd be
sympathetic.
I am sympathetic, but, please,
why do I have to train her?
Let her work in
someone else's section.
She's willing
and needs the job.
She's recently divorced.
I'm a widow with four kids.
Jerry should never
have died.
I'd be better off.
I could've divorced him.
Is that her?
Yes.
We're going to need
a special locker for the hat.
This way.
This is
quite a day for me.
I'll bet it is.
I was so excited,
I left an hour early
so I wouldn't be late.
It took 45 minutes
to find parking.
We park inside the building.
I just moved
to an apartment
near the airport.
Ah.
Hey, Violet,
what it is?
Hi, Eddie.
What do you hear
about your promotion?
Nothing now.
Uh, Eddie Smith...
Judy Bernly.
Judy starts work today.
What?
How will I ever
get out of this
mail room prison
if they keep hiring
from outside?
Lady, you're going
to hate it here.
Judy.
Okay. Now, we're
on the 12th floor.
Above us is
the executive suite,
where the president,
Mr. Hinkle, is
and the chairman of the board.
It sounds so big.
It is.
I've been here 12 years.
I've never even seen
the chairman of the board.
12 years? All I've done
is be a housewife.
I wanted to ask you
about my salary.
That's a very
touchy subject
around here.
You'll have
to take that up
with our boss
Mr. Hart.
Oh, I'm sorry.
It's all so new.
You'll get
the hang of it.
Then you'll really
be sorry.
Come on.
Well, welcome
to the front lines.
Uh-oh. Here comes
General Patton.
Violet, just a moment.
Come on.
Uh, just a moment.
Violet?
Oh, yes, Roz.
So sorry.
I've been meaning to talk to you
about Mr. Hart's rules
on office decor.
They seem to be getting
lax in your section.
Really? How?
I've typed it up here.
"No coffee cups
on the desks.
"No personal items
left in view‒
"photos...
plants, et cetera."
We mustn't look
cluttered or sloppy.
Mm-mmm.
An office that...
looks efficient
is efficient,
as Mr. Hart says.
As Mr. Hart says.
Oh, hello.
Judy Bernly, Roz Keith,
Mr. Hart's administrative
assistant.
Judy is starting
today.
It's nice to meet you.
Welcome to Consolidated.
I hope you enjoy it.
We're all
a happy bunch.
I think so.
Put this
on the bulletin board.
I know just where
to stick it.
Judy, if there's
anything I can do
to help you settle in,
just drop on by.
Thank you.
One thing you should know
about dear Roz‒
she's the eyes, ears, nose,
and throat of Mr. Hart.
Anything she hears,
he hears.
She's a company spy?
Shh! I wouldn't say that.
If you gossip
in the ladies' room,
check under the stalls
for her shoes.
Happy birthday, Myra.
She and Roz
are like this.
This section's
divided into three zones,
each with a supervisor.
As senior,
the other two supervisors
report to me.
I report to Mr. Hart.
That's his office there.
He was just made vice president.
I've never seen anyone
leapfrog so fast.
I have the bad back
to prove it.
Margaret, anything serious?
Nothing so far.
Uh-huh.
Margaret, please.
Roz is on my case.
Sorry.
I remember
when he was just
a management trainee.
In fact, I'm the one
who trained him.
What's he like?
I like to think, Judy,
if there is a word
to describe my philosophy
of business...
it's "teamwork."
Everybody
working together.
You girls, of course,
never got a chance
to play football
or baseball.
And I've always felt
like that's unfortunate
because I think it's‒
it's probably
the best place
to learn what teamwork
is all about.
I remember Coach Frye
used to tell us
"a chain is only as strong
as its weakest link."
Its weakest link‒
God damn it!
Get this chair fixed.
Well, I...
I'm not going to bore you
with a long harangue.
Just suffice to say that
it's a jungle out there,
but if we work together,
we'll cut the balls off
the competition
and be sitting pretty
on top of the hill.
Thank you, sir.
I'm happy
to be working here.
Well, you're
a welcome addition,
and a damn pretty one, too,
if I might add.
Thank you, sir.
I mean that.
You should see the crones
coming through here lately.
Real pathetic.
Right, Violet?
Oh, Violet,
my wife's coming by later.
I'd like to get her
a present.
Could you pick out a scarf?
We've discussed
this before.
It's not my place
to shop‒
God damn it.
For five minutes
I've been talking
about teamwork.
You're not there
for the hand-off.
All I'm saying,
Mr. Hart,
is my job description
says nothing
about making
purchases
for your wife.
All I'm saying is
I like people around me
who are flexible
and get along.
When I ask an employee,
especially one who wants
to be promoted to management,
I expect
a little cooperation.
You savvy?
Savvy.
Good. Silk, blue,
maybe a red stripe.
You're talking
to the right person.
Violet's the best.
First person I met here.
Knows more about
what's going on
than anybody
but Mr. Hinkle.
Oh, a deer.
Yeah. Lucky shot.
Listen, if you ever
have anything
of a serious nature
on your mind,
feel free
to talk to me,
because that's actually
why I have my office
on this floor‒
to be close to my girls.
Okay?
Certainly. Thank you.
Good.
Oh, is Doralee
back yet?
No.
Get me coffee
then, Violet.
No sugar.
Just Skinny and Sweet.
Yes, sir.
Well, that's
Franklin Hart, Jr.
But to me
he'll always be
F. Hart.
Oh, good.
She's back.
Hi, Violet.
How's everything going?
Oh, Doralee,
your boss wants coffee.
Great. I just got back
from gassing up his car.
I'm filling one tank
or another.
This is Judy Bernly.
Judy will be working
in my section.
Doralee Rhodes.
Nice to meet you.
Hope everybody's been
treating you friendly
and showing you around.
Everybody's been
very nice, thank you.
If there's anything
I can do, just holler.
I know what it's like
to be the new girl.
Thank you.
Judy, over here.
This is your typewriter,
Dictaphone, adding machine.
I better get you
a locker for that hat.
Hello.
Uh...
yes.
Hello?
Jo's leaving.
They won't let her
work part-time.
Of course they won't.
It would make things
too convenient.
Hi, Violet. Hi, Judy.
How's it going?
Fine, thank you.
Violet's going to show me
around outside.
Hart's asked me
to buy his wife a scarf.
Why doesn't he ask
Doralee?
She does
everything else for him.
Oh, she's too tired.
They've been
in conference together
all morning.
We'll see you later.
Come on, Judy.
Have fun.
Your salmon
looks good. Mmm!
$20?
I like this.
What did Margaret mean
about Doralee?
Well, rumor has it
that, uh...
she is banging the boss.
She and Mr. Hart?
I think that's awful.
Well, live
and let live.
Though, frankly,
I credit her
with more brains.
Certainly more taste.
That's how
my husband left.
He was having an affair
with his secretary.
I don't think Hart
will leave his wife.
She's been
too good a meal ticket
all these years.
Besides, she's bananas.
She adores him.
Doralee, would you
grab your pad
and bring your pretty face
in here, please?
Yes, sir.
Hold it right there.
What?
Turn around
just a second.
Something wrong?
Have I got something
on my dress?
Nothing's wrong.
Matter of fact,
everything is...
very, very right.
Shall we begin,
Mr. Hart?
Yeah. Um...
take a letter
to Vernon Henshaw
over at Metropolitan Mutual.
Dear Vern,
as you know,
the chairman of the board
of Consolidated Companies,
Mr. Russell Tinsworthy,
spends most of his time
in Brazil
working on the jungle
clearance operation.
Consequent‒
Oh, the pencils dropped.
It's all right.
I'll get it.
Here, let me...
Let me‒
Let me help you
with those.
That's okay, really.
I've got them.
There you go.
Okay.
Doralee.
Yes?
About my conduct
in the office here
yesterday...
I'm afraid I got
a little carried away. I'd...
I'd just like
to apologize to you.
Don't you worry
about it.
I've been chased
by swifter men than you,
and I ain't
been caught yet.
Shall we get back
to our letter now?
But could you just
come over here
for a second?
I have a little
something for you.
You know...
ever since I made
that stupid mistake
about the convention
in San Francisco, I...
Oh, you didn't
make a mistake.
I'll just have to make sure
the next time I'm asked
to work at a convention,
there's a convention
going on.
Right. And nothing happened anyway,
so let's forget the whole thing.
Fine.
Doralee...
you know, you mean
so much more to me
than just a dumb secretary,
so I bought this for you.
I picked it out myself.
Well, thank you.
You didn't have
to do that.
Oh, it's nice.
It's very nice.
It's also very nothing.
Doralee, I'm a rich man.
I've got a checkbook
on that desk.
Say the word,
you can write
your own figure.
I could do that now.
I sign your name
better than you do.
Doralee,
don't you understand?
I'm crazy about you.
You're all I think about.
I've told you before.
I'm a married woman.
And I'm a married man.
That makes it perfect.
Oh, Mr. Hart‒ Aah!
Doralee, please!
I want you.
Oh, for heaven's sake.
What are you doing,
Mr. Hart?
Call me Frank.
Frank?
Huh?
What are you doing
on the floor?
Nothing. I tripped.
Hit my knee
on the damn
coffee table.
Ow! Oh!
Did you hurt yourself?
No.
What are you
doing down here?
You know I hate it
when you come here.
You know that.
Don't be mad at me.
I just came
from the travel agency.
They have the most
wonderful cruises‒
Oh, hello, Doralee.
Hi, Mrs. Hart.
Well, how are you?
I'm fine, and you?
What a lovely scarf.
It's a present
from your husband.
Oh, Frank,
that was so thoughtful.
I'm just glad
he appreciates you.
Put it on.
Oh, it's absolutely
adorable.
And you are so attractive.
You're sweet.
I appreciate that.
Doralee,
that'll be all for now.
You can just finish
the letter later on.
Bye. Oh, Frank,
let me show you
these brochures.
It won't take a second.
You did promise to go.
Right.
Here's a lovely one.
An Italian line.
Looks just like
the Love Boat.
It does.
Four weeks of sunshine.
Four weeks? Are you
out of your mind?
I'm not spending
four weeks of my life
drifting around
on that dago boat.
Well, I'll be damned.
Just look and see
who got paid off
for services rendered.
That's‒That's the scarf
you bought.
Aw, who cares?
I suppose
she deserves it.
I'll bet you
can't wait to see
the Xerox room.
Now, all these rush memos
are always done
on regulation
Consolidated letterhead,
so you place it in here,
8 1/2 X 11.
Close the bin firmly,
turn on the power.
Several people
have lost their hearing
in this room!
Select the number
of copies,
make this a little darker,
and start the print.
Here it comes.
If anything goes wrong,
watch this panel.
The machine tells you
what to do.
I'll leave you to it.
Oh!
You're too much.
Your wife's going off
on vacation. There'll be
no stopping you.
I know. Wait till you hear
this new little
scheme I've got going.
Come on in here
a minute.
What the hell
is going on here?
I'm sorry, Mr. Hart.
It was going too fast.
Why didn't you just
shut it off right here?
Catch you upstairs, Frank.
Great little scheme
you got here.
Right here. Right here.
I'm sorry, Mr. Hart.
I thought
I could keep up.
Weren't you
checked out
on this machine?
Any moron could
operate this.
I was.
I know what to do
now, sir.
I suggest
you do it,
or your first day
will be your last,
understand?
Yes, sir.
Clean this mess up
and get back to work.
Yes, sir.
Dick?
Oh, Judy.
What are you doing here?
I just dropped by to
give you these papers.
They're the last.
You, uh, you sign them,
and then you give them
to your lawyer.
Okay.
How are things with you?
Everything's fine.
Terrific!
I got a job.
Oh!
I'm a...
I'm a secretary.
Well, how's Liza?
Fine. She's waiting in the car.
We‒We've got to go.
Well, so long.
Bye.
I feel like I was
just here a minute ago.
You'll get
used to it.
Everybody does.
Eventually.
Medicinal purposes.
Violet Newstead,
please hold.
Hi, this is Violet.
Mel, no, no.
That's 210, net 30.
Delivered in 9 days.
That's 2% of 4,405.50 is...
88.11.
Oh, my pleasure, Mel.
Violet Newstead,
please hold.
Hi, this is Violet.
Charlotte,
I've got it right here.
I was waiting for your call.
That route is...
32 via Dixie Express.
Don't worry.
I've got it under control.
Okay. Bye-bye.
Violet News‒
Come on, kids.
No fighting.
Believe me. There's more than one
peanut butter and banana
sandwich in the world.
What did I say this morning?
Okay. Love you, too.
No, I don't want to talk
to the dog. Bye-bye.
Oh, hi, Judy.
How's everything going?
Fine, thanks.
How'd you like to have
lunch today?
Well, I'm afraid
I can't, thanks.
Maybe tomorrow.
I know the cutest
little Italian restaurant
just a hop, skip,
and a jump from here.
I should stay
in the office
and learn
the routine,
but thanks anyway.
Yeah, sure.
You know, I just
don't get it, Dwayne.
What's that, honey?
I'm as nice
as I know how to be
to everyone at that office.
Everybody treats me
like a bastard
at a family reunion.
Well, come over here
and sit down.
Well, that hurts my feelings.
Where's my smile?
I don't have one.
They're just jealous
'cause you're so pretty.
They're not jealous.
Mm-hmm.
Now, where's my smile?
I want you to smile, okay?
You forget
all about them.
I'm going to give you
a real warm reception.
I just bet you will.
Violet, a little coffee.
Yes, sir.
Yeah. What else?
Did you have a chance
to look at the report
on color-coding of accounts?
Last month.
I gave it to you.
We could improve
efficiency 20%.
Sure, I looked
into that.
That needs
a little work.
I'll get back
to you on that.
Yeah. Mm-hmm.
Okay.
Oh, Violet,
I haven't heard
from you.
Did you get
my memo?
I did, Roz.
I tore right through it.
Good.
We must
clamp down hard
on any signs
of unionization.
Oh, here comes Mr. Hart
with Mr. Hinkle.
Coming from you,
that means a lot.
Hello, girls.
How's it going?
Just fine.
Hello, Mr. Hinkle.
Roz, you'll be getting
a copy of this report
Frank just gave me.
We're going to start
color-coding the accounts
from now on.
Frank's done
a brilliant study
with efficiency.
Really?
Congratulations,
Mr. Hart.
Thanks, Roz.
Was just‒just brilliant.
You're a fine piece
of manpower, Frank.
Any other reforms
you want to make
are fine with me.
Thank you.
This is your floor.
You run it
as you please.
Going up?
No. We're going down.
Oh, I can't believe
that man.
He has no shame.
He stood right there
and presented my idea
to the company's
president
like it was his own.
Why didn't you
call him on it?
Oh, because
I'm playing it safe, damn it.
In six weeks,
he makes the decision
about that promotion,
and until then,
I'm playing
the good girl.
You finished
up there?
Yeah.
Nice job.
Thanks.
Can you imagine
a mature woman
with four kids
installing
a garage door opener,
he still refers to me
as his girl.
Mom, you gotta relax.
I'm going to
roll you a joint.
Josh, you know how
I feel about that.
Besides, your grandmother
will pitch a fit
if she even hears you
mention marijuana.
She doesn't understand
moderation.
Besides, you're
the one that keeps
talking about
"harm springs
from excess," right?
Okay. Yes, I know.
I'm talking
about one joint.
Okay.
I don't like it, Josh.
How long have you
been waiting
for this promotion?
Slip it in my purse.
It works!
You did it.
What?
Don't go flying
off the handle.
You gave that promotion
to Bob Enright?
I've got five years
seniority over him.
I know.
Christ,
I trained him.
I know, but see,
the company‒
Oh, the company,
bullshit.
You promoted him.
You tell me why.
Well, in the first place,
Bob does have
a college degree.
Oh, brilliant.
While he's
away at college
getting
his useless degree,
I'm working
my butt off.
In the second place,
he's supporting a family.
And I don't?
What's that
got to do
with anything?
My hands are tied.
The company needs
a man in this position.
Clients would rather
deal with men
about figures.
Now we're getting at it.
I lose a promotion
because of some
idiot prejudice.
The boys in the club
are threatened,
and you're
intimidated by any woman that
won't sit at the back of the bus.
Spare me the women's
lib crap, okay?
I know your feelings.
I understand.
You understand zilch.
I understand
I'm still the boss here,
and though you
have your value,
you better get
hold of yourself.
God damn it.
Doralee, get in here!
Okay.
I told you
to have this chair fixed.
Okay,
I'm going to leave,
but I'm telling you
one thing‒
Don't you ever
refer to me as
your girl again.
What are you
talking about?
Doralee,
what's with this chair?
I'll tell you‒
I'm no girl.
I'm a woman.
You hear?
I'm not your wife
or your mother...
or even
your mistress.
What?
I am your employee,
and as such,
I expect to be treated equally,
with a little dignity
and a little respect.
What do you mean,
mistress?
She's just upset.
Doralee, the whole
company knows
you two are
having an affair.
Who's been saying
we're having an affair?
Who's been saying it?
He has.
What?
Violet, where
are you going?
I'm going
to get drunk.
Atta girl.
You've been
telling everybody
I'm sleeping
with you, huh?
Well, that's why
these people
treat me
like some floozy.
They think
I'm screwing the boss.
That's not it at all‒
You just love it,
don't you?
Gives you some
cheap thrill,
like knocking over
pencils‒
Let's don't get exc‒
Get your
scummy hands off me.
I've been
straight with you
since I got here.
I put up with
your pinching
'cause I need this job,
but this is
the last straw!
Let's just‒
I got a gun
in my purse.
I've been forgiving
because of the way
I was brought up,
but if you ever say
another word about me
or make another
indecent proposal,
I'll get that gun,
and I'll change you
from a rooster to a hen
with one shot!
Don't think
I can't do it!
Shit.
Where are you going?
I need a drink, Roz.
I'm taking the rest
of the day off.
Atta girl.
What do you want?
I'm busy.
I wouldn't
disturb you if this
weren't important,
but I just heard
one of the girls
commit a serious
infraction.
What?
Maria Delgado
was speaking
to a girl
whose voice
I didn't recognize
when I overheard her
reveal her salary
and make estimates
of yours and mine.
Get rid of her.
Dismiss her.
It isn't as if
she hasn't
been warned.
I clearly outlined‒
Did you hear me?
Fire the bitch.
What?
I don't believe it.
You were fired for that?
That's okay.
I wanted to spend
more time with
my kids anyway.
But it's so unfair.
We've got to
do something.
Sure. Let's all revolt.
No. Don't you get
in trouble for me.
It's not worth it.
I'll find another job.
It was hard for me
to work full-time
anyway.
I promised myself
I wouldn't cry.
Oh...
Where's Violet?
Does she know?
Not yet.
She's at Charlie's
getting drunk.
Well, I'm going to
tell her.
This is a disgrace.
Atta girl.
What a rat.
What a liar.
What a creep.
To think he told everybody
I was sleeping with him.
It's so unfair.
Just so unfair.
Twelve years of service,
and he shoots me down.
We've got
to do something.
He can't just treat
people like that.
Do? What's to do, quit?
Well, I can't quit.
It's the same
all over, anyway.
Couldn't we all
get together and...
and complain?
Complain to who?
Let's face it‒
We're in
a pink collar ghetto.
Let's have another drink.
This one's on me.
I've got it.
It's my turn.
I've really got it.
What's that?
I didn't think
you smoked.
You roll your own?
This is a gift
from my son.
Let's pop to
the ladies' room
and light up.
Is that one of them
marijuana cigarettes?
We don't have enough
for everybody. Cool it.
We can't, Violet.
Someone
might come in.
It is dangerous,
Violet.
Would you two show
a little spunk?
What are you,
a man or a mouse?
I mean a woman
or a wouse?
Let's go
to my house.
My husband's away.
We'll have the place
to ourselves.
We could have ourselves
an old-fashioned ladies'
pot party.
You know,
that stuff don't do
that much for me.
I smoked
a marijuana cigarette
at a party once.
I could never
figure out what
the big deal was.
Huh.
Threatening Hart
with a gun?
He knows
I've got one, too.
I keep it right here
at all times.
All I can think,
he must have peed
in his pants.
Have you ever fired it?
Have I ever fired it?
Well, really,
just once,
right after Dwayne
bought it.
I was coming home
from this rodeo
with a girlfriend,
and these two men
started hassling us.
They wouldn't let up.
I was being big
'cause I had a gun,
so I reached to get it,
and I shot a hole
clean through my purse.
But they ran off.
I bet they did.
Like turkeys.
Wow.
This is...
This is
really good pot.
What did you
call it again?
Maui wowee.
Well, I love it.
It's primo.
I don't think
I could ever carry a gun.
I don't understand
guys like Hart
who go out and
shoot those poor,
defenseless animals
like Bambi
and Thumper...
and that cute little skunk.
I'd like to hunt.
I'd like to hunt Hart.
I'd like to chase
his lily-white tail
and see how he likes it.
I think she's stoned.
Thumper.
Am I stoned?
I think
you're stoned.
Oh, it's so funny.
What's so funny?
Oh, I have
this image of Hart
running for his life,
and the whole office
is out to get him
and hunt him down.
There he is!
Get him!
Kill the bastard!
Aah! Who's there?
Hello, Hart.
Looks like you're
in a spot of trouble.
Judy?
You've
got to help me.
That mob's crazy.
They're trying
to kill me.
Why would they
want to do that?
I don't know. I'm not a bad guy.
You're a sexist, egotistical,
lying, hypocritical bigot.
So I have a few flaws.
Is that reason
to kill me?
You're foul, Hart,
a wart on the nose
of humanity,
and I'm going to
blast it off.
Judy, Judy, Judy...
Good-bye, boss-man.
It's quittin' time.
You can't
mean this.
1...2...3...
4...5...
Why me?
I'm an ordinary guy
trying to do his job.
8...9...
Holy shit.
10.
Hi?
That's great.
Well, I have just
wrecked my diet,
but I love good barbecue,
don't you?
Dwayne fixed these
last night.
Mmm...
Oh, that is
so wonderful.
Oh, these
olives. Mmm.
Everything tastes
so wonderful.
I can't get over it.
What about you,
Doralee?
What's your fantasy
for doing him in?
Me?
Well, I think I'd like to
just come ridin' up one day
and give him a taste
of his own medicine.
Hey, hot stuff,
grab your pad
and get your buns
in here.
Yes, ma'am.
Morning.
Hold it.
Hold it right there.
Something wrong?
No, no.
I just wanted to
check your bod.
Turn around
for a second.
You got
a nice ass, Frank.
You ought to get
your pants cut tighter,
bring 'em up
a little in the crotch.
You got a nice package.
Might as well
show it off.
Mrs. Rhodes.
Come over here.
I want you to take a memo.
To all personnel...
Boy, that's great cologne
you're wearing, Frank.
Oh, thank you.
It's turning me on.
What's that called?
Stud.
Ohh.
Well, it's very sexy,
only I don't like
that tie you're wearing.
What happened to
the ones I gave you?
Well, nothing. I just‒
Take it off.
Excuse me?
Can't work
with those stripes
glaring out at me.
How 'bout unbuttoning
that coat and your shirt?
You need to loosen up.
That's better.
Now, where were we?
The memo.
Oh, by the way,
I got a surprise for you.
I am a married man.
Forget about
your wife, Frank.
You may be hers
in the evening,
but you're my boy
from nine to five.
Look what
I got for you.
Isn't that pretty?
Yes, it's pretty.
Very pretty.
But you shouldn't
be buying gifts
for me, Mrs. Rhodes.
Let me put it on you.
Now, that wasn't
so bad, was it?
No.
I love your hair.
It's so sexy.
Go over on the couch.
I'll lock the door.
Mrs. Rhodes‒
Oh, let's be friendly, Frank.
You got to be
more cooperative
if you want to
keep this job.
Mrs. Rhodes,
I'm not that kind of boy.
Oh, get off it.
One little kiss?
What's that
going to hurt?
Who's gonna know?
No, no.
I won't.
No! No!
Jeez!
Frank,
you get back here.
I'm warning you‒
come back here.
No, I won't.
And he's out of the chute,
ladies and gentlemen.
Look out. That's a big bull
from the high glass tower.
Now, Miss Doralee Rhodes
is gonna try to rope him.
She's already got him down.
How long will it take
to hog-tie this sexist,
egotistical, lying,
hypocritical bigot?
Five seconds,
ladies and gentlemen!
Just five seconds!
I can just see
Hart hanging there
wondering what
the hell happened.
Ha, ha. Ohh.
What's your
fantasy, Violet?
How would you
bump off
the boss?
Oh, I have to
think about it.
For me, it would have to be
like a fairy tale,
something gruesome
and horrible
and real gory...
but kind of cute.
Violet, get me
some coffee.
Yes, sir.
Sorry.
Thank you.
Your coffee,
Mr. Hart.
Hmm?
Oh, you can
put it down.
Just the way
you like it.
More coffee,
Mr. Hart?
Coffee?
Aah!
Ooh.
Ooh...ooh...
I think
there was something
in that coffee.
I think you're right.
I think it was poison.
Right again.
I think you did it.
♪ Ha, ha-ha, ha-ha ♪♪
Uh...
But why?
Why?
Why do you think?
Because I'm a sexist,
egotistical, lying,
hypocritical bigot?
Bingo.
Aah!
♪ Hallelujah ♪
♪ Hallelujah ♪♪
Hip-hip hoorah!
Yay!
I had such
a good time
last night.
You know, we should
do that more often.
How is Hart? I haven't
seen him all morning.
He didn't say a word
about yesterday.
He's happy.
His wife left this morning
on a two-month cruise.
Lucky her.
She still has to
come back to him,
poor thing.
Let's have
lunch today.
I got to
go shopping.
We're running out
of everything‒
cat food, fish food,
ant spray, rat poison.
Hart wants me to take
papers to his lawyer.
I'll be gone
all afternoon.
Aw, damn it.
When you're away,
that only means
one thing.
Ahh.
Coffee, Violet.
Now.
Yes, sir.
I swear, Betty,
one of these days,
he'll push me too far,
then I'll let him
have it.
I mean,
enough is enough.
We're out of
Skinny and Sweet.
I got some
at lunch today.
Who does he think
he is anyway‒
a miserable, petty,
two-bit dictator,
ordering me around
like I'm
some sort of flunky?
I get so mad
at myself.
I've been
such a nerd.
Violet, he just
does it to annoy you.
Don't let him
get to you.
Besides,
the day's almost over.
You're right.
I tell myself
the same thing,
but the pressure's
building up.
I can't take
much more of this.
Something,
somewhere, sometime
is going to snap,
and then,
God help Mr. Hart,
because I won't
be responsible
for my actions.
Ahh, but right now,
I'm calm,
perfectly calm.
No.
Not for one second.
Right.
Hold it.
Hold it a minute.
I've already
told Bob Enright,
and now
I'm telling you.
When you get
anything at all
from Ajax Warehouse,
you bring it
directly to me.
Got that?
You're the boss.
You might remember that
a little more often.
Ha, ha, ha.
See he caught you.
I'm a tree.
I can bend.
Hang in there, honey.
It's almost 5:00.
Now, you listen to me.
Ajax is my deal.
You get your money
when I give it to you.
Don't ever call me
at this number again.
Jerk.
Doralee. Doralee!
Uhh.
Oh, my goodness.
Mr. Hart.
Mr. Hart!
Oh, Mr. Hart.
Mr. Hart.
Oh, no.
Oh, I'm sorry I'm late.
Violet,
where have you been?
You've missed
all the excitement.
What happened?
They took Hart away
in an ambulance
unconscious.
He had an attack
or something.
He did?
Well, where's Doralee?
Well, she went
with him.
I hope it's
not serious.
Me, neither.
Well, maybe
a little serious.
Some trifle that'll
keep him out for
the next 20 years.
Let's go.
I'll meet you
at the elevator.
Okay.
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God.
Ahh.
Oh.
Violet,
isn't it awful
about Mr. Hart?
How did it happen,
Roz?
Fell and hit his head
on the credenza.
What about
the coffee?
What?
Where is the coffee cup?
Oh, here.
It was by him
on the floor.
He must've been
drinking it
when he blacked out.
What hospital?
St. Ambrose.
Oh.
Oh, my God.
I know you feel.
Aah. Aah.
Judy.
Oh, Judy.
Hurry. Hurry.
What's the matter?
Something terrible's
happened.
You won't
believe it.
I don't believe it.
How could you make
such a stupid mistake?
I thought it was
Skinny and Sweet.
Here, look.
They're identical,
except for
the skull and crossbones
on the label.
Someone's
going to see you.
I've got to
go to the hospital.
They'll have to
pump his stomach.
Don't be hysterical.
You're right.
Keep calm. Keep calm.
You'd better speak
to admitting, ma'am.
Yeah. Right.
My boss was
brought in.
Franklin Hart.
There we go.
What's go‒
What's going on?
Take it easy now.
You blacked out.
How do you feel?
I feel fine.
I fell off a chair
and hit my head.
Uh-huh.
Ooh.
You got quite
a bump there.
I think we'll take you
upstairs for X-rays.
X-rays?
Mm-hmm.
Wait a minute, doc.
I don't want
any X-rays.
I like my head.
We ought to do some tests.
You do tests
on yourself.
I know what you guys
racket is.
You're not
suckering me
into hospital bills,
not for a little
bump on the head.
Hey, doc.
Cardiac arrest.
He stopped breathing.
Open his shirt.
Plug him into
the monitor.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5.
1, 2.
Hurry.
2, 3, 4, 5.
1, 2, 3, 4.
That bum.
He was our
only witness.
We had him all ready
to testify.
Now this.
There's Doralee.
Doralee.
What are you
doing here?
Doralee, something
terrible has happened.
What?
Violet put poison
in Hart's coffee.
It was an accident.
You mean,
that's why‒
It looks just like
Skinny and Sweet.
Good grief.
Where is he?
The emergency room.
First door
on the right.
Oh, my God.
There's a policeman.
What's he doing here?
I don't know.
The guy on the gurney,
how is he?
He's not so good.
Can I speak
to the doctor?
He knows
you're here.
He knows I'm here.
Oh, my God.
They found out already.
Don't panic.
Please don't panic.
How is he, doc?
Ah, he's dead.
Aw.
Oh, my God.
Can you tell
what caused it?
Not without
an autopsy.
You fellows can
come into my office.
I'm fairly certain
it was poison.
Poison?
Ahh.
It's okay.
Easy now.
Poison.
It's all over.
Did you hear‒
an autopsy?
I'll save them the trouble
and give them the poison.
Violet!
You want someone
to see it?
Who cares?
I'm finished.
I'm a murderer.
No, you're not.
I'm a murderess.
My poor kids.
Violet, you're nothing
until proven guilty.
They'll find
the poison when
they do the autopsy.
I'll get rid
of the poison.
of the body.
No, it's not murder.
They're are extenuating
circumstances.
It was an accident.
An accident?
She was thinking
about doing it
last night.
We all thought
about it.
She didn't do it
on purpose.
Oh, maybe
unconsciously I did.
I'm going to the pen.
Let's get
her a lawyer.
I'll be locked up for life.
Where's the phone?
Over there.
Do you have
any change?
I'm going to
lose my job.
Calm down.
I've killed the boss.
You think they're not going to
fire me for that?
Hush. Now just sit here.
We'll be right back.
Oh, medic,
this the guy
for the autopsy?
Yeah.
The doctor would
like to see you.
Right this way.
They're looking for
a second opinion.
I'm going to
go ahead.
So, look, if you can
get it to them by Friday...
Ma'am.
Ohh!
Excuse me. Where's
the coffee shop?
What?
The coffee shop.
The coffee shop?
No. I'm new here.
I'm new here, too.
Where do you work?
Downstairs.
The morgue?
That's right.
He's...
Yes, he is.
How?
Coffee,
too much coffee.
I'm just taking him
out for some air‒
Air for me.
He's coming along
for the ride.
You're a doctor.
I didn't see
your badge.
Sorry.
I'm a doctor.
Why am I talking
to you?
Piss off.
How's Violet?
Oh, honey, I think
Violet has flipped out.
Violet,
what are you doing?
Come on,
get in. Get in.
There's no time
for talking. Get in.
Violet, slow down.
Why are you
driving fast?
They can't
do an autopsy
without a body.
I told you
she's flipped.
She has just
absolutely flipped.
Where is the body?
In the trunk.
We'll get
cement blocks
and pitch him
off the pier.
No one will
ever know.
You're crazy.
They always find it.
Oh, crazy, am I?
They never found
Jimmy Hoffa.
Slow down.
Will you just
slow down?
Let's not panic.
There's a restaurant
up there.
Why don't we pull over
and stop for a bite?
How can you
think of food
at a time like this?
I'm not thinking
of food.
I'm not hungry.
Violet,
we're not criminal.
You're not a criminal.
It was an accident.
Well, we're
criminals now.
We've just
stolen a corpse
from a hospital.
That sounds like
criminal to me.
We'll just turn around
and take it back.
We'll get caught.
You think they'll
listen to us?
Will you please
stop arguing?
Think about
where we can get
some cement.
Look out!
Don't panic. Don't panic.
Aah.
What happened?
She panicked.
Nobody's hurt.
It's just a little accident.
We'll be out
of here in no time.
The front fender's
hitting the tire.
Oh, good Lord. Get out.
Let's look at it.
Oh, that ain't
too bad.
We'll pull
that fender out.
Give me a hand.
Oh, God.
Wait. That's no use.
We need a crowbar
or something.
There's a tire iron
in the trunk.
Judy, turn
the blinkers off.
Uh, Judy, would
you come back here
for a second?
What?
Look.
Who's that?
I don't know.
Where's Hart?
Oh, my God.
You mean, she‒
Oh, my God!
Violet, honey,
would you come over here
for a second?
What is the matter
with you?
We have got
to get the‒
Who is that?
I don't know.
What do you mean
you don't know?
What happened
to Hart's body?
It's not here.
You think it walked away?
But I‒
Violet,
how could you?
How could you?
I guess I must have
made a mistake.
You steal
the wrong body,
and all you can say
is, "I made a mistake."
It could happen
to anyone.
Oh, this is awful.
It's so improper.
It's so disrespectful.
He's dead.
He doesn't mind.
There's nothing to
get excited about.
We'll just take it back.
What?
No harm's done.
We'll take it back.
That's great.
We waltz in there and
say, "we made a mistake."
Maybe they'll give us
Hart's body in exchange.
There's no need
to get sarcastic.
You took it.
You take it back.
Stop it.
We're all
in this together.
Now we have
to be very calm.
We're going to
fix the fender.
We'll go back
to the hospital.
We'll figure
out a plan to
drop off the body.
Then we'll decide
what we're
going to do next.
I tried to tell
this woman‒
Will you two shut up?
It's not a bad plan.
It might work.
If we could just
find a wheelchair.
I saw a couple
outside the emergency
entrance before.
I think
that's a good idea.
I just wish we knew
what happened to Hart.
We're going to
find out soon enough.
What's that?
It's a siren.
It's a policeman.
He wants us
to pull over.
Do I make
a break for it?
I've got my gun.
Are you crazy?
Oh, my God.
Don't panic.
What does he want?
I don't know.
Pull over.
Be ready for anything.
Listen to what he says
and don't panic.
But what if he wants‒
For Christ's sake,
pull over! Pull over!
Good evening, ladies.
May I see
your license and
registration, please?
Why? I wasn't speeding.
I didn't say
you were.
Your taillight
is blinking.
It is?
Are your signals on?
No.
There's a short
in the trunk.
A short in the trunk?
We've got a short
in the trunk.
Probably just
a defective wire.
You want
to take a look?
Do we want
No, we can't, Officer.
We don't have time.
We're on an emergency.
That's‒that's right.
She's a doctor.
Oh, you're
a doctor?
What do think I am,
a beautician?
I didn't see
your badge.
What's
the trouble?
I'm taking this woman
to the hospital,
and she's sick.
Which one
of you is sick?
I am.
She is.
They're both sick.
What is that
you're hiding there?
What? This?
Yes.
It's rat poison.
She ate it.
What?
She ate
the rat poison.
That's why they're sick.
You ate the rat poison?
I thought it was
Skinny and Sweet.
It looks just like
Skinny and Sweet,
except for the little
skull and crossbones
on the label.
Can we go now,
Officer?
I'm not feeling very well.
Did you hear that?
She's not feeling
very well.
I've got a dying woman,
and you want to look
for a short.
I'm sorry.
If we don't
make it on time,
I'm holding you
responsible.
Don't worry.
I'll give you
an escort.
An escort?
He's going to
give us an escort.
Oh, Lord.
Hang on‒
Forget it, Mac.
We can't wait.
How did it go?
I couldn't find out
about Hart.
They don't know,
or they won't tell us.
What are we
going to do?
Nothing.
We're going to wait
until they come to us.
Go to the office
in the morning
and pretend like
nothing has happened.
Well, what about
the other matter?
Don't worry about it.
It's been taken care of.
Hey, Viv.
We got another stiff
in the john.
Morning, Judy.
Morning, Violet.
Doralee, uh,
no calls this morning.
I don't want to be
disturbed at all.
All that running
around last night
was useless.
Hart left with
a little bump
on his head.
I did put the poison
in the coffee.
I know it.
Well, he absolutely
did not drink it, Violet.
How could we
be so stupid?
Did anybody
think to look
under the stalls.
Yes. Yes.
And there's nobody there.
Look, I propose we forget
the whole thing.
It never happened.
That's okay with me.
I'll never
mention it again.
Thank God
it's Friday.
Why don't we start
the weekend
with a drink
at Charlie's?
You know,
we are so lucky.
I'm glad this whole
mess is finally over.
Oh, me, too.
Is this accurate?
They actually
said this?
Clearly as I could
make out.
My notes were
a little fuzzy.
Well, this is
very interesting.
Stealing corpses,
eluding the police.
May-Maybe they knew
you were hiding,
just‒just pulling
your leg.
I don't think so.
In any event, I think
you should be aware of
that coffee business.
Yeah. I think
I can use that
to some advantage.
Whoo! Look out,
Charlie's,
here we come.
Oh, Judy.
Wait just a second.
I'll be right back.
I'll‒I'll tell Violet.
It's 5:00, Mr. Hart.
You wanted to see me?
I did, Doralee.
I'd like you to come over
to my house tonight.
I'm not working
tonight.
This is Friday.
Who said anything
about work?
Oh, uh, by the way,
have you ever
heard of strychnine?
Strychnine
is a poison, I think.
Yes, it is a poison.
I just talked to
the hospital.
They found
traces of strychnine
when they pumped out
my stomach yesterday.
What? You told me
you just hit your head.
I had to be sure.
I think you need
evidence like that
if you're going to
accuse somebody of murder.
Murder?
Yeah.
You and Violet
and that girl Judy
tried to murder me
yesterday.
Put the rat poison
in my coffee.
Oh, my goodness.
I don't believe this.
It was all a big mistake.
That's very good.
You should be scared,
because I know
all about it.
All I have to do
is call the police.
It really
was a mistake.
Violet put the poison in
strictly by accident.
She might get a jury
to believe that.
Then again, she might not.
But the big question here
is whether or not
you want to take
that chance.
What are you
driving at?
It's very simple.
You come over
to my house,
and I'll forget
the whole thing.
You are disgusting.
Is that a no?
Too bad.
Mr. Hart,
I'm begging you,
think about
what you're doing.
I didn't start this.
You three girls
did all the plotting.
I won't let you
do this!
There's another phone
over there, Doralee.
Incidentally,
that's something else
you might want
to think about.
I'm very funny,
but I don't like it
when people give back
my presents.
Oh, you are rotten,
Mr. Hart.
Did anybody
ever tell you that?
I never thought
I'd say this about
another human being,
but you are evil‒
evil to the core!
I love it when you
get mad like that.
If you touch that phone,
I'll jerk it
clean out of the wall.
Ooh...
I mean it!
You think this
is all a joke.
You're going to
listen to me
whether you like it
or not!
Will you shut up now
and let me explain
what happened?
Let me loose
or I'm calling for help.
No, I don't want you
to call for help.
You won't listen,
but you'll shut up
and stay there!
I got to figure out
what to do.
Roz.
Is Mr. Hart in?
Yeah‒well, yeah,
but he's tied up
at the moment.
Oh. Well...
I guess it can wait
until Monday.
Have a nice weekend.
Yeah, you, too, Roz.
Oh, Judy.
Can you come here
a second?
You ready, Doralee?
No! Something awful
has happened.
Where's Violet?
She's in
the storage room.
What's the matter?
Hart knows everything
about last night.
What?
He really thinks
we were trying to kill him.
He was going to
have us arrested.
Oh, dear God.
Get in there
and watch him.
Lock that door,
and don't let
anybody in.
I'm getting Violet.
Oh, dear God.
Mr. Hart, I'm so sorry.
What?
Oh, I can't understand
what you're saying.
Thank God one of you
has come to your senses.
Now get me loose.
Doralee didn't mean
any harm, Mr. Hart.
Just get me untied, okay?
I can't do that
until they come back.
You think
I'm going to run away?
I won't do anything.
I give you
my word of honor.
Just get me untied.
There's a little pain
involved here.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Maybe I'll just
loosen it a little bit.
Good. Loosen it.
You've got to understand
what happened last night.
It was just a series
of misunderstandings.
Violet didn't mean
to kill you.
She just accidentally
put rat poison
in your coffee.
Get out of my way!
Mr. Hart.
Mr. Hart,
you gave me your word!
I lied.
God damn it.
You're not leaving
this office.
Watch me.
I was just pretending
a while ago,
but this thing
is getting out of hand.
Nobody makes a fool
out of me
in my own office.
I'm calling the police.
Hold it right there.
You're as crazy
as the other two.
Close that door
or I'll shoot.
Aah!
Hold it! Don't shoot!
I give up!
Don't shoot it!
Judy, put it‒
Judy, what are you doing?
Oh, my God.
Christ.
He‒He was going
to call the police.
I just feel terrible
doing this to him.
We'll get him to his place
and try to reason with him.
His wife's on vacation,
and that house
is so far off the road,
if he yells,
ain't nobody gonna hear him.
So what do we do now?
You'll pay for this.
I swear you'll pay for this.
If you'd only listen.
You listen to me.
I'll see you all in prison
before I'm through.
Kidnapping.
Attempted murder.
Roped, beaten,
rat poison.
I won't rest
until you all get
20 years in prison!
You understand that?
20 years!
God!
We can't just
keep him here forever.
Oh, you heard him.
He don't believe us.
He wants
to prosecute.
Why wouldn't he?
He's got you
for poisoning him
and me for roping him
and you for acting like
he was first prize
in a turkey shoot.
How are we going
to keep him from talking?
I say we hire
a couple of wranglers
to go upstairs
and beat the shit
out of him.
If we could only
find something on him,
maybe we could trade off.
Blackmail.
All that sounds good.
What could we
get on him?
A sex scandal.
Take a picture of him
in bed with a prostitute.
Oh, who would care?
Hart would just
buy up the copies
and send them out
as Christmas cards.
Oh, Lord.
We've gone over
everything.
Well, we might
as well face it.
He's got us.
We're licked.
Wait a minute.
What's this doing here?
What?
Maybe we do have something
to bargain with after all.
What is it?
An account book
for Ajax Warehouse.
There's
something suspicious
going on here.
This is out
in the middle of nowhere.
What do you see?
Nothing.
It's too dark.
Why don't you
climb up to that window?
I think we got him.
Ha, ha, ha!
I think we got him!
Aah!
Whoo! Yes, indeed,
it looks like Frank
has been a very
naughty boy.
An empty warehouse?
What's wrong with that?
That's what
Billie Sol Estes
said,
and they gave him
15 years
for embezzlement.
That warehouse
is supposed to be
filled with inventory
from Consolidated.
But you sold it
and pocketed the money.
You can't prove that.
I'm going to order
the invoices
from head office,
on Monday.
I think you'll...
see the light
when they arrive.
You start tangling with me,
you'd better be prepared
to play very rough,
because I'm not
going to be stopped
by three
dumb-witted broads.
I'm not‒
I'm going to get loose.
I'm going to break loose
if I have to kill somebody
to do it.
To keep him tied up
three of four days,
we need a better
system of confinement.
Yes. Something that
limits his movement,
but it should
wear well
and be comfortable.
We figure you'll
sign our statement
by the end of the week,
and then we'll
be able to let you go.
I got all the razors
and the scissors
and all the glass,
just in case.
I brought you
some books and magazines.
This one is really good.
This'll keep you
up-to-date on all
the soap operas.
Once you watch them,
you really get hooked.
And I got you cigars.
Judy will stay at night,
Doralee will bring
your lunch,
and in the daytime,
we have this little
security system.
I paid for it
on your
Master Charge.
You're out of your mind.
You think you can
keep me here for a week?
For Christ's sake,
I'm the boss.
Don't you think I might
be missed at the office?
Franklin Hart's office.
No, he's, uh, not here
right now.
Can I help you?
Yes, Mr. Strell.
Judy Bernly. Please hold.
Hello. Judy Bernly.
Hey, Violet.
What can I
do you for, Bob?
Would you look at this?
I can't make it out.
But, Doralee,
I want to talk
to him today.
Well, I will tell him.
He's not here.
He's not? Well,
that's kind of funny.
I thought he was.
Well, he hasn't
gone to lunch.
His coat's still here.
Look at that.
I've told him
a hundred times
this can be
very dangerous.
I'm sure
he'll be back, Roz.
You want to wait?
No, thank you,
but please tell him
it's very important
I talk to him
sometime today.
I will "soitenly"
tell him, Roz.
She is going
to be tough.
Hmm.
What about the others?
Piece of cake.
There were a few
questions we need
answered from‒
Yeah, I saw those.
And some letters
you should see,
but other than that
I think we're fine.
Did you want
a cup of coffee?
Oh. Sorry.
Hello, Mr. Hart.
It's lunch.
Where's the tray stand
that was here yesterday?
Oh, uh, it's behind
that pile of stuff
over there.
Aah!
Doralee!
Damn it!
I'll get your ass!
Promise.
I don't understand.
Did you give him
my message?
Yes, but he left the office
just this second.
But I'll bet you can
still catch him.
Judy!
Do you see Mr. Hart?
Uh, yes.
Well, stop him.
Mr. Hart!
Mr.‒
Oh, you just
missed him.
Mmm.
We can't keep that up
all week.
You're right.
She's going
to be a problem.
I've got
some bad news.
Here's the telex
from head office
in New York.
They've started
the computer changeover.
They won't be able
to send us
the inventory invoices
for Ajax Warehouse
for another
four to six weeks.
Four to six weeks?
We have to keep Hart
tied up all that time?
Do we have a choice?
I think we can
pull it off.
I never realized
how unpopular
Hart is.
Nobody wants
to see him
face-to-face.
Except Roz.
What if we sent Roz
on vacation?
That's only two weeks.
We've got to
keep her away longer.
Have you ever
heard of the Aspen
Language Center?
It's one
of these places
that gives you very
concentrated lessons
in foreign languages.
Why don't we
send her there?
You know,
that's not half bad.
We could get Hart
to write her
that it's top-secret.
Consolidated is opening
overseas centers,
and they need executives
who can...
I don't know‒
Speak French.
Do you think
she'd go?
Are you kidding?
If Hart asked her to?
Bonjour.
Hmm.
It was just so easy.
I just typed up this memo
and signed Hart's name.
She doesn't get back
until the 15th,
and Missy doesn't return
until the 24th.
Don't you feel sorry
for Missy?
I'll have Hart
send her some flowers
in Tahiti.
How's everything
upstairs?
Very subdued.
I think he's
plotting something.
It's going to be
a race
to see if he can
get free
before we
get the invoices,
sometime around here.
While I'm at it,
I'll just have Hart
let everybody
keep flowers
on their desks.
Change some things
around that office.
Some of those rules of his
are so depressing.
It's looking good.
But why don't we
make some changes
that really count?
Yeah.
Like sands
through the hourglass,
so are the
days of our lives.
I'm happy to see
you still have
a hearty appetite.
And I'll see you
tomorrow.
If you keep being
a good boy,
you'll be out of here
the end of the week.
Aah!
Dick.
Can I come in?
Thanks.
It's cold out there.
Dick, what are you
doing here?
You're supposed to be
in Mexico.
I was.
I came back.
Dick,
you can't stay here.
You're here alone,
aren't you?
W-Well, yes. I'm...
house-sitting
for a friend.
Yeah. I've been
casing the house
the last few days to make sure.
You could spare
a cup of coffee
for your freezing
old husband,
couldn't you?
Ex-husband.
Well, all right.
You sit down,
but then you're going
to have to go.
It was no good
from the start.
Nothing worked.
She left
after the first week.
Maybe you could
call me tomorrow
at work
and we could
have lunch,
talk some more.
I've wanted to see you.
I followed you
from the office.
I thought maybe
you were living
with someone.
No.
What was that?
Oh, it's nothing.
Probably the cat.
I'd better check.
I'll go with you.
It's all right.
I'll be right back.
Judy, you look
beautiful as ever.
Thanks.
Holy shit!
Oh!
Oh, my God.
Let go of me!
Get away from me!
Hey!
Oh! Hey!
Stay away!
I'll kill you!
Let go!
Help!
Judy?
Dick.
Let me down!
When I get
my hands on you‒
Judy.
You shut up!
What's going on?
Nothing.
Who's in that room?
Nobody.
Let's go downstairs.
Judy, there's somebody
in that room. Let me see.
Good God.
Oh.
Who is that?
A friend.
Obviously.
So, that's what
you're into now. Bondage.
What's that?
Bondage. S and M.
Sex games.
That's right.
I'm into everything.
Now get out of here.
I can't believe it.
Who is that guy?
He's my boss.
An affair with your boss.
Isn't that typical!
Just like you had one
with your secretary.
But, Judy, this isn't you.
You can't be serious.
Don't tell me
what I can or can't do.
Those days are over!
And if I want
to have an affair
or play sex games
or do M&Ms,
you can't stop me!
M&Ms?
Matter of fact,
I smoke pot.
I see what
it's done to you!
Well, I've changed.
I'll say. And not
for the better!
And I came here
tonight to ask you
to come back... Ha!
Fat chance.
Your leaving was
the best thing that
ever happened to me.
If that's
the way you feel,
there's
nothing more to say.
Oh, yes, there is.
Hit the road, buster.
This is where you get off.
What are we going
to do about Roz?
She gets back on Friday.
Well, if she causes
any more trouble,
we'll send her back
to language school
to learn German.
Bet she would.
Talking about Roz?
Forget her. I just
talked to New York.
The invoices will
be here Friday morning.
Perfect, three more days.
Ooh, good.
Uh, driver, would you
bring the bags inside,
please?
Missy.
Frank.
What on earth
are you up to?
Operator?
Uh, good morning.
Uh, would you find
a number for me, please?
Hello?
Doralee,
this is Missy Hart.
Missy.
Frank told me
never to call anybody
at the office,
so I'm calling
you at home.
I wanted to thank you.
Thank me?
I just realized
it must have been you
who sent me
those beautiful flowers
during my trip.
And you signed
Frank's name.
Well, it was his idea.
Oh, no, no, no.
It wasn't. I asked him.
That's why
I came back early...
Missy, did you just say
you've come back?
Yeah, three days ago.
Frank sent me to a hotel
for another week.
He's trying out
some kind of new exercise
program at the house.
Oh, my goodness.
You should see what
he's done to our bedroom.
Hello? Hello?
Hello.
What?
I don't believe it.
If she's back, then Hart
must've been free
for the last three days.
Listen, call Judy
right away.
If Hart's been doing
what I think he's been doing,
we've been had.
That's silly. I just
brought him breakfast.
He's tied up.
Or he's just pretending.
Look, you keep
ahold of my gun.
I'm coming over.
Sit tight till I get there.
Judy?
Judy.
He found your gun.
Wait a minute.
What happened
to the time clock?
You retired it.
What does
that mean?
Well, while
you were away,
we managed
to make a few changes.
Changes? What changes?
Holy shit.
What the hell
is going on?
Who authorized this?
You did, Mr. Hart.
It's your signature.
What are all these
people doing here?
It's not even 9:00.
It's another
of your programs.
It's called
flexible hours.
People set
their own time.
Some work
8:00 to 4:00
or 10:00 to 6:00
or 9:00 to 5:00.
Well, I'll put
a stop to that.
Let's go, girls.
Let's go.
Sir, it's working
very nicely.
Less absenteeism.
People really like it.
Oh, do they?
Well, I hate it,
and what I say goes.
Just keep going
to my office.
Good morning, Violet.
Here it is.
Oh, thanks, Eric.
Here are the invoices
we've been waiting for.
They're worthless now.
He's managed to put
all that missing equipment
back into the warehouse.
Cost me a pretty penny
to set it straight.
Well, you've won.
You've trumped our ace.
So now what?
Oh, I'm sorry, Violet.
Why don't you
sit down there?
I'm just getting ready
to send you three
bitches to jail.
Hello.
What?
Who's here?
Jeez,
I'll be right out.
And you better
tell Hart.
What?
When?
Holy shit.
No, no. No problem.
Okay, right. Thanks.
What is it?
Tinsworthy's here.
Who's that?
Russell Tinsworthy,
the goddamn
chairman of the board.
He's here to meet
with me.
All right, just...
Violet, you've
got to stand by me.
Holy shit,
there he is.
Here's the man himself,
Mr. Tinsworthy.
Franklin Hart.
Frank Hart.
My boy, I would like
to shake your hand.
And here is a, uh,
small token
of my esteem.
Thank you, sir.
It's an honor
meeting you.
You know, I don't
get up here very often.
But I keep tabs
on the situation
through Perkins.
And when I find
a division
that shows a 20% rise
in productivity
over a period
of six weeks,
I want to meet the man
who's responsible.
Huh, well, I...
We all appreciate that.
You've managed to create
a very, very splendid
environment here.
Very livable,
very personal.
Well, I find it very...
I don't know.
The people seem
to like it.
Keep the crew happy
and you can't go wrong,
eh, Frank?
That's the idea, sir.
Mr. Tinsworthy's
interested in
some of those other
new programs of yours.
Uh-huh.
Like the job-sharing program.
Job-sharing.
A bold concept.
How's it working out?
Well, I think
very well, sir.
Um... well, Violet.
Sorry, Mr. Tinsworthy.
I'd like you to meet
Violet Newstead.
She's my senior supervisor.
I'm very happy
to meet you.
How do you do?
I've heard a lot of
wonderful things
about you.
Thank you.
Violet is my right arm
around here.
In fact, Violet,
explain to Mr. Tinsworthy
the job-sharing situation.
It's been most effective,
Mr. Tinsworthy.
Maria Delgado
is a perfect example.
She shares her job
with another worker
who takes over
in the afternoon.
She does?
I mean, she does.
Both women are happy,
and we couldn't
be more pleased
with their
performance.
So you
pulled it off?
Well, I like
to think we did.
Good. Like
the day care center.
Day care center?
That reminds me,
during the war,
I set up day care centers
in all
the defense plants.
Glad you
brought it back.
That's the idea.
It...
The day care center...
Would you like to see it?
It's just down the hall.
Thank you. I can see
why Frank reposes
such trust in you.
Ha, ha. Exactly.
Thank you.
Violet...
Our day care center
has been open two weeks.
It's been wonderfully
successful.
Really?
Yes, our working
parents love it.
Oh, Mr. Hart. It's so
good to see you again.
Who are you?
Don't you recognize me?
Margaret Foster.
The old lush?
Yes! That was me.
But thanks
to the company's
alcoholics rehabilitation
program you started,
those days are over.
I'll never forget
those wonderful letters
of encouragement you sent.
God bless you,
Mr. Hart.
Good to see you.
Doesn't she look great?
Hold this.
When we transformed it,
the cost was minimal.
It's cut down on absenteeism,
and we loved doing it.
Well, Frank, I got
to give you credit.
You really
pulled it off.
That equal pay thing, though,
that's, uh, got to go.
Oh, yes.
It's a good incentive,
but we don't need to keep on
priming the pump.
I've been talking
to Hinkle over here.
Here, take her.
And, uh, you're my kind
of guy, Frank.
Creative, incisive,
get the job done.
Right, sir.
Now, I want you
to work with me.
Excuse me?
I need a man
like you, Frank.
A Brazilian operation
is just about to take off.
Brazil, sir?
You're going to
love it down there.
You'll get
a handsome bonus,
and you'll be
doing me a big favor.
Yes, but, how can
I move to Brazil?
Take a leave of absence.
Right, Hinkle?
Anything you say, R.T.
We'll go upstairs
and work this thing out.
My team needs you
right away.
Mr. Tinsworthy,
I appreciate this.
Teamwork, teamwork.
That's what
it's all about, huh?
Go where you're
most needed
when you're most needed.
Mr. Tinsworthy,
the jungle...
Hell, man! I'm offering you
the chance of a lifetime.
Two or three years there,
you'll never want
to come back.
Two or three years?
Yeah, you'll love it
down there.
Healthy climate.
Mr. Tinsworthy.
Hart!
Let me tell you
one thing.
I ain't the kind of boy
takes no for an answer.
Yes, sir.
Brazil?
Did you see the look
on his face?
I almost felt
sorry for him.
We actually
pulled it off.
And we didn't panic.
And Tinsworthy
loved what we did.
Everything except
that part about the money.
What'll we do
about that?
We've come this far,
haven't we?
This is just
the beginning.
And here's
to the beginning.
I'll drink to that.
To the beginning.
Monsieur Hart.
Holy merde.
Ah! God damn it!
♪ Working nine to five ♪
♪ What a way to make a livin ' ♪
♪ Barely gettin ' by ♪
♪ It's all takin ' and no givin ' ♪
♪ They just use your mind ♪
♪ And they never give you credit ♪
♪ It's enough to drive you ♪
♪ Crazy if you let it ♪
♪ Nine to five ♪
♪ For service and devotion ♪
♪ You would think that I ♪
♪ Would deserve a fair promotion ♪
♪ Want to move ahead ♪
♪ But the boss won't seem to let me ♪
♪ I swear sometimes ♪
♪ That man is out to get me ♪
♪ Nine to five ♪
♪ Yeah, they got you
where they want you ♪
♪ There's a better life ♪
♪ And you think about it, don't you? ♪
♪ It's a rich man's game ♪
♪ No matter what they call it ♪
♪ And you spend your life ♪
♪ Puttin ' money in his wallet ♪
♪ Nine to five ♪
♪ What a way to make a livin ' ♪
♪ Barely gettin ' by ♪
♪ It's all takin ' and no giving ♪
♪ Want to move ahead ♪
♪ But the boss won't seem to let me ♪
♪ I swear sometimes ♪
♪ That man is out to get me ♪
♪ Nine to five ♪♪