There's a bright golden
haze on the meadow
The corn is as high
as an elephant's eye
And it looks like it's
climbin' clear up to the sky
Oh, what a beautiful morning
Oh, what a beautiful day
I got a beautiful feeling
Everything's goin' my way
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
All the sounds of the
earth are like music
The breeze is so busy
it don't miss a tree
And a ol' weepin' willer
is laughin' at me
Oh, what a beautiful morning
Oh, what a beautiful day
I got a beautiful feeling
Everything's goin' my way
Oh, what a beautiful day
(ROOSTER CROWS)
(CHICKENS CLUCKING)
- Hi, Aunt Eller!
- Don't scare me to death.
- What you doin' around here?
- I come a-singin' to you.
Oh, what a beautiful morning
Oh, what a beautiful day
I got a beautiful feeling
Everything's goin' my way
If I wasn't an old woman, and if you
wasn't so young and smart-alecky,
why, I'd marry you and get you to
sit around at night and sing to me.
No, you wouldn't neither, 'cause I wouldn't
marry you nor none of your kinfolk.
- If I could help it.
- Oh, none of my kinfolks, huh?
And you can tell 'em
that too. All of 'em.
Including that niece of
your'n, Miss Laurey Williams.
Who you takin' to the
box social tonight?
I ain't thought much about it yet.
- Bet you come over to ask Laurey.
- What if I did?
You askin' me too?
I'll wear my fascinator.
- Yeah, you too.
- Yeah, yeah.
Oh, what a beautiful morning
Oh, what a beautiful day
I thought you were somebody.
I got a beautiful feeling
Everything's goin' my way
Is this all that's come a-callin' at
already 8:00 this Saturday morning?
You knowed it was me
before you opened the door.
- No such of a thing.
- Well, you did too.
You heared my voice.
You knowed it was me.
I heared someone singing
like a bullfrog in a pond.
You knowed it was me, so you set in
there, thinkin' up something mean to say.
I'm a good mind not to
ask you to the box social.
- Oh, you two.
- If you asked me, I wouldn't go with you.
Besides, how'd you take me?
You ain't bought a new buggy with
red wheels onto it, have you?
No, I ain't.
A spankin' team with their
bridles all a-jinglin'?
No.
Expect me to ride on
behind ol' Blue I guess.
You better ask that old Cummings
girl you took such a shine to.
If I was to ask you, Miss Laurey
smarty, there'd be a way to take ya.
Oh, there would?
How'd we get there?
When I take you out tonight with me
Honey, here's the way it's gonna be
You will set behind a team
of snow-white horses
In the slickest gig you ever see
Chicks and ducks
and geese better scurry
When I take you out in the surrey
When I take you out in the
surrey with the fringe on top
Watch that fringe
and see how it flutters
When I drive them
high-steppin' strutters
Nosy pokes'll peek
through their shutters
And their eyes'll pop
The wheels are yeller
the upholstery's brown
The dashboard's genuine leather
With isinglass curtains
you can roll right down
In case there's
a change in the weather
Two bright sidelights
winkin' and blinkin'
Ain't no finer rig I'm a-thinkin'
You can keep your rig
if you're thinkin'
That I'd "keer" to swap
For that shiny little surrey
with the fringe on the top
Would you say the fringe
was made of silk
(LAUGHS)
Wouldn't have
no other kind but silk
Has it really got a team
of snow-white horses
One's like snow
The other's more like milk
All the world will fly in a flurry
When I take you out in the surrey
When I take you out in the
surrey with the fringe on top
When we hit that road
hell for leather
Cats and dogs'll
dance in the heather
Birds and frogs'll
sing all together
And the toads will hop
The wind'll whistle
as we rattle along
The cows'll moo in the clover
The river will ripple out
a whispered song
And whisper it over and over
(SOFTLY) Don't you wish
you'd go on forever
Don't you wish you'd go on forever
And it'd never stop
In that shiny little surrey
with the fringe on the top
You'd sure feel like a queen
settin' up in that carriage.
Only she talked to me
so mean a while back,
- I'm a good mind not to take her.
- I ain't said I was goin'.
- Well, I ain't asked ya.
- Where'd you get such a rig at?
I'll bet he's went and hired a rig over
at Claremore, thinkin' I'd go with him.
I did not hire it. I made the
whole thing up out of my head.
- What? Made it up?
- Dashboard and all.
(LAUGHING)
Get off the place, you!
Aunt Eller, make him get hisself
out of here! Tellin' me lies.
Now hold on. Makin' up a few "purties"
ain't agin no law I know of.
Besides, don't you wish
there was such a rig though?
You could go to the play party and do a
hoedown till morning if you was a mind to.
Then when you was all wore out,
why, I'd just lift you onto the surrey,
jump up alongside you, and we'd
just point the horses home.
I can just picture the whole thing.
I can see the stars gettin' blurry
When we ride back home
in the surrey
Ridin' slowly home in the surrey
With the fringe on top
I can feel the day gettin' older
Feel a sleepy head near my shoulder
Noddin', droopin'
close to my shoulder
Till it falls, kerplop
The sun is swimmin'
on the rim of a hill
The moon is takin' a header
And just as I'm thinkin'
all the earth is still
A lark'll wake up in the medder
Hush, you bird my baby's a-sleepin'
Maybe got a dream worth a-keepin'
Whoa, you team and
just keep a-creepin'
At a slow clip-clop
Don't you hurry with the surrey
With the fringe
On the
Top
- Only... Only there ain't no such rig.
- Well...
Why'd you come around here with
your stories and your lies,
gettin' me all worked up?
Who'd wanna ride
alongside of you anyway?
Why don't you grab her and kiss her
when she acts that a-way, Curly?
- She's just aching for you to, I bet.
- I won't even speak to him,
let alone allow him to kiss me...
the braggin', bowlegged,
wished-he'd-had-a-sweetheart bum!
She likes you quite a lot.
She liked me any more,
she'd sic the dogs onto me.
- Hello, Jud.
- Hello, yourself.
Listen, who's the low filthy sneak
Laurey's got her cap set for?
- You.
- Never mind that.
There must be plenty of
men a-tryin' to spark her.
- Plenty.
- What about him?
Oh, she wouldn't take up
with a fella like that,
that bullet-colored,
growly hired hand.
Now, don't you go say
nothin' agin Jud.
Best hired hand I ever had.
Just about runs
the farm by hisself.
Well, two women couldn't do it.
You oughta know 'at.
He's around all the time, ain't he?
Takes his meals with you and
sleeps down in the smokehouse.
I changed my mind about
cleaning the henhouse today.
I gotta quit early 'cause I'm driving
Laurey to the party tonight.
- You're driving Laurey?
- I asked her.
Well, wouldn't that
just make you bawl?
Don't forget, Aunt Eller. You and
me still got a date together.
How we going, Curly,
in that rig you made up?
That there ain't
no made-up rig, you hear?
I done hired it over to Claremore.
- Why don't you go with him?
- I can't. I promised Jud.
Why ever did you?
'Cause Curly's too fresh
and too bigheaded,
waitin' till
the last minute to ask me.
Aunt Eller, are you really
going with Curly tonight?
I sure am. You didn't want him.
But you could go with me and Jud.
You picked your feller,
I picked mine.
That's the way
you want it, ain't it?
You're sure a pair.
Crazy young'uns.
Time I started for the station.
Hey, Curly. Tell all the
folks to stop by here
on their way to the Skidmore
party to freshen up.
I will, Aunt Eller. You see you got
your beauty spots fastened on proper,
so as you won't lose
them off, you hear?
That's a right smart turnout.
Ain't no finer rig I'm a-thinkin'
That I'd keer to swap
For that shiny little surrey
With the fringe on the top
(WHEELS RATTLING)
Aunt Eller!
Lookin' for me?
Gonna be a nice evenin'
for the party.
- Jud.
- What?
I don't think I can...
You ain't figurin' on goin'
with someone else, are you?
Well, I...
Laurey!
I'll come by for you
along around about sundown.
(TRAIN CHUGGING)
(DOG BARKING)
(BELL RINGING)
(CHATTERING)
What'd you do up at the
fair, Will? Bust any bones?
Aw, too smart for that. Just
made sure I landed on my head.
- Will Parker.
- Hi, Aunt Eller.
If you ain't got them fancy
lanterns for the Skidmore party,
- get back on that train.
- (LAUGHS)
- Here you are.
- You do any good in the steer ropin', Will?
Oh, I did pretty good.
I won prize money.
- That's my boy.
- I've got to get over to Ado Annie's.
Her pa said I could have her
if'n I was ever worth $50.
And I got that $50.
If Annie's pa keeps his promise,
we'll be dancin' at your wedding.
If'n he don't, I'll take her
right from under his nose.
Besides which, I won't give him
the present I brung for him.
Looky here, fellas, what I
got for Ado Annie's pa.
Excuse us, Aunt Eller. You hold
it up to your eye like this, see.
Then when you get a good look, you turn it
around at the top and the picture changes.
- Well, I'll be "sidegated."
- They call it the Little Wonder.
Silly goats!
The hussy!
Ought to be ashamed of herself.
You too. How do you turn the
thing to see the other picture?
- Right at the top, Aunt Eller.
- Wait, I'm gettin' it.
(GASPS)
(LAUGHS)
I'm a good mind
to tell Annie on you.
Bet you carried on
plenty in Kansas City.
Well, I sure did see a lot of
things I never did see before.
I got to Kansas City on a Friday
By Saturday I learned
a thing or two
'Cause up to then
I didn't have an idy
Of what the modren world
was comin' to
I counted 20 gas buggies
goin' by theirselves
Almost every time I took a walk
And then I put my ear
to a Bell telephone
And a strange woman
started in to talk
- To you
- What next
- Yeah, what
Everything's up to date
in Kansas City
They've gone about
as "fur" as they can go
They went and built a
skyscraper seven stories high
'Bout as high as
a buildin' oughta grow
Everything's like a dream
in Kansas City
It's better
than a magic lantern show
You can turn the radiator on
whenever you want some heat
With every kind of comfort
every house is all complete
You can walk to privies in the
rain and never wet your feet
They've gone about as fur
as they can go
Yes, sir
They've gone about as fur as they can go
Everything's up to date
in Kansas City
They've gone about as fur
as they can go
They got a big theater
they call a bur-lee-que
- For 50 cents you can see a dandy show
- Gals
- One of the gals is fat and pink and pretty
- Aha!
As round above
as she was round below
I could swear that she was padded
from her shoulder to her heel
And then she started dancin'
and her dancin' made me feel
That every single thing
she had was absolutely real
She went about as fur
as she could go
Yes, sir
She went about as fur as she could go
- What you doin', Will?
- Well, this is called a two-step.
That's all they're dancing nowadays.
Why, the waltz is through.
Of course, they don't do it
alone. Come on, Aunt Eller!
- Oh, that's about as fur as I can go
- Yes, sir
And that's about as
fur as she can go
- What you doing now, Will?
- Well, this here's called ragtime.
I seen a couple actors doin' it.
- Don't like it.
- Oh, Will, I do!
(HORSE NICKERS)
Still don't like it.
Come on, Aunt Eller, do-si-do!
Hey, ha, pick it up!
(CHATTERING)
Hey! Ha ha!
- Hyah!
- Ho!
(CHATTERING)
- Ha!
- Yahoo!
Hey there, Will Parker!
Come back here!
- (BELL RINGING)
- (TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
- GIRLS: Oh!
- (BELL RINGING)
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS)
(BELL CLANGING)
Ado Annie, I could ride with you
like this to the end of the world.
Please, Mr. Hakim,
don't start talkin' purty.
Laurey! Yoo-hoo! Laurey!
Whoa!
Laurey!
- Hello, Laurey.
- What you doing with that peddler-man?
- Will Parker gets back today.
- Will Parker. Oh, foot.
- I didn't count on today being Saturday.
- I can see that.
My, oh, my, Miss Laurey!
"Jippity" crickets.
Last time I come through here, you was
teeny like a shrimp with freckles.
Now look on you.
Quit a-bitin' me! If you ain't had no
breakfast, go eat yourself a green apple.
Are you coming in or going out?
Standing still while you're here.
Go up to the house and wait.
It'll be no trouble
at all to wait right here.
So much water.
Why don't we all
take a swim together?
In Persia, where I come from,
bathing is a social event.
- Well, this ain't Persia!
- I can already see you two young ladies
in those beautiful
Persian bathing suits.
What do they wear when they
bathe socially in Persia?
- Nothing.
- Nothing. Oh!
The peddler-man's gonna
drive me to the box social.
I got up sort of a tasty lunch.
But you're promised
to Will Parker, ain't ya?
Oh, ain't what you might say,
promised. I just told him maybe.
Don't you like Will no more?
Of course I do. There won't
never be nobody like Will.
Then what about this peddler-man?
Oh, there won't never be
nobody like him neither.
Well, you gotta make up your mind.
Which one do you like the best?
- Well, whatever one I'm with.
- Well, you are a silly.
Well, now, Laurey, you know that nobody
paid me no mind up till this year
on account I was scrawny
and flat as a beanpole.
But then I kinda
rounded up a little
- and now the boys act different to me.
- What's wrong with that?
Nothing's wrong. I like it!
I like it so much when a
fella talks pretty to me,
I get all shaky from horn to hoof.
- Don't you?
- Can't think what you're talking about.
Don't you feel kinda sorry for a fella
when he looks like he wants to kiss ya?
Well, you can't just go around
kissing every man that asks ya.
Didn't anyone tell you that?
Yeah, they told me.
It ain't so much a question
Of not knowin' what to do
I knowed what's right and
wrong since I been 10
I heared a lot of stories
And I reckon they are true
About how girls are put upon by men
I know I mustn't fall into the pit
But when I'm with a feller
I fergit
I'm just a girl who cain't say no
I'm in a terrible fix
I always say come on, let's go
Just when I oughta say nix
When a person tries to kiss a girl
I know she oughta
give his face a smack
But as soon as someone kisses me
I somehow sorta wanna kiss him back
I'm just a fool when lights are low
I cain't be prissy and quaint
I ain't the type that can faint
How can I be what I ain't
I cain't
Say no
What you gonna do
when a fella gets flirty
And starts to talk purty
What you gonna do
Supposin' that he says that
your lips are like cherries
Or roses or berries
What you gonna do
Supposin' that he says that
you're sweeter 'an cream
And he's gotta have cream or die
What you gonna do
when he talks that way
Spit in his eye
I'm just a girl who cain't say no
Kissing's my favorite food
With or without the mistletoe
I'm in a holiday mood
Other girls are coy
and hard to catch
But other girls
ain't havin' any fun
Every time I lose a wrestlin' match
I have a funny feelin' that I won
Though I can feel the undertow
I never make a complaint
Till it's too late for restraint
Then when I want to I cain't
I cain't
Say
No
It's like I told you, Laurey,
I get sorry for 'em.
And now that old Will
has to come home.
First thing you know, he'll start talking
pretty to me and changing my mind back.
- But Will wants to marry you.
- So does Ali Hakim.
- Did he ask you about marryin'?
- Not directly.
But how I know this,
he said this morning
that he wanted for me to ride
with him to the end of the world.
Well, if we drove only as far as "Catoosy,"
he couldn't bring me home till morning,
and that means a wedding, don't it?
Not to a peddler, it don't.
(WHISTLING)
(BELLS CLANGING)
I've been waiting for you to show
your face again, old peddler-man.
Remember what you told me?
You said that eggbeater you
sold me would beat up eggs
wring out dishrags, turn the ice cream
freezer and I don't know what all.
Now, Aunt Eller, just listen.
Don't you Aunt Eller me,
you little wart. I'm mad.
If the eggbeater don't work, I give you
something just as good. A present.
I wouldn't have it.
- What is it?
- Real silk. Made in Persia.
What would I do with
an old Persian garter?
It looks pretty.
Now gimme the other one.
Which one? Oh, you want to buy
this one to match that one?
What do you mean do I wanna buy it?
I can let you have it for 50 cents.
Do you want me to get that eggbeater
and ram it down your windpipe?
- Gimme that.
- Howdy, Aunt Eller.
- Hi, yourself.
- Now that all the ladies are here,
let me show you
some pretty "doodaddles."
Lace around the bottom and there
are bows running in and out.
Well, I never wear 'em myself,
but I sure do like to look at 'em.
How about these?
Yeah, they's all right
if you ain't goin' no place.
Don't nobody want to buy something?
How about you, Miss Laurey?
You must be wanting something,
a pretty young girl like you.
Me? Of course I want something.
I want a buckle made out of shiny
silver to fasten onto my shoes.
I want a dress with lace. I want
perfume. I want to be purty.
- I wanna smell like a honeysuckle vine.
- Give her a cake of soap.
I want things
I can't tell you about.
Not only things to look at
and hold in your hand,
but things to happen to you,
things so nice that if they ever did happen
to you, your heart would quit beating.
I got a-just the thing.
The elixir of Egypt.
A secret formula,
belong to pharaoh's daughter.
- Smellin' salts.
- But a special kind of smelling salts.
Here, read what it says
on the label.
You take a deep breath,
and you see everything clear.
That's what pharaoh's daughter used to do
when she had to decide what dress to wear
or which prince she ought to marry.
She would take a whiff of this.
- I'll take a bottle of that, Mr. Peddler.
- Oh, precious stuff.
- How much?
- Two bits.
- Throwin' away your money.
- Helps you decide what to do.
Put your trappings away
and come inside.
Come along, Laurey. Maybe we can
find him something to eat and drink.
Ali, Laurey and me
been having an argument.
- About what, baby?
- About what you meant
when you said that about drivin'
with me to the end of the world.
Well, I didn't really mean
to the end of the world.
Well, then how far
did you wanna go?
About as far as say... Claremore.
- What's at Claremore?
- The hotel.
In front is a veranda,
inside is the lobby
and upstairs, baby,
might be paradise.
I thought they's just bedrooms.
For you and me, baby, paradise.
You see, I knowsed I was right.
You do wanna marry me.
- Don'tcha?
- Oh, Ado Annie... What did you say?
I said you do wanna marry me,
don'tcha? What'd you say?
I didn't say nothing.
MAN: Ya-hoo!
Oh, foot, just when...
That's Will Parker.
Promise me you won't fight him!
(WHINNIES)
Ado Annie! How's my honey bunch?
How's the sweetest little 120
pounds of sugar in the territory?
Will, this is Ali Hakim.
Hiya, Hak!
Don't mind the way I talk.
It's all right.
I'm gonna marry her.
- Marry her? On purpose?
- No such other thing!
It's a wonderful
thing to be married.
- I got a brother in Persia got six wife.
- Six wives all at once?
Why sure. That's the way they
do it in them countries.
Not always. I got another brother
in Persia only got one wife.
He's a bachelor.
You know what I got
for first prize at the fair?
- Fifty dollars.
- Oh, well, that was good.
- You catch on?
Your pa promised I could marry you
if'n I could ever get $50
together all at one time.
That's right. He did.
Your pa's like all the
rest of them farmers.
Don't think us cowboys
got much sense.
Well, this'll show him. You know
what I done with the $50?
- I spent it all on presents for you.
- Oh!
But if you spent it,
you ain't got no cash.
What I got's worth more than cash.
The fella that sold me
the stuff told me.
- But, Will...
- Stop saying "But, Will."
When do I get a little kiss?
Oh, Ado Annie, honey, you ain't
been off my mind since I left,
all the time at the fairgrounds even
when I was chasing them steers.
I'd rope one under the hoofs,
and I'd pull him up real sharp,
and he'd land on his little old
rump and then I'd think of you.
Don't start talkin' purty.
See'd a lot of pretty girls in Kansas
City. I didn't give one a look.
How could you see 'em if
you didn't give 'em a look?
I mean, I didn't
look lovin' at them,
the way I look at you.
Oh, Will, please don't look
like that. I cain't bear it.
I won't stop looking like this
till you give me a little ol' kiss.
Oh, well, what's a little old kiss?
Nothin', less'n it comes from you.
Oh, you, you do talk purty.
No! I won't!
Supposin' that I say that
your lips are like cherries
Or roses or berries
What you gonna do
Can't you feel my heart
palpitatin' and bumpin'
A-waitin' for somethin'
Somethin' nice from you
I gotta get a kiss
and it's gotta be quick
Or I'll jump in a creek and die
What's a girl to do
when you talk that way
(YIPPING)
Must be the folks stopping
on their way to Skidmore's. Oh!
Oh, you're all welcome!
Glad you could all come.
Everybody come in
and have a good time.
Curly!
I've been 'bout behind you
the whole way.
I know. I heared you.
Oh, welcome. Everybody's welcome.
Oh, what a beautiful morning
Oh, what a beautiful day
I got a beautiful feeling
Everything's goin' my way
Oh, what a beautiful day
Girls, come on in the house
and freshen up.
You boys, better drive your
wagons down to the trough
and give your horses some water.
Hi, Laurey.
Hey, Curly, don't you reckon you
better take care of your horses too?
Thanks, Aunt Eller.
I reckon I better.
Oh, can't I come too, Curly? I just love
to watch the way you handle horses.
It's about all
I can handle, I guess.
(WOMAN CACKLES)
Another mile in that buggy with that
Perkins boy, and I'd have lost my mind.
I'll take Wilbur
if you don't want him.
Looks like Curly's took up
with that Cummings girl.
(GASPS)
What do I care about that?
Why should a woman
who is healthy and strong
Blubber like a baby if
her man goes away
A-weepin' and a-wailin'
how he's done her wrong
That's one thing you'll
never hear me say
Never gonna think
that the man I lose
ls the only man among men
I'll snap my fingers
to show I don't care
I'll buy me a brand-new
dress to wear
I'll scrub my neck
And I'll brush my hair
And start all over again
Many a new face will please my eye
Many a new love will find me
Never have I once
looked back to sigh
Over the romance behind me
Many a new day
will dawn before I do
Many a light lad may kiss and fly
A kiss gone by is bygone
Never have I asked an August sky
Where has last July gone
Never have I wandered
through the rye
Wondering where has some guy gone
Many a new day
will dawn before I do
Many a new face will please my eye
Many a new love will find me
Never have I once
looked back to sigh
Over the romance behind me
Many a new day
will dawn before I do
Never have I chased the honeybee
Who carelessly cajoled me
Somebody else just as sweet as he
Cheered me and consoled me
Never have I wept into my tea
Over the deal someone doled me
Many a new day will dawn
Many a red sun will set
Many a blue moon will shine
Before I do
Many a new face will please my eye
Many a new love will find me
Never have I once
looked back to sigh
Over the romance behind me
Many a new day will dawn
Many a red sun will set
Many a blue moon will shine
Before...
(WOMAN CACKLES)
Many a blue moon will shine
Before I
Do
Maurice, time we got out of here.
Back to the open road.
The open road
Ali. Ali, I'm sure sorry
to see you lookin' so happy
'cause what I got to say
will make you miserable.
- I gotta marry Will.
- Oh, well, that sure is sad news for me.
Well, he's a fine fellow.
Don't hide your feelings, Ali!
I can't bear it.
I'd rather have you come right out
and say your heart's busted in two.
- Are you positive you got to marry Will?
- Sure as shootin'!
There's no chance for you
to change your mind?
No chance.
All right then. My heart
is busted in two.
(GUNSHOT)
- Hello, Pa. What you been shootin'?
- Rabbits.
That true what I hear about
Will Parker getting $50?
That's right, Pa. He wants
to hold you to your promise.
Too bad. Still in all,
I can't go back on my word.
Listen to me, Annie, I advise you to
get that money before he loses it all.
Put it in your stocking
or inside your corset,
where he can't get at it...
Or can he?
But, Pa, he ain't exactly kept it.
He spent it all on presents.
See, what did I tell ya?
Well, now he can't have you.
- I said it had to be $50 cash!
- Is that fair, Mr. Carnes?
- Who the devil are you?
- Oh, Pa, that's Ali Hakim.
Well, shut your face, or I'll fill
your behind so full of buckshot,
you'll be walking around like
a duck the rest of your life.
Ali, if I don't have to marry Will,
maybe your heart don't have to
be busted in two like you said.
- I did not say that.
- Oh, yes, you did.
No, no, I did not.
Are you trying to make my
daughter out to be a liar?
No, I'm only trying to make clear to you
what a liar I am, if she is telling the truth.
- What else you been sayin' to my daughter?
- Oh! An awful lot.
- When?
- Last night in the moonlight.
- Where?
- Alongside a haystack.
- Oh, listen, Mr. Carnes.
- I'm listenin'. What else did you say?
- He called me his Persian kitten.
- What'd you call her that fer?
- I don't remember.
- I do. He said I's like a Persian kitten
'cause they is the cats
with the soft, round tails.
That's enough. In this country, that
better be a proposal of marriage.
- That's what I thought.
- That what you think?
- Look, Mr. Carnes...
- I'm lookin'. I'm lookin'.
I'm no good. I'm a peddler!
A peddler has to travel
up and down and all around.
You'd hardly ever
see your daughter no more.
That'd be all right.
Just take care of her, son.
- Just take care of my little rosebud.
- Oh, Pa, 'at's purty.
You sure for certain
you can bear to let me go?
- Are you sure, Mr. Carnes?
- You just try to change my mind.
Aw, Ali, ain't it wonderful,
Pa making up our minds for us?
And he won't change neither.
Once he gives his word that you
can have me, you've got me!
I know I got you.
Mrs. Ali Hakim,
the peddler's bride!
(WOMEN GIGGLING)
Oh, wait till I tell those girls!
Laurey! Laurey!
The peddler-man and me's
gonna get married!
(WOMAN CACKLING)
Congratulations.
I hope we'll be very happy.
Hi, Laurey. What you doin'?
Gonna pick peaches. What you doin'?
(GIGGLES) I peeked in your
basket up at the house.
I see you got gooseberry tarts too.
I wonder if they's
as light as mine.
Mine would like to float
away if you blew on them.
I just did blow on one of mine, and
it broke into a million pieces.
Ain't she funny? (LAUGHS)
Oh!
- Stop that!
- (INDISTINCT ARGUING)
- Stop it!
- Gertie!
Go on up the house and cool off!
Get along! Mind!
Don't forget tonight at the auction,
Curly, mine's the biggest hamper!
(LAUGHS)
So that's that old Cummings
gal I heared so much talk of.
- You seen her before, ain't ya?
- But not since she got so old.
Never did see anybody get so
peaked-lookin' in such a short time.
Yeah. Says she's 18.
Ha! Bet she's 19.
Are you really gonna drive to the
box social with that Jud fella?
- I reckon so. Why?
- Oh, nothing.
It's just that everybody seems
to expect me to take you.
Then maybe it's just
as well you ain't!
We don't want people
talkin' about us, do we?
Do you think people
really do talk about us?
Well, you know how they are,
like a swarm of mud wasps,
always gotta be buzzing
about something.
What are they saying,
that you're stuck on me?
Most of the talk is that
you're stuck on me.
Can't imagine how these
ugly rumors start.
Me, neither.
Why do they think up stories
that link my name with yours
Why do the neighbors gossip
all day behind their doors
I know a way to prove what
they say is quite untrue
Here is the gist a practical list
Of don'ts
For you
Don't throw
Bouquets at me
Don't please
My folks too much
Don't laugh
At my jokes too much
People will say we're in love
Who laughs at your jokes?
Don't sigh
And gaze at me
Your sighs
Are so like mine
Your eyes
Mustn't glow like mine
People will say we're in love
Don't start
Collecting things
Like what?
Give me my rose and my glove
Sweetheart
They're suspecting things
People will say
We're in
Love
Some people claim
that you are to blame
As much as I
Why do you take the trouble to bake
My favorite pie
Grantin' your wish
I carved our initials
On that tree
Just keep a slice of all the advice
You give so free
Don't praise
My charm too much
Don't look
So vain with me
Don't stand
In the rain with me
People will say we're in love
Don't take
My arm too much
Don't keep
Your hand in mine
Your hand
Feels so grand in mine
People will say we're in love
Don't dance
All night with me
Till the stars fade from above
They'll see
It's all right with me
People will say
We're in
Love
Don't you think you could tell that Jud
fella you'd rather go with me tonight?
Curly...
No, I couldn't.
Oh, you couldn't.
Think I'll go down to the
smokehouse where Jud's at.
See what's so elegant about him, makes all
the girls want to go to parties with him.
- Curly!
- What?
Nothin'.
(QUACKING)
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Well, open it, can't you?
Well, what do you want?
Oh, I... I done got through with
my business up there at the house.
I just thought I'd pay a call.
- You got a gun, I see.
- That's right.
It's a Colt .45.
Oh.
Say, now.
That there pink picture...
That's a naked woman, ain't it?
Plumb stark naked as a jaybird.
Shucks, that ain't a thing
to what I could show you.
Well, that's a good-lookin' rope.
Feels good too.
(GRUNTS)
That's a good, strong hook
you got there, Jud.
You know what? You could
hang yourself on that.
- I could what?
- You could hang yourself.
Yes, sir. Easy as
rollin' off a log.
Why, in five minutes
or less, with good luck,
- you could be dead as a doornail.
- What do you mean by that?
Oh, then folks would
come to your funeral.
- And they'd sing sad songs.
- (SCOFFS)
Why, they would.
You never know how many people
like you till you're dead.
You'd be laid out in a parlor.
All decked out in your best suit.
Your hair combed down slick,
high starched collar.
Lots of pretty flowers
all around you.
Would there be flowers, you think?
And palms too,
all around your coffin.
Folks would gather round,
and men would bare their heads.
Women would sniffle softly.
Some probably even faint,
ones that took a shine to
you whilst you was alive.
Now, what women
ever took a shine to me?
Why, lots of women.
Only they never come right out
and tell you how they feel,
unless you die first.
I guess maybe you're right.
They'd sure sing loud, though,
when the singin' would start.
Sing like their hearts would break.
Poor Jud is dead
Poor Jud Fry is dead
All gather round
his coffin now and cry
He had a heart of gold
And he wasn't very old
Oh, why did such a fella
have to die
Poor Jud is dead
Poor Jud Fry is dead
He's lookin', oh, so
peaceful and serene
And serene
He's all laid out to rest
With his hands across'd his chest
His fingernails
have never been so clean
And then the preacher'd
get up, and he'd say...
Folks, we are gathered here to moan
and groan over our brother Jud Fry
Who hung hisself up
by a rope in a smokehouse
And then there'd be weepin' and
wailin' from some of those women.
And then he'd say...
Jud was the most misunderstood
man in this territory
People used to think
he was a mean, ugly fella
And call him a dirty skunk
and ornery pig stealer
But the folks
that really knowed him
Knowed that beneath them two
dirty shirts he always wore
There beat a heart
as big as all outdoors
As big as all outdoors
Jud Fly loved his fellow man
He loved his fellow man
He loved the birds of the forests
And the beasts of the field
He loved the mice
and the vermin in the barn
And he treated the rats like equals
Which was right.
He loved all the little children
He loved everything
and everybody in the world
Only...
Only he never let on.
So nobody ever knowed it.
Poor Jud is dead
Poor Jud Fry is dead
His friends will weep and
wail for miles around
Miles around
The daisies in the dell
Will give out a different smell
Because poor Jud is
underneath the ground
Poor Jud is dead
A candle lights his head
He's layin' in a coffin
made of wood
Wood
And folks are feelin' sad
'Cause they used to treat him bad
And now they know their
friend has gone for good
Good
Poor Jud is dead
A candle lights his head
He'd lookin'
oh, so pretty and so nice
He looks like he's asleep
It's a shame that he won't keep
But it's summer
And we're runnin' out of ice
Poor
Jud
(CHUCKLES) Yes, sir.
(CHUCKLES)
That sure will be
an interesting funeral.
I wouldn't like to miss it.
Well, maybe you will.
Maybe you'll go first.
Well,
let's see now.
Where'd you work at
before you come up here?
Was up by Quapaw, wasn't it?
That's right.
Lousy they was to me too.
Always makin' out
they were better than I was.
Always treating me like I was dirt.
So, what'd you do? Get even?
Who said anything
about getting even?
No one I recollect.
Just come into my head.
If it come to gettin' even with
somebody, I'd know how to do it.
You remember the fire in the
Bartlett farm over by Sweetwater?
I sure do.
It was about five years ago.
Burned up the father and the
mother and the daughter.
It was a terrible accident.
That weren't no accident.
Fella told me.
Said that the hired hand was
stuck on the Bartlett girl
and one day he found her in the
hayloft with another fella.
And 'twas him
that burned the place?
Took him weeks to get the kerosene,
buying it at different times.
Fella that told me,
he made out like
it happened in Missouri,
but I knew all the time
it was the Bartlett farm.
What a liar he was.
Get a little air in here.
You ain't told me yet
what business you had here.
We got no cattle to sell
and no cow ponies.
Could be only one other thing
on this farm you could want
and it better not be that.
- That's just what it is.
- You keep away from her, you hear?
You know, somebody
ought to tell Laurey
just what kind of a man you are.
And for that matter, somebody ought
to tell you once about yourself.
Curly, you better get out of here.
In this country, there's just two
things you can do if you're a man.
You can live outdoors is one,
and you can live in a hole
is the other.
I set by my horse
in the brush somewheres
and I heared a rattlesnake
many a time.
(IMITATES RATTLESNAKE) He'd go...
Scared to death
somebody gonna step on him.
- Got his old fangs all ready.
- Curly, you better get out of here!
How did you get to be
the way you are anyhow?
Sittin' in here
in this filthy hole.
Why don't you do something
healthy once in a while,
'stead of stayin' shut up here,
a-crawlin' and festerin'?
(SHOUTS)
(GUN CLATTERS ON TABLE)
- (DOG BARKING)
- (CHICKENS CLUCKING)
Well.
You ought to feel better now.
I wish you'd let me
show you something.
There's a knothole over there,
about as big as a dime.
You see it a-winkin'?
(GUNSHOT)
Right through the knothole.
Slick as a whistle.
(CLAMORING)
Who fired off a gun?
Was that you, Curly?
Well, I... I shot once.
Well, what was you shooting at?
- Knotholes.
- Well, ain't you a pair of pretty nothings,
a-peckin' away at knotholes and
scarin' everybody to death. Well!
What happened, Aunt Eller?
What happened?
Nobody hurt. Just a pair
of fools swappin' noises.
Oh, excuse. Excuse.
Mind if I visit with you gents?
I got a few pretties to show you.
Private knickknacks,
special for the menfolk.
Not me. I gotta shine up that
surrey I done hired for tonight.
Laurey promised to go with me
and she better not change her mind.
She better not!
Now, take a look at those.
Straight from Paris.
- You got a frog-sticker?
- You mean one of them long knives?
I tell you what I'd like better.
You know them things
called a Little Wonder?
You hold it up to your eye. You look
through it. You see pictures.
You say to a fella, "Come here.
Look through here."
And when he's lookin' through it,
you press a little jigger on the end...
and out snaps a blade,
and then bang.
Down you come.
A good joke to play on a friend.
No, I don't have no things
like that. Too dangerous.
Here, take a look
at these postcards.
I'm sick of them things.
I want me a real woman.
I'm tired of all
these pictures of women.
Well, throw them away.
Buy some new ones.
If you get tired of a woman,
what can you do?
Nothing. You just keep
getting tireder and tireder.
I've made up my mind.
Oh, say, you know a girl
named Ado Annie?
- I don't want her.
- I don't want her either, but I got her.
Ain't you done your basket yet?
Lands, you ain't even dressed.
I believe you got something
worryin' on your mind.
Aunt Eller, I want everything
to stay just the way it is.
Well, won't it?
I like living the way we do.
I like the looks of the
prairie outside my window,
and the thicket where
the possums live,
and the way we set round in the
evenings in thrashing time,
eatin' mush melons
and a-singin', and...
Oh, lots of things.
Why should any of that have
to change, Laurey, honey?
- What if something happened?
- What could happen?
We got money in the bank
and it's gonna be another
good year for corn and oats.
(CHUCKLES)
You are a silly.
"Hold bottle two inches
from nostril.
"Close your eyes and inhale.
"Ask your heart
what you really want
"and wait for the answer."
(SNIFFS, COUGHS)
Elixir of Egypt,
make up my mind for me.
I'm waitin' for the answer.
Out of your dreams
Your dreams, your dreams
Out of my dreams
And into your arms
I long to fly
I will come as evening comes
To woo a waiting sky
Out of my dreams and into the hush
Of falling shadows
When the mist is low
And stars are breaking through
Then out of my dreams
I'll go
Into a dream
With
You
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING VARIATIONS)
(RUMBLING)
(RUMBLING CONTINUES)
(THUNDERCLAP)
(ORCHESTRA CONTINUES)
(SCREAMING)
(WIND WHISTLING)
(ORCHESTRA CONTINUES)
(ORCHESTRA STOPS)
(WIND STOPS)
(ORCHESTRA RESUMES)
(THUNDERCLAP)
JUD: Laurey?
Laurey?
(GASPS)
Time to go to the party.
(SHOUTING)
(SINGING)
(BANJO PLAYING)
La, la, la, la, la, la, la
La, la, la, la, la, la
la, la, la, la, la, la
(BANJO PLAYS)
La, la, la, la, la, la, la
(MEN WHOOPING)
Crawlin' along like this, we'll
get there when the party's over.
Last time I saw you alone
was in the winter.
I was sick,
and I remember you
brung me some hot soup,
out to the smokehouse
and you give it to me.
Me in bed.
And you asked me if I had a fever.
Put your hand on my head to see.
- I remember.
- Do you?
Bet you don't remember
as much as me.
I remember everything
you ever done,
every word you ever said.
I can't get it out of my mind.
You see how it is?
(WHIP CRACKS)
JUD: Whoa, boy! Whoa!
(LOUD CRACK)
- Whoa there!
- (WHINNYING)
Whoa there! Whoa!
(LAUREY SCREAMS)
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
- Whoa now. Whoa there!
- (SCREECHING)
Whoa, boy. Whoa, boy.
MAN: Quiet, everyone.
The farmer and the cowman
should be friends
Oh, the farmer and the
cowman should be friends
One man likes to push a plow
The other likes to chase a cow
But that's no reason why
they can't be friends
Territory folks
should stick together
Territory folks should all be pals
Cowboys dance
with the farmers' daughters
Farmers dance
with the ranchers' gals
CHORUS: Territory folks
should stick together
Territory folks should all be pals
Cowboys dance
with the farmers' daughters
Farmers dance
with the ranchers' gals
No, no, no.
I'd like to say a
word for the farmer
- Well, say it.
- Yeah!
He come out West
and made a lot of changes
and built a lot of fences
And built 'em right across
our cattle ranges
Why don't dirt scratchers go back
to Missouri where they belong?
(CLAMORING)
The farmer is a good
and thrifty citizen
He's thrifty, all right.
No matter what the cowman
says or thinks
You seldom see him
drinkin' in a barroom
Unless somebody else
is buyin' drinks
(LAUGHING)
But the farmer and the
cowman should be friends
Oh, the farmer and the
The cowman ropes a cow with ease
The farmer steals
her butter and cheese
But that's no reason why
they can't be friends
Territory folks
should stick together
Territory folks should all be pals
Cowboys dance
with the farmers' daughters
Farmers dance
with the ranchers' gals
Quiet, everybody.
I'd like to say a
word for the cowboy
Oh, you would, would you?
The road he treads
is difficult and stony
He rides for days on end with
just a pony for a friend
I sure am feelin' sorry
for the pony
(PEOPLE SHOUT)
The farmer should be
sociable with the cowboy
If he rides by and asks
for food and water
Don't treat him like a louse
Make him welcome in your house
But be sure that you lock up
your wife and daughter
Who wants an old farm woman anyhow?
Notice you married one so's
you could get a square meal.
You can't talk that-a-way
about our women.
He can say what he wants.
(CROWD CLAMORING)
Oh, the farmer and the
cowman should be friends
One man likes to push a plow
The other likes to chase a cow
- But that's no reason why
- (GUNSHOT)
Ain't nobody gonna
slug out anythin'.
This here's a party.
Sing it, Andrew. (VOCALIZES)
Oh, the farmer and the
cowman should be friends
Good, but louder. Sing it. Sing it.
Oh, the farmer and the
cowman should be friends
Sing. Come on, now, sing.
One man likes to push a plow
Come on. You hear? Sing.
The other likes to chase a cow
But that's no reason
why they can't be friends
Sing!
And when this territory is a state
And joins the Union
just like all the others
The farmer and the cowman
and the merchant
Must all behave theirselves
and act like brothers
I'd like to teach you all
a little sayin'
And learn the words by heart
The way you should
I don't say I'm no better
Than anybody else
But I'll be danged if
I ain't just as good
(LAUGHING)
I don't say I'm no better
than anybody else
But I'll be danged
if I ain't just as good
Territory folks
should stick together
Territory folks should all be pals
Cowboys dance
with the farmers' daughters
Farmers dance
with the ranchers' gals
(CHEERING)
Yeah!
Quiet, everybody. Quiet.
It's time to start the auction.
Who's gonna be the
auctioneer, Mr. Skidmore?
Why, Aunt Eller, of course.
- Say, Aunt Eller?
- Huh?
Laurey ain't here yet. What
do you reckon's happened?
Oh, they're just pokey.
Loosen up your pockets, fellas.
You've been pounding the floor
of the new schoolhouse.
Now let's get money
enough to raise the roof.
(CHEERING)
Mr. Skidmore's been generous
enough to give us the land.
- He's got more kids than the rest of us.
- (LAUGHTER)
Now, you know the rules, gentlemen.
You ain't supposed to know what
girl goes with what hamper.
Of course, if your sweetheart
has told you that hers,
will be done up in a certain kind of
way, with a certain kind of ribbon,
that ain't my fault.
I can't hardly lift this one.
Wonder what's in there.
I'm bound there's
a mince pie in here.
- Is there any rum in it?
- Well, come and sniff for yourself.
Is there?
- I'll vote two bits.
- Two bits!
Whoa.
- Hi, Laurey.
- Where's Aunt Eller? And Curly?
Well, up the house, I think.
Sold to Pete Larkin for six bits.
Well, Pete, you sure got a pretty
gal to go with your supper.
Well, let's go ahead.
Now, what am I offered
for this one?
Anybody just et?
- I'll give two bits.
- Two bits.
- Four bits.
I've heard enough bits.
Let's hear a mouthful.
Hello, young fella.
Well, Mr. Hakim, I hear you got
yourself engaged to Ado Annie.
- Well, I...
- Well, nothing.
I don't know what to call you.
Ain't pretty enough for a skunk.
Ain't skinny enough for a snake.
Too low to be a man,
and too big to be a mouse.
- I reckon you're a rat.
- Hmm. That's logical.
Answer me one question.
Do you really love her?
- Well, I...
- 'Cause if'n I thought you didn't,
I'd tie you up in that there
bag and drop you in the river.
- Are you serious about her?
- Yes, I'm serious.
Do you worship the ground she walks
on, like I do? You'd better say yes.
Yes. Yes.
Would you spend
every cent you had for her?
That's what I did.
See the bag? Full of presents.
Cost 50 bucks,
all I had in the world.
- If you had that $50...
- I'd have Ado Annie and you'd lose her.
Oh, yeah. I'd lose her.
Let's see what you got in the bag.
Might wanting to buy something.
What would you want with it?
I'm a peddler, ain't I?
Oh, hi! (BABBLING)
What a beautiful hot-water bag.
Looks French.
It must have cost you plenty.
- I give you eight dollar for it.
- Eight dollars?
- That wouldn't be honest. I only paid 3.50...
- All right.
I said I give you eight. I will.
- Oh, that's a crackerjack.
- Take your hands off that.
That was for our wedding night.
It don't fit you so good.
I give you $22.
- Well, what...
- All right, 22.50. Not a cent more.
(HUMMING)
Oh, mighty dainty.
Fifteen dollar. Let's see now.
Twenty-two and eight is 30,
and 15 is 45, and 50 is 45.50.
Forty-five fifty.
Say, that's almost...
- You wanna buy some more?
- Might.
You ever see one of these things?
- How much you give me for this here thing?
- Oh, no.
- I don't handle things like that.
- It's just a girl in a pink...
- No, it's more than that.
- Hey.
Either of you two see'd Laurey?
Up to the house, lookin' for Curly.
- How much you give me for this thing?
- I tell you, I don't...
What do you want for it?
Well, let's see.
- Three dollars and fifty cents.
- Sold.
Now, 3.50 from him, 45.50 from you.
That makes $50, don't it?
No. One dollar short.
Oh, darn it.
I must have figured wrong.
Well, how much for the rest of
the stuff in this here bag?
- One dollar.
- Done.
Now I got the $50, ain't I?
Know what that means?
Means I'm gonna take
Ado Annie back from you.
- You wouldn't do a thing like that to me.
- Wouldn't I?
When I tell Ado Annie's pa who I
got most of the money off of,
(LAUGHS)
maybe he'll change his mind
about who's smart and who's dumb.
Say, young fella,
you certainly buncoed me.
(HUMMING)
Oh. Ah.
Now here's the last two hampers.
Whose they are, I ain't got no idy.
The big one's mine, and the
next one to it is Laurey's.
(LAUGHTER)
That's the end of that secret.
Now, what am I bid
for Annie's hamper?
MAN: Two bits.
- MAN #2: Four.
- Who says six? You?
- Ain't nobody hungry no more?
- (LAUGHTER)
What about you,
peddler-man? Six bits?
No, no. I don't care.
- Bid 'em up.
- Six bits!
Oh, six bits ain't enough for
a lunch like Annie can make.
Let's hear a dollar. How about you?
You won her last year.
Hey, Annie, you still got the same
sweet potato pie like last year?
You bet!
Same old sweet potato pie.
What do you say?
I say it gimme
a three-day bellyache.
(LAUGHTER)
Never mind about that.
Who bids a dollar?
Come on, bid.
Mine was the last bid.
I got her for six bits.
- Bid a dollar.
- Ninety cents.
Ninety cents. We're gettin' rich.
Another desk for the schoolhouse.
Do I hear more?
You hear $50.
- Fifty dollars!
- Hey!
Nobody ever bid $50 for a lunch.
Nobody ever bid 10.
- He ain't got $50.
- Oh, yes, I have.
If you're a man of honor, you'll say Annie
belong to me like you said she would.
- Where's your money?
- Right here in my hand.
That ain't yours. You just bid it,
didn't you? Give it to the schoolhouse.
I still say the peddler
gets my daughter's hand.
- Now, wait a minute! That ain't fair!
- Going for $50.
- Going, going...
- Fifty-one.
- You crazy?
- Fifty...
Wait a minute. Hold on.
Aunt Eller,
if'n I don't bid no more,
- I can keep my money, can't I?
- You sure can.
Then I still got $50,
and this is mine.
- You simple-minded shag poke.
- Going, going,
gone for $51, and that means
Annie'll get the prize, I guess.
- Oh! Oh!
- And I'll get Annie, I guess.
And what are you
getting for your $51?
- A three-day bellyache.
- (LAUGHTER)
Now... Now, here's
my niece's hamper.
- (MURMURING)
- I took a peek inside a while ago,
and I must say
it looks mighty tasty.
- What do I hear, gents?
- Two bits.
- Four bits.
- What you say, six?
- MAN: One dollar.
- More like it. Do I hear two?
- A dollar and a quarter.
- (CROWD MURMURING)
MAN: Two dollars.
MAN #2: Two-fifty.
- Three dollars.
- And two bits.
MAN #3:
Three dollars and four bits.
- MAN #4: Four dollars.
- And two bits.
Four dollars and a quarter.
Ain't I gonna hear any more?
Curly?
(MURMURING)
I got a bid of four and
a quarter from Jud Fry.
You gonna let him have it?
Andrew.
- Four and a half.
- Four and a half! Going for...
Four seventy-five.
Come on, gentlemen.
Schoolhouse ain't built yet.
Got to get a nice "chimbley."
Five dollars.
- Five dollars! Going for...
- And two bits.
Too rich for my blood.
Can't afford no more.
Five and a quarter.
Ain't got nearly enough yet.
Not for cold duck and stuffing,
- and that lemon meringue pie.
- Six dollars.
- Six dollars!
- And two bits. And two bits.
My, you're stubborn, Jud.
Mr. Carnes is a richer man than you
and I know he likes custard
with raspberry syrup.
- Oh, let it go.
- Anybody gonna bid any more?
No, they all dropped out.
Can't you see?
- You got enough, Aunt Eller.
- MAN: Yeah, let's get on.
- I got the money.
- Hold on, you.
- I ain't said "going, going"...
- Say it!
Going to Jud
for six dollars and two bits.
Going.
- Going.
- (CROWD MURMURING)
- Who'd you say was getting Laurey?
- Jud Fry.
- And for how much?
- Six and a quarter.
I don't reckon that's quite
enough, do you, Aunt Eller?
More than you got.
Got a saddle here. Cost me $30.
You can't bid saddles.
You gotta bid cash.
Thirty-dollar saddle must be
worth something to somebody.
I'll give you 10 dollars.
Don't be a fool, boy. You can't
earn a living without a saddle.
- You got cash?
- Right in my pocket.
Let's don't waste time.
How high you going?
Higher than you, no matter what.
- Aunt Eller, I'm bidding all of this 10 dollars.
- Ten dollars! Going, going...
Ten dollars and two bits.
Curly?
- Most of you boys know my horse, Blue.
- (CROWD MURMURING)
He's kind of a nice horse.
He's gentle. He's well broke.
Don't sell Blue, Curly.
it ain't worth it.
I'll give you $25 for him.
Sold.
Aunt Eller, that makes the bid 35.
Curly, you're crazy.
But it's all for the
schoolhouse, ain't it?
- Going for 35...
- Hold on. Hold on now.
I'm not finished bidding yet.
You just sold everything you
got in the world, didn't you?
You can't sell your clothes
'cause they ain't worth nothin'.
You can't sell your gun
'cause you're gonna need it.
Yes, sir, you're gonna need it bad.
Well, I'm just as good as
Curly at gettin' what I want.
I'm gonna bid everything
I got in the world.
Forty-two dollars and 31 cents.
(CROWD GASPS)
Anybody want to buy a gun?
I bought it brand-new last
Thanksgiving. It's worth a lot.
- Curly...
- MAN: Give you 18 for it, Curly.
Sold.
Aunt Eller, that makes the bid $53.
anybody going any higher?
Sold!
(LAUGHTER)
Going, going, gone.
Well, what's the matter
with you folks?
Ain't nobody gonna
cheer or nothin'?
(CHEERING)
Ah, ah, ah, ah.
Now, come on, you two.
Shake hands.
That's better.
- Curly?
- What?
Can I show you something?
Excuse us, Laurey?
You ever seen one of these?
Just what is it?
It's something special.
(INAUDIBLE)
You just put it up to your eye and
you look through it, like that.
Curly! Curly!
- What you doing?
- Nothin'.
What do you want to squeal
at a man like that for?
You scared the livin' lights
out of me.
Well, then stop lookin'
at them old French pictures.
And ask me for a dance. You brung
me to the party, didn't you?
All right, all right, you silly old
woman. I'll dance with you.
Sam, pick that banjo to pieces.
(BAND PLAYS)
Now that I got that $50,
you name the day.
- August 15.
- Why August 15?
'Cause that was the
first day I was kissed.
Was it? I didn't remember that.
You wasn't there.
Now, lookee here. We gotta
have a serious talk.
Now that you're engaged to me,
you gotta stop havin' fun.
I mean, with other fellas.
You'll have to be
a little more standoffish
When fellers offer you a buggy ride
I'll give a imitation of a crawfish
And dig myself a hole
where I can hide
I heared how you was
kickin' up some capers
When I was off in Kansas City, Mo
No!
I heared some things
you couldn't print in papers
From fellers who been
talkin' like they know
Foot!
I only did the kind of things I oughta
Sorta
To you I was as faithful as can be
For me
Them stories 'bout the way
I lost my bloomers
Rumors
A lot of tempest in a pot of tea
The whole thing don't
sound very good to me
Well, you see...
I go and sow my last wild oat
I cut out all shenanigans
I save my money
don't gamble or drink
In a back room down at Flannigan's
I give up lots of other things
That a gentleman never mentions
Before I give up any more
I wanna know your intentions
With me it's all or nothin'
Is it all or nothin' with you
It can't be in between
It can't be now and then
No half-and-half romance will do
I'm a one-woman man
home-lovin' type
All complete with slippers and pipe
Take me like I am or leave me be
If you can't give me all
give me nothin'
And nothin's what
you'll get from me
Not even somethin'
Nothing's what you'll get from me
- It can't be in between
- Uh-uh.
It can't be now and then
No half-and-half romance will do
Would you build me a
house all painted white
Cute and clean and
pretty and bright
Big enough for two
but not for three
Supposing that we
should have a third one
He better look a lot like me
The spittin' image
With you it's all or nothin'
All for you and nothin' for me
But if a wife is wise
She's gotta realize
That men like you are wild and free
So I ain't gonna fuss
ain't gonna frown
Have your fun
Go out on the town
Stay up late and don't
come home till 3:00
And go right off to sleep
if you're sleepy
No use waitin' up for me
Aw, Ado Annie
Come on and kiss me
(CHATTERING, LAUGHING)
Why'd you drive off
and leave me like that?
Like I said, didn't want
to be late for the party.
You didn't want to be with me, you mean,
not a minute more than you had to.
I ain't good enough for you, am I?
I'm a hired hand.
I got dirt on my hands. Pig slime.
I ain't fit to touch, am I? You're better.
Oh, you're so much better.
Well, we'll see how much
better you are, Miss Laurey,
and you won't be so free and easy
and highfalutin with your airs.
- You such a fine lady!
- Are you makin' threats to me?
Are you trying to tell me if I don't
allow you to slobber over me like a hog,
why, you're gonna do
something about it?
Well, you ain't
a hired hand for me no more.
You can just pack up
your duds and scoot.
Don't you as much as set foot
inside the pasture gate,
or I'll sic the dogs on to you!
You said your say.
You brought it on yourself.
I can't help it.
I can't never rest.
I told you how it was.
You wouldn't listen.
You ain't never
gonna get rid of me. Never.
Hey, Laurey, have you seen Annie?
- She's gone again.
- Will, will you do something for me?
Will you find Curly
and tell him I'm here?
I wanna see Curly awful bad.
I gotta see him.
Why don't you turn around
and look, you crazy woman?
Oh, Curly! (CRYING)
Well, you found yours.
I'm still lookin' for mine.
What on earth is ailing
the belle of Claremore?
Well, by gum, if you ain't cryin'.
Oh, Curly, I'm afraid,
afraid for my life.
- Jumpin' toadstools.
- Don't you leave me!
- Gosh a-mighty.
- Don't mind me cryin'.
I can't help it.
- You can cry your eyes out.
- I don't know what to do.
Well, here. I'll show ya.
That's about all a man can stand in
public. You go away from me, you.
Oh. You don't like me, Curly?
Like you? You get away from me,
I tell ya. Plumb away from me.
Curly, you're sittin' on the stove!
(SHOUTS)
It's cold as a hunk of ice.
Wished it had burned
a hole in your pants.
- You do, do ya?
- You heared me.
Now, look, Laurey, you stand
right there where you at
and I'll sit right over here.
Now, you can tell me
what you wanted with me.
Well, Jud was here.
He scared me.
He talked wild, and he threatened
me, sol... I fired him.
I wished I hadn't. There ain't
no tellin' what he might do now.
You fired him?
Well, then,
that's all there is to it.
I'll stay in the place myself tonight,
if you're nervous about that hound dog.
Look, you quit your
worryin', or I'll spank ya.
Hey,
while I think of it,
how about marrying me?
Gracious.
What'd I wanna marry you for?
Well, couldn't you maybe think
of some reason why you might?
I can't think of nothin'
right now, hardly.
Laurey,
Please, ma'am, marry me?
I don't know what I'm
gonna do if you don't.
Curly, why, I'll marry ya
if you want me to.
I'll be the happiest man alive
as soon as we're married.
Well, I gotta learn to be
a farmer. I can see that.
Quit thinkin' about
throwin' that rope
and start gettin' my hands
blistered a new way.
Things is changin',
Laurey, right and left.
Buy up mowin' machines
and cut down prairies,
shoe your horses and drag
them plows under the sod.
They gonna make a state out of this.
They gonna put it in the Union.
Country's a-changin'.
I gotta change with it.
- Bring up a pair of boys.
- Curly!
Well, new stock to keep up with the way
things is goin' in this here crazy country.
Now I got you to help me,
I'll amount to somethin' yet.
I remember the first
time I ever see'd ya.
It was at the fair, and you was
ridin' that gray filly of Blue Stars.
I says, "Who's that skinny little thing sittin'
up there with the bang on her forehead?"
Yeah, I remember. And you
was ridin' broncs that day.
- That's right.
- And one of 'em throwed ya.
Yeah. It did not throw me.
- Guess ya jumped off then.
- Why, sure I jumped off.
- Yeah, you sure did.
- (LAUGHS)
Hey, if there's anybody out and around
this shout who can hear my voice,
I want 'em to know that
Laurey Williams is my girl!
Curly!
Ha-ha! And she went and got
me to ask her to marry me.
They'll hear you all
the way to Catoosy.
Let 'em.
Let people say we're in love
Who keers what happens now
Just keep your hand in mine
Your hand feels so grand in mine
Let people say we're in love
Starlight looks well on us
Let the stars beam from above
Who keers if they tell on us
Let people Say
We're in love
Well, I'll say good-bye here, baby.
Time for the lonely gypsy
to go back to the open road.
I wished I was goin'. Then
you wouldn't be so lonely.
Look, Annie, there is a man who loves
you like nothing never loved nobody.
That is the man for you...
Will Parker.
Oh, yeah. Well, I like Will a lot.
Sure. He's a fine fellow.
He's strong like an ox.
He's young and handsome.
Oh, I love him, all right, I guess.
Of course you do. And you love
those clear blue eyes of his
and the way his mouth
wrinklies up when he smiles.
Do you love him too?
I love him because he'll
make my Ado Annie happy.
Oh.
Good-bye, baby.
I will show you how we
say good-bye in Persia.
That was good-bye?
We have an old song
in Persia. It says...
One good-bye is never enough
Hello, Will. Ali Hakim's
saying good-bye.
Ah, Will, I wanna say
good-bye to you too.
No, you don't. I just
saw the last one.
Aw, be good to her, Will,
and you be good to him, baby.
- Oh, friend of the family.
- Did you say you was goin'?
I show you how we say
good-bye in my country.
Oh, friend of the family.
Oh, lucky fellow.
I wish it was me she was
marrying instead of you.
It don't seem
to make much difference.
Well, back to the open road,
the lonely gypsy!
Giddyap, boys!
You ain't gonna think of that old
peddler-man anymore, are ya?
Of course not. I never think
of no one less'n he's with me.
Then I'll never leave your side.
Well, even if you never go away,
can't you once in awhile,
give me one of them
Persian good-byes?
Persian good-bye? Why, that ain't
nothin' compared to Oklahoma hello.
Hello, Will!
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(CATTLE LOWING)
(MEN WHOOPING)
(WHISTLING)
- Sleepin' in the saddle?
- Worse than that.
I got to thinkin'. Last time
for me, Mr. Skidmore.
No more roundups. Not no more.
Think you're gonna
like being a farmer?
If Laurey can marry a
good-for-nothing cowhand,
without a red cent in his
britches, I gotta love farmin'.
I reckon you'll be
a good enough husband.
Can't say about the farmin'
I don't like farmin'. Never did.
That ain't gonna keep you
from the weddin', is it?
Wouldn't miss it for anything.
After all, the farmer and the
cowman should be friends.
With this ring, I thee wed.
I pronounce you man and wife.
(CHATTERING, LAUGHING)
(CHATTERING, LAUGHING CONTINUE)
MAN: Let's give three cheers
for the happy couple!
- Hip, hip! Hip, hip!
- GUESTS: Hooray! Hooray!
- Hip, hip!
- Hooray!
They couldn't pick a better
time to start in life
It ain't too early
and it ain't too late
Startin' as a farmer
with a brand-new wife
Soon be livin' in a brand-new state
Brand-new state
Gonna treat you great
Gonna give you barley
carrots and potatoes
- Pasture for the cattle
- Spinach and tomatoes
Flowers on the prairie
where the june bugs zoom
Plenty of air and plenty of room
Plenty of room to swing a rope
Plenty of heart and plenty of hope
(WOMEN SQUEALING)
Oklahoma
Where the wind comes
sweepin' down the plain
And the wavin' wheat
can sure smell sweet
When the wind comes
right behind the rain
Oklahoma
Every night my honey lamb and I
Sit alone and talk and watch a hawk
Makin' lazy circles in the sky
We know we belong to the land
And the land we belong to is grand
And when we say
ALL: Yeow
A-yip-i-o-ee-ay
We're only sayin'
you're doin' fine, Oklahoma
Oklahoma, okay
(GUESTS WHOOPING)
GUESTS: Oklahoma
Where the wind comes sweepin'
down the plain, Oklahoma
Where the wavin' wheat
can sure smell sweet
When the wind comes
right behind the rain
Oklahoma
Every night my honey lamb and I
Every night we sit alone
and talk and watch a hawk
Makin' lazy circles in the sky
- We know we belong to the land
- Yo ho
And the land we belong to is grand
Ylippee yi, yippee yi
Yippee yi, yippee yi
And when we say
Yeow
A-yip-i-o-ee-ay
We're only sayin'
you're doin' fine, Oklahoma
Oklahoma, you're okay
Oklahoma, Oklahoma
Oklahoma, Okla...
We know we belong to the land
And the land we belong to is grand
And when we say
Yeow
A-yip-i-o-ee-ay
We're only sayin'
you're doin' fine, Oklahoma
Oklahoma, O-K-L-A-H-O-M-A
Oklahoma
(GUESTS WHOOPING)
Say, you better hurry and get in that
other dress. We gotta get goin'.
You hurry and pack your own
duds and lean on over my...
(GUESTS CHATTERING)
- Come on now. You girls...
- (CONTINUES, INDISTINCT)
(SHOUTS OF PROTEST)
- I wanna go!
- Me too!
What you gonna do, Pa, give
Laurey and Curly a shivaree?
- That's right.
- I wished you wouldn't.
It's a good, old-fashioned
custom never hurt nobody.
Wait. You ladies just
stay right here now.
Vamoose! Go on! Scat!
Seems like there's times when men
ain't got no need for women.
There's times when women
ain't got no need for men.
- Yeah, but who wants to be dead?
- (GERTIE CACKLING)
- Thought you's in Bushyhead.
- Just come from there.
Too bad you missed
Laurey's weddin'.
- Been havin' one of my own.
- (GASPING, CHATTERING)
Lands, who'd you marry?
Where is he?
- There he is.
- Oh.
- Is that him?
- GERTIE: That's him.
Oh, hello, Ado Annie.
- GERTIE: Did you see my ring, girls?
- (WOMEN GASPING)
- How long you been married?
- Four days.
(CACKLING)
Four days with that laugh should
count like a golden wedding.
But if you married her,
you must have wanted to.
Oh, sure, I wanted to.
I wanted to marry her
when I saw the moonlight
shining on the barrel of
her father's shotgun.
- I thought it would be better to be alive.
- (CACKLES)
Now I ain't so sure.
Hey, Will, did you hear the news?
Gertie married the peddler.
Mighty glad to hear
that, peddler-man.
I think I oughta kiss the bride.
Oh.
Oh, friend of the family, remember?
Hey, Gertie, you ever had
an Oklahoma hello?
- (MUFFLED SHOUT)
- (WOMEN GASPING)
(SCREAMS) No, you don't!
(WOMEN SHOUTING)
(SHOUTING CONTINUES)
(SCREAMING)
Hey, hey! What are you doing?
I'm gonna keep Ado Annie
from killin' your wife.
Mind your own business.
- (CLOTH RIPPING)
- (SCREAMS)
- (BELLS JINGLING)
- Shh! Shh! Somebody'll hear ya.
They ain't listening
to anybody but theirselves.
Shh! Shh!
(LAUGHS)
- (WHISPERING)
- (LAUGHING)
(MEN WHOOPING)
Go on out of here,
you bunch of pig stealers!
Why don't you go on back
home where you belong?
(MEN SHOUTING)
(MEN WHOOPING)
- Up the ladder with ya, pretty thing!
- Boost her up!
Put your foot in the
right place, boy!
Go on, Mr. Bridegroom.
There's your bride.
(ALL SHOUTING)
- (PANS CLANGING)
- (MEN WHOOPING)
MAN: Maybe we'll let you down
in time to catch your train!
Hey, Laurey, here's
a girl baby for ya!
(LAUGHTER)
(WHOOPING, CLANGING CONTINUE)
Fire! Haystack's a-fire!
Get some water!
Get water! Hurry up!
Get the water!
Curly, I got a present for ya!
I didn't get to kiss the bride,
but I got a present for you!
(LAUREY SCREAMS)
There's a present for you!
Come on! Come on!
- Ike! Slim! Quick!
- Come on!
(SCREAMS)
- What'd you do to him?
- I knowed this was gonna happen.
- They've been feudin' for quite a spell.
- (CHATTERING)
- What happened?
- He fell on his own knife.
- Stuck clean through the ribs.
- He's still breathing, ain't he?
Let me look at him.
Can't do a thing here.
Better get him to a doctor.
Carry him over to my rig.
We'll take him to Doc Tyler's.
I don't see why this had to happen,
just when everything was so fine.
Don't let your mind run on it.
I can't forget it, I tell you.
I never will.
Don't try, honey.
You got to get used to havin' all
kinds of things happenin' to you.
You got to look at all
the good on one side
and all the bad on the other side
and say, "Well, all right
then," to both of them.
Lots of things happen to a woman,
sickness or being poor
and hungry even,
being left alone in your old age,
being afeared to die,
and you can stand it.
There's one way.
You gotta be hardy. Ya gotta be!
Oh, I wished I was the way you are.
Oh, fiddlesticks! Scrawny and old?
You couldn't hire me
to be the way I am.
Oh, what'd I do without you?
You're such a crazy.
Sure as you're born.
(FOOTSTEPS)
Jud's over to Doc Tyler's.
They'll take care of everything.
Is he alive?
(MURMURING)
Laurey, honey, Cord Elam here,
he being federal marshal and all,
thinks I oughta give
myself up, and right now.
Oh, no!
Their train leaves Claremore in less
than an hour. It's their honeymoon.
The best thing is for Curly to go of
his own accord and tell the judge.
- Why, you're the judge, ain't you, Andrew?
- Yeah.
Then tell him now
and get it over with.
It wouldn't be proper.
It's gotta be done in court.
Oh, fiddlesticks. Let's do it here
and say we done it in court.
- Can't do that. That's breakin' the law.
- Let's not break the law.
- Let's just bend it a little.
- (LAUGHTER)
Come on, Andrew. Start the trial.
- We ain't got but a few minutes.
- Sure.
- Andrew, I got to protest.
- Aw, shut your trap.
We can give the boy a fair trial without
lookin' him up on his honeymoon.
All right. Here's the long
and the short of it.
What's your plea?
That means, Why'd you do it?
Well, Jud's been pesterin' Laurey.
- And I always swore...
- Just a minute.
Don't let your tongue wobble around
in your head. Listen to my question.
What happened last night
that made you do it?
Why, he tried to burn us to death,
and he come at me with a knife.
- And you had to defend yourself, didn't ya?
- Yes. Furthermore...
Never mind the "furthermores."
The plea is self-defense.
- All right. Order. Wait. Is there a witness,
- (CHATTERING LOUDLY)
wait a minute,
who's seen this happen?
- Absolutely.
- All right. Order.
I feel funny about it.
I feel funny.
You'll feel funny when I tell your wife
you're carrying on with another woman.
I ain't carrying on with no one!
Maybe not, but you'll sure feel funny
when I tell your wife you are.
Laugh all you like,
but as federal marshal...
Aw, shut up about being
federal marshal.
If we get to be a state, we're
gonna elect ourselves a sheriff.
If you don't keep your mouth shut,
ain't nobody gonna vote for ya.
Come on!
Yeah, let's get movin' and get
the happy couple on the train!
- (SHOUTING)
- Wait a minute! I ain't said the verdict yet.
- The verdict's not guilty, ain't it?
- 'Course, but I gotta say it.
- Then say it.
- (TOGETHER) Not guilty!
- Court's adjourned!
- (CHATTERING)
Got the rice?
Ado Annie, where you been?
You missed all the excitement.
Oh, no, we didn't.
- Hello, Will.
- (CHUCKLES)
Gotta get the young'uns on
that train, or they'll miss it.
Hey, there, bride and
groom, ya ready?
- Here we come!
- (PEOPLE CHEERING)
- (CHEERING CONTINUES)
- Oh, my crazy young'uns!
I don't know what
I'm gonna do without you!
- All right.
- Take care.
(PEOPLE WHOOPING)
- Good luck, Curly!
- Thank you! Bye!
Yaw!
Oh, what a beautiful morning
Oh, what a beautiful day
I got a beautiful feeling
Everything's goin' my way
Oh, what a beautiful day