Hey, lady, what kind of tattoo
did you get on you?
- I got a rose tattoo.
- Where did you get it, lady?
- Where did he put it on you?
- Right over my heart, little boy.
64 Front Street, lady.
Wait here.
- Little girl.
- Yes?
- You're a twig off the old rosebush.
- What?
Is the lady that does
the sewing in the house?
Nobody's here but Daddy and me.
And Daddy's asleep.
Do you mind if I wait on the porch
till she gets back?
She won't be long.
Where is your mama?
Ideal Grocery Store.
Look, she buys Grade A.
I buy Grade B.
- Now, which is which?
- Oh, yeah.
Don't mix up those eggs.
What difference is it?
Which is it?
I'll tell you the difference.
I got a Grade A husband,
that's the difference.
Oh, then I got a Grade B husband?
I don't know which grade
is your husband.
I got a Grade A husband,
and I know the difference.
Yeah, I know the difference,
and I don't give a Grade A husband
a Grade B egg for his breakfast.
- OK?
- Package. Your package, lady.
Where is somebody, please, to carry
this package for me on the street?
My husband don't allow me
- to carry big packages...
- Next.
- Like a horse on the street. Please!
Oh, my.
OK.
Thank you, huh?
- Buon giorno, Serafina.
- Buon giorno, Padre.
You are dressed for a party?
No, I am dressed
for a big celebration.
I got some wonderful news
to give my husband.
Oh? What news?
I got to tell this news
to my husband first.
I'm sorry, Father. Goodbye.
Goodbye.
Oh, my.
Mama.
- Is Papa home, cara?
- Yes, he's here.
A lady's waiting for you
on the porch, Mama.
- Lady?
- Yes.
- Open the door for me.
- All right.
Ale!
Oh, please.
Let me see. Let me see!
Let me see.
Such a perfume.
- My! Where is Papa?
- In the bedroom, sleeping.
- Sleeping?
- Yes.
Why don't you tell me he was
sleeping before I slam the door?
- Scimmia.
- He has to make a night run, Mama.
Don't make any noise.
Amore.
Come sai di buono.
I like the smell of rose oil
in your hair.
Good.
Oh, love, tonight is a feast, you know.
Because I have been to the doctor.
I have a new life in my body.
Yeah.
It's true. It's true.
Oh, love, stay with me tonight.
Don't go, please.
I don't understand these strange
night runs that you make.
I don't understand. I don't like it.
I don't like it.
Stay with me, please.
This... This night run
is the last that you make.
Is the last. You hear me?
You hear me, darling?
You... You promise me, darling.
- Si, last run. Si.
- OK.
OK, thank you. OK.
Mama? The lady says she can't wait.
Yeah. Vengo.
Rest, love. Rest.
I come back right away. Right away.
- Hello.
- Do you want something?
- I heard you do sewing.
Talk soft, please. My husband
is sleeping in there.
What do you want sewed?
How fast can you make
a shirt for me?
Oh, that depends.
I have some silk with me
I want made into a shirt.
- There.
- Wonderful.
Look at that colore.
Rosa, huh?
Wonderful stuff
for a blouse, pajamas.
Oh, I want a man's shirt
made out of it.
Silk this color for a...?
For a shirt for a man?
Well, this man's wild like a Gypsy.
He likes to feel
silk on his skin and wants
everything rose-colored.
A woman should not encourage
a man to be wild. Never.
If a man's wild, he's hard
for a woman to hold.
But if he's tame, would a woman
want to hold him?
I told you soft, please.
My husband's sleeping.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'm a married woman in business.
I don't know nothing about wild men
and wild women. I'm sorry.
I'll give you twice
what you ask me for it.
Money isn't the object,
but it has to be ready tomorrow.
- Tomorrow? Oh, it's impossible.
- Twenty dollars!
- Impossible.
- But it has to be ready tomorrow.
Because tomorrow's the anniversary
of the day we met,
me and this man I love.
I want him to wear this shirt
in honor of the occasion.
I have his measurements
right here with me.
Mama! The black goat
is loose in the yard!
- The black goat is loose in the yard!
- Keep him out of the yard.
Stop shouting. Let Papa sleep.
Pin the measurements,
your name on the silk,
and the shirt will be ready
tomorrow. I'm sorry.
My name's Estelle Hohengarten.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Catch him! My tomat...
Oh, my!
- The goat is loose.
- The goat's loose! The goat's loose!
Hey! Come back here!
- Mardi Gras Club.
- Rosa! Rosa!
You go in the house!
Don't look at the strega.
- Why do you call her a witch?
- She has the evil eye.
- Go in the house.
- She has a cataract.
On strillare.
She shook hands with the devil.
She did not shake hands with the devil.
She has rheumatism.
Malocchio. On strillare.
Go in the house.
And wash your face with saltwater,
and throw the saltwater away.
Go in the house!
Go in, quick! She's coming.
Malocchio.
Rosario.
Mama...
...why did Papa run away like that?
I don't know, Rosa.
Car 61 calling Car 62.
Come in, please.
Car 62, come in.
Be on the lookout. Five-ton truck
with brown canvas cover.
Left the Mardi Gras Club
ten minutes ago.
The Baron of Roses
picked up his load
at the Mardi Gras Club
ten minutes ago.
Check with Micky at the Four-Mile
Bridge and see if...
Standby. I think he's coming now.
- He made his last night run.
- Yeah.
He should've stuck
to hauling bananas.
Who's gonna tell her, Father?
I think a woman should.
I hear the sewing machine.
She's working.
She's holding up a piece
of rose-colored silk.
I think Assunta should tell her.
I think she already knows
what we have come to tell her.
- Something is wrong.
- What? What did you hear?
Come, ladies, we must go inside.
Don't speak.
Don't speak. Don't speak.
Don't speak. Please don't.
Don't speak.
Don't speak, please. Don't speak.
Don't speak. Don't speak.
She's lost the baby.
But Serafina's a strong woman.
She's going to pull
through this all right.
But she's trying not to breathe.
So she's got to be watched
and not allowed out of bed.
- You know how to give injections?
- Yes.
Needle. I use.
- I know how.
- Oh, fine. I'll get you some stuff.
Doctor, I wanted to talk to you.
The... The body.
The body of the man
must not be burned.
Rosario's body was burned
when the truck was burned.
Deliberate cremation
is not the same thing.
She wants the body cremated
so she can keep the man's
ashes in the house.
Well, if keeping the ashes in the house
will be any comfort to her...
But the body is dead.
The body must be buried.
Just a moment.
Father.
Where's the body?
Who are you?
Who are you? Please, who are you?
- Estelle Hohengarten.
- You cannot go in there.
See him, I have to.
- The body cannot be seen.
- I have to see him.
- You must go away, please.
- I've gotta see him.
- Please, you cannot go in there.
- I've got to.
- I've gotta see him.
- No, the body cannot be seen.
- But you must go away, please.
The widow knows nothing about you.
- Assassina!
- Vigliacca!
Sporcacciona!
Somebody stop the piano!
Stop it!
Stop it. Ferma!
Ferma.
Go home.
My father is dead.
Rosa, you're not going
to have any fun at the dance
unless you just forget
all about your dress.
Mama made five formals
for other girls.
She wouldn't make one for me.
She said if my Daddy was living
he wouldn't allow me to go
to a high-school dance.
But your father's been dead
three years. You're grown up now.
Rosa, you stop crying, or I won't
go another step with you.
I'm the only girl without a formal.
Wait. Just a minute.
I wanna fix your face.
Lutie, this is Jack Hunter.
- Hello.
- How do you do?
Who is that boy with Pauline Hunter?
That's her brother, Jack.
I think he's a dream of a dream.
- Girls, this is Art Noble and Ray Brinn.
- Hi.
- Good evening, Rosa and Violetta.
- Hello.
Jack, I'd like you to meet
Rosa Delle...
Why did Rosa run away like that?
She's all upset because
she's not wearing a formal.
Well, it's not important.
Not all girls have formals.
Excuse me.
La tua voca gentile
Piu non allieta il mio core
Come le rose d'Aprile
Le gioie d'amore...
Rose?
How do you know my name?
What other name could it be?
I'm not disappointed.
Honest, I'm not.
Well, I'm disappointed, sure, but...
What I mean is, I...
I respect you for it.
Actually, I did want to let you kiss me.
You know something?
We're locked in this place.
Locked?
Mama will kill me.
Hey, back there, did you
really want to let me?
I was scared to, though.
- My heart was beating so fast...
- You don't need to explain.
- Maybe next time I...
- When? When?
Is tomorrow OK?
Tomorrow and tomorrow
and tomorrow is OK, OK, OK.
Then tomorrow, I'll let you kiss me.
Civics, you study civics...
...till a quarter past one?
Yes, I study civics.
Civics is very important,
and tomorrow's the final.
Oh, I know.
I'm very tired, Mama.
Help me unfold the sofa, will you?
Come here, Rosa.
Come on.
Kneel to Our Lady and swear
to me you study civics.
No, I will not.
Because you don't study
no civics tonight.
"Don't study no civics."
Why do you talk like you just
came over in steerage?
This isn't Sicily, Mother,
and you are not a baroness.
You do sewing. Daddy...
Daddy hauled bananas.
He hauled bananas and something
under the banan...
You don't study no civics no more.
- Hey, where you going?
- I'm going to Serafina house.
Yesterday she don't
give me the dress.
She don't even open the door.
We break in and get them.
And to me, she said all week,
"Domani, domani."
But yesterday I told her, you know.
I says:
"Wait, Serafina, domani is
the high-school graduation,
"and I gotta have the dress,
because I gotta try it on my daughter."
Because my daughter got fat,
and she's gotta give it to me today.
Come on, let's go for the dresses.
- Giuseppina, go open the door.
- In just a minute.
Serafina!
Serafina Delle Rose!
Serafina, we want the dresses!
Rosa, take it off,
or I tear it to ribbons.
Mama, please.
I've got to go to school.
- It's the last day.
- Take it off.
- Let me at least go out for graduation.
Now I'm mad! And she's gotta give me
the dress whether she wants to or not.
I'm going to give them their dresses.
You ain't running out!
OK?
Rosa! Rosa!
You know I don't understand Italian,
so please.
- Now, what's happening here?
- Shut up.
You know, we came here
for the dresses...
- She cut her wrist, my daughter!
- Good heavens!
Call the doctor, please, someone.
Call the doctor.
Come in!
Mrs. Delle Rose, your daughter
has not cut her wrist.
- No? What?
- Your daughter's all right.
And you ladies, please, go away.
We don't go without our dresses.
The graduation begins,
and the girls ain't dressed.
Rosa. Come here.
Show your mother
- that you're not bleeding to death.
- Let me see.
Leave me alone. I'm so ashamed
I could die. Yes, so ashamed.
This is the way she goes
around all the time.
She hasn't put dress on
since my father was killed.
For three years,
she never puts a dress on
or goes out of the house,
and now...
Now she has locked up
my clothes so I can't go out.
She wants me to be like her,
a freak of the neighborhood.
The way she is!
Next time I won't cut my wrist,
but my throat!
On parlare cosi!
Mrs. Delle Rose, please give me
the key to your daughter's clothes
so she can dress for the graduation.
Please, Serafina, give us
our dresses, will you, please?
Now, you ladies, please.
I wanna chat with Mrs. Delle Rose.
I know, I know.
Well, you just wait outside.
Thank you. Just a moment.
Now, Mrs. Delle Rose, your daughter
missed her final examinations.
But her grades have been so good
that she'll be allowed to graduate
with her class and take
the examinations later.
You understand me,
Mrs. Delle Rose?
You see? I got a wild thing
in the house.
Now, let's not have any more
outbursts of emotion.
What?
Outbur...?
You make me sick.
Sick at my stomach, you make me.
Your school.
You make all this trouble.
You give this dance
where she gets mixed up...
Where she gets mixed up
with a sailor. With a sailor.
You're talking about
Pauline Hunter's brother Jack,
who attended the dance
with his sister?
- Attended with sister?
- Yes.
What sister? My... My daughter,
she's nobody's sister.
Don't listen to her, Miss Yorke.
Don't pay any attention to her.
- Rosa...
- I'm ready to go now.
She's lovely.
Come kiss Mama, darling.
Stop now.
- Kiss mama once...
- Leave me alone.
Don't go like that! Please!
Don't you dare come out
looking like that!
Rosa! How high is this high school
where she gets mixed up
with a sailor?
How high is this high school?
I will show you.
It's high like that horse's dirt
on the street.
That's your high school!
Scuola maledetta!
- Scuola maledetta!
- Mrs. Delle Rose,
I don't understand how a woman
that acts like you
could have such a sweet and refined
young girl for a daughter.
Oh, my.
Do you want me to talk refined,
do you?
Then do me one thing, please.
Stop ruining the girls
at the high school!
- OK?
- Serafina, look at yourself.
All these ladies here,
and you are not dressed.
I'm dressed OK! I'm not naked!
I'm so ashamed I could die.
I'm so ashamed.
Mama, you look disgusting.
Yes, disgusting!
Disgusting.
Did you hear what...?
What my daughter say to me?
"You look disgusting."
She calls me disgusting.
Serafina, now we must
go in the house.
Come on. Come on.
How pretty she look, my daughter,
in a white dress, like a bride.
How pretty.
Go away, please.
Did you hear what my daughter
called me?
She called me disgusting.
Disgusting.
There, Serafina. Thank you
very much. Thank you.
Disgusting.
Oh, the band.
I go to the high school.
Shut up, you.
I fail to understand why
we have to take a chance
missing the 12:00
just to pick up a blouse.
I told you this blouse can mean
the difference between a not-so-good
and a very good time
in New Orleans.
Wait till you see how sexy.
Where did I put the wristwatch?
Is my blouse ready, honey?
Oh, I'm late for the graduation
of my daughter.
- I can't find her graduation present.
- Well, I'm late, too.
- Come on, now. Where's the blouse?
- Blouse?
What blouse?
Oh, no ready.
I had to make 14 graduation
dresses. You know?
Well, now, a promise is a promise,
and an excuse is just an excuse, now.
Yeah, but I got to go
to the high school now.
Yeah, I know, but we gotta go
to the convention in New Orleans.
- Where is that wristwatch?
- Here. Here. Here it is.
Now, come on, woman.
Get started and sew them
bandanas together.
If you don't do it, I'm gonna report you
to the Chamber of Commerce
and have your license revoked.
What license you talking about?
I have no license.
You hear that, Flora?
- She don't have no license.
- No.
She's operating against the law
without no license?
Yeah.
I stitch them together, OK.
OK. OK.
OK.
Train's pulling out!
- You and your stinking blouse.
- Flora.
You know there's another one
at 12:45.
I fail to understand
why it's so important
for you to pick up
a polka-dot blouse.
- You make me sick.
- Come on, now, Flora. Sit down.
You're gonna wear your feet out
before we get to the city.
You let me worry about my own feet.
I heard that the convention delegates
caught a girl on Canal Street.
- Yeah?
- And they tore the clothes off her
and sent her home in a taxi!
I double-dog dare anybody
to try that on me.
You?
You'd walk home.
You two ladies,
watch how you talk in here.
This is a respectable house.
Oh, well...
...excuse me.
Polly want a cracker?
No, he don't want a cracker.
Polly, no.
There's some delegates
to the convention on the highway.
- No kidding?
- Yeah. Right there, see?
Yell something at them!
Mademoiselle from Armentieres
- Parlay-voo
Parlay-voo
Mademoiselle from Armentieres
Hasn't been kissed in 40 years
Look at that one. Isn't he cute?
- Come on over here.
- Come on out.
I told you women.
You are not in a honky-tonk.
You. Take your blouse now
and get out.
Get out on the streets
where you belong.
This is the house
of Rosario Delle Rose,
and I won't have dirty talk in here.
- Who's talking dirty?
- Yeah, who is?
You. You are. You are.
Dirty talk.
All the time, "Men, men, men."
- You two man-crazy things, you.
- Sour grapes.
Sour grapes is your trouble.
You are just wild with envy.
Come on, Bessie, let's get
out of here. Forget the...
Now just wait a minute. I don't accept
insults from anybody. Hear?
Go on. Go on the street and pick up
a man on Canal Street,
but not in my house at my windows.
Here is the memory of my husband,
with a...
With a body like a young boy
and skin on him smooth and sweet
as a yellow rose petal.
I'm satisfied to remember,
because I had the best,
and not the second best,
but the only best, a rose.
- A rose, was he?
- A rose, a rose.
Yeah, a rose of an Italian
that got shot
smuggling stuff under a load
of bananas.
Get out. Get out! I'm satisfied
to remember the love of a man
that was mine, only mine.
Never touched by nobody.
Nobody but me. Just me.
- Never touched by nobody?
- Nobody. Nobody but me.
Well, I know somebody
that could a tale unfold.
And not no further
than the Mardi Gras Club is.
Estelle Hohengarten,
the blackjack dealer from Texas.
Bessie, get into your blouse,
and let's get out of here.
Well, everybody knows.
All come out at the inquest.
Serafina was laying there in bed
with her eyes shut tight
and the sheet pulled over her head
like a... Like a female ostrich.
Tie this blasted thing on me,
will you?
It was a romance too.
Not no fly-by-night thing,
but a real steady affair
that went on for more than a year.
Oh, leave her in ignorance.
Ignorance is bliss.
He had a rose tattoo on his chest,
the stuck-up thing.
Estelle was so gone on him that
she went down to Bourbon Street
and had one put on her too.
Yeah, a rose tattoo on her chest,
same as the macaroni's.
- Liar! Liar!
- Bessie, let's go.
- Let's get out of here.
- Let her howl her head off.
You don't know what you're saying!
- You don't understand! Liar!
- A rose tattoo on her chest!
- Police!
- Liar!
- Get out!
- Murder! Police!
- Sour grapes! That's your problem.
- Sour grapes!
- Help! Murder! Police!
I'm gonna have her arrested.
I'm gonna call the police.
I'm gonna have you arrested,
hear?
- Oh, leave. Let's go.
- Have me arrested.
You and your yellow rose petals.
- Sour grapes!
- Have me arrested.
Sour grapes!
Rosario, give me a sign.
Tell me is not true.
Rosario, tell me is not true.
Lady, give me a sign.
Tell me is not true.
It's my money.
I can spend it how I like.
Well, pretend you didn't
buy them for me.
Tell Mama they're for her.
You're sure dying for me to make
a good impression on her, aren't you?
She's got the wrong idea about you,
that's why.
Now, say the roses are for her.
Please, Jack.
Mama must have gone out.
There is a key in the mailbox.
- How do you know she's out?
- The door was locked.
And all the shutters are closed.
Put down the flowers.
Come here.
I want to teach you a little Italian word.
- The word is bacio.
- Bacio? What's it mean?
This.
And this.
Just think.
A week ago Friday
I didn't know boys existed.
Did you know girls existed
before the dance?
I knew they existed.
Do you remember what you said
to me on the dance floor?
"Honey, you are dancing too close."
Well, it was hot in the gym,
and the floor was crowded.
When my girlfriend was teaching
me how to dance, I asked her,
"How do you know which way
the boy is going to move?"
And she said,
"You've got to feel how the boy's
going to move with your body."
I said,
"How do you feel
with your body?"
And she said,
"By pressing up close."
That's why I pressed up close.
I didn't realize that I was.
You're blushing.
Don't go away.
And a few minutes later
you said to me,
"Gee, you're beautiful."
I said, "Excuse me,"
and I ran to the ladies' room.
Do you know why?
To look at myself in the mirror.
For the first time in my life,
I felt I was beautiful.
You made me feel beautiful
when you said I was.
You are beautiful, Rosa.
So much, I...
Sta' zitta, cretina.
- I knew somebody was in here.
- Mama?
- Are you there, Mama?
- No, no. I'm not.
I'm dead and buried.
- Maybe I'd better go wait outside.
- No. No, you stay right here.
Mama...
...Jack is with me.
Are you dressed up nicely?
Why is it so dark in here?
Jack, open the shutters.
I want to introduce you to my mother.
- Hadn't I better go out...?
- No.
Mama, you said you were
dressed up pretty.
Jack, stay out for a minute, huh?
What's happened?
What's happened, Mama?
Look, put this on.
So... So... Here.
Here we are.
Good.
Let's fix your hair.
There you are.
Fine.
Jack?
Mama is ready to meet you.
Mama, su. Su, Mama.
Mama didn't sleep good last night.
Mama, this is Jack Hunter.
Hello, Mrs. Delle Rose.
It sure is a pleasure to meet you.
I was hoping to see you
at the graduation, Mrs. Delle Rose.
My sister was graduating.
My mother was there, and my father.
I... I was hoping you could
all get together.
Mama.
Jack... Jack brought you
some flowers.
I hope you are as partial
to roses as I am.
Mama.
Mama, say something.
Say something simple, like, "Thanks."
Thanks.
- I think your mama...
- No.
Oh, my diploma.
Yes, show Mama my diploma.
- Where is it?
- It's on the table there, near the piano.
Excuse me. I'll get it.
Mama. Mama, what's happened?
Can't you tell me, Mama?
Is it because of this morning?
Look, it's only a scratch.
Forget it, Mama.
Think it was just a bad dream
that never happened.
Here it is.
Look what I got, my diploma.
Father De Leo gave them out.
- Diploma?
- Si, right there.
You got the diploma?
Put it in the drawer,
with your father's clothes.
Mrs. Delle Rose, you should be very,
very proud of your daughter.
You know, Rosa was so pretty
when she walked on the stage
that people went:
Just like that.
Do you know what I mean?
They all went:
Because your daughter, Rosa,
was so lovely-looking.
How does it feel to be the mother
of the prettiest girl in the world?
Would you mind shutting up? Pazza.
Shut the front door, please.
There was a policeman come here
because of some trouble.
Mama, I've never seen you like this.
What will Jack think?
What do I care what Jack thinks?
You wild, wild, crazy thing, you,
with the eyes of your father.
Yes, ma'am, you certainly got a right
to be very proud of your daughter.
I'm proud of the memory
of her father.
He was a baron.
And who are you?
- What are you?
- Mama, I just introduced him.
- His name is Jack Hunter.
- Hunter?
Yes, ma'am, Hunter. Jack Hunter.
- What are you hunting, Jack?
- Mama. Mama.
What all of them are hunting.
To have a good time,
and the devils cares who pays for it.
I'm sick of men,
and I'm sick of women.
You, Rosa, get out... till I talk
to this boy, huh?
- I didn't bring Jack here to be insulted.
- No, it's all right, honey. It's all right.
Go on, let your mama talk to me.
I think your mama's just got
a slight wrong impression.
I got a... I got an impression.
Well, I'll get dressed.
Mama... Mama, please don't
spoil it for me.
The happiest day of my life.
- Mrs. Delle Rose...
- Delle Rose.
- Delle Rose. OK.
I'm sorry about all this. Believe me,
the last thing I had in mind
was getting mixed up
in a family situation.
Look, I come home
after three months at sea.
My sister was going to a high-school
dance, and she took me with her.
And there I met your daughter.
- What did you do?
- At the dance?
- We danced.
- What did you do after that?
We went to a place and had
an ice-cream soda, chocolate.
You mean you haven't been
alone with my Rosa, huh?
Alone or not alone,
what's the point of that question?
- I still don't see the point of it.
- No.
I'll show you the point.
We are Sicilians.
We don't leave the girls with the boys
they are not engaged to.
Mrs. Delle Rose,
this is the United States.
I know, but we are Sicilians.
We are not cold-blooded.
My girl is innocent, pure.
She is, or she was.
I would like to know which.
Mrs. Delle Rose,
I gotta tell you something.
You may not believe it.
It's a hard thing to say.
Say it. Say it.
Well, maybe I'm a sailor and all that,
and the things they say about sailors...
But all of us...
I mean, a girl in every port and all.
- No?
- I haven't got a girl in every port.
I haven't got a girl in no port,
anyplace.
What I'm getting at is...
...I am innocent too.
What? No.
- I don't believe it.
- Well, it's true, though.
This is the first time
I really wanted to.
Wanted to what?
Make love.
You, a sailor.
Well, I had opportunities to, but...
Well, I always thought of my mother.
Well, I always asked myself,
would she or would she not think
this or that person was decent.
But...
But with my daughter, my Rosa,
your mother tell you,
"OK, go ahead, son." Huh, no?
Oh, Mrs. Delle Rose...
Mrs. Delle Rose, I...
She say she's in love.
And you?
You say you are in love?
Yes, ma'am, I do.
I'm in love, very much.
Cretini. Tutti e due.
I'm ready for Diamond Key.
Get out on the porch, Diamond Key.
Ale, ale.
Ale.
- Yes, Mama.
- OK.
- What are you, Catholic?
- Me? Yes, ma'am. Catholic.
- You don't look Catholic to me.
- Mama, how do Catholics look?
Do they look different
from anyone else?
You will stay out on the porch. Huh?
- All right.
- Thank you.
Turn around, will you?
- Do what, ma'am?
- I said, turn around.
Mama, what are you doing?
Get out till I call you!
Why do they make them Navy pants
so tight? I don't know.
That's a question you'll have to ask
the Navy, Mrs. Delle Rose.
Mama, will you stop asking
so many questions?
You see what I got?
A wild thing in the house.
Mrs. Delle Rose...
Delle Rose,
I guess Sicilians
are very emotional people.
I want nobody
to take advantage of that.
Look, you got the wrong idea
about me, Mrs. Delle Rose.
I know what men want.
Not to eat ice cream with girls
or dance on the floor, no.
And boys are the same,
only younger.
- Come here.
- Mama!
Mama! Let me in the door, Jack!
Mrs. Delle Rose,
your daughter's calling you.
Let her call. Don't worry about it.
Come here. Come here.
- You said you're a Catholic, ain't you?
- Yes, ma'am.
- Kneel down here.
- Mama, now what?
Go away, will you?
And say after me what I say.
What? Why? Why?
I promise the Holy Mother
- that I will respect the...
- Mama!
Today I kill you if you don't leave.
- Are you gonna say it?
- Yes, ma'am.
OK.
- Go ahead.
- What was it again?
I promise the Holy Mother...
That I will respect the innocence...
Of the daughter Rosa
of Rosario Delle Rose.
of Mrs. Delle Rose.
No, Rosario Delle Rose.
Of Rosario Delle Rose.
Get up.
I'm satisfied.
- Wonderful!
- I'm satisfied.
- Wonderful, Mama.
- Let me breathe. Let me breathe.
Let me go! Let me go!
- No, please, Mama.
- Crazy thing. Crazy...
- Jack, kiss Mama.
- Mama, kiss Jack.
Won't kiss Jack! Won't kiss Jack!
Are you crazy, kiss? Me? Me?
Oh, my.
Kiss my hand.
- OK.
- Mama, get some wine glasses.
There, there.
Oh, they're here.
They're calling. Coming!
Come on, Jack!
Come on, Rosa!
OK, OK! Goodbye, Mama.
Goodbye.
- Good night, Mrs. Delle Rose.
- Goodbye, but...
But the wine.
Come on, let's go!
The wristwatch.
Where is it?
Rosa! Rosa!
Your little wristwatch!
With seventeen jewels in it! Rosa!
Rosa, Rosa.
Oh, Lady, speak to me.
Tell me it isn't true.
Give me a sign.
Get your ice-cold lemonade.
Fine soft drinks.
N-37.
Thirty-one. N-31.
B-46.
Serafina Delle Rose, come sta, cara?
Come and sit down.
I got to see Father De Leo.
Where is Father De Leo?
- Sit down, please.
- No, I must find Father De Leo now.
- Have a seat, lady.
- I want you to meet my brother.
- Pleased to...
- Hello, hello.
- Take my chair.
- No, just find me the Father now.
This is the bachelor brother
I talk to you about.
He is working.
He is in his work clothes.
I am sorry you should meet him
like this in his work clothes.
Yeah, I got a big load of bananas
in my truck.
- I bring the folks here, now I go.
- Later, later.
Later I come back to pick up the folks.
Silence. Shut up, stupid.
Speak English.
You look tired.
Here, sit down in the chair.
Father De Leo!
I'm sorry.
- B-10!
- Me, me. Bingo. Bingo, me.
Bingo, bingo. Bingo.
Father De Leo...
- I got to see you, Father.
- Why, Serafina?
Let me talk to you, Father, please.
Come away from here.
You know these ladies.
- I know, I know. Hello.
- Serafina.
But this is private, Father.
You ladies, please, go.
Play with the bingo.
Thank you.
Bingo! I can't talk here, Father.
Come away from here.
Calm yourself, Serafina.
- We can talk in my office.
- Yes, thank you.
No. No, Father.
Not through the church, please.
- What's the matter?
- Where I was married, no.
Where you were married, where
your child was baptized and confirmed.
No, Father, please.
Not through the church.
Here.
We can talk here.
I fell down when I was married.
Do you remember, Father?
You collapsed at the altar.
I had just come to this country.
Do you remember?
Yes, I remember.
The marriage had been
arranged by letter,
exchanged between you and...
You remember.
I thought he would be ugly.
I couldn't speak.
I couldn't speak
from the moment I saw him
till the night after the marriage.
Then I said only, "Oh, love."
"Oh, love."
I had married a rose.
I didn't know I was
going to marry a rose.
I couldn't speak nothing in English
except, "Oh, love."
"Oh, love."
"Oh, love." Oh, Father!
I can't breathe in this building.
I can't breathe in this building
where I was married, Father.
Serafina. Serafina.
I am not going to spare
your feelings, Serafina.
I'm gonna talk to you honestly,
as your spiritual father.
I am shocked. I am shocked
at the change in your...
In your appearance and behavior
since the loss of your husband.
Grief is a natural and dignified thing,
but like every other emotion, Serafina,
it can become excessive.
Then... Then it becomes
a sort of self-indulgence.
I knew this was going to happen
when you refused to obey
the laws of the church
and had your husband cremated.
I remember you dressed in blue silk.
Yes, yes. Like a lady wearing
a piece of the weather.
You walked tall and proud.
Now, you crouch and you shuffle.
You... You live and dress
like a convict.
You have no companions.
You're rude to your neighbors.
You don't mix with the women who...
They make the life without glory.
I gave my husband much glory.
I was the peasant,
but I gave him glory.
I came to him with one dress,
but I brought him glory.
He was a baron,
and I brought him glory.
I brought him glory, glory.
Glory.
I don't believe that he took this glory
I gave him and gave me horns.
I don't believe he gave me horns,
Father!
What do you want from me?
Go to the bingo.
- Per I'amor di Dio.
- Go!
Serafina, the ladies only want
to be your friends.
Friendly?
They think they know something
that Serafina don't know.
They think I have these on my head.
But I ain't. No, I ain't!
Serafina, I think you
imagine too much.
The ladies want to be
your companions.
Companions. Them ladies.
The dummies I got in my house,
they make much better companions,
because they don't make up no lies.
No, no. What kind of ladies
are them women, huh?
At 30 years old, they got
no more use for the marriage,
except for the money,
the shoes, the food.
- What do you call this kind of ladies?
- Attenzione.
To me the marriage was beautiful,
like a religion.
Now my marriage
is dreams and memories only.
And I don't believe that the man
I keep in my heart gave me horns.
I don't believe, no!
I don't believe!
I don't believe he gave me horns!
The whole village is... Well,
the whole village is laughing at you.
Me too, I'm laughing.
- Listen to me! I'm laughing too!
- Serafina.
- Laughing!
- Serafina Delle Rose.
- Why aren't you laughing anymore?
- I think you had better go home.
- Serafina.
- No.
I think you had better go home.
Yes, I'll talk to you later.
No. Later's too late, Father.
You've got to tell me now.
Tell you what?
You used to... You used to hear
the confession of my husband.
Father, please,
did my husband ever speak of a...?
- Of a woman to you?
- Serafina.
Oh, Father, rispondetemi...
...this one question.
Did he ever speak of a woman to you?
- Serafina, how...?
- Tell...
- How can I tell you something I...?
- Tell me, Father. You got to tell me.
Serafina...
- Father, tell me. Please, tell me.
- Serafina.
You know better than to ask me
such a question.
The secrets of the confessional
are sacred to the priests.
- I know.
- They are never...
- They are never repeated.
- I know, but tell me.
You got to tell me.
- Tell me, Father.
- Please, Serafina. Let go of me.
Not till you tell me this question,
this answer. I want it. I want it.
Let go of me. Let go of me.
- Tell me, I let go.
- Let go of me.
- You don't tell, I never let go.
- Please.
I go mad! I go crazy! I never let go!
I never let go, Father.
- I tell you, Father.
- Mr. Mangiacavallo.
Mr. Mangiacavallo, please help me
calm this woman down.
I'll speak to her later,
when she's more calm.
Father! Father!
Oh, please. Please.
Father De Leo!
Father De Leo, tell me please.
Tell me, please. Tell me, please.
Tell me. Tell me.
Come on.
You'll be all right.
- Where am I?
- This... This is my truck.
It's OK.
- No, where...?
- You're OK.
I drive you home from the church.
You rest.
I'm sorry I couldn't take
you home in a taxicab.
But I'm a bachelor
with three dependents,
I can't afford no cab fare.
And you didn't have a purse with you.
Oh, yeah. Where is my purse?
- Did you have a purse with you?
- I think so. I don't know.
You want to go back and get it?
- We'll look for it?
- No, no, no.
- You sure?
- I want to go home, please.
That's almost where you are now.
When somebody else
is crying I gotta cry too.
I'm sympathetic.
I got too much of a heart.
Don't cry. Why should you cry?
I know. It ain't like a man.
Oh, a man sometimes
has to cry like anyone else.
You're very understanding.
Sometimes a man has to cry
the same as a woman.
A man is not so different
from anyone else.
- Take it.
- Oh, grazie.
You stop that, then I'll stop too, huh?
No, you stop first, and I'll stop.
No, you first.
Ladies first, you know?
Ladies first.
I stop. OK?
OK, me too. I stop, see?
Your shirt is torn, huh?
Oh, yes, Mrs. Delle Rose.
You tore it when I pulled you
away from the priest.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- I'll sew it for you.
- Oh, that's nothing. It's nothing.
- Forget it.
- I'll sew it for you. Come on.
I'm ready to laugh now.
Oh, my.
I'm sorry you lost your pocketbook,
you know?
How much money you got
in the pocketbook? Much?
Don't worry about it.
Let me worry about it.
Give me your shirt.
And, please, will you
open the shutters for me?
- I can't see.
- Oh, sure. Sure.
A little bit.
What, lady?
The light on the body was like
a man that lived here.
- What?
- Oh, my.
Ma che strano.
Your people,
they come from Naples?
- No, no. Sicily.
- Sicily!
Well, what's the matter?
- Nothing. Nothing.
- Che c'e?
Nothing. Nothing.
You got a bathroom in your house?
- You got a bathroom in your house?
- Of course we have a bathroom.
- We don't have one at our house.
- No?
And I would like to wash up,
because I think maybe I smell
like a goat, you know?
- Oh, please. Help yourself.
- Grazie.
- This way.
- Con permesso.
Prego.
Oh, Madonna Santa.
Madonna Santa, my husband's
body with a head of a clown.
A clown that smells like a goat.
Oh, Lady. Lady, speak to me.
Is it the sign, this?
Oh, please.
- Ciao!
- Oh, ciao. You startled me.
I washed up. I feel better.
You feel better too?
Yeah, much better, thank you.
Now I cried, and I feel much better.
That's good.
Yeah, and now I can't get up.
- You mean you can't get down.
- I mean... Yeah, I can't get down.
What's that you got in your hand?
A bottle of vino?
- What?
- Vino. Is that vino?
Yeah, Spumanti it is. Yeah.
It comes from the house
of the family of my husband.
A very great family, you know.
The Delle Rose. Barons.
- Barons?
- Yes. I...
I was a peasant,
but I married a baron.
I married a baron
when I didn't have shoes.
Oh, shoes. What shoes?
You had three very sweet things.
Heart, face and figure.
And even a baron's human.
- You know, like a truck driver.
- Yeah.
- I sew the shirt now for you, huh?
- OK.
I'm a very frank person.
I'll tell you something.
My old-maid sister, she wanted us
to meet each other.
- Yeah? Why?
- Well, she says,
"This very nice lady, this widow,
this baronessa,
"she's lonely and you're lonely.
Why don't you get acquainted?"
She wanted us to meet each other
before this time, you know?
- Really?
- Yeah, really.
I'm a frank person, too,
and I'll tell you something now.
You can tell your sister
I don't need to meet nobody,
because my husband is with me.
We are not separated.
I turn around, and I see my husband
here with me in this...
Bottle?
Bottle.
Urn. Marble urn. Come here.
You see, the ashes of the rose
that I keep in my heart.
I'm sorry, I...
No, it's nothing.
The priest was against it.
It broke the laws of the church.
I know.
But I had...
I had to have something.
And this was all I could have.
I think God has forgiven.
What makes you think
that God has forgiven?
- I know him.
- You know him?
I know him. He has forgiven.
You'll see.
Nobody knows how lonely
someone can be.
There's nothing wrong with it.
The body would've decayed,
but the ashes always stay clean,
you know?
Gentle.
You see,
this is our wedding picture.
Hey. Che bell'uomo.
Yeah, a rose of a man, my husband.
A rose, a rose.
On his chest he had
a rose tattoo, you know?
- A rose tattoo?
- Yeah.
- No.
- A rose tattoo.
- Let me see.
- Oh. "Let me see."
- "Let me see."
- Yeah, right.
Do you believe strange things?
I would like to tell you something,
but I got to speak frankly, you know?
Speak frankly. We're both
grown-up adult people.
Yeah. You know, my husband,
he had this rose tattoo on his chest.
One night I woke up
with a burning pain on me here.
I turned on the light in the bedroom,
and I looked in the mirror.
On my breast, I saw
the rose tattoo of my husband.
On me here, his tattoo.
- Strano.
- Yeah.
And this was the night that...
- Yeah, but I got to speak frankly.
- Speak frankly. Come on.
That was the night that I got my son.
The little boy that I lost
when I lost Rosario.
- When I lost my husband.
- Strano.
Ah, si. Che davvero.
Would you be willing
to show me the rose tattoo?
- What?
- Well...
It's gone now. Oh, please.
It only lasted a moment,
but I saw it so clearly.
So clearly, I saw it.
- You believe me?
- Si, si. Lo credo.
Maybe it could be back, no?
I don't know why I told you,
you know?
- Well, I just...
- Only because I liked what you say.
That bodies decay, but the ashes
always stay clean. Immacolato.
But there are some people...
Oh, there are some people,
they want to make everything dirty.
Everything dirty, believe me.
Two of them kind of people
come in the house today
and told me a terrible lie...
about my husband.
So terrible a lie that if I thought
it was true, you know,
I would smash it.
Smash the urn, like...
- Like this!
- No, no, lady.
- Not the wine.
- Oh, no.
- Not the wine. No, don't be afraid.
Not the wine. Not the wine.
- Will you open the wine for me?
- Sure, sure.
- Thank you. Oh, my head.
- What...?
Well, what kind of a lie
did they tell you?
No, no, no.
I don't want to talk about it.
I don't believe the lie.
The memory of the rose
in my heart is perfect.
Oh, I like a lady that laughs
with all her heart.
And a lady that cries with her heart?
I like everything a lady
does with her heart.
- Look at your face!
- I know!
- Here.
- What's happening?
Hey, you kids! Get off of that truck!
Keep your paws off
of them bananas!
Oh, I forgot.
- You haul bananas?
- Si, signora.
I was supposed to get my truck
into Biloxi an hour, two hours ago.
It's a five-ton truck?
- A three-ton truck.
- Three?
My husband hauled bananas
in a five-ton truck.
- Well, he was a baron.
- He was...
- Yeah. Did you haul just bananas?
- Just bananas. What else?
My husband hauled bananas,
but underneath the bananas
was something else, you know.
Oh, he was wild like a Gypsy.
He was wild like a Gypsy.
Where did I hear that before?
He was wild like a Gyp...
I hate to start to remember,
you know?
And then not to remember,
I better call my boss in Biloxi,
explain how come I'm so late.
- It's a long-distance call?
- Don't worry about it.
No, no, please. I don't worry
about it. You will pay.
- Hello, operator?
- Umber, please.
Get me the Southern Fruit Company
in Biloxi, 2-4-6-8-1. That's right.
- Yes, sir.
- Oh, my number is 6-6-9-9.
That's right.
You know, you got a nice,
cozy little home-like place here.
Yeah. How is the place
where you live in?
I got a place with three
dependents in it.
The line is busy.
- Prego.
- Hey, grazie.
What dependents?
- Is good Spumanti.
- This is good.
Well, there's...
There's the one old-maid sister,
one feeble-minded grandmother
and one lush of a pop
who ain't worth the powder it takes
to blow him to... Scusatemi.
You know,
they got the Parchesi habit.
- Yeah?
- They play the game of Parchesi
morning, night and noon.
And they pass the cans of beer
around the table.
They got the beer habit too?
And the numbers habit.
You know, this spring
my old-maid sister,
she gets some kind of lady trouble.
Mostly mental, I think.
And she turns the housekeeping over
to the feeble-minded grandmother,
who's a very sweet old lady,
but who don't think it's necessary
to pay the grocery bills
as long as she's got money
to play the numbers.
She plays the numbers.
She's got a perfect system,
but it don't ever work.
And the grocery bills go up, up,
up so high you can't see them.
- I better try my boss again.
- Yeah.
I'll tell you my hopes and dreams.
- Who, me?
- Operator. The number, please.
Oh, excuse me.
Hello, operator?
The Southern Fruit Company
in Biloxi, 2-4-6-8-1.
- That's right.
- May I have your number?
My number is 6-6-9-9.
- 6-6-9-9, that's right.
- Yes, sir.
I'm hoping to meet some
sensible older lady, you know?
I don't care if she's a little bit too plump
or not such a stylish dresser.
The important thing
in a lady is understanding.
- Good sense, you know?
- Yeah.
And I want her to have a nice,
well-furnished house
and a profitable little business
of some kind.
I see. And...
...such a lady, with a well-furnished
house and business,
what does she want with a man
with three dependents
and the Parchesi and the beer habit,
plays the numbers? Oh, my!
Love and affection in a world that...
That's lonely and cold.
Yeah, it might be lonely, but I would
not say cold on this particular day.
Love and affection is what I got
to offer on hot or cold days
in this lonely old world.
I got nothing else.
- Mangiacavallo has nothing.
- Who?
- Me! Alvaro Mangiacavallo.
- Oh, yeah.
You know, Mangiacavallo means
"eat a horse". You know this.
But I don't have a horse to eat,
not even a chicken.
I'm the grandson
of the village idiot of Riveri.
- Oh, I see you like to make jokes now.
- No, no. No joke. Davvero!
He chased my grandmother
in a flooded rice field.
She slipped on a wet rock:
Ecco, here I am.
Oh, please. You should be
more respectful, you know?
What have I got to respect?
The rock my grandmother slips on?
Yourself at least.
You don't work for a living?
Hey, if I don't work for a living
I would respect myself more.
- Yeah?
- Baronessa, I'm a healthy young man.
Hey, I exist without
no genuine love life.
I look at them pictures
in the magazines...
Them girls in the advertisements,
you know what I mean.
They got a little bitty thing here,
a little bitty thing there.
That's all they need,
they're so skinny!
Yeah. It's a long-distance call,
you know.
Is the line busy?
- Not the line, the boss.
- The boss.
Get your boss on the phone
or hang up.
- OK, OK.
- Hello. Pilade talking.
Oh, hello!
Oh, hello, Mr. Pilade!
How's things at the Southern
Fruit Company this hot afternoon?
Yeah, Mangiacavallo!
- I got a complaint about you.
- What? Well, what complaint?
- What happened?
- I tell you. Over three hours ago,
Joe passed the church
and seen your truck parked
with the bananas and
you playing bingo.
Ow, you get them bananas here.
You're fired, you hear?
- What?
- Drive your truck for somebody else.
Mr. Pilade!
Well, wait a minute, Mr...
- What's happened?
A man with three dependents
out of a job.
And my truck ain't even paid for.
I can't see no more. I got
a suggestion to make you, huh?
Open that drawer, and you will
find a package with a shirt in it.
- This one?
- You can wear it
and call for this one later.
- There's a name on it.
- No, don't tell me the name, please.
Throw it away. Out the window.
Ecco fatto.
Seta! Seta puro!
Oh, this shirt's too good
for Mangiacavallo.
Everything here is too good
Nothing's too good for a man,
if the man's good.
Put it on. You are welcome to it.
- Bella?
- Oh, bella.
- Can I...?
- Sicuramenti. Prego.
- How does it feel, the silk on you?
- Just feels like a girl's hands on me.
It will make you less trouble,
believe me.
You know, there's nothing more
beautiful than a gift between people.
- No?
- Yeah.
You like me a little better now, huh?
You know what they should
have done when you was a baby?
- What?
- They should have put tape
on your ears... to hold them back.
Like this. Lookit.
Is not much better, huh?
So when you grow up,
they wouldn't stick out
like the wings of a little kewpie.
Lady, lady! The black goat
is loose again!
II becco della strega.
Look at my tomatoes.
Look at my...! Oh, the strega.
She has a demon eye, you know.
Now, don't get excited.
Don't worry.
I will catch the black goat, and I'll give
him a kick he'll never forget.
Come on! Come on!
I got a friendship with goats.
Come on!
It was nothing.
Oh, no. Please.
Look.
Oh, my.
In here. Yeah.
- OK.
- You're troppo gentile, signora.
Delle Rose.
Signora Delle Rose.
I have to go now.
I know, I know. Please. Please.
Wonderful. Oh, wonderful!
Excuse the way I'm not dressed.
I'm not always like this, no.
Sometimes I fix myself up, yeah.
When my husband was living,
when my husband comes home...
When he was living, I had
a clean dress on, you know?
And sometimes even...
Even I put a rose in my hair.
A rose in your hair would be pretty.
Oh, yeah, but not for a widow.
It's not the time of roses.
Why? You make a mistake.
It's always for everybody
the time of the roses.
- Yeah?
- The rose is...
The rose is the heart
of the world like the...
Like the heart is the heart
of the body. How's that?
Good, eh?
But you, baronessa, you know
what I think you have done?
- What have I done?
- You have put your heart
in the marble urn with the ashes.
Oh, yes.
And if in a storm sometimes,
or sometime if a five-ton truck
goes down the highway
and the marble urn was to break...
Look! Look, baronessa!
Look what? I don't see.
I was pointing to your heart.
Broken out of the urn!
Rondinella felice!
Che buffone. I take you serious,
and you make jokes.
Your heart is a happy bird.
When I can bring the shirt back?
- When you pass by again.
- I'll come back tonight, volete?
OK.
Then look at the window tonight.
If the shutters are open
and there is a light in the window,
you can stop by for your shirt.
But if the shutters are closed,
you better not stop because
my Rosa will be home.
- Rosa?
- Yeah. Rosa's my daughter.
There's nothing wrong in two grown-up
people having a quiet conversation,
but Rosa's 15.
I must be careful to set her
a perfect example.
- I will look at the window!
- OK.
I will look at the win...
- Bang, bang!
- Hey, you little monkey.
- Get down off that truck.
- Go chase your head!
Come on. Come on. Get down.
Here we go. Come on.
Jump!
You little monkey,
you lay off of them bananas.
They're the property
of the Southern Fruit Company.
Of which I am no longer
a truck driver.
Ciao.
Hey, you!
Oh, Rosario, forgive me
for thinking the terrible lie
could be true.
Forgive me.
You're in a mood.
You act disgusted with me.
Ever since you met Mother,
you've acted different.
How different?
Cold.
Honey, your mother made me
understand the responsibility of...
- Of what?
- Loving a very young girl.
I'm old enough to get married.
Married?
Yes! Married and have a baby.
That's something to dream of.
You dream.
I am not a dreamer.
I am not satisfied with dreams.
Look, they can see us.
Lift the anchor and
take the boat out further.
Miss Yorke has field glasses.
Field glasses! Field glasses!
Well, they're German military field
glasses with 20 magnification.
Field glasses!
- Alvaro, what happened?
- You didn't get enough games today?
- Oh, che bello!
- Here, wrap this up, quick. Subito.
- What? What?
- I borrowed it from the widow.
- How's the Parchesi today?
- Oh, she cheats me.
Sei tu che sei un imbroglione!
- Imbroglione?
- On giochi bene, te I'ho detto!
- Onna, gioca. Tocca a te.
- Stupido! Anche tu! Anche tu!
Perche' gli lasci prendere
la-tua cravatta?
Ma perche' tu imbrogli sempre,
imbrogli sempre? On lo vuoi capire.
- Hello.
- Oh, hello. You...?
You Mama Shigura?
You want tattoo? Portrait?
No. Tattoo.
But can you do it now?
Because I ain't got a lot of time.
OK. Very fast. Very good.
Formerly New Orleans.
Formerly Galveston.
Formerly Yokohama.
Very good.
I want a rose tattooed here,
here on my chest.
You understand? A rose.
OK. Six dollar.
Oh, no. That's too much.
I give you $2.
OK. Four dollar. No stem.
Just a rose.
Two-fifty is all I got to spend
on a rose tattoo, see?
I'll show you.
OK. Very good.
Take off shirt. Sit down.
But you got to make me a nice,
big, beautiful rose, huh?
But for $2.50,
no leaf, no stem. Just the rose.
- The rose is all I need.
- OK.
It's cold!
I give you a little stem.
Where is it? Where is it?
Eccola qua. Quarda dov'era.
Rondinella felice!
I will look at the window!
C'e nessuno?
Anybody home?
Sono qua.
Here I am.
Where you go?
- Well, good evening.
- Good evening.
- Well!
- What?
Say, you... Hey!
- You... Look, your hair...
- What's...? What's the matter, huh?
I didn't expect to see
you looking so pretty.
You're a young little widow,
you know?
- You are... Fix yourself up.
- Yeah. I went to the Ideal Barbers.
I got the whole works,
including the bath.
- No!
- Yeah.
Magnifique!
Oh, you got oil of roses
in your hair.
Si, si! Olio di rose.
- You like the smell of it? Smell it.
- Yeah, yeah. I like the smell of it.
You don't like the smell of it.
I'll wash it out. I'll take it off.
I like it! I like it! I like.
I like the smell of it. I like.
OK.
Shall we sit down
in the parlor, huh?
I guess that's better than
standing up in the kitchen, no?
I think so. OK. OK.
Oh, hey. Let me help you.
I'll take it. I'll take it.
Oh, grazie.
Oh, excuse me. Ladies first.
Shall we...? Shall we sit
down on the sofa?
Yeah. You... You take the sofa.
I will sit down on this chair.
But it's more easy to talk
with two on the sofa.
Yeah, but I lean back
too far on that sofa,
and I like a straight back
behind me, you know?
But it's more easy to talk with two
on the sofa. You know what I mean?
I talk just good on this chair as I talk
on that sofa. Sit down, please.
- Oh, can I help you?
- Oh, no. I'll put it over there.
- It's all right.
- Thank you.
- I got a good surprise for you.
- Yeah?
- Wait till you see.
- No! Oh, my purse.
- Father De Leo had it in his office.
- Oh, thank you.
Open it. Count the money.
- Why should I count the money?
- You're rich, and I'm poor.
How do you know
I didn't steal from you?
Oh, such an idea.
I would never think such a thing.
I would never dream of it,
believe me.
I want you to know that
I may be honest, but I'm poor.
I'll put away the purse.
- Excuse me, eh?
- Sure.
- Good evening again.
- Good evening.
Good evening.
I bet you counted the money, huh?
Yeah. I see you like
make jokes again, huh?
- I got another surprise for you.
- No. What?
- For you.
- Oh, no! Chocol...
Chocolate... Chocolates...
Thank you, but, you know,
I'm too fat to eat candy.
- Oh, no.
- I can't.
Oh, no. You're not fat.
You're just pleasing
and plump, you know?
Yeah.
- Don't make me nervous now, huh?
- All right.
Thank you. Thank you.
- It's all right.
- Thank you. Bella.
Oh, I see you got a piano.
Yeah, yeah.
But I never touch it, no.
It's electric. You know,
I don't understand it.
I think it might give me a shock.
- I'm afraid of this. I'm afraid.
- There's no... There's nothing to it.
I'll show you.
- It's very simple.
- Don't touch it!
- You press this.
- Don't touch! I can't stop now.
I'm afraid, oh...
Look at... He's crazy, he's...
Oh, my!
Will you stop the dance?! Please!
Oh, look!
Chiudi quella finestra! Ma che modi!
Chiudi quella finestra!
- A guardano!
- Oh, yeah, yeah. OK.
Dio mio! Turn on the lights!
- What? What?
- Turn on the lights, please!
Turn on the lights!
I can't hear you!
Sit down like a gentleman,
or go home like a clown!
- Oh, scusatemi, baronessa!
- Va bene!
- I like the music too much.
- Sit down!
OK. Take it easy. Take it easy.
Sit down.
Oh, I'm afraid now.
Oh, now, don't be afraid.
It's easy. Look.
There you are. OK.
Oh, please. Look at this.
I got a daughter, 15, no?
- Fifteen daughters?
- Yeah, 15 daughters.
Age 15. One daughter. Clown!
- I just make a joke.
- Yeah, I see. I see.
- Oh, excuse me.
- May I now?
- Well, I'm so nervous tonight.
- Here, let me help you.
Why are you nervous?
- Because she's going out with a sailor.
- Your daughter?
Yeah. Sit down, please.
No, no. Not here.
Over there, over there.
I made him promise to respect
the innocence of my Rosa.
But how do I know that he will
respect the promise, you know?
Oh, baronessa, you got to face facts.
Sooner or later the innocence
of your daughter cannot be respected
if the family's gonna continue,
you know?
Please, don't make comparisons,
huh?
Did he have a tattoo?
Did who have a what?
"Did who have a...?" The sailor.
The sailor your daughter has met,
did he have a tattoo?
Why do you ask me if he had a tattoo?
Well, you know, most sailors
have got tattoos.
How do I know if he had a tattoo
or not? Are you crazy?
- I got a tattoo.
- No, really?
Yeah!
Oh, you make me laugh.
What kind of a tattoo you got?
- What kind do you think?
- Oh, it's easy.
A South Sea girl without clothes on.
- Oh, no, no.
- I'm sure.
- No South Sea girl without clothes on.
- No?
- No, no.
A big, red heart with "Mama".
"Mama" written across it.
You're wrong again, baronessa.
- What kind of tattoo you got?
- I show you.
See?
Well, what's the matter?
- I'm sorry.
- What's the matter?
I don't feel good.
Oh, I'm sorry, I...
- I got to go outside.
- I'm sorry, baronessa.
I got to go outside to breathe,
please.
Mi dispiace molto.
I didn't mean to surprise you.
Don't talk about it.
Anybody could have a rose tattoo.
It don't mean nothing.
- Sure, I know.
- You know, I can't breathe.
It's too hot tonight.
You know how a tin roof is.
Yeah, I know.
It catches the sun all day,
- and it don't cool off until midnight.
- Yeah.
Then it gets hot in the bedroom,
and the covers, they...
No, please! Please.
We got a strega.
A witch next door. Please!
Please don't touch me!
You got a bright house.
- You're burning kilowatt hours. Why?
- That's all right.
You don't have to pay
the light bill. Please!
Yeah, I know. But don't you feel
self-conscious with all the light on?
Everybody looks in. They watch us.
They see what we do.
Nothing is going on here
to be ashamed of.
- Nothing.
- Nothing!
Nothing.
Yeah. What are you
doing that for now?
You know, the night is warm,
but my hands are freezing.
- Bad circulation.
- Too much circulation.
I feel the sweet warmth of a lady.
You know?
You talk a sweet mouth
to fool a...
- To fool a woman, huh?
- No, no, I know.
That's what warms the world,
what makes it summer.
Without it, the rose wouldn't
grow on the bush.
The fruit wouldn't grow on the tree.
And the truck would not haul
the bananas,
Mr. Mangiacavallo, I know!
What, you don't like my poetry?
No, I don't like your poetry!
How can a man talk to you?
No, please!
Is that your poetry?
Andate a casa. Cialtrone!
- Go home!
- Understanding is so necessary.
- I understand plenty. Go home!
- Please, baronessa.
- Go home! Don't touch me!
- So soft is a lady...
Go home.
Everything in my life
turns out like this!
Get up, you idiot's grandson!
Get up! Please!
Get up.
Go home!
And where is the shirt I loaned you?
- What?
- Yeah, where is the shirt I loaned you?
My sister wrapped it up.
She was happy I met this nice lady.
Your sister.
Now, Mr. Mangiacavallo, please.
Tell me the truth about something.
When you put on the tattoo
on your chest, huh? When?
I got it tonight.
You got it because I told you
about my husband's tattoo.
No, I wanted to be near you,
to make you happy, that's all.
Tell it to the Marines, please.
You are not smart enough.
Now, take the shirt back.
I don't want it! You can keep it now!
You just asked me for it.
What's the matter?
Oh, you make me so nervous.
Please!
Is it my fault you been
a widow too long?
- You make a mistake.
Both of us make a mistake tonight.
Both of us make a mistake!
You know, we should
have been friends.
I think maybe we meet
on the wrong day.
I'll go out again, come in.
We start all over.
No, no. I think it's no use,
because the day was
wrong to begin with.
Because of two women.
They told me my husband
was having a steady affair
with a woman at the Mardi Gras Club,
you know?
You know?
What was the name on the shirt?
On the slip of paper?
- I threw it out the window.
- Yeah, but tell me.
You remember the name?
What was the name?
I remember the name
because I know the woman.
- What is...?
- The name is Estelle Hohengarten.
That was the name.
That was the woman.
Yeah. You made me forget
for a little while.
OK. OK!
- Take me there!
- Oh, no, baronessa.
- Take me to the Mardi Gras now.
- No, don't go. Please stay.
Take me to the Mardi Gras now,
please!
Baronessa.
Serafina, please.
We go someplace else.
We dance maybe.
- We have fun.
- Let me go in, please, will you?
Where is the woman
Estelle Hohengarten, please?
Estelle Hohengarten?
Nobody knows where is the woman
Estelle Hohengarten.
Go away. I want to speak
to Estelle Hohengarten!
Where is this woman? Please!
Please.
Oh, please!
What do you know about my husband?
I'm the wife, remember?
What is the lie?
You liar!
- Liar!
- Estelle, tell her it's a lie.
- Tell her!
- What's a lie?
Liar! Liar!
Remember? I brought you the
rose-colored silk to make him a shirt.
You said, "For a man?" I said, "Yes,
for a man that's wild like a Gypsy."
Remember?
I remember.
Let me at her! Let go of me!
Let me at her! I'll show her
whether it's a lie or not.
I have the proof. I have proof!
What proof? Please! What proof?
If she thinks it's a lie,
let me show her this.
This!
See for yourself.
His rose tattooed on my chest.
Let go of me! I'm gonna kill her!
I'm gonna kill her!
Let me get at her!
Let go of me!
Let go of me! Oh!
Let me go!
Hey!
- That'll be 2.50, please.
- Two-fifty.
- Two dollars?
- Two dollars and fifty cents, yes, sir.
Hey!
- What did you do?
- I smashed...
I smashed the urn.
Hey, mister.
Two-fifty.
- We don't have the money.
- Well, just ask the lady.
- The lady's sick.
- What happened?
- Her husband just died.
- I'm sorry.
- That's all right.
Don't look at it.
Look outside. You know?
Look out at the moon.
- Yes.
- Well, look at me.
After a while, you will stop
feeling the pain. I know.
You need human comfort.
Lean on me.
I don't want that.
What? Tell me.
You go now.
- I go?
- Yeah, you go and come back.
But leave the truck somewhere else.
So everybody can't hear.
And say to me in a loud voice:
"Goodbye, Mrs. Delle Rose.
We had a good conversation."
Si, si, ho capito.
I understand you very good,
baronessa.
- OK.
- Goodbye, Mrs. Delle Rose.
- Goodbye!
- Goodbye, Mr. Mangiacavallo!
Goodbye, Mrs. Delle Rose!
- Tell everybody hello!
- OK!
- Goodbye!
- Oh, goodbye, baronessa!
Give everybody my love!
Goodbye.
Give everybody my love.
Who's that out there?
Who's out there?
Baronessa, where are you?
In the parlor.
You turned out the lights.
Well, the...
The moon is enough.
Vengo! Vengo!
Amore! Amore!
What's happened?
- Hey!
- Amore. Amore.
You!
You! Hey!
Please! Blood?
Whiskey.
Get up. Get up.
Get up, you!
A clown has passed out in my house.
You want to sleep, huh?
A clown like that
with my husband's body.
There.
Go on. Don't wait for me.
I want to walk home.
When are you going back
to New Orleans?
Tomorrow.
What time must you be
on the boat?
Ship. Why?
Just tell me what time.
Five. Why?
What will you be doing till five?
Well, what difference
does it make?
It don't make no difference
to you what I'm gonna be doing.
All right.
All right, I'll tell you what
I'm gonna be doing till five.
I'm gonna check in
at the Rampart Hotel.
I'm gonna check in at the Rampart,
and I'm gonna get loaded.
Do me a little favor.
Before you get loaded,
look in the lobby of the Rampart Hotel
at 12 o'clock noon.
Why?
You might find me there...
...waiting for you.
Look, are you trying to buy me
a ten-year stretch in the brig?
I want you to give me the little
gold ring to put on my finger.
Are you talking about getting married?
Yes.
Yes, I want to give you my heart
to keep forever and ever and ever.
In all my born days,
I never felt nothing so sweet
as the feel of your warm
little body in my arms.
Honey...
...I gotta leave now.
Do you understand?
Only if you promise
to be at the Rampart Hotel.
I gotta go, Rosa!
Look for me!
I'll be there.
Che bella.
Sporcaccione!
Oh, baronessa.
Baronessa!
I didn't know what I was doing.
I got all twisted around in the house.
Young lady, I thought you was
your mama.
"Your mama"?! Oh, please!
- Mama. Mama, stop!
- Sporcaccione!
Mama!
- Baronessa, please!
- Don't "baronessa" me.
No, that's...! That's enough!
- I kill you!
- Stop!
- I kill you.
- That's enough!
- No. No!
- Police!
- Do you want everybody to know?
- Know what, cara? Know what?
Just give him his clothes
and let him get out!
- What clothes?
- I was dreaming.
- I didn't know...
- Don't speak to her!
- But, baronessa...
- Don't call me baronessa!
Who is this man? I don't know
how this man get in...
Don't say anymore. Just give him
his clothes and let him get out!
What clothes are you
talking about, huh?
- Get out, please!
- I'm sorry.
- I'm so sorry.
- Get... Put your shirt on!
- But, baronessa...
- Put your shirt on, you idiot's grandson.
- Serafina, please understand.
You idiot's grandson, you.
- Don't talk to me.
- But, Serafina...
Don't tell me nothing, or I kill you.
I kill you!
- But, baronessa, I love you.
- You love me?
Put your shirt on! Cialtrone!
Cialtrone!
Baronessa, I love you.
Again?
Baronessa! I love you!
Go home. Go home!
Cialtrone!
Them Italians is at it again.
Had a truck driver
in the house all night.
Has the man gone?
- That man?
- Yes, "that man."
I don't know how that man get in.
I don't know.
- Maybe the back door was open.
- Yes, maybe it was.
Why not, cara? Maybe...
Maybe he climbed in a window.
Or fell down the chimney, maybe.
Why do you put on the white things
I saved for your wedding, cara?
Because I want to.
That's a good enough reason.
Rosa, darling.
I want you to understand
about that man, you know?
That was a man...
- That... That was...
- You can't think of a lie?
He was a truck driver, cara.
He was chased by policemen.
Did they chase him
into your bedroom?
Bedroom?
In the dining room.
I took pity on him.
I gave him first aid.
I let him sleep on the floor.
- He gave me his promise, you know?
- Did he get on his knees?
Did he promise he would
respect your innocence?
Did he?
Rosa.
He was Sicilian.
He had oil of roses in his hair.
And the... And the rose tattoo
of your father.
I closed my eyes...
...and dreamed he was your father.
But he came to me drunk,
and he fell flat down on his face.
Stop it!
The only thing worse than a liar
is a liar that's also a hypocrite!
Rosa, don't look at me like that, with...
With the eyes of your father.
Yes, I look at you with
the eyes of my father.
I see you the way he saw you.
- Don't, please.
- Like this.
This pig!
I need $5 so I can go
and find Jack.
Go in.
Go in the house.
Thanks.
Rosa...
Rosa, I couldn't sleep.
My Rosa.
Rosa.
My daughter, she has on the white
things I saved for her wedding.
Will...? Will you marry my daughter?
Mama.
That man didn't touch me.
He just said "che bella."
How beautiful she is, my daughter.
Get up.
Go with the boy.
Oh, Mama.
Oh, don't cry. Don't cry.
Don't cry.
Don't cry. Go with the boy.
Go with the boy.
The wristwatch.
Oh, my.
Rosa!
The wristwatch.
Rondinella felice!
I'm a happy bird!
- Rondinella felice!
- Serafina!
- Serafina Delle Rose!
- Baronessa!
Baronessa Delle Rose!
There is a man on the roof
without no shirt!
Si, si. Senza camicia!
All he's got on his chest
is a rose tattoo!
Come on, Serafina. Why do you
wanna lock up his shirt like that?
So he can't go to the high school?
Come on!
- Serafina!
- Brava, Serafina!
Here is a silk shirt for him!
OK?
I'm a happy bird!
Va!
Baronessa?
Serafina?
Now we can go on
with our conversation.