Five thousand years ago...
a fierce warrior known
as the Scorpion King...
led a great army on a campaign...
to conquer the known world.
After a vicious campaign
which lasted seven long years...
the Scorpion King and his army
were defeated...
and driven deep into
the sacred desert of Ahm Shere.
One by one, they slowly perished
under the scorching sun...
until only the great warrior himself
was left alive.
Near death...
the Scorpion King made a pact
with the dark god Anubis...
that if Anubis
would spare his life...
and let him conquer his enemies...
he would give him his soul.
Anubis accepted his offer
and spared his life.
Anubis gave the Scorpion King
command of his army...
and like an evil flood,
they washed away...
all that lay before them.
When his task was done...
Anubis forced the Scorpion King
to serve him for all time.
His army was returned
to the sands from whence they came...
where they wait, silently...
to be awakened once again.
Alex?
What were you thinking,
a mummy had come back to life?
I'll tell you a story some time.
What are you doing down here?
I told you to wait for us in the temple.
It's dangerous down here.
- But I saw your tattoo.
- You saw what?
On a wall by the entrance.
There's a cartouche just like it.
With the pyramid and the eye...
and the two kings and everything.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Okay. Well, I'll be up to take
a look at that in a minute.
In the meantime, I want you
to wait for us up there.
Pick up your stuff,
and I'll see you up in the temple.
Go on.
And what should I do?
I don't know. Surprise me.
- Build a better mousetrap.
- Okay.
While your mother goes
and desecrates another tomb.
Go away.
- Those are poisonous, you know.
- Only if they bite you.
What was all that about?
Nothing.
Alex wanted to show me something.
I swear...
the kid gets more and more
like you every day.
You mean
more attractive, sweet...
and devilishly charming?
No, he's driving me crazy.
Now, where were we?
Hammer and chisel.
All right, all right!
Let's do it your way.
Thank you.
Ever since I had that dream...
this place is all
I can think about.
Ever since you had that dream,
I haven't had a decent night of sleep.
I feel like I've been here before.
I know I've been here before.
Evy, nobody's been here before,
not in at least 3,000 years.
Except for these guys.
Then how do I seem to know
exactly where I'm going?
Let's go.
Knock, knock. Anybody home?
You two check out that stuff,
see if it's there.
I'll sort out the O'Connells.
If you move that fast enough,
you can almost write your name.
I just had a vision.
It was like my dream,
but it was real.
It was like I was actually here
in ancient times.
Well, if you actually were here...
could you show me
how to open this thing?
Hold this.
- Now you're starting to scare me.
- I'm starting to scare myself.
What is this?
Look at the state of this rubbish.
The Egyptians never had a clue.
Look at that stuff.
It's all chintz and stuff.
Look at that.
Cheap pottery, this.
Ancient rubbish.
Jacques,
something's hit me head!
Shut up, Spivey.
This place is cursed.
We do not want to wake the gods.
That's the emblem
of the Scorpion King.
He's supposed to be pure myth.
No trace of him has ever been
found before. No artefacts.
No archival evidence.
Maybe they didn't want
anybody to find him.
- Let's open this.
- Evy, I don't know.
- I don't have a good feeling about this.
- It's only a chest.
No harm ever came
from opening a chest.
Right, and no harm ever came
from reading a book.
- Remember how that one went?
- Come on. We can't stop now.
Just remember,
I was the voice of reason here.
For once.
Rubbish.
Dreck. Chintz.
God, that hurt!
Hon? Let's do it your way.
The bracelet of Anubis.
I'll take care of this.
Oh, my God.
It's a bit late for that!
- Put it in your rucksack.
- Let's leave it here.
- It's a bit late for that!
- What's it say?
"He who disturbs this bracelet...
shall drink from the Nile."
That doesn't sound too bad.
Jacques is gonna make
a nice fillet out of you, my son.
Spivey! Jacques!
Let's get the hell out of here!
Come on.
This is bad, Evy.
- We've had bad before.
- This is worse.
Mom? Dad?
I can explain everything.
The Book of the Dead gives life.
And the Book of the Living...
takes life away.
I thought that was my job.
We're getting close.
Did you acquire it?
We're getting very close.
We found him.
We found him! We found him!
Step aside there.
Out of the way.
Imhotep.
It's him. It's Imhotep.
Now we must raise
those that serve him.
Get out of my way.
Get out of the way.
Get out of my way
or I'm gonna shoot you in the face.
He means it.
He shot someone before.
Give it to me.
The opportunity passed us by.
- We need that bracelet.
- We need it before it opens.
Enough.
My dear Hafez...
I told you
I should have handled it.
I did not want
your past history...
to cloud the issue.
Don't worry. We know where it is.
We'll take care of it.
No, we'll take care of it.
I have a different chore
for you now.
Where is the bracelet?
It's on its way
to merry old London.
Then London is where we must go.
I think the bracelet
is some sort of guide...
to the lost oasis of Ahm Shere.
Evy, I know what you're thinking...
and the answer's no.
We just got home.
That's the beauty of it.
We're already packed.
Why don't you just give me
one good reason?
It's just an oasis...
darling.
A beautiful...
exciting...
romantic...
oasis.
The kind with the white, sandy beach
and the palm trees...
and the cool, clear, blue water?
We could have some of those big drinks
with the little umbrellas.
- Sounds good.
- Sounds too good. What's the catch?
Supposedly it's the resting place
of Anubis's army.
You see? I knew there's a catch.
There's always a catch.
How did I know that?
And let me guess.
It was commanded
by that Scorpion King guy?
Yes, but he only awakens
once every 5,000 years.
And if someone doesn't kill him,
he's gonna wipe out the world.
- How did you know?
- I didn't, but that's always the story.
The last known expedition
to actually reach Ahm Shere...
was sent by Ramses the Fourth
over 3,000 years ago.
- He sent over a thousand men.
- None of them was ever seen again.
- How did you know?
- I didn't, but that's always the story.
- Did I mention the pyramid of gold?
- Twice.
Alexander the Great
sent troops in search of it.
- Hooray for him.
- So did Caesar.
- Look what happened to his career.
- And Napoleon.
Yeah, but we're smarter than him.
- Taller too.
- Exactly.
- That's why we're gonna find it.
- Because we're taller?
- That's why I love you.
- Nice try.
Mom!
What do I do with this chest?
Sucker weighs a goddang ton.
Alex, watch your language.
Rather weighty, this.
Evy, that first weird dream of yours
was exactly six weeks ago, right?
Yes, but what's that
got to do with anything?
It just happens to coincide
with Egyptian New Year.
That's right.
What a coincidence.
Maybe.
All I'm saying
is let's be cautious.
If anything happened to you,
I would never forgive myself.
You and Alex are the only thing
that matter to me.
Well...
the Bembridge scholars
have been begging me...
to run the British Museum.
Cripes, how do you get
this thing off?
Have I kissed you today?
I hate it when you do that.
Why?
- Makes me agree to anything.
- Anything?
Those knickers are not mine.
Jonathan.
Alex, behave yourself
for five minutes, all right?
You betcha.
- Happy to be home?
- Couldn't be happier.
It's the Year of the Scorpion.
- Neat.
- Thought you might like that.
So I killed the mummy and his minions
and stole his sceptre.
Oh, you're so brave.
And rich.
Did I mention rich?
What do you think I'm doing here?
- Sorry, we must be in the wrong house.
- You said this was your house.
- I didn't.
- Call me!
- You're not Sheila's husband?
- No.
If you work for Johnny,
I was gonna pay him back on Tuesday.
I don't know any Johnny.
We are looking for
the bracelet of Anubis.
Oh, good for you. Good thing to have,
the old bracelet of Anubis.
Where is it?
Ah, you're looking here
for the bracelet. I see.
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
Mr. O'Connell,
you try my patience.
Mr. O'Connell? Hold on a minute.
You've got the wrong ma...
That bracelet.
Now I remember.
- I lost it in a card game.
- For your sake, I hope not.
It can't be.
- Where's your wife?
- My wife?
You mean Evy.
I think she went off to Baden-Baden
or Tibet or something.
The girl's a free spirit.
Did I mention I was single now?
Egyptian asps
are quite poisonous.
It's downstairs.
There's a safe.
The combination is 3-20-58.
393-something.
It's in the safe downstairs.
I told you!
And your point is?
- I told you so you wouldn't kill me.
- When did we make that arrangement?
Jonathan, I thought I said
no more wild parties.
Well, when you're popular...
I'm serious. If you've lost
that key, you're grounded.
I haven't lost it. I just can't find it.
There's a difference.
Well, you better
start finding it then.
I will, Mom.
There's nothing to worry about.
Good evening.
Who are you?
What are you doing here?
I'm looking for the chest,
of course.
Give it to me now.
Get out of my house.
Whoa, Mom.
- Maybe not the best idea.
- Alex, get back there.
Definitely not the best idea.
I think it's time
to yell for Dad now.
- I will kill you and take it anyway.
- I think not.
Ardeth.
What are you doing here?
Perhaps explanations
are best kept for later.
Ardeth Bay.
Lock-Nah.
Hey, folks,
knowing my brother-in-law...
he probably deserves whatever
you're about to do to him...
but this is my house.
I have certain rules
about snakes and dismemberment.
Shoot him!
Whoa, Mom!
- Where did you learn to do that?
- I have no idea.
That I learned from your father.
I'll take that.
Not bad for a Medjai.
Let go!
- What's in the chest?
- The bracelet of Anubis!
They must not get the bracelet.
Get it and get out of here!
Mom, look out!
Evelyn!
What'd you do this time?
I haven't done anything
to anybody.
- Lately.
- Come on!
Rick!
Look out, Rick!
Dad! Dad!
- Are you all right?
- Yeah.
What the hell are you doing here?
Scratch that. I don't care.
Who are those guys
and where are they taking my wife?
My friend, I'm not sure...
but wherever this man is...
your wife will surely be.
Hey, I know him.
He's the curator.
- He works at the British Museum.
- Are you sure?
Better believe him. He spends more
time there than he does at home.
Okay, you're here.
The bad guys are here.
Evy's been kidnapped.
Let me guess.
They once again removed
the creature from his grave.
Not to point fingers, but isn't it your
job to make sure that doesn't happen?
That woman with him knows things
no living person could possibly know.
She knew exactly where
the creature was buried.
We hoped she would lead us to
the bracelet. She obviously did.
Now they have it.
I wouldn't get
too nervous just yet.
Is that gold?
When I stuck it on,
I saw the pyramids at Giza.
Then whoosh... straight across
the desert to Karnak.
You have started a chain reaction that
could bring about the next apocalypse.
You, lighten up.
You, big trouble.
You, get in the car.
I am sorry if I alarmed your son,
but you must understand.
Now that the bracelet's on...
we have
7 days before the Scorpion King awakens.
We? What we?
If he is not killed,
he will raise the Army of Anubis.
- I take it that's not a good thing.
- Oh, he'll wipe out the world.
The old "wipe out the world" ploy.
Whomever can kill
the Scorpion King...
can send his army back
to the Underworld...
or use it to destroy mankind
and rule the Earth.
They dug up Imhotep 'cause he's tough
enough to take out the Scorpion King.
That is their plan.
Alex, I got a big job for you.
Stay here and protect the car.
- I could do that.
- Protect the car?
Come on. Just because I'm a kid
doesn't mean I'm stupid.
- I know.
- Dad!
If you see anyone come running out
screaming, it's just me.
Maybe you should stay here
and watch him.
Now you're talking.
- You want the shotgun?
- No, I prefer the Thompson.
If I were to say to you, I'm a stranger
travelling from the east...
seeking that which is lost...
Then I would reply that I am
a stranger travelling from the west.
- It is I whom you seek.
- Then it is true.
- You have the sacred mark.
- What, that?
That got slapped on me
in an orphanage in Cairo.
That mark means
you're a protector of man...
a warrior for God, a Medjai.
Sorry.
You've got the wrong guy.
Mr. Hafez.
They found him.
Imhotep.
Do not be frightened.
I am not afraid.
You know...
a couple of years ago, this would've
seemed really strange to me.
Lord Imhotep will be much pleased.
Where is it?
Where is the bracelet?
I think I know.
At the very top of the gold pyramid,
there was a huge diamond.
How huge?
It was so big,
it would reflect the sun...
and wink at distant travellers...
beckoning them to their deaths.
Get off! Get off!
Oh, my God.
You wait!
I'll put you in your grave again.
Our thinking was, not if we
put you in your grave first.
Burn her!
You bast...
- Open it! Open it!
- I'm trying!
- Hurry up!
- Come on, come on!
- You broke it!
- Be quiet!
If there's gonna be any hysterics,
they'll come from me!
Go, go, go!
Oh, no. Not these guys again.
What are we gonna do?
You're asking me?
I'm only eight years old!
Honey, what you doin'?
These guys don't use doors.
Where the hell's Jonathan?
- Alex!
- What's the matter with my car?
I was forced to find an alternative
means of transportation.
- A double-decker bus?
- It was his idea.
- Was not!
- Was too!
- Just go!
- It was too!
No, not my car!
Oh, I hate mummies.
- Glad to see me now?
- Just like old times, huh?
Turn, turn!
No! Get out of the way!
Look out!
Great driving, Uncle Jon.
Yeah.
You all right?
This was my first bus ride.
- What would I do without you?
- Are all librarians this much trouble?
Jeez, get a room.
Let me go!
Silence!
Stop!
Please do not fear
for your son, my friends.
They cannot hurt him,
for he wears the bracelet of Anubis.
Alex is wearing the bracelet?
When he put it on, he said he saw the
pyramids at Giza, the temple at Karnak.
At Karnak, the bracelet will show him
the next step of the journey.
If we don't get to Karnak before them,
we won't know where to look for him.
Seems to me...
like we need a magic carpet.
When Lord Imhotep last
encountered the O'Connells...
they sent his immortal soul
to the Underworld.
As powerful as he will become,
he is still vulnerable.
Only with the Army of Anubis
will he be invincible.
He will need your help.
Keep this with you always.
The Book of the Dead!
What a bright little child.
Your mother must be
missing you terribly.
If you wish to see her again,
you'd better behave.
Lady, I don't behave
for my parents.
What makes you think
I'm going to do it for you?
Silence!
Because your parents wouldn't slip
poisonous snakes into your bed...
while you were sleeping.
Lord Imhotep wishes
to meet the boy.
Now we shall see
how brave you are.
Hey, watch the suit.
Ow! Me fingers.
Nice.
Very nice.
Did you acquire what we asked?
We acquired it, all right.
You know what?
We had to kill two of those guards
at the mausoleum to acquire it.
This chest is cursed.
It says there is one...
the undead...
who will kill all those
who open this chest.
Yes, and the creature will suck them dry
then become whole again.
We've all heard this story before.
Yeah, but I heard the Yanks
who found it nine years ago all died.
Horrible deaths, they were.
- So with that in mind...
- We want ten.
Quiet!
The agreement was for five.
Well, we want ten
or we'll take it elsewhere.
- If you...
- Ten will be just fine.
Follow me, gentlemen.
Get in.
It is you
who are the chosen one...
you who will take me
to Ahm Shere.
What if I don't?
What if I get a little lost?
You have strength, little one.
You are your father's son,
but I know something you don't.
This bracelet is a gift...
and a curse.
The sands of time...
have already begun
to pour against you.
Yeah, I already heard this part.
From the minute
I put the bracelet on...
seven days do I have
before the Scorpion King wakes up.
Did you also hear that if you
do not enter the pyramid...
before the sun strikes it
on that very morning...
that the bracelet
will suck the life out of you?
That part I missed.
Hey, wait a minute. That means
I've only got five days left.
Then I believe it will be best
if we do not get lost, don't you?
My dad is going to kick your ass.
I do not think so.
In here, gentlemen,
you shall receive your just rewards.
No tricks now, woman.
We're not givin' up this chest
till we're satisfied.
Don't worry.
There is much satisfaction to be had.
What's going on?
This place is cursed.
- What is it with you and curses?
- He ain't happy without a good curse.
"This is cursed. That is cursed."
Give it a rest, will ya?
Christ!
He wants you to open the chest.
Open the chest!
Where'd he go?
- This is the magic carpet?
- It'll be fine. He's a professional.
Izzy!
He definitely remembers you.
He's a little shy.
Jonathan, get our bags.
- Oh, my hands are full.
- Now.
- Right. I'll get the bags.
- I'll deal with the flight details.
- Honey, you're not a subtle man.
- We don't have time for subtle.
Izzy, come here.
- Doesn't look happy to see you.
- Never turned me down yet.
Whatever it is, whatever you need,
I don't care. Forget it, O'Connell.
Every time I hook up with you,
I get shot.
Last time I got shot in the ass.
I'm in mourning for my ass.
- Remember that bank job in Marrakesh?
- Bank job?
- It's not like it sounds.
- It's exactly how it sounds.
I'm flying high,
hiding in the sun.
The white boy here flags me down,
so I fly in low for the pick-up.
The next thing you know,
I get shot.
I'm lying in the middle of the road
with my spleen hanging out...
and I see him waltzing up
with some belly dancer girl.
Belly dancer girl?
- Izzy, I think you and I should talk.
- As long as I don't get shot.
Quit your whining.
You're gonna get paid this time.
Have you looked around here any?
What do I need money for?
What the hell am I
gonna spend it on?
I'm gonna keep this short.
My little boy's out there.
I'm gonna do whatever it takes
to get him back.
If you give me that gold stick,
you can shave my head...
wax my legs
and use me for a surfboard.
Didn't we do that in Tripoli?
Say, by the way,
when did you lose your eye?
I didn't. I just thought
it made me look more dashing.
Come on. Get to work.
- You're not catching me at my best.
- Oh, I'm sure I am.
I knew it.
I'm gonna get shot.
These are the commanders
of the 12 tribes of the Medjai.
Horus.
Pet bird.
My best and most clever friend.
He will let the commanders know
of our progress so that they may follow.
If the Army of Anubis arises...
they will do all they can
to stop it.
- Are you sure Izzy is reliable?
- Yeah, he's reliable-ish.
- Isn't she beautiful?
- It's a balloon.
It's a dirigible.
- Where's your airplane?
- Airplanes are a thing of the past.
- Izzy, you were right.
- I was?
Yeah, you're gonna get shot.
She's faster than she looks.
And she's real quiet.
Perfect for sneaking up on people,
which is a very good thing.
Unless, of course,
we go with your approach...
barging in face first, guns blazing,
gettin' your friends shot in the ass.
Why can't you people ever
keep your feet on the ground?
O'Connell does not want to believe,
but he flies like Horus to his destiny.
Yes, very interesting.
Tell me more about this gold pyramid.
It is written that since
the time of the Scorpion King...
no man who has laid eyes upon it
has ever returned to tell the tale.
Where is all this stuff written?
Hello!
Got it.
Pretty nice, eh?
This is all I have left
in the world.
The rest of my fortune was lost...
to some rather unscrupulous
characters, actually.
If the curator reacted the way you say,
it must be very important.
If I were you,
I would keep it close.
My friend, the gods
couldn't take this away from me.
- That's mine.
- No, it's not!
Keep your hands off it.
I want him back, Rick.
I want him in my arms.
I know.
We taught him well.
He's smarter than you.
He's tougher than me.
- I love him so much, I just can't...
- I know. We both do.
Alex knows that.
I'll get him back, Evy.
I promise.
I know you will.
- Are we there yet?
- No.
That was amazing.
Perfect aim.
What are you talking about?
I missed.
I have to go to the bathroom.
Make it quick.
Hurry up.
- Hey, reading material!
- Now!
I can't go when someone's watching.
I don't trust you.
You'll look.
Darn!
Oh, my God!
Doesn't anyone around here know
how to flush a toilet?
Karnak.
If a man does not embrace his past,
he has no future.
Look...
even if I was some sort
of sacred Medjai...
what good does that do me now?
It is the missing piece
of your heart.
If you embrace it and accept it,
you can do anything.
Sounds great.
Listen, what can we expect
from our old friend Imhotep?
His powers are returning quickly.
When he reaches Ahm Shere, even the
Scorpion King won't be able to stop him.
Evy, I know you haven't been yourself
lately with these dreams and visions...
No, they're memories
from my previous life.
Honestly, I'm not losing my mind.
It all makes perfect sense now.
- That's why we found the bracelet?
- Exactly.
- I was its protector.
- Now do you believe, my friend?
Clearly, you were destined
to protect this woman.
Right. She's a reincarnated princess,
and I'm a warrior for God.
Your son leads the way to Ahm Shere.
Three sides of the pyramid.
This was all preordained
thousands of years ago.
And how does the story end?
Only the journey's written,
not the destination.
Convenient.
How else do you explain
Evy's visions?
That it is your son
who wears the bracelet?
- How do you explain your mark?
- Coincidence.
My friend, there is a fine line
between coincidence and fate.
Don't even think about it.
Hold on there, partner.
When the time comes...
I shall truly enjoy killing you.
But until that time...
you'd better be
a little nicer to me.
Now, where's my water?
No ice?
Make sure he doesn't move!
They've gone.
We've lost them.
Alex left us his tie...
and he made us
a little sand castle.
It's the Temple Island of Philae.
- They've gone to Philae.
- Attaboy, Alex. Come on!
The great temple of Abu Simbel.
That's the Blue Nile down there.
We must be out of Egypt by now.
In ancient times, all this
still belonged to the upper kingdom.
The oasis must be
around here somewhere.
Don't worry. We'll find him.
He's a smart kid.
He'll leave us a sign.
Surprised to see me?
Leaving bread crumbs, huh?
We're in trouble!
Horus, fly!
Izzy, come hard right!
Starboard! Starboard!
Was there a little something
you forgot to mention?
People?
Ahm Shere.
Right.
He's back!
Hang on!
Well, that's not good.
Mom?
Dad?
We're gonna go get my son.
Then we're gonna want to get out of here
fast, so make this work, Izzy.
You don't understand. This thing was
filled with gas. Not hot air, gas.
I need gas to get this thing in the air.
Where am I gonna get gas around here?
Bananas? Mangoes?
Tarzan's ass?
Maybe I could finagle it
to take hot air.
But do you know how many cubic meters
I'd need? It's too big!
If anybody can fill this thing up
with hot air, Izzy, it's you.
Come to Daddy.
So, Rick, what's the plan?
Let's find some higher ground.
- I must go.
- Where?
To tell the commanders where we are.
- If the Army of Anubis arises...
- I need you to help me find my son.
Then first I shall help you.
Thank you.
Look. Roman legionnaires.
And here, turn-of-the-century French.
Napoleon's troops.
What in the name of Anubis did this?
- You hear that?
- What?
Nothing.
Absolutely nothing.
My word!
I say, chaps, look at this.
Shrunken heads.
I'd love to know how they do that.
Just curious.
You any good with that?
Three times Fox and Hound's
grand champion. You any good with that?
You'll know soon enough...
because the only way to kill an Anubis
warrior is by taking off its head.
I'll remember that.
Try to remember to...
just keep it tight
in the shoulder and...
lead the target a little bit,
and then...
squeeze the trigger...
don't pull it.
I won't miss.
Pyramid.
Cripes, I'm in trouble now.
Now may I kill him?
- Retrieve that bracelet.
- With pleasure.
Something is coming.
That's my husband
and my son down there.
Make me proud.
Today's that day, Evy.
Where's the boy?
The Black Book!
Let's go!
There you are!
The time has come,
my little friend.
Let go!
- Dad!
- Alex!
Time to remove that bracelet,
my good son.
Behind you!
- Let's go.
- Thank God for that.
The two of you must
sacrifice yourselves for me.
You shall be rewarded in heaven!
Nice shootin', Tex.
- What were those creepy pygmy things?
- Just the local natives.
- Are you sure?
- I'm sure. It was nothing.
Come on, Mom. Come on, Dad.
We have to get to the pyramid.
I have to get the bracelet off now!
Leave it on.
Looks good on you.
No, you guys, you don't understand.
It'll kill me if I don't get inside
the pyramid before the sun hits it...
today!
Oh, my God.
Time to go!
I thought you said
it was nothing!
Where's Jonathan?
Look! There's a burial ground!
We're safe! We're safe!
They'll never cross
those sacred stones!
- You are sure?
- Yes, of course I'm sure.
Sorry. My mistake.
- Wait for me!
- Hurry up, Jonathan!
Wait for me!
- What's that for?
- Just something in case of an emergency.
Let's go, Alex.
Run! Come on, Alex, faster!
Dad! The bracelet!
Come on! Come on!
You know...
it's not easy being a dad.
Yeah, but you do it really good.
Thanks.
They made it.
Thank God.
Yes. Great.
Fabulous.
- She's going to be all right, isn't she?
- She'll be fine.
Take him.
Mommy's fine.
It's okay.
Your mother's
going to be fine. Okay?
You're real strong.
You're gonna make it.
You're fine.
What do I do?
Take care of Alex.
Sweetheart, no.
I love you.
Come back, Evy.
Come back.
Stay here.
Try to think of it
like this, Alex.
She's gone to a better place.
- Like it says in the good book.
- The book!
- What?
- That's it.
- That's it!
- That's what?
Come on, Uncle Jon!
That's it! The book!
You're too late, O'Connell.
I have released
the Army of Anubis.
Lord Imhotep shall soon
kill the Scorpion King...
and take command.
Not after I get through with him.
You realize, of course,
that this can only be done...
by someone who can actually read
ancient Egyptian.
I don't know about you,
but I'm a tad rusty.
- Now where?
- We go right.
How do you know?
Basically,
"This way to the Scorpion King."
Mum taught me.
This just might work.
It's time someone taught you
a lesson, wench. Come on.
This is for my sister.
Is that all you've got?
Hurry up, Alex!
Uncle Jon, I don't know
what this last symbol is!
What's it look like?
It's a bird. A stork!
I know that one!
Then what is it?
That's it!
Why don't you pick on somebody
your own size?
Oh, my God.
- Evy!
- Take Alex. Go and help Rick.
- But, Mom...
- No "buts."
Come on.
I'll be just fine.
- We did it, Uncle Jon!
- Right, partner.
Now let's go help your dad.
That's a little something new.
My lord!
Save me! Save me!
Okay, now I'm a believer.
It's a spear!
The golden stick thing!
Really?
Doesn't look like a spear!
That's because
it opens up into one!
Yes? And?
It opens up into a spear!
- Twist it!
- Push!
You have to pull!
Jonathan, quick!
Throw it!
Kill the Scorpion King!
Send his army
back to the Underworld!
Step aside, Alex.
I'm a professional.
Go to hell,
and take your friends with you!
Get out of here!
Just get out of here!
Hang on, Rick!
Let's go up!
This whole damn place is gonna
get sucked up! Let's move up! Go!
Go, Alex!
Rick, we're trapped!
Get your butts moving! Hurry up!
I haven't got all day!
You're next! Go!
Jonathan! Hold on!
- Pull him up!
- Pull me up!
Wait! Wait!
Let me down! Let me down!
- It's not worth your life, you idiot!
- Yes, it is! Yes, it is!
Right.
Pull me up! Pull me up!
- O'Connell, you almost got me killed!
- At least you didn't get shot.
Thank you! Thank you!
O'Connell, who the hell have you
been messing with this time, huh?
You know, the usual.
Mummies, pygmies...
big bugs.
I thought
I almost lost you there.
For a moment there, you did.
Would you like to know
what heaven looks like?
Later.
- Oh, please!
- That's half mine, you know.
- What?
- That's half mine.
- What are you talking about?
You took my gold stick!
I swear on the head of my wife, I have
no idea what you're talking about.
You ain't got a wife!
I don't have
your gold stick either!