Truck looks great.
Must be a fortune here.
I know, just not in front of him, OK?
Fellas, what's going on?
I've been here too long.
- Give us a minute.
- No. Check this out.
You can't get no cleaner. These are
very popular with the children.
This is a federal tax stamp.
You can't get no cleaner.
You keep 'em
if it's such a great deal.
l ain't from Detroit. I don't know
nobody who can handle a job this big.
You're supposed to have the
connections. Do what you want to do.
- lt ain't easy to get rid of this.
- I know, but I'm a businessman.
Warm up the truck.
Let's get the fuck out of here.
- Here you go.
- You're a sharp kid.
Thank you.
Cousin, my man, don't dash yet.
This looks like $2,000, not $5,000.
- Let me see.
- The deal is for 5,000.
l told my people
there should be five grand.
- They stiffed us.
- No, they stiffed you.
You can't count on anybody.
But let's not hassle about it now.
Take the two grand and on the next
score, I'll make it up to you.
Don't jerk me off. This is bullshit.
l need $5,000, not $2,000.
Don't do this to me.
Come on, you ain't dealin'
with Johnny Bananas.
l know I ain't.
Can I have my money?
Can I say it slow for you?
l need $5,000. Read my lips.
$5,000 is what I need.
l can't do nothing with that.
You want to be an asshole,
smoke 'em yourself.
l don't smoke Lucky Strike.
l smoke King Size Kent.
Fuck this.
Nice doing business with you.
What you doing here?
Officer, you know what happened?
You ain't going to believe it.
The truck just stopped. You got
some cables, you give me a jump?
- Don't I know you?
- No, I'm from Buffalo.
Break out some lD.
Let's get the fuck outta here!
Shit!
Freeze, asshole!
Foley, we should have known
it was you!
Axel. Way to go!
- I don't have time.
- Todd's after you.
He said it's your worst fuck-up.
l don't think that's true.
- He's not in there.
- I see that.
lf you'd busted them, maybe he
wouldn't be so mad, but you haggled.
$2,000 wasn't enough.
They'd have known I was a cop.
- Leave me alone.
- Don't go anywhere.
- You asshole.
- I'm not saying you did wrong,
but if you had busted them,
it would have been better.
- Where you going?
- Out of here.
- Big mistake. You want my advice?
- No.
Go in there, talk to him.
He'll be right back.
Jeff, get away from me.
I'm going to shoot you.
- You know what I would do?
- Lighten up. I'm not listening. OK?
You're making it a lot worse
for yourself.
Look at this. Thank you, guys.
Axel, you got a cigarette?
- Did you write that one?
- Everybody knows about the truck.
Will you listen to me?
l am not listening to you.
Great. Real mature.
l am not listening to Jeffrey,
but he's still talking.
- I hate when you do that.
- Stop, then!
- ls that fucking Foley in here?
- There's Todd, it's show time.
Boss, I know...
Where do you come off going
undercover without my authorisation?
You want to play cowboy cop,
do it in someone else's precinct.
- Want to hear my side of the story?
- What's your side of the story?
Let's hear your side of the story.
Do you know how much this stunt
of yours is going to cost this city?
Cost isn't the issue. It's my blatant
disregard for proper procedure.
You're damn right, wise-ass!
The mayor called the chief,
he called the deputy,
he chewed my ass out.
You see I don't have any of it left!
Where the fuck d'you get
the cigarettes from, anyway?
- From the Dearborn hijack.
- That bust went down last week.
- That truck should be in the pound.
- I told you.
- It's none of your business.
- This isn't my locker.
Listen, Axel.
No more set-ups, you understand?
You're a good cop
with great potential,
but you don't know
every fucking thing.
I'm tired of taking the heat for you.
Once more and you're on the street.
- Do you understand?
- Look...
Do you understand me?
Yeah, I understand. Boss...
Chief ain't chewed it all.
You still got some ass.
Don't fuck with me, Axel.
Not now. Go on, go home.
How you doing, man? How you doing?
Still breaking in people's houses.
What do you expect with that lock?
Buy a real lock.
l got my pistol.
I'll shoot somebody.
l can't afford no electric, close
my fridge. There's roaches in there.
So what's up, man? Look at you!
- When did you get out?
- Six months ago.
And you're just coming to see me now?
l got out early for good time and
l went to California, get some sun.
l gotta show you something.
l ain't seen you in two years, man.
What's up?
10,000 Deutschmarks.
- Deutschmark?
- Yeah.
- What is that?
- They're bearer bonds. Untraceable.
You stole 'em?
- No.
- I don't want to hear it.
- It's just good to see you.
- I missed you, man.
- What were you doing in California?
- Working.
- Working where?
- Guess.
- I don't know.
- Beverly Hills.
- What were you doing?
- You won't believe this.
l was a security guard.
Who'd hire you as a security guard?
- Jenny Summers.
- Jenny Summers?
l haven't seen Jenny in years.
- What's she up to?
- She's doing great.
She's manager of this art gallery.
The Hollis Benton Art Gallery,
Beverly Hills.
It's world famous. Ever hear of it?
Yeah, I buy all my art there.
Corner pocket, two cushions.
- 50 bucks you don't make that shot.
- Bullshit.
- 100.
- You got a bet.
- What are you gonna do?
- You're as bright as always.
20, 40, 60, 80, take it.
Have a party.
Pleasure doing business with you.
What the fuck you gonna do?
Miss, two more Scotch and sodas.
l got a great idea.
Let's steal a car.
Are you serious?
I'm a fucking police officer.
l can't steal cars no more.
How many times
have you stolen a car, man?
A fucking Cadillac!
Driving on the expressway
like two fucking maniacs.
l remember you went to jail for that.
- No, it was state school.
- That's jail when you're 15.
That ain't jail, man. That's like
day camp compared to jail.
How come you didn't tell on me
when you got caught?
You don't know?
- You don't know?
- No.
Because I love you, man.
One more round.
Hold still. Mike, I gotta open
the door, OK? Balance yourself.
Here we go, Mike.
I'm opening the door now, OK?
Here we go.
Axel!
Hey, Mikey, where have you been?
What's up, Zack?
What have you got there, Mikey?
What is this? Your laundry?
l swear,
l was going to bring 'em back.
- You got lost?
- No.
l came to see my friend. I had 'em
with me. I figured, you know...
- What you doing?
- What am I supposed to do, Mikey?
There was a whole box of them. l
didn't think anybody'd miss a couple.
l figured l'd take 'em...
- Shut up.
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
No, shut up.
- Man, please.
- Just shut up, Mikey.
l swear...
l swear, if you ever show
your face out there again...
- Ever.
- I won't. I promise you. I'm sorry.
l fucked up, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- Ever.
- I'm sorry.
Axel, go to the hospital and get
that bump on your head checked out.
- My head is all right, man.
- It's not a request, Axel.
Boss. Boss...
Can I talk to you for a minute?
l heard you got Rand on this case.
He doesn't know the time of day.
Don't mess with me.
He hasn't left his desk in 12 years.
At least he's had 12 years.
Anyway, it's a homicide case and it
belongs to Rand. Go to the hospital.
- Can I ask around a bit?
- Don't do a thing.
You're skating on thin ice as it is.
We're talking about a friend of mine!
Yes, we are, aren't we?
Let's take a close look at that.
One, a hoodlum friend.
Two, a professional hit.
Three, in a cop's apartment.
This whole thing
stinks to high heaven.
- Why a professional hit?
- I didn't just walk into this town.
Whoever killed your friend
wasn't worried about you.
lf they were, you'd be lying
beside him in that meat wagon.
Don't do a damn thing.
Stay out of this.
I'm owed some vacation time.
l want to take my vacation now.
Stay away from this case.
l just need a little vacation,
that's all.
All right, as soon as you finish
at the hospital, you're on vacation.
Thank you.
But if you decide
to butt into this case,
it'll be the longest vacation
you ever heard of.
- Checking in today, sir?
- That depends. This hotel expensive?
Not for Beverly Hills.
Can I get your bags for you?
Yeah, that's my bag
in the front seat.
I'm sorry, sir, we just
have nothing available tonight.
l suggest next time
you call for a reservation
at least a week in advance.
Thank you.
- Hi.
- The nerve of some people!
May I help you?
You have a reservation
for Axel Foley.
Let's see.
I'm sorry, I don't see
anything under that name.
Check Rolling Stone Magazine's
Axel Foley, that's what it is.
No, no Rolling Stone, no Axel Foley.
I'm sorry, sir.
You probably just made a mistake.
Just give me another room.
Sorry, sir,
but there are none available.
Don't you think I realise what's
going on? Who do you think I am?
lf I was some hotshot
from out of town
and you'd made a reservation mistake,
l'd be the first to get a room.
I'm not some hotshot, I'm
a small reporter from Rolling Stone,
here to do an interview
with Michael Jackson,
that's gonna be
in every major magazine.
l wanted to call it Jackson
ls Sitting On Top Of The World.
Now I'll call it
Jackson Can Sit On Top Of The World
But Not ln The Beverly Palm Hotel
Cos There's No Niggers Allowed.
Excuse me, sir, it seems
we have a last-minute cancellation.
There is a room available, a suite,
but I'll charge you
the single-room rate.
Thank you. I'm sorry,
it's probably jet lag.
- I understand.
- What's the rate?
That'll be $235 a night, sir.
Fine.
- That'll be suite 1035.
- Thank you very much.
- Yes, sir.
- Thank you.
lf Michael calls,
tell him what room I'm in.
Of course.
- How you are doing?
- Hi.
I'm fine. My name is Serge.
How can I help you?
I'm looking for Miss Jenny Summers.
It's very busy today.
You give me your name?
- My name's Axel Foley.
- What it's pertaining?
- I didn't understand.
- Pertaining, meaning, regarding...
Oh, what's it regarding?
I'm an old acquaintance.
Donny.
One moment.
Donny, tell Miss Summers
that Ahmed Farley's here to...
- No, Axel Foley.
- Ahmel...Ahwell...
Foley's here,
he's an old acquaintance.
Cover this up.
It's like the breast of a dog
to scrub for the customer.
- It's not sexy, it's animal.
- Not sexy at all.
May I offer you something to drink?
Wine, cocktail, espresso?
No, thank you.
l make it myself, with a lemon twist.
You should try it.
No, I'm fine.
- I see you look at this piece.
- How much would it go for?
$130,000.
- Get the fuck outta here.
- No, I cannot.
It's a very important piece.
- Ever sold one of these?
- Yesterday.
- Get the fuck outta here.
- I'm serious. I sell it myself.
What are you doing here?
- How you doing?
- I'm fine. Hold on a second.
Great. Excuse me, Serge.
- What are you doing here?
- How you doing?
It's good to see you.
How've you been?
- Look at you!
- You like?
Yeah. You're getting old.
Fuck you.
- What is this?
- A moustache.
- Peach fuzz.
- No, that's man style now.
You have someplace we can talk?
Yeah. Over there. Come on.
- You've filled out.
- Yeah, I filled out.
No, it looks good, though.
Sit down.
- I want to talk about Mikey.
- ls he in trouble again?
He's dead.
What?
He came into Detroit
and somebody killed him.
l don't believe this.
Look, I can't right now.
I'll be up in a second.
Mikey mentioned
that you helped him get a job.
Yeah...
The guy who owns this gallery
hired him as a favour to me.
- Who's this guy?
- His name is Victor Maitland.
He was working for Victor
at the gallery's warehouse.
l can't talk now,
l have to go upstairs.
That's cool.
I'll call you later on
and we'll get together and talk, OK?
Sure.
Be good.
Hi. Delivery for Victor Maitland.
I'll take it upstairs to him.
Maybe I should give it to him myself.
Deliveries should be left here.
He has to get these flowers.
I'll go up myself.
You're not supposed to.
Floral delivery is my life.
l have to take it.
- Who let you in?
- I let myself in.
How you doing? I have some questions
about Michael Tandino.
Speak to you later, darling.
What, may I ask,
is your interest in Mr Tandino?
He was my best friend. He visited me
in Detroit a couple of days ago.
Soon after he got there,
someone killed him.
Oh, my God. That's terrible.
It's fucked up.
And? What do you wish to know?
- He worked for you, didn't he?
- Yes, yes, he did.
Good gracious!
I'm really sorry to hear this.
Would you like to sit down?
Can I get you anything?
- No, I'm all right.
- How on earth did this happen?
Detroit is a very violent city,
isn't it?
Yeah.
l do hope the police have procured
some intelligent leads.
Exactly what did Mikey do for you?
I'm sorry, I didn't catch your name.
My name is Foley.
Excuse me, Mr Foley,
if I appear a little rude,
but this sounds like something
for the authorities in Detroit.
So, if you'll forgive me,
l must get back to work.
- All I want to know is...
- Please show Mr Foley to the door.
- Get the fuck off me.
- Hey, take it easy.
Get off me, man.
Get the fuck off me. Get off!
Get the fuck off me, man. Get off!
Get off me. Think I'm playing games?
I'm fucking somebody up.
What the fuck is this shit?
Did you see that?
l can describe them all.
Put your hands
on the hood of the car.
- What's with you guys?
- You heard him, sir. Do it now.
What kind of shit is this?
Wait a second.
You're arresting me
for getting thrown out of a window?
l got thrown out of a window, man!
Gun, partner!
Sir, you're under arrest.
You have the right to remain silent.
Anything you say will be used
against you in court.
You have the right
to have an attorney.
l understand the rights.
This is bullshit.
l got thrown out of a window.
- Get in the car.
- What's the charge?
Possession of a concealed weapon
and disturbing the peace.
l got thrown out of a window!
What's the charge for getting
pushed out of a car, jaywalking?
This is bullshit!
You know, this is the cleanest and
nicest police car I've ever been in.
It's nicer than my apartment.
Officers, if we see any movie stars
could you point them out to me?
That's enough talking.
OK, that's cool.
This is nice.
It's about time. I thought
you'd forgot me. I was hungry.
I've never seen a cell with a phone.
Could I stay cos I ordered pizza?
Somebody'll eat it.
Have a seat right over there, please.
I'm Sergeant Taggart and this
is my partner, Detective Rosewood.
Do you always treat visitors
from out of town like this?
Why didn't you say you were a police
officer when you were arrested?
Where do you get off
arresting somebody
for getting thrown out of a window?
Six witnesses say you started
tearing up the place,
then jumped out the window.
You believe that? What the fuck
are you, cops or doormen?
We're more likely to believe
an important local businessman
than a foul-mouthed jerk.
Foul-mouthed? Fuck you, man.
- Watch your mouth.
- Don't square off on me.
- Don't push me.
- Fuck you, man.
Taggart!
- Yes, sir.
- Come here.
Sir...
l apologise for striking you.
l have no excuse.
Forget about it.
l am Lieutenant Bogomil of
the Beverly Hills Police Department.
Do you wish to file charges
against Sergeant Taggart?
ls this a joke?
Do you wish to file charges
against this officer for assault?
Where I'm from, cops don't
file charges against other cops.
No, I don't want to do that.
ln Beverly Hills,
we go strictly by the book.
Why didn't you inform us
when you came to town?
I'm on vacation.
Then why were you
in Victor Maitland's office?
l had to go to the bathroom.
lt looked like a nice clean place.
- Always take your gun on vacation?
- Don't know. Never been on vacation.
But, in Detroit,
cops must always carry a firearm.
lf you want to carry a gun,
go back there.
l really can't wait to get back.
ls that so? I just spoke
to lnspector Todd in Detroit.
Does that name ring a bell?
- He's my boss.
- You may not be welcome back.
He says you're
an outstanding young detective.
l find that difficult to believe.
It's true.
He also says he nearly fired you.
l find that very easy to believe.
What are you doing here?
I'm on vacation.
l went to the bathroom
and six guys threw me out a window.
lnspector Todd gave me a message
for you. Wanna hear it?
No.
He says if you're here
investigating the Tandino murder,
don't bother coming back.
lf we inform him
you are working on this case,
he'll have you fired.
One last time, what are you doing?
I'm on vacation!
Vacation.
Rosewood, take Mr Foley
over to the courthouse
and let him arrange for bail.
Follow me, sir.
l got to hand it to you guys,
you are extremely polite.
Pretty good punch you got, Taggart.
After you.
You guys are so sweet, you know that?
Thanks for bailing me out, Jen.
lf l'd known why you'd been arrested,
l wouldn't have come.
- You don't mean that.
- No, I don't mean that.
lf it wasn't for Victor Maitland,
l'd be a waitress.
The day Mikey got killed, he showed
up with a bag of German bearer bonds.
l think he stole them
from whoever killed him.
When I mentioned Mikey's name,
Maitland threw me out.
You look like a hoodlum. You barge
into his office, carrying a gun.
lf I didn't know you,
l'd throw you out.
ls this your car?
No. ln Beverly Hills
we just take the closest one.
l remember you used to drive
that crappy blue Chevy Nova.
What are you driving now?
The same crappy blue Chevy Nova.
Do you think it's too late
for me to study art?
Axel, why were you bothering Victor?
You don't think he has anything
to do with Mikey's death?
No, I was just poking around.
l don't think he did nothing.
Victor is one of the top art dealers
in the US, he has been for ten years.
I'm impressed.
- What are you looking at?
- The cops, they're following us.
What? Where?
ln the back, on the right.
Beige Ford.
Can you believe this place?
How can you afford this?
They only charged me
the single-room rate.
- How can you afford that?
- I can't.
ln the bathroom they got little robes
with the hotel's initials on it.
l love this place, I can't leave.
- I'm going to steal one. Want one?
- No.
You want some slippers?
I'm going to steal them, too.
Excuse me, two seconds.
Hello, room service?
This is Mr Axel Foley in suite 1035.
l'd like to order something
from your late supper menu.
l want you to deliver it
to this beige Ford on Wilshire.
Send down one bay shrimp
salad sandwich. OK?
Right. And is the cold poached salmon
in dill sauce tasty?
OK, send one of those down.
And send down something for dessert.
All right. Thank you.
You're quite a sport.
How long are you going to stay?
Until I find out who killed Mikey.
And I'm considering checking out
the warehouse where he worked.
Really?
How you planning on getting in?
- Good evening, sir.
- What is that?
Late supper,
compliments of Mr Axel Foley.
- Foley? How'd he know we were here?
- Because I let you drive.
l need a couple of bananas. How much?
The buffet plate is $12.50. You get
peaches, plums, oranges and bananas.
All I need is a couple of bananas.
Go ahead, take those bananas.
Thank you.
- I'm not eating that. Take it back.
- Certainly.
This really looks great.
- Could I get some extra mayo?
- Certainly, sir.
- Ready to go?
- Yeah.
There's the Mercedes.
Will you get rid of that stuff?
What the hell are you doing?
This the place?
Yeah, but I'm not sure
l should do this.
OK, but when you hear glass breaking,
don't get scared.
It's just me kicking in the window.
Sit tight.
All right. Come on, Axel.
- What's happening, baby?
- Grow up.
- Did you find something?
- Coffee grounds.
So?
You know what this is used for?
People add hot water and drink it.
I'll take this home, add hot water
and drink it in the morning.
What are we hiding for?
l wish you'd been with me last night.
- What happened?
- We stopped in a joint for a drink.
- Which one?
- A local joint.
Some guy comes in,
sits a couple of stools away.
He's got one of them eyes
that's going like this.
l didn't know whether he was trying
to put the make on me.
l thought l'd take you there tonight,
let him have a shot at you
before I tore his head off.
Let's go. I want to get out of here.
- Just get off my back.
- Come on.
l got it.
- What the hell's going on?
- I'll tell you later.
Hurry up.
- Give me the key.
- Ever driven a Mercedes?
A car's a car.
l drive mine every day.
- I'm driving, I've seen your car.
- Shit, that's cold.
How could you not notice a man
sticking a banana in your tailpipe?
- He distracted us.
- How?
He sent us a late supper.
This waiter comes over...
Billy, he gets the point.
A late supper?
And what did you have, Rosewood?
l think it was
a shrimp salad sandwich, sir.
- A shrimp salad sandwich?
- Yes, sir.
l want you two to go back
to the hotel and wait for Foley.
lf you lose him again,
don't bother calling in. Got that?
- Yes, sir.
A late supper.
We've got something for you, Billy.
An anti-banana disguise.
- lt may come in handy.
- A little extra protection, Billy.
Very funny.
Let's go.
- You take the car and go home.
- What about you?
l want to find out about this place.
It's a bonded warehouse.
They hold our foreign shipments
till they clear customs.
I'm going to check it out. Go home.
Damn it, Axel.
I'm not going to bail you out again.
Go home.
How you doing?
Come here for a second, please.
- Hi, you have a match?
- No smoking in here.
I'm going to smoke when
l go outside. Thank you very much.
- ls your supervisor here?
- ln the office.
- Will you get him?
- What's the problem?
You security?
Then you're the fucking problem.
Get your supervisor. Now.
Now!
OK.
He didn't come back yet.
What do we do now?
We wait.
OK.
- Can I help you?
- Are you the supervisor?
- Yes. Who are you?
- lnspector Rafferty, US Customs.
- Has all this gone through customs?
- No, this is the bonded area.
Then tell me,
how can a black man, dressed like me,
just march in and start poking around
without being asked any questions?
- I don't know.
- That's the answer I wanted.
Give me your lD numbers.
Somebody's going to lose their job.
- He gave me a match.
- You gave him a match?
Listen. I do security checks
all over the nation.
And apart from Cleveland,
this place has the worst security
in the nation.
Call your wives
cos we'll be here all night.
We're gonna check the background
of every crate,
starting with this one.
lt says here that by the time
the average American is 50,
he's got five pounds
of undigested red meat in his bowels.
Why are you telling me this?
What makes you think
l have any interest in that at all?
Well, you eat a lot of red meat.
The inspector needs
the information on those bills.
All the manifests, too.
And records of all shipments
due into the same destination.
- What's this about?
- Just do it.
You got a warrant for this?
You have a very big mouth, sir.
Are you hiding something from me?
l bet that's your Porsche outside.
ls it?
Would you like me to have the lRS
crawl up your ass with a microscope?
It's not pretty.
l want you to know something.
l want you all to know, I could
have 25 agents here in 15 minutes,
to march in here, snatch your bond
and you'd be out of business,
if you don't cooperate. Understood?
We'll give you everything you need.
- Everything you need.
- That's not my Porsche, sir.
You've nothing to worry about, then.
You all take me for a fool. Hurry!
l notice you've been drinking
a lot of coffee lately.
l think that's why
you have a hard time relaxing.
Jesus Christ!
You almost gave me a heart attack.
- What are you doing here so late?
- You're a cocky son of a bitch.
lf you're still mad
about the banana, I'm sorry.
l needed some time to myself.
l wish l'd seen your face
when the car conked out.
Very funny. The lieutenant
docked us two days' pay.
Get outta here!
- He's not kidding.
- No, he's not kidding.
By the way, thanks for the sandwich.
lt was a joke, like the bananas.
l know what it's like on a stakeout.
That food was from the heart.
Bullshit!
Why are we always arguing? We're all
cops. We should work together.
We've all had a rough day.
What do you say we go get something
to drink, make up and be friends?
Forget it.
OK, fuck it. I'm going to get
a drink. Follow me if you want.
But I lost you once, I can again.
Why don't we get something
to drink together? Let's be friends.
- We don't drink on duty.
- OK. Fine.
But listen. I found
the perfect place. I saw it today.
It's perfect for you. It's
very conservative. You'll love it.
It's nice. Trust me.
- Hi. Can I get you something?
- Yes!
Can I have a Scotch and soda?
What do you want?
- Light beers for them.
- Two club sodas.
You crack me up
with this ''on duty'' shit.
Billy, you don't have to be
embarrassed if your dick is hard.
Your dick is supposed to get hard.
That's the whole object.
Taggart's dick is hard,
but he won't say. He's the boss.
Boss's dick got to stay limp.
l ain't on duty
so my dick can be hard.
Taggart, look. I found that
at Maitland's warehouse.
- Billy! Give her this.
- No.
Stuff that in her thing.
She'll go nuts.
Excuse me.
Billy.
- What do you think?
- Coffee grounds. So?
You guys don't know nothing
about nothing, do you?
Make sure we get the right drinks.
l drink club soda, I'll throw up.
Thank you so much.
Thank you very much.
- She likes you.
- Think so?
No doubt.
Taggart... See that guy
over there in the black coat?
- Black jacket?
- Yeah.
It's June.
lsn't it hot for a long leather coat?
- Yeah, a little.
- Yeah.
Look at his partner.
They just came in.
Something's getting ready to go down.
- Go and cover that guy.
- What's going on?
I'll check out this asshole at the
bar. Billy will make sure I behave.
Will somebody tell me
what's going on?
No bullshit this time.
Just sit tight, Billy.
Philip!
Man, what's happening, Phil?
He said you don't come here no more,
but I said, ''It's Phil''.
- Get out of here, man.
- I told you!
- Give me a kiss, baby.
- I said get outta here!
Everybody freeze!
Turn around. Turn around!
- Phil!
- Keep your hands on the table!
What's wrong?
What's all the hostility?
- Get back.
- What's all this gun, man?
You changed.
Get back or I'll
blow your brains out.
Police. Move and I'll kill you.
Don't move! Turn over!
Way to go, Rosewood.
You're some cop. You know that?
Sorry for the disturbance, folks.
Everything's under control.
Taggart.
Would you explain why
you and Rosewood were in a strip bar
out of our jurisdiction
while you were on duty?
Before you chastise these officers,
there's something you should know.
The only reason they were at a strip
bar is because they were tailing me.
They were outside
wondering what I was doing.
l was in having a good time.
I'm into those things.
These guys waited outside
and the only reason they came in
was because they saw two men with
bulges in their jackets going in.
Well, these guys
were going to commit a robbery.
They watched them, waited for them to
make their move, then foiled a crime.
l did not know what was going on.
I'm freaked out.
They must have a sixth sense.
l don't know what you teach them,
but they're not just regular cops.
They're supercops.
The only thing missing
on these guys are capes.
ls this what really happened?
No, sir.
Would someone tell me what happened?
Well...
Foley invited us to this bar.
We accepted.
- We ordered club sodas, sir.
- Right.
And while we were there,
Foley observed the two suspects
casing the establishment.
And before we knew what was going on,
he'd already disarmed one of them.
Detective Foley deserves
all the credit for the arrests, sir.
Detective Foley,
we appreciate your assistance,
but if you want to practise
law enforcement,
l would prefer you did it in Detroit.
l understand. I'm sorry.
But before I go
l want you two to know,
the supercops story was working.
OK? lt was working
and you guys just messed it up.
I'm trying to figure you guys out,
but I haven't yet. But it's cool.
Just fuck up a perfectly good lie
and it's all right.
You guys are off the case.
Foster, McCabe, your turn.
- Don't lose him.
- Not a chance, sir.
And you two...
ln my office.
Morning, gentlemen.
Coffee and doughnuts?
- What?
- Coffee and doughnuts.
There he is.
Morning, officers.
You the second team?
We're the first team.
We won't fall
for a banana in the tailpipe.
You won't fall
for the banana in the tailpipe?
lt should be more natural,
brother, like this.
''l ain't falling for no banana in my
tailpipe.'' It's more natural for us.
You've been hanging out
with this dude too long.
I'm sorry, I'm just fucking with you.
That's funny to me.
- You gonna try to keep up with me?
- No problem.
- lsn't this Victor Maitland's house?
- Yeah, I think so.
I've seen enough.
You want something to drink?
l got some stuff in the trunk.
Excuse me.
For a man on vacation,
you look like you're on a stakeout.
Stakeout? No, no. I'm picnicking.
This is a picnic area.
I've been shooting the shit
long enough.
Time for me to take in some sights.
Excuse me.
What the hell's he doing?
Can you put this in a good spot?
This shit happened
last time I parked here.
May I help you?
I'm looking for Victor Maitland.
You realise that
this is a members only club?
l have to talk to Victor.
It's very important.
- Victor Maitland, are you sure?
- Yes.
Grey-haired gentleman.
Very dark skin. Capricorn.
Why don't you give me the message
and I'll take it to him?
OK. Tell Victor that Ramon,
the fella he met about a week ago...
Tell him that
Ramon went to the clinic,
and I found out that I have...
herpes simplex 10.
l think Victor should check himself
out with his physician
before things start falling off
on the man.
Perhaps you better tell him that.
- I think that would be best.
- So do l.
Hi, Victor.
I'm back.
Look, guys, don't even try it.
Why don't you
get the hell out of here?
Get the fuck away from me, man.
Very good, Victor. Could you teach
him to roll over and sit, too?
- What do you want?
- I wanna talk to you.
- Last time, I didn't get the chance.
- I've nothing to say to you.
That's cool, I'll do all the talking.
This is a very nice place, Vic.
Hi. I like this. This is nice.
Glad you like it.
l must make you a member.
Victor, I know that you're into
a lot of crooked shit.
And I have a pretty good idea
that you had Mikey killed.
And when I find out for sure,
I'm going to fuck you up real bad.
ls that so?
Now listen to me,
my tough little friend.
l don't know
from under what stone you crawled
or where you get
these ridiculous ideas about me,
but it seems painfully obvious
you haven't
the slightest fucking idea
who you're dealing with.
Now, my advice to you
is crawl back to your little stone
in Detroit
before you get squashed, OK?
- Please step away from the table.
- Gotta go now, Vic.
- Nice meeting you again.
- Yeah.
Catch you later, Vic.
l can't wait.
Don't I know you guys?
You look so familiar.
Detective Foley,
this is becoming very irritating.
Why are you bothering
Victor Maitland?
l had a friend, Michael Tandino,
who used to work for him.
Maitland had him killed. When I can
prove it you'll be the first to know.
Forget what you can prove,
talk to me.
OK. Listen. Everybody knows Victor
Maitland is a hotshot art dealer.
But I poked around.
Art's not the only thing he deals.
l saw some guys in his warehouse
unloading a crate
of German bearer bonds.
Michael Tandino had bonds
like this on him, coincidentally,
when he was killed.
Just because Maitland invests
in the same bonds
doesn't mean he's a killer.
The man's not an investor,
he's a smuggler,
be it bonds, drugs or whatever.
The crate I saw
didn't even pass through customs.
Maitland is paying
to get his shipments out
before they're inspected.
When his guys get it, they take
the drugs or bonds out of the crates
and they send it back before customs
even knows what's going on.
- And you witnessed this?
- Everything except for the drugs.
But I found coffee grounds
everywhere.
- Coffee grounds?
- What does that mean?
Drugs are packed in coffee.
The scent throws off the dogs.
Very good. Now what do we do?
Look, Detective Foley, l...
I'm sorry.
l'd really like to help you.
lf you'd found the drugs,
that's one thing,
but if your only evidence is coffee,
we can't get a search warrant.
We can get around that.
We don't ''get around''
search warrants.
Taggart, I want you
to start checking this out.
Start with the LAPD,
the FBl and the Customs Service.
Wait a minute.
Maitland is much smarter than that.
We snoop around, he'll close down
and get his shipments from elsewhere.
Really? ls that what your
extensive experience tells you?
l haven't been on the force...
Shit.
- ls this the man?
- Yes, sir.
The gentleman that crashed
through Victor Maitland's window?
Who disabled an unmarked unit
with a banana?
Yes, sir.
Who lured Taggart and Rosemont
into a gross dereliction of duty
at a striptease establishment?
It's Rosewood, sir.
Yes, sir.
ls this the gentleman
who ruined the buffet
at the Harrow Club today?
Yes, sir.
l just bet you are the pride
of your department in Detroit.
Lieutenant,
l'd like to see you in your office.
Yes, sir.
ls this the man who wrecked the
buffet at the Harrow Club today?
- Lower your voice.
- Can he hear me through the wall?
Yes, he can.
Rosewood, take Detective Foley
back to his hotel room,
watch him pack,
and escort him to the city limits.
Then you can give him his gun back.
The two charges of disturbing the
peace have been dropped against you.
But if you return to Beverly Hills,
the charges will be reinstated
and you will be prosecuted
to the limit of the law.
- Sir, may I say something?
- What?
He seems to have enough...
You want to tell that to the chief?
- No, sir.
- Then I suggest you get moving.
Come on, Axel.
Right. Let me check on that tomorrow
and get back to you.
Thank you.
- Hi.
- Victor, hi.
- Sit down. I'm not interrupting?
- Of course not.
There's a gentleman in town
from Detroit
who says he's a friend
of Michael Tandino.
He came by the office yesterday and
asked me all sorts of odd questions.
Excuse me, darling.
l believe his name is Foley.
Since you were a friend of Michael,
l was wondering
if you knew the fellow.
We grew up in the same neighbourhood.
Really? Have you seen him lately?
He came in yesterday.
What? He came by here?
And?
He told me that Mikey
had been killed.
Yes. Yes, I know.
- And then?
- That's it.
He left and I haven't seen him since.
Jenny, darling,
do you know where he's staying?
l have some information
which might be helpful for him.
No, I have no idea.
l hope I didn't disturb you.
- No problem.
- We'll have dinner soon, yes?
- That'd be lovely.
- Take care.
l read the manifests. They're
expecting another shipment in today.
Bogomil...
This is a chance for me and you
to blow this case wide open.
l wish I could, but I can't.
Why?
Because Bogomil would kill me.
I'm not going to drive you
to the art gallery.
It's easy. Jenny will let us in
Maitland's warehouse.
The shipment arrives, we nail them.
- How can you be sure it'll be drugs?
- I got a hunch.
A technique by which many crimes
outside Beverly Hills get solved.
Why didn't you tell Bogomil
about this shipment?
He does everything by the book.
ls everybody in this town a robot?
This thing is very personal to me.
All he asked me to do
was drive you out of town.
Now I'm going to screw that up, too.
Billy, I love you.
l just fell in love with you.
Jenny, how are you?
This is my buddy Billy Rosewood.
Jenny Summers.
- Billy's a Beverly Hills cop.
- How do you do?
That's Serge.
Can you get my friend an espresso?
You want it with a lemon twist?
Sure, if it's no bother.
No, don't be stupid.
Victor Maitland was here
asking questions about you today.
He was acting real weird.
Look, I want to get back
inside the warehouse.
How about I go with you?
You work in a gallery.
You're not a cop.
lf this has to do with Mikey's death,
l want to check it out.
l don't have time to argue with you.
Let me get my keys
and we'll argue on the way.
Billy, you sit here and observe.
Don't move till I get you.
- Why can't I come in?
- Cos you're a cop in this town.
Without probable cause,
it's an illegal search.
Didn't they teach you that
in cop school?
- I find some evidence, I'll get you.
- You can't...
Be cool, all right? lf anything
jumps off, I'll come and get you.
ls there any chance
you'll let me go in by myself?
No chance.
Fuck. Come on.
- Seems they've been already.
- What are you looking for?
This.
A crate from overseas that
hasn't passed through customs yet.
What is that?
Coffee?
Yeah, it's coffee on top.
But this ain't sugar.
Go get Rosewood.
Welcome to the party.
lt seems we have guests.
How nice. I do like surprises.
Jeannette.
l just can't tell you how
disappointed I am to find you here.
Shut up!
l don't want to hear it.
Take her to the car and wait for me.
What are you going to do with him?
You should be more worried about
what we're going to do with you.
Don't worry. We've got cocaine and
coffee, we're going to have a party.
Thanks for having me over, Vic.
This is very nice.
Did you say something?
lf something happens to her...
I'm all ears.
I'll kill you.
Really? That would be a neat trick.
- Well, cuz.
- Are you still pissed at me?
No. But I should have
taken care of you in Detroit.
When I popped your little buddy.
Goodbye, Mr Foley.
- Have a nice day.
- I'll try.
Damn it.
Oh, boy.
How's that little bump
on the head I gave you in Detroit?
Healed up nice, I hope.
Freeze!
Thanks.
Tell Taggart to check out
the warehouse. I'll explain later.
Sergeant Taggart is here,
he wants to talk to you.
Shit!
Billy, what the hell is going on?
- Sorry, Sarge, I can't talk now.
- What do you mean?
Just check out the warehouse and
please don't say anything to Bogomil.
- He's not transmitting any more.
- Shit.
- What's the matter?
- Billy's doing something dumb again.
- Was he calling from the hotel?
- No, sir.
Right now, his car's heading north
on Palm Canyon Road.
- We were there this morning.
- What?
Foley was looking over
Maitland's house.
- Do you have that warehouse address?
- Yes, sir.
Check that place out, let me know
what's going on over there.
Don't talk to anybody but me.
Hold it, Foley. You're under arrest.
Billy, why are you here?
- I forced him at gunpoint.
- No, he didn't.
Everything he said about Maitland
is right. He's kidnapped a woman.
- Let's get her.
- What do you think I'm doing?
- We'll have a warrant in 20 minutes.
- She could be dead in 20 minutes.
Stop. You're coming with us.
I'm going inside.
You want to stop me, shoot me.
Me, too. You can do what you want,
but I'm going in.
This is really serious trouble.
lf you're lucky,
you'll just get fired.
- Got it.
- This is my last warning.
I'm sorry, Sarge. I've got to.
Shit. Wait a minute.
- What's that?
- Looks like East Gate.
Punch it up.
Who the hell is that?
Better get Maitland up here.
Where is everybody? ls Rosewood back?
- No, sir.
- Seen Taggart?
He took off about 10 minutes ago.
Foley's on the grounds.
How the hell should I know?
Get some people out there right away.
Don't take your eyes off that screen.
Try to locate Taggart and Rosewood.
Come on.
- They must be away from the car.
- I can see that. Keep trying.
- DD-13, come in please.
- What's their 20?
609 Palm Canyon Road.
Who lives at that address?
A Victor Maitland, sir.
- Let's go around.
- Come on, we can do it. Come on.
Ready, one, two...
three!
You all right?
What the fuck am I doing here?
Drop it!
- Good shot, Billy.
- Let's go.
- Jesus Christ!
- These guys are serious.
l hate machine guns.
Cover me.
Go around front.
I'm going to check the back.
We have a report of shots fired at
that location. 609 Palm Canyon Road.
Put out a 998,
officers need assistance.
- Undercovers on scene.
- Sir?
l want all north end units to roll.
South end units stay in their area.
- Damn! Let's go.
- Undercover officers at location.
Police! You're all under arrest!
Do that again, I'll shoot you myself.
Know what I keep thinking about?
Know the end of Butch Cassidy?
Redford and Newman
are almost out of ammunition.
And the whole Bolivian army
is out in front of this little hut.
I'm going to make you pay for this.
- Hanging around?
- Fuck, no.
Freeze it! Hold it right there.
Shit!
Be careful, old boy,
it might hit me.
Freeze!
Police! You're all under arrest!
Lay down your weapons and take
two steps back with your hands up!
Very good.
Great.
What the hell's going on here?
Shit.
- What's this man doing here?
- Bleeding, sir.
How come he isn't wearing cuffs?
Well, he isn't actually
in custody, sir.
Place him in custody.
Or would you like me to?
Wouldn't you like to hear
my report first, sir?
You have a report
that explains all this?
Yes, sir.
Well, I will be very glad to hear it.
Miss Jeannette Summers, the manager
of Mr Maitland's art gallery,
accidentally discovered
what she suspected was cocaine
in the gallery's warehouse.
She immediately communicated her
discovery to Detective Axel Foley.
Detective Foley was, at the time,
cooperating in a joint
Beverly Hills-Detroit investigation.
Detectives Foley and Rosewood
proceeded to the warehouse
where Rosewood discovered
approximately 80 kilos of cocaine.
Rosewood called for back-up
and I despatched our officers.
Sergeant Taggart
was the first on the scene.
Believing a felony was in progress,
Sergeant Taggart joined Rosewood,
with Detective Foley present
only as an observer,
and proceeded to enter the grounds.
ln defending ourselves,
we shot several suspects,
including Mr Maitland.
You expect me to believe that report?
That's the report I'm filing, sir.
Sergeant Taggart,
why don't you tell me what happened?
Happened just like
the lieutenant said, Chief.
Well, I suppose
congratulations are in order.
Thank you, sir.
That report better be
on my desk in the morning.
Yes, sir. First thing.
You were lying your ass off.
Go to the hospital
and get your shoulder looked at.
Excuse me, sir.
Could you do me a favour, sir?
- Your favours are all used up.
- I understand.
l just hoped you could
call lnspector Todd
and straighten things out for me,
but that's all right.
I'm out of a job. It's cool.
l think I'll stay in Beverly Hills.
I'm going to start
a private investigation company.
I'll talk to Todd first thing.
- Really?
- You bet.
Thank you so much.
Hi, I'm Axel Foley
checking out of suite 1035.
One moment, sir. I'll get your bill.
Guys, you didn't have to come
to see me off, but I'm very moved.
Bogomil ordered us to make sure
you got out of town.
That doesn't matter. What matters
is that you came down here.
I'm all choked up.
I've got a lump in my throat.
Look a little misty yourself,
Taggart.
- There you go, sir.
- Thank you.
Excuse me, the Beverly Hills Police
Department is picking that up.
Get outta here.
Guys, that's the last straw.
You guys are too nice.
Do you sell those Beverly Palm robes?
- Yes, sir. $95 apiece.
- Put them on my tab.
l have to have two of them, though.
Billy, you saved my life.
I'll never be able to repay you,
but as a token of my appreciation,
l want you to have
this fine Beverly Palm robe.
Each time you get in the shower,
think about our friendship.
Think about Axel Foley.
l love you, Billy.
Thanks, Axel.
Here, let me take this.
You should rest that arm.
Billy, take care of the tab.
- Taggart...
- Here you are, sir.
This is for you.
No, that's all right.
You keep it as a souvenir.
l already have three of them
in my bag.
Thank you, sir.
Not going to say goodbye?
Aren't you tailing me
to the city limits?
- Yes, we are.
- I figured you would.
l was thinking
about stopping for a drink.
- We figured you would.
- Then will you join me?
l don't think so, Axel.
We're still on duty.
l don't think
one beer's going to kill us, Billy.
Right. Listen to Taggart. Lighten up.
One drink's not going to kill us.
But guys, if you fall too far behind,
don't be afraid to honk, OK?
- Where we going, anyway?
- Don't worry, just follow my lead.
l know the perfect place.
You guys'll love it. Trust me.