Don't grieve,
Admiral.
It is logical.
The needs
of the many outweigh...
the needs of the few.
Or the one.
And I have been
and always shall be
your friend.
Live long...
and prosper.
We are assembled
here today
to pay final respects
to our honored dead.
This death takes place
in the shadow of new life,
the sunrise
of a new world,
a world
our beloved comrade
gave his life to protect
and nourish.
He did not feel
this sacrifice
a vain or empty one.
Of my friend,
I can only say this.
Of all the souls
I have encountered
in my travels,
his was the most...
human.
Honors, hup!
Space, the final frontier.
These are
the continuing voyages
of the Starship Enterprise.
Her ongoing mission-
to explore
strange new worlds,
to seek out
new life forms
and new civilizations.
To boldly go
where no man has gone
before.
U.S.S. Enterprise,
Captain 's personal log.
With most of our
battle damage repaired,
we're almost home.
Yet I feel uneasy,
and I wonder why.
Perhaps it is
the emptiness
of this vessel.
Most of our trainee crew
have been reassigned.
Lieutenant Saavik
and my son David
are exploring
the Genesis planet,
which he helped create.
And Enterprise feels
like a house
with all
the children gone.
No. More empty
even than that.
The death of Spock
is like an open wound.
It seems that
I have left
the noblest
part of myself
back there,
on that newborn planet.
Status, Mr. Sulu.
On course, Admiral.
Estimating space dock
in 2.1 hours.
Mr. Chekov, I'll need
a pre-approach scan.
Take the science
station, please.
Yes, sir.
Uhura.
Any response from Starfleet
on our Genesis inquiries?
No, sir. There
is no response.
That's very odd.
Scotty,
progress report.
It's almost done, sir.
You'll be automated
by the time we dock.
Your timing
is excellent.
You fixed
the barn door
after the horse
has come home.
How much refit time
is needed?
Eight weeks, sir,
but I'll do it in two.
Have you always multiplied
your repair estimates
by a factor of four?
How else can I
keep my reputation
as a miracle worker?
Your reputation
is secure, Scotty.
Mr. Sulu,
take the con.
I'll be
in my quarters.
Aye, sir.
Sir?
I was wondering,
are they
planning a ceremony
when we get in?
I mean a reception?
A hero's welcome-
is that what you'd like?
God knows
there should be.
We've paid for the party
with our dearest blood.
Steady.
Steady, boys.
Keep scanning.
I thought you
people were reliable.
Where is he?
He's been here
for some time.
Put me on
hailing frequency.
Commander Kruge.
This is Valkris.
Well done,
Valkris, well done.
What the hell is-
What the hell's
going on?
When do
I get paid off?
Soon, Captain.
Quite soon.
Approach control,
this is Enterprise,
ready for
docking maneuver.
Enterprise is
cleared to dock.
Lock on.
Systems locked.
Spacedock,
you have control.
Affirmative,
Enterprise.
Enjoy the ride,
and welcome home.
Enterprise confirms.
Would you
look at that.
My friends,
the great experiment...
the Excelsior,
ready for trial runs.
She's supposed to
have transwarp drive.
Aye. And if
my grandmother had wheels,
she'd be a wagon.
Come, come,
Mr. Scott.
Young minds, fresh ideas.
Be tolerant.
Acknowledge
doors are closing.
Stand by, umbilical
and gravitational
support systems.
Moorings activated.
All systems standing by.
Admiral.
This is not possible.
Mr. Chekov?
An energy reading
from "C" deck,
from inside
Mr. Spock's quarters.
I ordered Spock's
quarters sealed.
Yes, sir. I sealed
the room myself.
Nevertheless, I'm reading
a life form there.
This entire crew seems on
the edge of obsessive behavior
concerning Mr. Spock.
Sir, security reports the door
to Spock's quarters
has been forced.
I'm on my way.
Mr. Sulu, continue
docking procedure.
Aye, sir.
Hmm?
Jim...
Help me.
You left me
on Genesis.
Why did
you do that?
Help me.
Bones.
What the hell
are you doing?
Have you
lost your mind?
Help me, Jim.
Take me home.
Bones, we are.
We are home.
Then perhaps
it's not too late.
Climb
the steps, Jim.
Climb the steps
of Mount Seleya.
Mount Seleya?
Bones, Mount Seleya
is on Vulcan.
We're home, on Earth.
Remember.
Admiral,
docking is completed.
Starfleet Commander Morrow
is on his way
for inspection.
Uhura, get
the medics down here!
Get them now!
You've all done
remarkable service
under the most
difficult conditions.
You'll be receiving
Starfleet's
highest commendation,
and more importantly,
extended shore leave.
That is,
all but you, Mr. Scott.
They need your wisdom
on the Excelsior.
Report there tomorrow
as Captain of Engineering.
With all
appreciation, sir,
I'd prefer
to supervise
the refit of
Enterprise.
I'm afraid that
won't be necessary.
But, sir...
I'm sorry, Mr. Scott,
but there
will be no refit.
Admiral.
I don't understand.
The Enterprise is not-
Jim, the Enterprise
is 20 years old.
We feel
her day is over.
But we had
requested...
We'd hoped to take
her back to Genesis.
That is out
of the question.
Why?
In your absence,
Genesis has become
a galactic
controversy.
Until the Federation
Council makes policy,
you're all under orders
not to discuss with anyone
your knowledge
of Genesis.
Consider it
a quarantined planet
and a forbidden subject.
To fully understand
the events I report,
it is necessary
to review
the theoretical data
on the Genesis device
as developed by Doctors
Carol and David Marcus.
Genesis, simply put,
is life from lifelessness.
We intended to introduce
the Genesis device
into a preselected area
of a lifeless space body-
a moon or
other dead form.
The device,
when delivered,
would instantaneously
cause the Genesis effect.
Instead of a dead moon,
a living, breathing
planet now exists,
capable of sustaining
whatever life forms
we see fit
to deposit on it.
So?
Speak.
Great power
to control...
dominate.
Speak.
Impressive.
They can make
planets.
Oh, yes.
New cities,
homes in the country,
your woman
at your side,
children playing
at your feet,
and overhead, fluttering
in the breeze,
the flag
of the Federation.
Charming.
Station.
Yes, my lord.
Share this
with no one.
Understood,
my lord.
We are going
to this planet.
Even as our emissaries negotiate
for peace with the Federation,
we will act for the preservation
of our race.
We will seize the secret
of this weapon.
The secret
of ultimate power!
Success, my lord.
We have reached
the destination planet
at.035.
Very well,
Lieutenant.
Helm, execute
standard orbital approach.
Standard orbit.
Aye, sir.
Communications.
Send a coded message
for Starfleet Commander-
priority one.
"Federation science
vessel Grissom
"arriving Genesis planet
to begin research.
J.T. Esteban,
commanding."
Aye, sir.
Coding now.
Dr. Marcus,
it's your planet.
Begin scanning,
please.
This is where
the fun begins, Saavik.
Just like your father-
so human.
All units functional.
Recorders are on.
Scanning Sector 1.
Foliage in fully-developed
state of growth.
Temperature-22.2 Celsius.
Sector 2 indicating
desert terrain.
Minimal vegetation.
Temperature-39.4.
Sector 3-
subtropical vegetation.
Temperature
decreasing rapidly.
It's snow.
Snow in
the same sector.
Fantastic.
Fascinating.
All the varieties
of Earth's land and weather
within
a few hours' walk.
Metallic mass.
Close-range scan.
A photon tube.
Gravitational fields
were in flux.
It must have
soft-landed.
In code to Starfleet-
"Captain Spock's tube
located on Genesis' surface."
Yes, sir.
Coding your message.
I don't believe it.
What is it?
If equipment
is functioning properly,
indications are
an animal life form.
You said there
wouldn't be any.
There shouldn't be any.
Cross-referenced
and verified.
An unidentifiable
life form reading.
Shall we advise Starfleet?
Wait a minute.
We don't know what
we're talking about here.
Let's
beam it up.
No, you don't.
Regulations
specifically state
nothing shall
be beamed aboard
until danger of contamination
has been eliminated.
The logical alternative
is obvious.
Beaming down
is permitted.
If the Captain
decides the mission
is vital and reasonably
free of danger.
Captain, please, we've got to
find out what it is.
Or who.
Absent friends.
Admiral, what will happen
to the Enterprise?
She's to be
decommissioned.
Will we get
another ship?
I can't get
an answer.
Starfleet is
up to its brass
in a galactic
conference.
No one has time
for those who wait.
Sir, about
Dr. McCoy...
how is he?
He's home,
resting comfortably.
Pumped full
of tranquilizers.
They say
it's exhaustion.
He promised me he'd stay put.
We'll see.
Ah, Mr. Scott.
Come.
Sarek!
Ambassador, I had no idea
you were here.
You know my crew.
I will speak
with you alone, Kirk.
Please excuse us.
Ambassador, I would
have come to Vulcan
to express
my deepest sympathies.
Spare me your
human platitudes.
I have been
to your government.
I've seen the Genesis
information and your own report.
Then you know your son
met his death bravely.
Why did you leave
him on Genesis?
Spock trusted you,
and you denied him
his future.
I saw no future.
Only his body
was in death.
You were the last
one to be with him.
Yes, I was.
You should have come
with him to Vulcan.
But why?
Because
he asked you to.
He entrusted you
with his
very essence,
with everything
that was not of the body.
He asked you
to bring him to us
and to bring that
which he gave you-
his Katra-
his living spirit.
Sir...
your son meant more to me
than you can know.
I'd have given my life
if it would have saved his.
Believe me, he made
no request of me.
He would not have
spoken of it openly.
Then how...
Kirk, I must
have your thoughts.
May I join your mind?
Certainly.
He spoke
of your friendship.
Yes.
Asked you
not to grieve.
Yes.
The needs
of the many...
outweigh...
the needs
of the few.
Or the one.
Spock.
I have been...
and always
shall be...
your friend.
Live long...
and prosper.
No.
Forgive me.
It is not here.
I had assumed
he mind-melded with you.
It is
the Vulcan way
when the body's
end is near.
We were separate.
He couldn't touch me.
I see.
Then everything
that he was...
everything
he knew...
is lost.
Please wait.
He would have
found a way.
If there was
that much at stake,
Spock would have
found a way.
Yes. But how?
What if he joined
with someone else?
Engine room,
flight recorder visual.
Stardate 8128. 78.
Go.
The ship...
out of danger?
Yes.
Back.77.
Flight recorder
visual 28. 77.
Go.
No! You'll flood
the whole compartment.
He'll die.
He's dead already.
Back.76.
Flight recorder
visual 28. 76.
Go.
You're not
going in there.
Perhaps you're right.
What is Mr. Scott's
condition?
I don't think he-
Sorry, Doctor,
I have no time
to discuss this logically.
Freeze.
Repeat and augment.
Remember.
McCoy!
One alive, one not,
yet both in pain.
What must I do?
You must bring them
to Mount Seleya on Vulcan.
Only there
can both find peace.
What you ask...
is difficult.
You will
find a way, Kirk.
If you
honor them both,
you must.
I will.
I swear.
Transporter room,
stand by to energize.
Aye, sir.
Energizing now.
Grissom to Saavik.
We're picking up radiation
from the life form.
Affirmative,
Captain.
Our readings are well below
danger level.
Exercise caution,
Lieutenant.
This landing
is Captain's discretion,
and I'm the one
who's out on a limb.
I'll try
to remember that.
There are your
life forms.
These were microbes
on the tube's surface.
We shot them here
from Enterprise.
They were fruitful
and multiplied.
But how could they have
evolved so quickly?
Saavik.
What is it?
Spock's burial robe.
Aaahhh...
No. Absolutely not,
Jim.
You're
my best officer,
but I am Commander-
Starfleet,
so I don't
break rules.
Don't quote rules.
I'm talking about
loyalty and sacrifice.
One man
who's died for us,
another with
emotional problems.
This business about
Spock and McCoy-
honestly, I never understood
Vulcan mysticism.
You don't
have to believe.
I'm not even sure
that I believe.
But if there's
even a chance
that Spock has
an eternal soul,
then it's
my responsibility.
Yours?
As surely as if
it were my very own.
Give me back
the Enterprise.
With Scotty's help-
No. The Enterprise would never
stand the pounding.
Then I'll find a ship.
I'll hire a ship.
Out of the question.
The council
has ordered
that no one
but the science team
goes to Genesis.
Jim, your life
and your career
stand
for rationality,
not for
intellectual chaos.
Keep up this
emotional behavior,
and you'll lose
everything.
You'll destroy
yourself.
Do you
understand me, Jim?
I hear you.
I had to try.
Of course.
Thanks for the drink.
Anytime.
The word, sir?
The word is no.
I am therefore
going anyway.
You can
count on our help.
Thank you.
I'll need it.
Shall I alert
Dr. McCoy?
Please. He has a long
journey ahead of him.
Long time, Doc.
Yeah. Anybody been
looking for me?
I have.
What will it be?
Altair water.
That's not your
usual poison.
To expect one to order
poison in a bar
is not logical.
Got it.
To your planet,
welcome.
I think that's
my line, stranger.
Oh, forgive.
I here am new.
But you are known,
being McCoy
from Enterprise.
You have me
at a disadvantage, sir.
I name
not important.
You seek l.
Message received.
Available ship
stands by.
How much and how soon?
How soon is now.
How much is where.
Somewhere in
the Mutara sector.
Oh...
Mutara restricted.
Take permits many.
Money more.
There aren't going
to be any damn permits.
How can you get a permit
to do a damn
illegal thing?
Look, price you name.
Money I got.
Place you name.
Money I name.
Otherwise,
bargain no.
All right, damn it.
It's Genesis.
The name of the place
we're going is Genesis!
Genesis?
Yes, Genesis!
How can you be deaf
with ears like that?
Genesis allowed
is not.
Is planet forbidden.
Look,
my backwards friend,
Genesis may be
planet forbidden,
but I'm damn well-
Sir, your voice
is carrying.
You don't want to discuss
this subject in public.
I'll discuss
what I like!
Who the hell
are you?
Could I offer you
a ride home, Dr. McCoy?
Where's the logic?
lf I wanted a ride home,
would I be chartering
a space flight?
How do you know
who I am?
Federation
security, sir.
You're going to get
a nice long rest, Doctor.
Saavik to Grissom.
We are definitely reading
a second life form.
We concur.
Proceed with
caution, Saavik.
What the hell
is going on down there?
Make it quick,
Admiral.
They're moving him
to the Federation funny farm.
Poor friend.
I hear he's fruity
as a nutcake.
Two minutes.
Jim!
How many fingers
do I have up?
That's not very funny.
You're sense
of humor's returned.
The hell it has.
What's that?
Lexorin.
Lexorin? What for?
You're suffering from a Vulcan
mind-meld, Doctor.
That green-blooded
son of a bitch!
It's his revenge for
those arguments he lost.
Let's see your hand.
This will make you
well enough to travel.
Where's Admiral Kirk?
He's with
the prisoner.
Get him quickly.
Commander Starfleet
wants him right away.
Oh, hum.
Keeping you busy?
Don't get smart, Tiny.
Admiral, Starfleet-
This man's sick.
Take a look.
Side elevator.
Agents coming up.
Don't call me Tiny.
The Kobayashi Maru
has set sail
for the promised land.
Acknowledge.
Message acknowledged.
All units will be informed.
You're taking me to
the promised land?
What are friends for?
Ah, Mr. Scott.
Calling it a night?
Uh, yes, sir.
Looking forward to breaking
some speed records tomorrow.
Yes, sir.
Good night.
Level, please.
Transporter room.
Thank you.
Up your shaft.
Roger. Old City Station
at 2200 hours. All is well.
Understood.
All stations clear.
You amaze me,
Commander.
How is that?
A 20-year space veteran,
yet you choose
the worst duty station.
This is
the hind end of space.
Peace and quiet
appeals to me, Lieutenant.
Maybe that's okay
for someone like you,
whose career
is winding down.
But me, I need some challenge
and adventure in my life.
Maybe even
just a surprise.
You know
what they say.
Be careful
what you wish for.
You may get it.
Good evening, Commander.
Is everything ready?
Step into my parlor,
gentlemen.
That's Admiral Kirk.
My God!
Very good for you,
Lieutenant.
But it's damn irregular.
No destination orders,
no encoded IDs.
All true.
What'll we do?
I'm not doing anything.
You're going to sit
in the closet.
The closet?
Have you lost
all your sense of reality?
This isn't reality.
This is fantasy.
You wanted adventure.
How's this?
The old
adrenaline going?
Good. Now get
in the closet.
Okay.
Uh...
Go on. Go on.
I'll just get
in the closet.
Okay!
I'm glad
you're on our side.
I'll have Mr. Adventure
eating out of my hand,
and I'll see you
at the rendezvous.
Oh, and, Admiral...
All my hopes.
As promised,
she's all yours, sir.
All systems
automated and ready.
A chimpanzee
and two trainees could run her.
I'll try not
to take that personally.
My friends, I can't ask
you to go any further.
Dr. McCoy and I
have to do this.
The rest of you do not.
Admiral, we're losing
precious time.
What course,
please, Admiral?
Mr. Scott?
I'd be grateful
if you'd give the word.
Gentlemen...
May the wind
be at our backs.
Stations, please.
Engage all the systems.
Aye. Engaged!
Clear all moorings.
Clearing, sir.
One quarter
impulse power.
One quarter impulse.
Sir.
Commander Starfleet
orders you
to surrender this vessel.
No reply, Chekov.
Steady as she goes.
Yellow alert.
Captain to the bridge.
How can you have
a yellow alert in spacedock?
Sir, someone is stealing
the Enterprise!
I'm on my way.
Alert. Yellow alert.
All stations,
yellow alert.
Alert. Yellow alert.
All stations,
yellow alert.
One minute to space doors.
Are you just going
to walk through?
Calm yourself, Doctor.
Sir, Excelsior powering up
with orders to pursue.
Yellow alert.
Status?
All automates ready
and functioning.
Automatic moorings
retracted.
All speeds available
through
transwarp drive.
Incredible machine.
Helm.
One quarter
impulse power.
30 seconds
to space doors.
Warning.
Secure space doors.
And...now,
Mr. Scott.
Sir?
The doors,
Mr. Scott.
Aye, sir.
I'm working on it.
Danger.
Space doors are closed.
We have cleared
space doors.
Full impulse power.
Aye, sir.
Standby tractor beam.
Tractor beam, aye.
If he tries to get away
with warp drive,
he's really in
for a shock.
Excelsior closing
to 4,000 meters.
We'll need everything
you have.
Aye, sir.
Warp drive standing by.
Kirk, if you do this,
you'll never sit in
the captain's chair again.
Warp speed.
Aye, sir.
Prepare for warp speed.
Standby transwarp drive.
Transwarp
at your command.
Full power available.
Execute.
...Power available...
Transwarp drive,
full...power... available....
maximum velocity
in 5, 4, 3, 2, 1.
Scotty, as good
as your word.
The more they over think
the plumbing,
the easier it is
to stop up the drain.
Here, Doctor, souvenirs
from one surgeon to another.
I removed them from her
transwarp computer drive.
Nice of you
to tell me in advance.
You shouldn't miss
staff meetings.
Your work today
has been outstanding.
I'll recommend you all
for promotion...
in whatever fleet
we end up serving.
Best speed to Genesis.
The Genesis wave.
His cells could have
been regenerated.
Captain,
this is Saavik.
Come in, please.
Yes, Saavik.
Go ahead.
We have found
the life sign.
It is a Vulcan child,
perhaps 8-10 Earth
years of age.
A child?
How did he get there?
It's Dr. Marcus' opinion
that this is...
that the Genesis effect
has regenerated...
Captain Spock.
Uh...
Saavik, that's, uh...
That's extraordinary.
What will you do next?
Request permission
to beam aboard immediately.
Does Dr. Marcus think
there's any chance
of radioactive
contamination?
No.
None that he can detect.
I'll advise Starfleet
and get instructions.
I'm sure Starfleet
would approve.
Probably true,
but let's follow rules.
Stand by
on this channel.
Go.
Starfleet Command,
this is U.S.S. Grissom
on subspace
coded channel 98.8.
Come in, please.
Something is jamming
our transmission.
An energy surge.
Locate.
It's from astern,
Captain.
Oh, my God!
Captain,
what is happening?
We're under attack!
Stand by for evasive.
Bah!
May I suggest-
Say the wrong thing!
If you
want prisoners,
there are
life signs there.
Perhaps the very
scientists you seek.
Very good.
Grissom,
this is Saavik
on emergency frequency.
Come in, please.
What happened
to them?
Grissom was destroyed
by an enemy attack.
We must go.
They will soon
come after us.
Estimating Genesis,
2.9 hours, present speed.
Can we hold speed?
Aye. She's got
her second wind.
Scan for vessels
in pursuit.
Scanning.
Indications negative at this time.
Well, did I
get it right?
Great, Bones,
just great.
It's time for total
truth between us.
This planet is not
what you intended
or hoped for, is it?
Not exactly.
Why?
I used protomatter
in the Genesis matrix.
Protomatter.
An unstable substance
which every ethical scientist
in the galaxy
has denounced as
dangerously unpredictable.
It was the only way
to solve certain problems.
So, like your father,
you changed the rules.
If I hadn't,
it might have
been years or never.
How many have paid the price
for your impatience?
How many have died?
How much damage
have you done?
And what is
yet to come?
This planet's aging
in surges.
And Spock with it.
It seems
they' rejoined together.
They are.
How long?
Days...
maybe hours.
I'm sorry.
It will be
hardest on Spock.
Soon he will feel the burning
of his Vulcan blood.
I don't understand.
Pon Farr.
Vulcan males
must endure it
every seventh year
of their adult life.
Whoever they are,
they're getting closer.
I'll go.
No.
I'll do it.
Give me
your phaser.
Sir, Starfleet
calling U.S.S. Grissom.
A warning about us.
Response?
Nothing, as before.
What's the Grissom
up to?
Will she join us
or fire on us?
Break silence. Send
Captain Esteban my compliments.
Aye, sir.
How are we doing?
It's funny you should
put it quite that way, Jim.
We are doing fine,
but I'd feel safer giving him
one of my kidneys
than what's scrambled
in my brain.
Admiral, there's no response
from Grissom on any channel.
Keep trying, Chekov...
at regular intervals.
It is called Pon Farr.
Pon Farr.
We are secured
for warp speed.
Now entering
Genesis sector.
Proceed at impulse power.
Vessel entering
sector.
Yes. Federation
battle cruiser.
Have they scanned us?
Not yet.
Ahh.
I'd swear there
was something there, sir.
What did you see?
For an instant,
a scout-class vessel.
Could be Grissom.
Patch in
a hailing frequency.
Grissom, this is
Enterprise calling.
Please come in.
Grissom, this is
Enterprise calling.
Do you read?
Yiahuq!
Spock!
Dah!
I've come a long way
for the power of Genesis,
and what do I find?
A weakling human,
a Vulcan boy,
and a woman.
My lord, we are survivors
of a doomed expedition.
This planet will
destroy itself in hours.
The Genesis experiment
is a failure.
A failure.
The most powerful destructive
force ever created.
You will tell me the secret
of the Genesis torpedo.
I have no knowledge.
Then I hope pain is
something you enjoy.
Johwi'.
I ordered
no interruptions!
But, sir, Federation
starship approaching.
Bring me up.
Grissom...
this is Enterprise
calling.
Do you read?
Grissom, this is
Enterprise calling.
Please come in.
Grissom.
This is Admiral Kirk
calling Captain Esteban
or Lieutenant Saavik.
Please come in.
Report status.
We are cloaked.
Enemy closing
on impulse power.
Range,
5,000 kellicams.
Good.
This is the turn of luck
I've been waiting for.
Nothing
on my scanner.
Short range scan,
Mr. Chekov.
Put it on visual,
Mr. Sulu.
Range, 3,000 kellicams.
Steady.
Continue on
impulse power.
Range, 2,000 kellicams.
Stand by to transfer
energy to weapons...
at my command.
There.
That distortion.
See it?
It's enlarging
as we close in.
Firing range, sir.
Opinion, Mr. Sulu.
It's an
energy surge.
Enough to hide
a ship?
A cloaking device.
Red alert,
Mr. Scott.
Aye, sir.
1,000 kellicams,
closing.
Power to
weapons systems.
Wait.
No shields?
My guess is right.
They have to decloak
before firing.
May all your
guesses be right.
Vaq valis qeliqap.
Tyrusch.
Shoha!
Klingon bird of prey, sir.
She's arming torpedoes.
Fire!
Good shooting, Mr. Scott.
Precautionary,
Mr. Chekov.
Shields up.
Aye, sir.
Emergency power
to the thrusters!
Sir, the shield's
nonresponsive.
Scotty?
The automation system's
overloaded.
I didn't expect
to go into combat.
Bah!
Emergency power.
Prepare to return fire.
Can you transfer power
to the phaser banks?
I don't think so.
What happened?
They've knocked out
the automation center.
I've got no control.
Mr. Sulu?
Nothing, sir.
So...
we're a sitting duck.
Ready to fire
emergency tube.
Why haven't they
finished us?
They outgun me
10 to 1.
My lord, the enemy
commander wishes a truce.
Put him on-screen.
This is Admiral
James T. Kirk
of Federation starship
Enterprise.
So...the Genesis
commander himself.
A violation of treaty-
your presence here
is an act of war.
You have two minutes
to surrender,
or we will destroy you.
He's hiding
something.
We may have hit him
more seriously
than I thought.
How can you tell?
I trust
my instincts.
Admiral Kirk, this is
your opponent speaking.
Don't lecture me
about treaty violations.
The Federation, in creating
an ultimate weapon,
has become a gang
of intergalactic criminals.
It is you
who will surrender.
On the planet below,
I have three prisoners
from the team who developed
your doomsday weapon.
If you do not
surrender immediately,
I will execute them
one at a time
as enemies
of galactic peace!
Who is this?
How dare you
take prisoners?
Who I am
isn't important.
That I
have them is.
I will allow you
to speak to them.
Admiral, this is
Lieutenant Saavik.
Saavik!
Is David with you?
Yes. Also
a Vulcan scientist
of your acquaintance.
This...
Vulcan...
Is he alive?
He's not himself,
but he lives.
He's subject
to rapid aging.
Hello, sir.
It's David.
I'm sorry I'm late.
I should've
known you'd come.
This planet will
destroy itself in hours.
David,
what went wrong?
I went wrong.
I don't understand.
Just don't surrender.
Genesis doesn't work.
I can't believe
they'd kill us for it.
I meant
what I said.
To show that my intentions
are sincere,
I shall kill one
of the prisoners.
Wait!
Allow me to talk.
Saavik?
David?
Admiral,
David is dead.
You Klingon bastard,
you've killed my son.
You Klingon bastard!
There are two more
prisoners, Admiral.
Do you want
them killed, too?
Surrender your vessel.
All right.
All right, damn you.
Give me a minute
to inform my crew.
I give two minutes
for you and your
gallant crew.
Take every last man.
Form a boarding
party armed heavily.
They outnumber us.
We are Klingons!
Once you control
the ship,
we'll transfer
our flag there
and take Genesis from their own
memory banks.
Mr. Sulu,
what is the crew complement
of a bird of prey?
About a dozen
officers and men.
With some of them
on the planet.
I swear to you,
we're not finished yet.
Bones, you and Sulu
to the transporter room.
The rest of you,
we have a job to do.
Commander,
Klingon vessel...
Prepare to board
on my next signal.
No tricks, Kirk.
You have one minute.
No tricks.
I'm looking
forward to meeting you.
Computer, this is
Admiral James T. Kirk.
Request security access.
Computer,
destruct sequence one,
code 1-1 a.
Computer, Commander Montgomery
Scott, chief engineering officer.
Destruct sequence two,
code 1-1 a-2b.
Computer, this is
Commander Pavel Chekov,
acting science officer.
Destruct sequence three,
code 1 b-2b-3.
Destruct sequence
completed and engaged.
Awaiting final code
for one-minute countdown.
Code zero zero zero.
Destruct.
Zero.
Destruct sequence
is activated.
Kirk, the time
runs out.
All set?
Aye, sir.
Commander,
Klingon vessel.
We are energizing
transporter beam now.
Transporter, stand by.
Hara.
My lord, the ship appears
to be deserted.
How can that be?
They're hiding!
The bridge
is run by computer.
It's the only
thing speaking.
Speaking?
Let me hear.
9...8...7...6...
5...
Get out!
Get out of there!
1...
My God, Bones,
what have I done?
What you had to do.
What you always do.
Turn death into
a fighting chance to live.
Planet core readings.
Unstable,
changing rapidly.
What about
surface life signs?
There.
Yaaa!
Aah!
No, don't
touch him.
Bones.
What happened?
He gave his life
to save us.
Rapid aging.
All genetic functions
highly accelerated.
What about his mind?
His mind's a void.
It seems I've got
all his marbles.
Is there anything
we can do?
Only one thing-
get him off this planet.
His aging is part
of what's going on around us.
Klingon Commander, this is
Admiral James T. Kirk.
I'm alive and well
on the planet surface.
I know this will come
as a pleasant surprise,
but our ship had
an unfortunate accident.
Sorry about your crew,
but as we say on Earth,
c'est la vie.
I have what you want.
I have the secret
of Genesis.
You're going to have to
bring us up there to get it.
Do you hear me?
I'm waiting for you.
What is your answer?
Aaahhh!
Drop all weapons!
Over there.
All but Kirk.
Maltz.
Prisoners are
at beam coordinates.
Take the Vulcan, too.
No!
But why?
Because you wish it.
Genesis.
I want it!
Beam the Vulcan up,
and we'll talk.
Give me what I want,
and I'll consider it.
You fool,
look around you!
The planet's
destroying itself!
Yes, exhilarating,
isn't it?
If we don't help each other,
we'll die here.
Perfect. Then that's
the way it shall be.
Give me Genesis!
Aah!
Give me your hand!
I...
have had...
enough of you!
Maltz...
Jolyichu!
Don't.
How many more?
Just him, sir.
Bones, help Spock.
We've got to
break out of orbit.
You,
help us or die.
I do not
deserve to live.
Fine. I'll
kill you later.
Let's get
out of here.
Where's the damn
anti-matter inducer?
This?
No, this!
That or nothing.
If I'm right,
we have full power.
Go, Sulu.
Goodbye, David.
We are clear
and free to navigate.
Best speed to Vulcan.
Take the prisoner below.
Aye, sir.
Wait. You said
you would kill me.
I lied.
Spock,
for God sakes,
talk to me.
You stuck this damn thing
in my head, remember?
Remember?
Now tell me
what to do with it.
Help me.
I'm going to
tell you something
that I never thought
I'd ever hear myself say.
But it seems
I've missed you.
I don't know
if I could...
stand to
lose you again.
Ambassador,
they're on approach.
They're requesting
permission to land.
Permission granted.
Tell them...
tell Kirk...
we'll be ready.
Mr. Sulu,
you're on manual.
It's been a while, sir.
Here we go.
Retrothrusters.
Sarek is waiting
above, sir.
Kaltorfalikal.
Sarek...
Child of Skon,
child
of Solkar...
the body of your son
breathes still.
What is
your wish?
I ask for
Fal-tor-pan,
the re-fusion.
What you seek has not
been done since ages past...
and then,
only in legend.
Your request
is not logical.
Forgive me, T'lar.
My logic...is uncertain
where my son
is concerned.
Who is the keeper
of the Katra?
I am.
McCoy,
Leonard H.,
son of David.
McCoy, son of David,
since
thou art human,
we cannot
expect thee
to understand fully
what Sarek
has requested.
Spock's body lives.
With your approval,
we shall use
all our powers
to return
to his body
that which
you possess.
But, McCoy,
you must
now be warned.
The danger
to thyself
is as grave
as the danger to Spock.
You must
make the choice.
I choose the danger.
Hell of a time
to ask.
Ben... val...navu.
I'm all right, Jim.
What about Spock?
Only time
will answer.
Kirk...
I thank you.
What you
have done-
What I have done...
I had to do.
But at what cost?
Your ship, your son.
If I hadn't tried,
the cost would've
been my soul.
My father says
that you have
been my friend.
You came back
for me.
You would have done
the same for me.
Why would
you do this?
Because the needs
of the one...
outweigh the needs
of the many.
I have been
and ever shall be
your friend.
Yes.
Yes, Spock.
The ship...
out of danger?
You saved the ship.
You saved us all.
Don't you remember?
Jim.
Your name is Jim.
Yes.