Tell her what you got.
Male, Caucasian,
mid 40s,
appears to
have been shot.
Where?
In his room.
Very funny.
O.K., O.K.
The wound's
below the heart.
Shot once?
Seems to have been, yes.
First you said
appears to have been shot.
Mr. Turner.
Oh, Dr. Lappe,
I'm sure
he'll be here
any second now.
Really?
Mr. Turner's
late again.
Get back to work.
We can dope it out in five
minutes and get back to work.
Know what
Joey would say?
He isn't the only
mind in this place.
Come on.
Uh, what kind
of a slug?
You're missing
the point, ray.
What do you mean?
The machine will
come back with
"please express
in other words."
what should we
feed in?
[ doorbell rings ]
[ buzz ]
Turner, Joseph.
No middle initial.
You're 17 minutes late.
Make it 12,
will you?
I was bucking headwinds.
Dr. Lappe, anything in
the early pouch for me?
Dr. Lappe?
Yes?
Nothing in response
to your report.
Please have the book
I left on your desk
analyzed
and on the computer
by 4:00.
Yes, sir.
Better get the telemias
moved closer to the light.
You're getting a blight
on the leaf.
At ease, sarge.
At ease.
Going to rain today.
10:20.
RAY:
There's got to
be more details.
HAROLD: I only read
two chapters.
No other clues?
Not yet.
JANICE: What time they find
him?
Early evening.
They never said
what the caliber
of the bullet was.
Apparently .38.
Apparently?
It made
an entry wound
characteristic
of a .38.
They couldn't
recover the slug.
Hey,
we're getting somewhere.
You guys figure it out.
I have far east
journals to read.
Was the slug
smashed against the wall?
No.
Actually,
there was no
exit wound.
We're not getting anywhere.
Finish the book, Harold .
Hi.
What we've got
so far is--
Ice.
Instead of lead.
The murderer pours water
into a .38 caliber mold,
freezes it,
and keeps it solid
until the crime.
Then he shoots the guy
with the ice bullet.
Cops show up,
there's just a few
drops of water.
No bullet,
no ballistics.
That's great.
Hey.
Yeah?
What is this?
Mmm.
Calligraphy's
getting beautiful.
What is it?
Ten.
That means heaven.
That's it?
Nothing else?
Well, it can mean
the best.
Tops sometimes.
Why?
I'm not sure.
We're going to Sam
and Mae's tonight, right?
Mm-hmm.
Talk to Sam
about it.
About this?
Mm-hmm.
I did.
He says,
"That's interesting,
but it's not
my department,"
which means
he doesn't think
there's anything,
just like Dr. Lappe.
And you.
Well,
there's not much.
A mystery
that's been
translated?
A mystery
that didn't sell
has been translated into
a very odd assortment
of languages--
Turkish, but not French,
Arabic, but not Russian.
or German.
Dutch.
Spanish?
Yes.
Hey, where'd you
get that thing
about the ice?
Dashiell Hammett ?
Dick Tracy.
Are you sure
about this ideogram?
Look at this face.
Could I be wrong
about an ideogram?
It's a great face.
But it's never
been to China.
When can I get
computer time?
Dick Tracy?
He was a very
underrated detective.
There's free time
at 2:45.
Morning pickup.
No, no, no, no.
Stay on schedule.
I'll get it.
Four pieces, right?
Right.
Hold it.
Five.
Affirmative.
Fiver.
Where is Mr. Heidegger?
Called in sick,
Dr. Lappe.
He's probably
hung over again.
This is extraordinary.
I was
checking the files
and came across
this carbon copy
of an inquiry he sent
to Persian Gulf command.
He did that for me.
It never went through
my office.
I asked him to do
some research
for me.
I wish you people
would go through channels.
[ door opens ]
Uh, what's on your mind?
O.K.
[ buzz ]
[ not audible ]
this was in the pouch
from New York center.
HQ at Langley said
there's nothing
from any other
intelligence source
to support
your theory.
Gentlemen.
Is this your idea
of working on that book?
I'll have it
on the computer
by 4:00.
We have people
to service these machines.
These things are simple.
They just look complicated.
Mr. Turner,
I wonder if you're
entirely happy here.
Within obvious limits,
yes, sir.
Obvious limits?
It bothers me
I can't tell people
what I do.
Why is it
taking you long
to accept that?
Well...
I actually trust
a few people.
That's a problem.
I believe
it's your turn
to bring in lunch.
What time is it?
11:22.
The rain's
going to stop
by 11:30.
You can wait
eight minutes.
Ah, yes.
Yes.
Mr. Turner?
Hey! Hey!
Hey!
Damn it.
It's not
a proper exit.
He always
goes out that way
when it rains.
Personnel should
enter and exit
the premises
by authorized
means only.
[ thunder ]
Jimmy.
Hey, Shakespeare, how's it
going?
Terrific.
I'm building up
a great collection
of rejection slips.
Yeah,
I know the feeling.
I always
wanted to be
Escoffier .
Maybe it's not too late.
Van Gogh was 30
before he started
to paint.
No kidding?
There's no mayonnaise
on Dr. Lappe's.
On the other hand,
Mozart was three
when he started
playing the piano.
He was
composing at six.
Fast starter.
It's probably better.
I don't know.
Van Gogh never
sold a painting
in his lifetime.
Mozart died a pauper.
Where am I,
the public library?
That's a very
bright man.
It's educational.
That's why
I'm here.
You come in here
to get sick
like everybody else.
Come on.
No butter
on Ray's sandwich.
He gets panicky
about butter.
[ doorbell rings ]
[ buzz ]
[ typewriter ]
Give it to Jennings
in the back.
He'll sign for it.
[ gunfire ]
Edwinna rose.
[ clock chimes ]
Mrs. Russell,
was the Kirkus Report
in this--
Wait, wait, wait!
Aah!
Uhh!
Would you move
from the window, please?
Pardon?
Would you move
from the window, please?
I won't scream.
I know.
A little breakdown
in the security there?
Well, what--
what are you doing?
What?
Wh--
Come here.
Come on.
Harold.
[ horn honks ]
For Christ's sake!
What the hell
you doing, Mac?
Do your sleeping
at night, will ya?
[ beeping ]
This is the major.
This is Joe Turner.
Identification.
What?
Name's Turner.
I work for you.
Identify yourself.
I--
I don't--
What is your designation?
Uh, Condor.
Section 9,
department 17.
The section's
been hit.
What level?
Level of damage.
Everybody.
Dr. Lappe, Janice, Ray,
Harold .
Harold was
in the, uh--
Are you on
a company line?
No. I'm in
a phone booth.
I'm in the street.
You're in violation
of secure communication
procedures, Condor.
Listen,
you son of a bitch!
I came back with lunch.
The house was murdered.
Everybody is dead.
Has the incident
been discovered
by anyone
outside the company?
I don't--
I don't know.
I don't think so.
Are you damaged?
Damaged?
No.
Are you armed?
I don't--
I have Mrs., uh--
I can't remember
her code name.
Nightingale.
She kept a gun.
I've got the gun.
Identify the armament.
It's a .45 automatic.
Will you bring me in, please?
I'm not a field agent.
I just read books.
Leave the area.
All right. Well--
Do I come in to
headquarters now?
Negative.
Find a secure location.
Where?
Avoid any place
you're known.
Do not go home.
Surface again
in two hours
and call the major.
That'll be 1430,
your time.
Wait--wait a minute.
All right.
2:30, right?
Walk away
from the phone.
Don't hang it up.
Don't--[ click ]
This is the panic officer.
Section 9-17
may have been hit.
Activate
following procedures--
NY 127..
DC 469er.
Replay on the report
upcoming. Stand by.
[ children shouting ]
Augie One
to New York center.
New York center.
Go ahead.
Who am I talking to?
Higgins.
Deputy director.
Go ahead.
Hit confirmed.
Maximum as reported.
Six cold items.
The quality?
Clean, fast,
first-rate.
Did you say six?
Excepting Condor,
there should be seven.
Repeat. Six.
Here's a rundown
on those items.
Lappe, Chong,
Russell, Jennings,
Martin, Mitchell .
All right, Augie One.
Find seven.
Thank you.
[ door closes ]
Condor.
"Researcher,
tide pool.
Likes to read
comic strips."
[ street band plays
Good King Wenceslas ]
[ buzz ]
Who is it?
Jesus.
Hey, you.
You ring my buzzer?
It was a mistake, buddy.
Not you guys.
[ door closes ]
Hey...
hey...
hey, who are you?
Hey, who the hell are you?
Augie Three here.
We found item seven.
Ralph Heidegger .
He bought it at home.
HIGGINS: Button it up, Augie .
I'll send you more janitors.
[ buzz ]
I need Langley
right away.
Yes, sir.
[ telephone rings ]
Garber speaking.
This is Higgins,
deputy director.
Let me have
department 17.
Somebody took out
one of your sections.
What?
9-17.
That's New York.
Somebody got mugged maybe.
They were hit.
They're bookworms.
They got seven
of eight.
We're on the shuttle
to La Guardia . 30 minutes.
One of my people
is O.K .?
Condor.
You know him?
No. Can he say
what happened?
He was literally
out to lunch.
What does he say
happened?
He's not in yet.
First call was
a little wild, scared.
Who's bringing him in?
Higgins.
Already booked
on the shuttle.
Wicks,
O.I.C . Department 17.
I want a chopper
fueled for New York now.
Oh.
Hello.
They're waiting for you.
What?
Your two friends.
They said
you'd be home early.
They just got here,
said you gave them
the keys.
Mr. Turner?
[ helicopter ]
[ beeping ]
This is the major.
This is Condor.
Stand by, Condor.
I'm routing you
to New York Center.
Condor on 1-1,
Mr. Higgins.
Hello, Condor.
Who is this?
Deputy Director Higgins, New
York Center.
I'm controlling now, Condor.
Where are you?
How come I need
a code name,
and you don't?
Where are you, Turner?
Here.
You all right?
Are you insane?
Everybody's dead.
Take it easy.
Just take it easy,
and we'll bring you home.
Here's how
we'll do it.
Do you know
the Ansonia Hotel?
Broadway and, uh...71st.
Broadway and 73rd.
There's an alley
behind the hotel.
One hour from now
at exactly 1530,
enter that alley from
the 73rd street side.
Will you be there?
The head of your department
just came from D.C .
He'll bring you home.
I've never met him.
Don't worry.
He's studying
your photos now.
Turner?
Turner!
I don't know you, either.
We'll meet.
He'll be carrying
a Wall Street Journal
in his left hand.
Guys were
at my house.
What were you doing there?
You were told not to go there!
I was homesick.
Who were they?
They were ours.
What were they doing
in my house?
I'm not going
into any alley.
Fuck the Wall Street Journal!
It's been a long day.
You've been under--
Damn right
I've been under.
All right, Turner.
We'll bring along
a familiar face,
somebody you know.
Who's left?
Got a friend
in statistics
named Sam Barber.
Sam.
You guys
are something.
Will he do?
Yes, Sam will do.
All right, Turner.
Stay well for 60 minutes,
and you're home.
Can I ask
a question?
Sure.
What is happening?
I'll talk to you
in 60 minutes.
You've got 55.
This is ridiculous.
You're not
a field agent.
Standard
procedure.
To pick up a friend?
What about you,
Mr. Wicks?
No, thanks.
Side arm?
Do you have a .45?
You bet.
Here, let me
help you with that.
How long have you
known Condor?
Who, Joey?
I knew him before
he was a bird even.
We went to CCNY .
My wife Mae, too.
Was she ever
Condor's girl?
Here you go,
Mr. Wicks.
Hey...
can you tell me anything
about what happened today?
When?
This morning.
Uh, those murders.
What murders?
Sam?
Here he is.
Joe!
Hey, Sam .
Where--where's
that other--
what are you doing?
That's him! It's him!
Joe!
[ siren ]
[ store P.A . plays
silver bells ]
um...
Katherine Hale.
H-a-l-e.
08, 1156,
172, 208, 875.
Amount, 51.86.
Where's there
enough snow
this early?
Vermont.
I hope.
What's open now.
Sugarbush?
I don't do downhill.
This is for cross-country.
Don't like
the lift lines, huh?
474?
Thank you.
[ sirens ]
Kathy !
Kathy.
Where have you been?
W-wait a minute.
Shh.
Don't do anything.
Be quiet.
Get in the car.
Don't make a sound.
Don't be dumb.
Come on.
Hurry up.
Get in.
Listen,
please don't hurt me.
Where do you live?
Brooklyn Heights.
Alone?
I live with a friend.
Uh...
you live alone.
Let's go.
[ door buzzes ]
Leave the stuff.
Hey, Kathy .
You should have
said hello.
Where is it?
Here.
"Condor shot us both."
That was the only statement
he could make
before they took him
into the operating room.
And the other man--
Barber--he's dead?
Before
he hit the ground.
You should add
that it was
a remarkable shot.
A half inch above
his flak jacket.
I thought
this guy--
wait a minute.
Was Condor qualified
with a handgun?
"Two years
military service--
"Signal corps.
"Telephone lineman,
long lines,
"Switchboard
maintenance--
six months overseas.
"Separated 9/61.
"Worked at bell labs communication research.
College
on the G.I Bill."
the question was,
Mr. Higgins,
is he qualified
with a handgun?
No handgun, sir.
M-1 rifle
and carbine.
Evidently,
it was sheer luck.
[ telephone buzzes ]
Or else...
Yes?
Or else what,
Mr. Higgins?
This Condor isn't the man
his file says he is.
Where did he learn
evasive moves?
He reads.
He r--
what's that mean?
It means, sir,
that he reads everything.
But I don't understand.
Yes. Very good.
Has operations
got anything?
Absolutely
nothing, sir.
Extraordinary.
It was very
well-executed.
Which requires planning,
communications, tracks.
I'm not asking
for footprints,
but a blade of grass,
a broken twig--
something disturbed.
Yes, sir.
Wicks is
all we've got.
Where do we have him?
We don't.
They rushed him
to Guvenor emergency
before we got word.
Maybe we should
leak the name
of the hospital,
make Condor
make his move.
Of course, Len,
don't expect too many
mistakes from this man.
He does seem
rather more interesting
than just another
of our reader/researchers.
For example,
has he gone into business
for himself?
Was he turned around?
Does someone
operate him?
Homosexual?
Broke? Vulnerable?
Could he be
a soldier of fortune?
Did he arrange the hit?
Is that why he's
still in flight?
Still, he...
may be an innocent.
But then, why didn't he
come in gently
with Mr. Wicks?
Tentrex Industries.
It's a cover.
I work for the CIA .
Oh, Jesus .
Your assignment
for today
was to go out
and kidnap a girl.
Look it up.
Look it up--
Tentrex Industries.
Then look up
the number
for the CIA .
They're listed,
like my Aunt Gladys ?
Under U.S. Government
agencies. Go on.
So is this what you do?
This photography?
O.K. Uh--
It's the same number.
You could have
had the card made--
yes, I could have,
but I didn't.
You really get
into it, don't you?
Sit down!
I told you
I had a friend.
15 1/2, 34.
I dig 15 1/2, 34s.
What size are you?
What are you,
a clown?
- I'm scared!
- So am I !
Why?
You've got the gun!
Yes!
Yeah, and it's
not enough.
Listen...
I work for the CIA.
I'm not a spy.
I just read books.
We read everything
that's published
in the world,
and we--
we feed the plots--
dirty tricks, codes...
into a computer,
and the computer...
checks against
actual CIA plans
and operations.
I look for leaks,
new ideas.
We read adventures
and novels and...
journals.
I--
I can--
Who'd invent
a job like that?
I--listen!
People are trying
to kill me!
Who?
I don't know,
but there's a reason.
There is a reason!
And I just need...
some safe,
quiet time
to pull things together.
Here.
That's only fair.
[ rat-a-tat-tat ]
[ hiss ]
Where's the guy
with the shirts?
He--he's
at a ski place...
in the Green Mountains.
We just want to go
cross-country skiing
for a couple of weeks,
away from everything.
When does the news
go on, 6:00?
6:00.
40 minutes.
Come here.
No, please.
Please don't.
Lie down.
Lie down
against the wall.
Put this arm
behind you,
and keep it there.
Now you listen to me.
I am tired.
I've got to close
my eyes for a while.
I can't think straight.
If you try and move...
or climb off the bed...
I'll know it.
I'll feel it.
And I promise you
I'll hurt you.
Couldn't you let me
stay in the other room?
No.
I believe
what you told me.
No, you don't.
I don't know if I do.
That includes Condor,
of course.
Yes.
I owe you Condor.
Otherwise--
Otherwise
does not exist.
Will Condor take long?
Do you want
an estimate?
There is
a time factor.
Always
with you people.
Condor
is an amateur.
He's lost, unpredictable...
perhaps even sentimental.
He could fool
a professional.
Not deliberately,
but precisely
because he is lost.
Doesn't know
what to do...
unlike wicks...
who has always
been entirely predictable.
The man...
Condor killed
in the alley.
Some friend of his.
Close friend?
I suppose so. Why?
It interests me.
What
was his name?
I don't know.
He was nobody.
[ speaking French ]
Right.
What about wicks?
You want the firm
to question him?
They will, you know.
We don't want that.
Cost you nothing.
I was careless
with Condor.
Wicks will be done
for nothing.
What time is it?
What time--
It's news time.
Get up.
♪ Take a second now
♪ Look up in the sky
♪ Can't you
see the blue bird? ♪
♪ That's an eastern plane
♪ Flying through the sky
♪ Shouldn't that
be you there? ♪
♪ Suddenly you stop,
and you're wondering why ♪
♪ You're down there,
and they're up
in the sky ♪
♪ You gotta believe
it's for you ♪
♪ Dreams come true
♪ You gotta believe
in lookin' up now ♪
♪ Eastern's
lookin' up now ♪
♪ Look at us,
look at you ♪
♪ And you gotta believe
Lonely pictures.
♪ You can fly,
you can fly ♪
So?
♪ You can fly
♪ Do what you want to
You're funny.
♪ Fly, be what you want
You take pictures of...
empty streets
and trees with
no leaves on them.
♪ Fly eastern ♪
It's winter.
Not quite winter.
They look like...
November.
Not autumn, not winter.
In-between.
I like them.
Thanks.
Eyewitness News continues
with an update--
sit down.
of the Ansonia shootings.
The shootings
behind the Hotel Ansonia
remain a complete mystery
at this hour.
The victims' identities
have not yet been revealed.
Victims?
Drugs were not involved.
Did he say victims?
seem to have been
a robbery.
Lieutenant,
can you tell us
about the
possible motive?
Not at present.
Have you identified
the victims?
They were employees
of an insurance company.
What?
Doing a routine inspection
for possible violations.
Did the victims know
their assailants?
Absolutely not.
Well, there you have it.
One man dead,
one seriously wounded,
in an alley on
the west side of Manhattan .
The man with the gun
still at large.
Stan Roberts, Eyewitness
News, New York.
Sam.
Jesus Christ.
Victims.
What is he s--
What happened
in that alley?
I didn't shoot him.
You said
you shot somebody.
But not Sam!
Nobody in that alley
said anything
about the CIA.
But--
but they were there.
Wait a minute.
You're telling me...
They had to have been
to change that story.
What did Higgins say?
He said
he wouldn't be there.
He said the section
chief was coming in.
Wait a minute. He's--
section chief would be
coming in from Washington .
He'd have to reach Sam.
Sam would call me.
[ woman's voice ]
Hello.
Hello?
I need your car.
That's called grand theft.
You don't want trouble
with the police.
This guy in Vermont
what will he do
when you don't show up?
Probably call.
Very soon now.
Will he show up
here?
That gun gives you
the right to rough me up.
It doesn't
give you the right--
rough you up?
Yes!
You're in my house!
Have I--
have I raped you?
The night is young.
You don't believe
anything I've said.
I believe
you're in trouble...
danger...
but I don't know
what kind,
and I'm not sure
how much of it is...
made up.
Real, but, uh...
doesn't make
any difference.
Doesn't matter.
Wait a minute.
Will you--
forget it.
I'm trying to understand!
Aah!
Ow!
What are you doing?
Let me go!
Ow! You're
hurting me.
Wait a minute.
You--
Oh! You bully!
Don't tie me up!
Come on, please!
This is...
unfair!
I know.
[ doorbell buzzes ]
Oh.
Hi, Joey.
You're early.
Come on in.
Hey, is Janice
working late?
So is Sam .
[ It Came Upon
a Midnight Clear plays ]
Hey, pour one for me,
too, will you, Joey?
It's their own fault
if we're zonked
when they get here.
Hey, I've got it.
We'll give them
an hour.
If they're not here,
it's you and me,
just like old times.
Joey.
What is it?
Hey, what is it,
Joey?
What?
What's wrong?
Mae,
how do you know
Sam's working late?
What do you think
he's doing?
When did he call?
I don't know.
2:00 or 2:30.
What did he say?
Exactly.
He didn't exactly.
He had the center call.
Who at the center?
I didn't
recognize his voice.
It wasn't that lady
that usually--
[ telephone rings ]
[ ring ]
Hello.
[ click ]
What is it?
Third damn time tonight.
Third time?
Some burglar
casing the joint.
Get out of here.
I can't, Joey.
I'm cooking.
Do what I tell you.
What about dinner?
Go to Bill and Eileen's.
Joey,
what's going on?
Please.
Joey, you--
Don't argue. Move! Move!
Joey--
Go upstairs
and stay there.
Do what I'm telling you.
I'll call you.
And stay there.
Joey--
I'll call you.
Do what I tell you.
What about Sam ?
Yours?
No.
♪ Happy Birthday
to Grandpa ♪
You're always
pushing the buttons.
Would you stop it, please?
Fifth floor. Uh,
ladies' underwear.
Kids.
Probably the same everywhere.
[ door opens ]
[ door closes ]
This is
the second floor.
I do it all the time.
After you.
No. Go ahead.
All right.
Anybody here good
with a coat hanger?
What?
I locked my keys
in my car.
I'll give you money.
How much?
You can't tell me
you've never busted
into a car.
So how much?
Five bucks.
Five bucks?
Can you give me
a break?
Do you mind?
All right.
5 bucks.5 bucks.
I'll be
right back.
Come on, man.
Merde.
The money.
Wait a minute.
Gimme
the money.
Hey!
Hey.
[ ring ]
Ow.
I want you to answer
the phone.
I'm not going to
answer the--uh.
Ow!
I'm not answering
any phone!
Answer it.
You answer the phone!
Tell him what a brave
son of a bitch you are.
Ow.
I want you to be
casual and nice.
[ ring ]
h-hello?
Where the hell
are you?
Ben?
Who do you
think it is?
Ben.
You were supposed to be
up here by now.
I know.
You haven't
even left yet.
I was held up.
That's no excuse.
Come on, what's going on?
Doesn't this trip
matter to you?
It matters.
Yeah, I'm sure.
No, it does.
This has happened
over and over again.
Last minute, some excuse.
No, this is different.
So, what?
The car...
what about it?
Bro-broke down.
What? What?
What broke down?
The g-generator went.
Oh, Christ, the generator.
That's going to
take forever.
Maybe not.
I--I tried to call you
before, but...
the generator--it's going
to take too long.
Why don't you just--
forget about the car.
Take the bus up
first thing tomorrow.
I'll try.
Try?
What's--what the hell
is going on?
Are you O.K.?
What--what's..
No, I'm O.K.
I'm fine.
You don't sound
so fine.
I--I wish you
would understand.
I do.
I do, I do.
It's just--
Goddamn it,
I'm just disappointed,
that's all.
I really, uh,
I really wanted to be
with you here,
tonight, babe,
you know?
I know.
We'll have time.
Yeah.
Look, get--
get the very first bus out
in the morning, O.K..?
All right.
Good night, sweetheart.
Good night.
[ click ]
Listen, I 'll be going...
in the morning.
Where?
Was it all right?
All right?
Outside--was it safe?
Wherever you went.
Oh.
I'm not sure.
Oh, God.
I wish I knew more.
About you.
About yesterday.
Today.
I don't remember yesterday.
Today it rained.
Why did you tie me up
like that?
I mean, you thought
I'd call the police.
I wouldn't have.
Why?
Well, sometimes...
I take a picture
that isn't like me,
but I took it,
so it is like me.
It has to be.
I put those
pictures away.
I'd like to see
those pictures.
We don't know
each other that well.
Do you know anybody
that well?
I don't think I want
to know you very well.
I don't think you're
going to live
much longer.
Well, I may...
surprise you.
Anyway, you're not
telling the truth.
What do you mean?
You'd rather be
with somebody
who's not going to
live much longer,
at least somebody
who would be on his way.
I'm not--
You take pictures.
Beautiful pictures,
but of empty streets
and trees with no leaves. November.
Why haven't you asked me
to untie your hands?
H-how much
do you want...
I just...
want to stop it.
For a few hours.
For the rest of the night.
And then I'll go.
Joe!
What was his name?
What is it Higgins said?
Was it...
the head of your department
just came from D.C.
He'll bring you home.
I've never met him.
Anything in
the early pouch?
Headquarters at Langley
says there's nothing
from any other
intelligence source
to support your theory.
Headquarters at Langley
says there's nothing
from any other
intelligence source
to support your theory.
Wicks.
You didn't sleep well.
You didn't?
No,
you didn't.
You're up early.
Oh, I had--I had
some thoughts.
I've got a plan.
I don't know if it'll
work or not, but...
I'll need your help.
Have I ever denied you
anything?
Hey.
Well, when things
quiet down...
you're really
a very sweet man
to be with.
You had bad dreams.
Talked in your sleep.
What did I say?
Who's Janice ?
Well, was she a volunteer
or a draftee like me?
She was...
a friend.
She's dead.
Do I have permission
to take a shower?
You don't have to
help, you know.
No, I'll help.
You can always depend
on the old spyfucker.
O.K.
I'm sorry.
No.
No, I didn't mean--
I didn't mean
to say that.
I'm really sorry.
I'd like to
help you.
[ heart monitor beeping ]
[ P.A . System ]
♪...The lord is come
♪ Let earth
receive her king ♪
♪ Let every heart
♪ Prepare him room
♪ And heaven
and nature sing ♪
and heaven and.. ♪
[ monitor flatlines ]
Eighteen. Isn't that--
Yes.
A.I.D. In I.C.U.,
10-9-8.
[ doorbell rings ]
Yeah?
Insured package
for Katherine Hale.
Uh...
Could you leave it
out on the stoop?
Somebody's got to
sign for it.
Well, she's in--
she's not here.
It's O.K. You can sign.
Yeah?
Her name on top.
Yours on the bottom.
All right.
Oh, wonderful.
Government pens.
Look, I don't have
another pen.
I'll get one.
KATHY: Aah !
Don't--don't--
No, no. No.
Now listen.
You're O.K.
Now listen to me.
Can you get dressed?
You're O.K.
Please, hurry.
[ ring ]
Stella Boutique.
Ex-extension 1-8-9-1, please.
Pardon me?
Is--is this 662-3799?
Yes. Who's this?
There's no
extension 1891?
Are you kidding?
We're lucky if we have
phone service at all.
Sorry.
[ ring ]
Operator.
Operator, what's
the area code
for Washington ?
D.C.
That's 2-0-2.
Kathy.
6-3-1-1.
Cia? Langley?
Extension 1891.
[ ring ]
1891.
Let me speak
to Mr. Wicks.
Um, he's not here
just now.
May I ask who's
calling, please?
How do you feel?
You O.K..?
What did you do
to those people?
What people?
I don't know who they are.
I file a report. A guy
in Washington reads it.
He's supposed to--
he's my section chief.
He comes to New York
to shoot me.
Did you know him?
No.
Did you know
the mailman?
No,
but the guy
in Washington did.
You won't know
the next one.
I'm not waiting
for the next one.
Has he gone double
or dirty?
I don't know, sir.
You think he's still
in New York City?
I wouldn't be.
Question--is there
an intelligence network
undetected by CIA,
linking certain
Arabic-speaking
countries
with Dutch
and Spanish-speaking ?
We're already visible.
Let's not become conspicuous.
If company agents
aren't enough,
use freelance.
Use whatever it requires,
but end it.
O.K.
Let's get it
over with, O.K..?
Kathy.
Thanks.
[ horn honks ]
Applications here.
O.K.
See Mr. Addison.
Turn right. First door
on your left.
Mr. Marcus.
Mr. Addison?
No.
He's in clearance.
Passed it.
It's on your left.
Oh. Sorry.
Uh, thank you.
Yep.
I didn't get the job.
Looks good,
but, um,
I have this friend,
and he asked me to
give you a message.
Quote...
"Dear Mr. Higgins,
"This will introduce
a friend of mine,
"Sparrow Hawk.
"Please accompany her
"to the Nassau Street exit
of this place.
Now."
Personally, I'd do it,
because he has
this huge gun,
and he's looking
at us right now.
I'll save this for you.
Shall we?
To your left, please.
O.K., sit up.
Sit up!
All the way up.
Back up against the panel.
Take it easy.
I'm not armed.
They could be DF-ing us
if you have a transmitter
hidden in your clothes.
What's this?
DF, huh? You do
read everything.
Somebody or something
is rotten in the company.
You never complained
till yesterday.
You didn't start
killing my friends
till yesterday.
Who's she?
Who hit the lit society?
We had a big meeting
about that.
Your name came up.
Five Continents Imports.
Ring a bell?
Where'd you
get that?
The mailman.
Mailman?
The one you sent
with the uniform, pouch,
automatic gun.
We never use mailmen.
Are you familiar
with a tall gentleman,
6'4", blond hair,
strong like a farmer,
not American, accent,
country near Germany,
maybe Alsace-Lorraine?
[ telephone rings ]
[ ring ]
yes?
Was the letter delivered?
The return receipt
has not arrived.
You should have
delivered it yourself.
A more complicated package
had to be handled,
but I might have underestimated
this one.
I was told you never make
that kind of mistake.
What will you do?
Wait.
For what?
People who move
leave word of
change of address.
I want to see
that report.
Do you know him?
Professionally, yes.
Professionally,
he kills people.
Yes.
He works for
the company?
He did once.
He's a contract agent.
Contract agent.
Freelance.
Where did you see him?
Uh-uh.
It would help
if I knew.
Who would it help?
Who'd hire him now?
Anybody.
Terrific answer.
I wouldn't
accept it, either.
What's his name?
When I knew him,
Joubert .
Come on, Higgins .
Who'd hire him?
You don't look up Joubert
in the yellow pages.
That's right.
It'd have to be somebody
in the community.
Community?
Intelligence field.
Community!
Jesus, you guys are kind
to yourselves. Community.
I want to see
that report, Turner.
That report was sent
to headquarters
and disappeared.
Who read it?
You mean, besides wicks?
You tell me.
I pick up traces
of what I think's
an intelligence network
the company
doesn't know about,
and I report it.
Now, why is that going
to make anybody mad?
Unless it was
the company's network
and you didn't
want it blown,
even to your own guys.
Unless somebody
is lying, Higgins .
Come on.
Why is everybody so shy?
I'm not shy.
I don't know.
That's what worries me.
Ask Wicks.
Wicks died.
Someone yanked him off
the life support system
at Guvenor Hospital.
Get me in, Higgins .
What good would that do
if you're right,
and they are inside?
What good would it do
to bring you in?
What am I supposed
to do?
I'm sorry.
You're sorry?
You're sorry.
Oh, I get it.
I get it.
You expect me
to draw fire,
like one of those
penny arcade bears
that parades back and forth,
waiting for somebody,
somebody good,
to take another shot.
You'll pick him up
before he does it?
Or just after?
I'll try and find out
what's going on.
Nice talking to you,
Higgins .
Now wait a minute.
Have a nice day.
Where will I find you?
I'll find you.
Do you trust him?
Trust.
Does he trust you?
He's in
the suspicion business.
He can't trust anybody.
How could anybody
fool them?
Maybe nobody did.
Then.
Maybe there's
another CIA.
Inside the CIA.
Hey, Sal.
Hey, the lights
went off.
Come on over here.
The generator
went off.
It's a hotel room.
What hotel?
There's no tag.
It's room 819,
city of New York.
There's a code number
cut in the edge.
You in the trade?
I read about it
in a story.
Was the story
about locksmiths?
It's the lock
manufacturer's code.
He can give you
the hotel name.
I don't want
to read about you
in the paper.
Will you make the call?
[ ring ]
Yes?
I'm doing a survey.
Do you believe
the Condor's
really an endangered
species?
[ operator ]
Your room number, please.
819.
[ telephone rings ]
[ ring ]
MAN:
Hello?
Yes. I just had
an interesting call.
Who is this?
In reference to an
all-but-extinct bird--
the Condor.
Have you had
such a call?
You're a fool
to call me.
You had no such call?
No.
Must have been
the Audubon Society.
I assume they're still
located in New York.
[ ring ]
Langley computer.
State your program
at the tone.
[ beep ]
G.
Carriage return.
T-R-S.
Tone.
Symbol for number.
Computer is ready.
[ beeping ]
That number is
202-227-0098.
[ ring ]
CNA, Mrs. Coleman speaking.
This is Harold Thomas,
Mrs. Coleman.
Customer service,
requesting a CNA
on 202-227-0098.
One moment, please.
That would be
a Mr. Leonard Atwood .
365 MacKenzie place.
Chevy Chase, Maryland.
All right.
Cross-check this tape
against wicks
and hold any intersects.
Hat size.
Lucifer.
All right, run lucifer.
Coming up.
I'll be damned.
[ beeping ]
This is the major.
Condor.
Find me Higgins .
Routing you, Condor.
Stand by.
Hello, Condor.
The Holiday Inn,
57th Street.
Is that where
you are now?
Room 819.
You'll find the Alsatian
gentleman we spoke of.
Where are you,
Condor?
Where are you?
Shh.
Quiet down.
Hey, Higgins?
Yeah, I'm right here.
Who is Leonard Atwood?
Where are you, Higgins?
Ain't we pals anymore?
[ dial tone ]
Something?
Major?
Got him.
Let me see that.
What's he doing
in Brooklyn?
Condor.
We can get a unit--
wait.
What's going on, major?
Son of a bitch
wired together 50 phones.
What?
Everybody in Brooklyn's
talking to each other.
I didn't know
you smoked.
I quit
three years ago.
You're pale.
It's the light in here.
What are you
going to do there?
See a guy.
More secrets.
Like those pictures
you hide.
Yes.
Someday, I--
I'd like to show
them to you...
if you live through this.
You could drive me
to Washington .
No, I couldn't.
You've--
you've a lot of very
fine qualities...
but--
What fine qualities?
You have good eyes.
Not kind, but...
they don't lie,
and they don't
look away much,
miss anything.
I could use
eyes like that.
But you're overdue
in Vermont.
Is he a tough guy?
He's pretty tough.
What will he do?
U-understand, probably.
Boy,
that is tough.
Last call, train six.
Newark connects
to Penn Central
to Baltimore,
Washington, D.C .
All aboard.
Kathy,
I need time.
Hmm?
Eight hours or so,
that's all.
Till noon, to do
what I have to do.
Do you understand
what I'm saying?
Are you going
right to Vermont?
Yes.
What I mean is don't...
call anyone.
Don't stop, please.
Don't tell anyone about...
Of course.
Jesus.
I--I didn't...
All aboard!
Hey.
You take care
of yourself.
I'll do my best.
Do your best.
Why aren't you
further along,
Mr. Higgins?
You mean with
the company?
You seem perfect for it.
Are you perfect for it,
Mr. Higgins?
I've tried to be, sir.
You were recruited
out of school?
No, sir.
Company interviewed
a few of us
in Korea.
You served with
Colonel Donovan
in the O.S.S.,
didn't you, sir?
I sailed the Adriatic
with a movie star
at the helm.
It doesn't seem like
much of a war now,
but it was.
I go even further back
than that.
Ten years after
the great war,
as we used to call it,
before we knew enough
to number them.
Do you miss that kind
of action, sir?
No.
I miss that kind
of clarity.
[ intercom buzzes ]
Yes?
Thank you.
He's being held
at New York Center.
Mr. Higgins,
you do understand
the company's position?
There's nothing in the way
of your doing this, is there?
♪ And I want ya
♪ Right where
I've got you ♪
♪ And I 've got ya
♪ Right where
I need you, baby ♪
♪ And I need you
♪ Right where
I've got you ♪
♪ And I 've got you
♪ Right where
I want you, baby ♪
♪ And I want you
♪ Right where
I've got you ♪
♪ And I 've got you
♪ Right where
I need you, baby ♪
♪ And I need you
♪ Right where
I've got you ♪
♪ Yeah
♪ Ow!
♪ Make it funky...
What is this?
What's going on?
[ music stops ]
Who are you?
What are you
doing here?
I'm Condor.
Sit down.
What do you do
for a living?
Don't be ridiculous.
What do you do?
Exactly?
Deputy Director
of Operations.
What section?
Middle East.
What are you working on?
What are you doing?
What's the secret
worth murdering everybody
at the A.L.H.S. House?
There's no secret.
Wicks showed you
my report.
What report?
Yes.
It was your network
I turned up.
Doing what?
What does operations
care about a bunch
of goddamn books?
A book in Dutch.
A book out of Venezuela.
Mystery stories in Arabic .
Wait.
What the hell
is so important about--
Oil fields.
Oil.
That's it, isn't it?
This whole damn thing
was about oil.
Wasn't it? Wasn't it?
Yes, it was.
Don't turn for a moment.
Put your thumb in front
of the hammer.
Release it slowly.
Set down the gun
on the desk.
And don't move.
Back up.
You were quite good,
Condor, until this.
This move was predictable.
Hey!
What?
Did you touch anything
except the chair?
You're working for
the company again.
Yes.
I am.
Jesus. They took you back.
Just for this.
For Atwood.
How--wha--
He's with the company.
Why?
I don't interest myself
in why.
I think more often
in terms of when,
sometimes where,
always how much.
I suspect he was
about to become
an embarrassment.
As you are.
So you're not finished.
Pardon?
Oh, no. I have
no arrangement
with the company
concerning you.
They didn't know
you'd be here.
I knew you'd be here.
But didn't you send
the mailman?
That was a business
arrangement with Atwood,
but you see.
Come on.
Come.
Tell me about the girl.
What about the girl?
She was chosen...
How?
By--by age?
Her car?
Appearance?
At random.
Chance.
Really.
Can I drop you?
[ sigh ]
I'd like to go back
to New York.
You have not
much future there.
It will happen this way.
You may be walking.
Maybe the first sunny day
of the spring,
and a car will slow
beside you,
and the door will open,
and someone you know,
maybe even trust,
will get out of the car.
And he will smile,
a becoming smile.
But he will leave open
the door of the car
and offer to give you
a lift.
You seem to understand
it all so well.
What would you suggest?
Personally,
I prefer Europe.
Europe?
Yes.
Well, the fact is,
what I do is not
a bad occupation.
Someone is always
willing to pay.
I would find it...
tiring.
Oh, no. It's quite restful.
It's almost peaceful.
No need to believe
in either side or any side.
There is no cause.
There's only yourself.
The belief is in
your own precision.
I was born
in the united states, Joubert.
I miss it when
I'm away too long.
A pity.
I don't think so.
Is it any trouble
to drop me at
the union station?
Oh, no.
It would be
my pleasure.
For that day.
[ carolers ] ♪ Remember
Christ, our savior ♪
♪ Was born
on Christmas day ♪
♪ To save us all
from Satan's power ♪
♪ When we're
gone astray ♪
♪ Oh, tidings of
comfort and joy ♪
♪ Comfort and joy
♪ Oh, tidings of
comfort and joy ♪
Higgins !
Higgins!
♪ Oh, tidings of
comfort and joy ♪
♪ Comfort and joy
♪ Oh, tidings of
comfort and joy ♪
Why'd you call so late?
We were worried
about you.
Likewise. The car for me?
It's all right.
It's safe.
You'll have a few hours
of debriefing.
Hey, Higgins ? Yeah?
Let's say, for the purposes
of argument,
I had a .45
in one of my pockets
and I wanted you
to walk with me.
You'd do it, right?
Which way?
West.
And slowly.
Stay in front of me
about three or four steps.
Where we going?
Wave them on ahead.
Do we have plans to invade
the Middle East?
Are you crazy?
Am I ?
Look, Turner--
Do we have plans?
No. Absolutely not.
We have games.
That's all.
We play games--
What if?
How many men?
What would it take?
Is there a cheaper way
to destabilize a regime?
That's what we're
paid to do.
Walk on.
Go on.
So Atwood just
took the games
too seriously.
He was really going
to do it, wasn't he?
A renegade operation.
Atwood knew 5412 would
never authorize it,
not with the heat
on the company.
What if there hadn't
been any heat?
Suppose I hadn't stumbled
on their plan?
Different ballgame.
Fact is, there
was nothing wrong
with the plan.
The plan
was all right.
would've worked.
Boy, what is it
with you people?
You think not getting
caught in a lie
is the same thing
as telling the truth?
No. It's simple economics.
Today it's oil, right?
In 10 or 15 years--
food, plutonium,
and maybe even sooner.
What do you think
the people
are going to want us
to do then?
Ask them.
Now now. Then.
Ask them when
they're running out.
there's no heat
and they're cold.
Ask them when
their engines stop.
Ask them when people who
have never known hunger
start going hungry.
Want to know something?
They won't want us
to ask them.
They'll want us
to get it for them.
Boy,
have you found a home.
There were seven people
killed, Higgins .
The company
didn't order it.
Atwood did.
And who the hell
is Atwood ?
He's you.
He's all you guys.
Seven people killed,
and you play fucking games!
Right.
And the other side
does, too.
That's why
we can't let you
stay outside.
Well, go on home, Higgins .
Go on. They've got it.
What?
You know where we are.
Just look around.
They've got it.
That's where they ship from.
They've got all of it.
What? What did you do?
I told them a story.
You play games,
Oh, you--
you poor, dumb
son of a bitch.
You've done
more damage
than you know.
I hope so.
You're about to be
a very lonely man.
It didn't have
to end this way.
Of course it did.
Hey, Turner.
How do you know
they'll print it?
You can take a walk,
but how far if they
don't print it?
They'll print it.
How do you know?