[♪♪♪]
[MUTED DIALOGUE]
[PHONE RINGING]
[PEOPLE SCREAMING]
[SIRENS WAILING]
[♪♪♪]
[BOMB WHISTLING]
MAN: ♪ Captain Walker didn't come
home His unborn child will never know him ♪
♪ He's believed to be missing
With a number of men ♪
♪ Don't expect to see him again ♪
[CROWD CHEERING]
♪ It's a boy, Mrs. Walker ♪
♪ It's a boy ♪
NURSE & DOCTOR:
♪ A son ♪
♪ Hear the joyful celebrations
In the streets ♪
♪ It's a boy born
On this first day of peace ♪
♪ We've won ♪
♪ A son ♪
♪ We've won ♪♪
[AIRPLANES FLYING PAST]
[♪♪♪]
♪ I'm your friendly green coat ♪
♪ And I welcome you to
Bernie's Holiday Camp ♪
♪ One day and you'll be happy ♪
♪ It's Bernie you will thank ♪
♪ You must be little Tommy ♪
♪ Well, call me Uncle Frank ♪
[WHISTLING]
♪ Welcome you too, Mrs. Walker ♪
TOMMY: ♪ Did you know I had an Uncle Frank?
♪
♪ You'll always find a helping hand ♪
TOMMY: ♪ I've never met him ♪
♪ Lookie, Mom, a cage of budgies
Swimming pool and donkey rides ♪
♪ Oh, please ♪
♪ A camp with the extras ♪
♪ I'm in Chateau Number 11 ♪
♪ It's all free, Mom ♪
♪ When you come to Bernie's ♪
♪ You might think you're in heaven ♪
♪ Here we have the winner, folks ♪
♪ Have you ever seen
A lovelier pair? ♪
♪ What a shapely ankle ♪
♪ What a perfect shin ♪
♪ If you could feel this silken thigh ♪
♪ You'd know who has to win ♪
♪ You'd know ♪
♪ You don't know
How much I've missed ♪
♪ To feel a man again ♪
♪ To dance, to kiss ♪
♪ Your eyes reveal you're lonely ♪
♪ This evening must pass slowly ♪
♪ Until we're one ♪
♪ My heart won't rest ♪
♪ Will Tommy share
Our happiness? ♪
♪ Of course he will
I'll make him smile ♪
♪ You don't know ♪
♪ I'll take him out
To cinemas and fairs ♪
♪ How much I've missed ♪
♪ To feel a man again
To dance, to kiss ♪
♪ Football and cricket
Never been a happier lad ♪
♪ I'll be more than an uncle ♪
♪ I'll be just like a dad ♪
TOMMY:
♪ I will be a green coat too ♪
♪ And when I'm big
I'll own a holiday camp ♪
♪ A camp with a difference ♪
♪ Always be good weather ♪
♪ When you come to Tommy's ♪
♪ The holiday's forever ♪
♪ I'm glad you like
Your Uncle Frank ♪
♪ He'll surely love you too ♪
♪ Just like a dad ♪
♪ He's very nice, I think ♪
♪ Did he fight in the war? ♪
♪ When he's got his green coat on ♪
♪ I love him even more ♪
♪ I love him even more ♪♪
[♪♪♪]
♪ Got a feeling '51's
Going to be a good year ♪
♪ Especially if you and me
See it out together ♪
♪ So you think that '51
ls gonna be a good year ♪
♪ We'll marry now
And see it out together ♪
♪ I have no reason
To be overoptimistic ♪
♪ But somehow when you smile ♪
♪ I can brave bad weather ♪
[MUTED DIALOGUE]
♪ What about the boy? ♪
♪ What about the boy?
He saw it all ♪
♪ You didn't hear it
You didn't see it ♪
♪ You won't say nothin' to no one
Ever in your life ♪
♪ You never heard it ♪
♪ How absurd it all seems
Without any proof ♪
♪ You didn't hear it
You didn't see it ♪
♪ You won't say nothin' to no one
Ever in your life ♪
♪ You never heard it ♪
♪ How absurd it all seems
Without any proof ♪
♪ You didn't hear it
You didn't see it ♪
♪ You never heard it
Not a word of it ♪
♪ You won't say nothin' to no one ♪
♪ Never tell a soul
What you know is the truth ♪♪
[♪♪♪]
MAN:
♪ Now he is deaf ♪
♪ Now he is dumb ♪
♪ Now he is blind ♪
♪ The guilty are safe ♪
♪ But always accused
By his empty eyes ♪
♪ Nothing to say
Nothing to hear ♪
♪ And nothing to see ♪
♪ Each sensation makes a note
In his symphony ♪
♪ Sickness will surely take the mind ♪
♪ Where minds can't usually go ♪
♪ Come on the amazing journey ♪
♪ And learn all you should know ♪
♪ A vague haze of delirium
Creeps up on him ♪
♪ Soaring and flying images spin ♪
♪ He is your leader
He is your guide ♪
♪ On the amazing journey
Together you'll ride ♪
♪ Sickness will surely take the mind ♪
♪ Where minds can't usually go ♪
♪ Come on the amazing journey ♪
♪ And learn all you should know ♪
♪ His eyes are the eyes
That transmit all they know ♪
♪ The truth burns so bright
It can melt winter snow ♪
♪ A towering shadow
So black and so high ♪
♪ A white sun burning
The Earth and the sky ♪♪
[♪♪♪]
Tommy.
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
♪ Did you ever see the faces
Of the children? ♪
♪ They get so excited ♪
♪ Waking up on Christmas morning ♪
♪ Hours before
The winter's sun's ignited ♪
♪ They believe in dreams
And all they mean ♪
♪ Including heaven's generosity ♪
♪ Peeping 'round the door to see ♪
♪ What parcels are for free
In curiosity ♪
♪ And Tommy doesn't know
What day it is ♪
♪ He doesn't know who Jesus was
Or what praying is ♪
♪ How can he be saved ♪
♪ From the eternal grave? ♪
FRANK:
♪ Tommy, can you hear me? ♪
NORA:
♪ Tommy? ♪
♪ Tommy, can you hear me? ♪
♪ Can you--? Can you hear me? ♪
♪ How can he be saved? ♪
TOMMY:
♪ See me ♪
♪ Feel me ♪
♪ Touch me ♪
♪ Heal me ♪
♪ See me ♪
♪ Feel me ♪
♪ Touch me ♪
♪ Heal me ♪
♪ Tommy, can you hear me? ♪
CHORUS:
♪ How can he be saved? ♪
♪ Surrounded by his friends
He sits so silently ♪
♪ And unaware of anything ♪
♪ Crazy-eyed he picks his nose
He smiles, he cries ♪
♪ He pokes his tongue at everything ♪
♪ I believe in love ♪
♪ But how can men who've never
Seen light be enlightened? ♪
♪ Only if he's cured ♪
♪ Will his spirit's future level
Ever heighten ♪
♪ And Tommy doesn't know
What day it is ♪
♪ He doesn't know who Jesus was
Or what praying is ♪
♪ How can he be saved ♪
♪ From the eternal grave? ♪♪
[♪♪♪]
♪ You talk about your woman ♪
♪ I wish you could see mine ♪
♪ Every time she starts to love ♪
♪ She brings eyesight to the blind ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ You know,
Her daddy gave her magic ♪
♪ I can tell by the way she walks ♪
♪ You know,
Her daddy gave her magic ♪
♪ I can tell by the way she walks ♪
♪ Every time she starts to shake ♪
♪ The dumb begin to talk ♪
♪ Talk, talk, talk ♪
♪ She's got the power to heal you ♪
♪ Never fear ♪
♪ She has got the power to heal you ♪
♪ Just one word from her lips ♪
♪ And the deaf can hear ♪
♪ Hey ♪
♪ She's got the power to heal you ♪
♪ Never fear ♪
♪ One word from her lips
And the deaf can hear ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪♪
ACID QUEEN: ♪ If your child
Ain't all he should be now ♪
♪ This girl will put him right ♪
♪ I'll show him
What he could be now ♪
♪ Just give me one night ♪
♪ I'm the Gypsy
The Acid Queen ♪
♪ Pay me before I start ♪
♪ I'm the Gypsy
And I'm guaranteed ♪
♪ To mend his aching heart ♪
♪ Give us a room
Close the door ♪
♪ Leave us for a while ♪
♪ You won't be a boy no more ♪
♪ Young but not a child ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm the Gypsy ♪
♪ The Acid Queen ♪
♪ Pay me before I start ♪
♪ The Gypsy
I'm guaranteed ♪
♪ To tear your soul apart ♪
♪ Gather your wits
And hold on fast ♪
♪ Your mind must learn to roam ♪
♪ Just as the Gypsy Queen must do ♪
♪ You're gonna hit the road ♪
♪ My work's begun
Now look at him ♪
♪ He's never been more alive ♪
♪ His head it shakes
His fingers clutch ♪
♪ Watch his body writhe ♪
♪ I'm the Gypsy
The Acid Queen ♪
♪ Pay me before I start ♪
♪ I'm the Gypsy
I'm guaranteed ♪
♪ To break your little heart ♪
♪ If your child
Ain't all he should be now ♪
♪ This girl will put him right ♪
♪ I'll show him
What he could be now ♪
♪ Just give me one more night ♪
♪ I'm the Gypsy
The Acid Queen ♪
♪ Pay me before I start ♪
♪ I'm the Gypsy
I'm guaranteed ♪
♪ To tear his soul apart ♪♪
[CACKLING]
[♪♪♪]
♪ Do you think it's all right ♪
♪ To leave the boy
With Cousin Kevin? ♪
♪ Do you think it's all right? ♪
♪ There's something 'bout him
I don't really like ♪
♪ Do you think it's all right? ♪
♪ I think it's all right
Yes, I think it's all right ♪
♪ We're on our own, cousin ♪
♪ All alone, cousin ♪
♪ Let's think of a game to play ♪
♪ Now the grownups
Have all gone away ♪
♪ You won't be much fun
Being blind, deaf and dumb ♪
♪ But I've no one to play with today ♪
♪ Do you know how to play
Hide-and-seek? ♪
♪ To find me
It would take you a week ♪
♪ But tied to that chair
You won't go anywhere ♪
♪ There's a lot I can do to a freak ♪
♪ How would you feel ♪
♪ If I turned on the bath? ♪
♪ Ducked your head under ♪
♪ And started to laugh? ♪
♪ Maybe a cigarette burn ♪
♪ On your arm ♪
♪ Would change your expression ♪
♪ To one of alarm ♪
♪ I'm the school bully ♪
♪ The classroom cheat ♪
♪ The nastiest play friend ♪
♪ You ever could meet ♪
♪ I'll put glass in your dinner ♪
♪ And spikes in your seat ♪
♪ I'll drag you around ♪
♪ By a lock of your hair ♪
♪ And give you a push ♪
♪ At the top of the stairs ♪
♪ What would you do ♪
♪ If I shut you outside ♪
♪ To stand in the rain ♪
♪ And catch cold so you die ♪
♪ I'm the school bully ♪
♪ The classroom cheat ♪
♪ The nastiest play friend ♪
♪ You ever could meet ♪
♪ I'll stick pins in your fingers ♪
♪ And tread on your feet ♪
♪ We're on our own, cousin ♪
♪ All alone, cousin ♪
♪ We've thought of
Some nice games to play ♪
♪ While the grownups
Had all gone away ♪
♪ You weren't too much fun
'Cause you're blind, deaf and dumb ♪
♪ But I'd no one to play with today ♪
[♪♪♪]
♪ Do you think it's all right ♪
♪ To leave the boy with Uncle Ernie? ♪
♪ Do you think it's all right? ♪
♪ He's had a few too many tonight ♪
♪ Yes, I think it's all right
Yes, I think it's all right ♪
♪ I'm your wicked Uncle Ernie
I'm glad you won't see or hear me ♪
♪ As I fiddle about, fiddle about,
Fiddle about ♪
♪ Your mother left me here
To mind you ♪
♪ And I'm doing exactly
What I bleedin' well want to ♪
♪ Fiddling about, fiddling about,
Fiddle about ♪
♪ Down with your bedclothes ♪
♪ Up with your nightshirt ♪
♪ Fiddle about, fiddle about,
Fiddle about ♪
♪ You won't shite as I fiddle abite ♪
♪ Fiddle abite, fiddle abite
Fiddle abite ♪
[GRUNTING AND MUMBLING]
[THUDDING]
[ERNIE PANTING AND CACKLING]
[♪♪♪]
[ERNIE CONTINUES CACKLING]
♪ Do you think it's all right ♪
♪ Leaving Tommy by the mirror? ♪
♪ You would think he had sight ♪
♪ Been staring half the night ♪
♪ Do you think it's all right? ♪
♪ I think it's all right
Yes, I think it's all right ♪♪
[SIREN WAILING]
[PEOPLE CHEERING]
WOMAN: ♪ Extra, extra Pinball bonanza ♪
♪ Deaf, dumb and blind kid
Makes the big game ♪
♪ Saturday, the final
He faces the champ ♪
♪ Extra, extra ♪
♪ Pinball, big time
A million in hand ♪
♪ You can rule the world
From a yacht in the bay ♪
♪ Champagne flowing
You're a popular man ♪
♪ Pinball, let's play ♪
♪ Tommy keeps on winning
He's a millionaire ♪
♪ Mama's got a brand-new Cadillac ♪
♪ Hurry to the show
We're nearly on the air ♪
♪ Extra, extra ♪♪
♪ Ever since I was a young boy
I played the silver ball ♪
♪ From Soho down to Brighton
I must have played them all ♪
♪ But I ain't seen nothin' like him
In any amusement hall ♪
♪ That deaf, dumb and blind kid
Sure plays a mean pinball ♪
♪ He stands like a statue
Becomes part of the machine ♪
♪ Feelin' all the bumpers
Always playin' clean ♪
♪ He plays by intuition
The digit counters fall ♪
♪ That deaf, dumb and blind kid
Sure plays a mean pinball ♪
♪ He's a pinball wizard
There has to be a twist ♪
♪ A pinball wizard
Got such a supple wrist ♪
CROWD:
♪ How do you think he does it? ♪
♪ I don't know ♪
CROWD:
♪ What makes him so good? ♪
♪ Well, he ain't got no distractions
Can't hear no buzzers and bells ♪
♪ Don't see lights a-flashing
He plays by sense of smell ♪
♪ Always has a replay
Never tilts at all ♪
♪ That deaf, dumb and blind kid
Sure plays a mean pinball ♪
♪ He can't beat me now
I've always been the champ ♪
♪ I know every trick ♪
♪ No freak's gonna beat my hand ♪
♪ Even on my usual table
He can beat the best ♪
♪ His disciples lead him in
And he just does the rest ♪
♪ He's got crazy flipper fingers
I've never seen him fall ♪
♪ That deaf, dumb and blind kid
Sure plays a mean pinball ♪
♪ He's a pinball wizard
There has to be a twist ♪
♪ A pinball wizard
Got such a supple wrist ♪
♪ He's a pinball wizard
He scores a trillion more ♪
♪ A pinball wizard
The world's new pinball lord ♪
♪ He's scoring more ♪
♪ I thought I was
The Bally table king ♪
♪ But I just handed
My pinball crown to him ♪
♪ To him ♪
♪ To him ♪♪
[MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING
ON TV]
[♪♪♪]
CHORUS:
♪ Take one lady totally demanding ♪
♪ Join the banquet
At her commanding ♪
♪ Eat no fat and eat no lean ♪
♪ Eat Rex Beans
Fit for a queen ♪
♪ Eat no fat and eat no lean ♪
♪ Eat Rex Beans
Fit for a queen ♪
♪ Today it rains champagne ♪
♪ A son was born again ♪
♪ A genius untamed ♪
♪ A life of wealth and fame ♪
♪ Wealth and fame ♪
♪ Champagne flowing down
Just like rain ♪
♪ Caviar breakfasts every day ♪
♪ Merchant banks
And yachts at Cannes ♪
♪ Servants and cars
And private sand ♪
TOMMY:
♪ See me ♪
♪ Feel me ♪
♪ Touch me ♪
♪ Heal me ♪
♪ See me ♪
♪ Feel me ♪
♪ Touch me ♪
♪ Heal me ♪
♪ They flock in, thousands strong ♪
♪ We'll just play along ♪
♪ A million in reserve ♪
♪ For a love
A just deserve ♪
♪ Just deserve ♪
♪ Francs and dollars
And peacock's wings ♪
♪ Sequined gowns
And birds that sing ♪
♪ Private planes
And fishing lakes ♪
♪ Bigger crowds
And bigger, bigger, bigger takes ♪
♪ But what's it all worth? ♪
♪ What's it all worth
When my son is blind? ♪
♪ He can't hear the music
Nor enjoy what I'm buying ♪
♪ His life is worthless
Affecting mine ♪
♪ I'd pay any price ♪
♪ To drive his plight ♪
♪ From my mind ♪
TOMMY:
♪ See me ♪
♪ Feel me ♪
♪ Touch me ♪
♪ Heal me ♪
♪ See me ♪
♪ Feel me ♪
♪ Touch me ♪
♪ Heal me ♪♪
[♪♪♪]
♪ There's a man I've found
Could bring us all joy ♪
♪ There's a doctor I've found
Can cure the boy ♪
♪ A doctor I've found
♪ There's a man I've found
Could remove his sorrow ♪
♪ He lives in this town
Let's see him tomorrow ♪
♪ Let's see him tomorrow ♪♪
[♪♪♪]
♪ He seems to be
Completely unreceptive ♪
♪ The tests I gave him showed
No sense at all ♪
♪ His eyes react to light
The dial's detected ♪
♪ He hears but cannot answer
To your call ♪
TOMMY:
♪ See me ♪
♪ Feel me ♪
♪ Touch me ♪
♪ Heal me ♪
♪ See me ♪
♪ Feel me ♪
♪ Touch me ♪
♪ Heal me ♪
♪ There is no chance
No untried operation ♪
♪ All hope lies with him
And none with me ♪
♪ Imagine, though, the shock
From isolation ♪
♪ When he suddenly can hear
And speak and see ♪
TOMMY:
♪ See me ♪
♪ Feel me ♪
♪ Touch me ♪
♪ Heal me ♪
♪ See me ♪
♪ Feel me ♪
♪ Touch me ♪
♪ Heal me ♪
♪ His eyes can see
His ears can hear, his lips speak ♪
♪ All the time
The needles flick and rock ♪
♪ No machine can give
The kind of stimulation ♪
♪ Needed to remove his inner block ♪
♪ I often wonder
What it is he's feeling ♪
♪ Has he ever heard a word I've said ♪
♪ Look at him now
In the mirror, dreaming ♪
♪ What is happening in his head? ♪
FRANK:
[COUGHING]
♪ I wish I knew ♪
NORA: ♪ I wish I knew ♪
NORA: ♪ I wish I knew ♪♪
[♪♪♪]
♪ Tommy, can you see me? ♪
♪ Can I hope to cheer you? ♪
♪ Tommy, can you hear me? ♪
♪ Can you feel me near you? ♪
♪ Oh, Tommy? ♪
♪ Tommy? ♪
♪ Tommy, can you hear me? ♪
♪ Can you feel me near you? ♪
♪ Oh, Tommy, can you see me? ♪
♪ Can I help to cheer you? ♪
♪ Oh, Tommy ♪
♪ Tommy ♪
♪ Tommy? ♪
♪ Tommy ♪♪
[♪♪♪]
♪ You don't answer my call
With even a nod or a twitch ♪
♪ But you gaze at your own reflection ♪
♪ You don't seem to see me ♪
♪ But I think you can see yourself ♪
♪ How can the mirror affect you? ♪
♪ Can you hear me
Or do I surmise ♪
♪ That you fear me
Can you feel my temper rise ♪
♪ Rise, rise, rise ♪
♪ Do you hear or fear or ♪
♪ Do I smash the mirror? ♪
[♪♪♪]
♪ I'm free ♪
♪ And freedom ♪
♪ Tastes of reality ♪
♪ I'm free ♪
♪ Whoa, I'm free ♪
♪ And I'm waiting ♪
♪ For you to follow me ♪
♪ If I told you what it takes
To reach the highest high ♪
♪ You'd laugh and say
Nothing's that simple ♪
♪ But you've been told
Many times before ♪
♪ Messiah's pointed to the door ♪
♪ No one had the guts
To leave the temple ♪
♪ I'm free ♪
♪ And I'm waiting ♪
♪ For you to follow me ♪
♪ I'm free ♪
♪ And I'm waiting ♪
♪ For you to follow me ♪♪
[♪♪♪]
♪ Tommy, can you hear me? ♪
♪ Tommy? ♪
TOMMY:
♪ Mother ♪
♪ Father ♪
♪ Touch me ♪
♪ Feel me ♪
♪ Who am I?
Where did I come from? ♪
♪ Have you known me?
Have you seen me? ♪
♪ Mother ♪
♪ You're a hero
You are famous ♪
♪ You're a champion of the young ♪
♪ You are rich
But it's so absurd to try ♪
♪ To explain all the things
You've done ♪
♪ You're adored and you're loved ♪
♪ Thousands watch you play ♪
♪ Pinball
It's a fever ♪
♪ And you're the master of the game ♪
♪ And now that you're whole ♪
♪ You'll be champion
Of their very souls ♪
♪ Yes, I'm healed ♪
♪ Delivered from silent darkness ♪
♪ No more locked doors
Or stifled screams ♪
♪ Pinball
What I see now before me ♪
♪ Is far beyond a game ♪
♪ Beyond your wildest dreams ♪
♪ Those who love me ♪
♪ Have a higher path to follow now ♪
♪ And you, dear Mother too ♪
♪ Must be prepared ♪♪
[♪♪♪]
CHORUS:
♪ Extra, extra, read all about it ♪
♪ The pinball wizard
In a miracle cure ♪
♪ Extra, extra, read all about it ♪
♪ Extra, extra ♪
♪ Right now, right now
Story and pictures ♪
♪ Pinball bonanza
A mother's joy ♪
♪ World tours, show times
Lessons and lectures ♪
♪ Extra, extra ♪♪
[♪♪♪]
MAN: ♪ Outside the house
Mr. Simpson announced ♪
♪ That Sally couldn't go
To the meeting ♪
♪ He went on cleaning
His black Rolls-Royce ♪
♪ She ran inside weeping ♪
♪ She got to her room
And tears splashed the picture ♪
♪ Of the new Messiah ♪
♪ She picked up a book
Of her father's life ♪
♪ And threw it on the fire ♪
♪ She knew from the start
Deep down in her heart ♪
♪ She and Tommy were worlds apart ♪
♪ But her mother said never mind ♪
♪ Your part is to be
What you'll be ♪
♪ The theme of the sermon was
Come unto me ♪
♪ Love will find a way ♪
♪ So Sally decided to ignore her dad ♪
♪ And sneak out anyway ♪
♪ She spent all afternoon
Getting ready ♪
♪ Decided she'd try to touch him ♪
♪ Maybe he'd see that she was free ♪
♪ And talk to her this Sunday ♪
♪ She knew from the start
Deep down in her heart ♪
♪ She and Tommy were worlds apart ♪
♪ But her mother said never mind ♪
♪ Your part is to be
What you'll be ♪
♪ She arrived at 6
And the place was swinging ♪
♪ To gospel music by 9 ♪
♪ Group after group appeared
On the stage ♪
♪ But Sally just sat there sighing ♪
♪ She bit her nails
Looking pretty as a picture ♪
♪ Right in the very front row ♪
♪ And then one of the faithful
Came on-stage ♪
♪ And shouted: ♪
♪ Here we go ♪
♪ The crowd went crazy ♪
♪ As Tommy hit the stage ♪
♪ Little Sally got lost
As the police bossed ♪
♪ The crowd back in a rage ♪
♪ Your happy welcome is like a favor ♪
♪ I must now return ♪
♪ The darkness of
My childhood passed ♪
♪ And flames of love now burn ♪
♪ The pinball game I play so well ♪
♪ Reflects a way of life ♪
♪ This meeting is just another game ♪
♪ Let's play to win tonight ♪
♪ She knew from the start
Deep down in her heart ♪
♪ She and Tommy were worlds apart ♪
♪ But her mother said never mind ♪
♪ Your part is to be
What you'll be ♪
♪ Her cheek hit a chair
And blood trickled down ♪
♪ Mingling with her tears ♪
♪ Try to walk the path I walk
Never mind the pain and fear ♪
♪ Each one of you has freedom ♪
♪ In your heart without my grace ♪
♪ Let me see you raise your hands ♪
♪ See joy upon your face ♪
♪ The crowd went crazy ♪
♪ As Tommy left the stage ♪
♪ Little Sally was lost
For the price of a touch ♪
♪ A gash across her face ♪
♪ Her pretty face ♪
♪ Sixteen stitches put her right
And her dad said ♪
♪ Don't say I didn't warn ya ♪
♪ Sally got married
To a rock musician ♪
♪ Who came from California ♪
♪ Tommy always talks about the day ♪
♪ The disciples all went wild ♪
♪ Sally still carries the scar
On her cheek ♪
♪ To remind her of his smile ♪
♪ She knew from the start
Deep down in her heart ♪
♪ She and Tommy were worlds apart ♪
♪ But her mother said never mind ♪
♪ Your part is to be
What you'll be ♪♪
[♪♪♪]
CHORUS: ♪ While Tommy
flies The world is turning ♪
♪ Life goes on for you and me ♪
♪ Our chief concern
ls money-earning ♪
♪ Why can't someone set us free? ♪
♪ Can't you feel him? ♪
TOMMY:
♪ You'll feel me coming ♪
♪ A new vibration ♪
♪ From afar you'll see me ♪
♪ I'm a sensation ♪
♪ I overwhelm as I approach you ♪
♪ Make your lungs
Hold breath inside ♪
♪ Grounded angels
Your wings are broken ♪
♪ Time to mend and learn to fly ♪
♪ They worship me and all I touch ♪
♪ Hazy-eyed
They catch my glance ♪
♪ Pleasant shudders
Shake their senses ♪
♪ My warm momentum
Throws their stance ♪
♪ You'll feel me coming ♪
♪ A new vibration ♪
♪ From afar you'll see me ♪
♪ I'm a sensation ♪
♪ Soon you'll see me
Can't you feel me, I'm coming ♪
♪ Send your troubles dancing
I know the answer ♪
♪ I'm coming ♪
♪ I'm a sensation ♪
♪ You'll feel me coming ♪
♪ A new vibration ♪
♪ From afar you'll see me ♪
♪ I'm a sensation ♪
♪ I leave a trail of rooted people ♪
♪ Mesmerized by just the sight ♪
♪ The few I touched
Now are disciples ♪
♪ Love as one
I am the light ♪
♪ I am the light ♪
♪ Come to my house ♪
♪ Be one of the comfortable people ♪
♪ Come to this house ♪
♪ We're drinking all night
Never sleeping ♪
♪ Milkman coming ♪
♪ And you, baker ♪
♪ Little old lady, welcome ♪
♪ And you, shoemaker ♪
♪ Come to this house ♪
♪ Into this house ♪
♪ Be one of us ♪
♪ Make this your house ♪
♪ You can help
To collect some more in ♪
♪ Young and old people
Let's get them all in ♪
♪ Come to this house ♪
♪ Into this house ♪
♪ Ask along that man
With the big, red carnation ♪
♪ Bring every single person
From Victoria Station ♪
♪ Go into a hospital
And bring the nurses and patients ♪
♪ Everyone go home
And fetch their relations ♪
CHORUS:
♪ Come to this house ♪
♪ Be one of the comfortable people ♪
♪ Lovely, bright home ♪
♪ We're drinking all night
Never sleeping ♪
Hold on, Tommy.
There's more at the door.
They'll come through the floor.
♪ There's more at the door ♪
♪ There's more at the door
There's more ♪
♪ We need more room ♪
♪ Build an extension ♪
♪ A colorful palace ♪
♪ Spare no expense, now ♪
♪ Come to me now ♪
♪ Come to me now ♪♪
Welcome.
[♪♪♪]
♪ He'll raise
Your weary spirits high ♪
♪ My son will teach
Your silent hearts ♪
♪ To talk ♪
♪ Every home will have his picture ♪
♪ Pilgrims all will touch his hand ♪
♪ Pinball tables
Gold and silver ♪
♪ Altars to the master's plan ♪
♪ Rio, Paris ♪
♪ New York, London ♪
♪ Moscow, Peking, Tokyo ♪
♪ The world! ♪
♪ A Tommy camp in every city ♪
♪ Millions flocking in like sheep ♪
♪ What they want ain't cheap
It's a pity ♪
♪ But who am I
To upset their dreams? ♪
[ORGAN MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS]
ERNIE:
Good morning, converts.
I'm your brother Ernie
and I welcome you
to Tommy's Holiday Camp.
The camp with the difference.
Never mind the weather.
When you come to Tommy's,
the holiday's forever.
Welcome.
Get your Tommy T-shirts
and your stickers
and your Tommy mirrors
to smash!
Don't rush. Keep steady.
Have your money ready.
Buy your way to heaven.
That comes to one pound, seven.
Bless your heart.
Buy his shades and earplugs here.
Keep in line.
I've got a huge supply.
Get your Tommy records.
You can really hear him talk.
Tommy pics and badges,
half a nicker for the cork.
Keep in line, playmates!
You lucky people!
The camp with the difference,
so never mind the weather.
When you come to Tommy's,
the holiday's forever.
CHORUS:
♪ These pricey deals don't teach us ♪
♪ Your freedom doesn't reach us ♪
♪ Enlightenment escapes us ♪
♪ Awareness doesn't shape us ♪
♪ How can all this trivia ♪
♪ Take us to the goal you reached? ♪
♪ We came here to be like you ♪
♪ And find the world you've reached ♪
♪ These pricey deals don't teach us ♪
♪ Your freedom doesn't reach us ♪
♪ Enlightenment escapes us ♪
♪ Awareness doesn't shape us ♪
♪ How can all this trivia ♪
♪ Take us to the goal you reached? ♪
♪ We came here to be like you ♪
♪ And find the world you've reached ♪
♪ Welcome to the camp ♪
♪ I guess you all know
Why we're here ♪
♪ My name is Tommy ♪
♪ And I became aware this year ♪
♪ If you want to follow me ♪
♪ You've got to play pinball ♪
♪ And put in your earplugs
Put on your eyeshades ♪
♪ You know where to put the cork ♪
♪ Hey, you, gettin' drunk ♪
♪ So sorry ♪
♪ I got you sussed ♪
♪ Hey, you, smokin' mother nature ♪
♪ You missed the bus ♪
♪ Hey, old hung-up Mr. Normal ♪
♪ Don't try to gain my trust ♪
♪ 'Cause you ain't gonna follow me
Any of those ways ♪
♪ Although you think you must ♪
♪ Now you can't hear me ♪
♪ Your ears are truly sealed ♪
♪ You can't speak either ♪
♪ 'Cause your mouth is filled ♪
♪ You can't see nothin' ♪
♪ And pinball completes the scene ♪
♪ Here come willing helpers
To guide you to ♪
♪ Your very own machine ♪
♪ We're not gonna take it ♪
♪ Never did and never will ♪
♪ We don't have to take it ♪
♪ Gonna break it
Gonna shake it ♪
♪ Let's forget it better still ♪
♪ We're not gonna take it ♪
♪ Never did and never will ♪
♪ Don't want no religion ♪
♪ And as far as we can tell ♪
♪ We ain't gonna take you ♪
[SIREN WAILING]
♪ Never did and never will ♪
♪ We're not gonna take you ♪
♪ We forsake you ♪
♪ Gonna break you ♪
♪ Let's forget you ♪
♪ Better still ♪♪
♪ See me ♪
♪ Feel me ♪
♪ Touch me ♪
♪ Hear me ♪
♪ See me ♪
♪ Feel me ♪
♪ Hear me ♪
♪ See me ♪
♪ Feel me ♪
♪ Touch me ♪
♪ Hear me ♪
♪ See me ♪
♪ Feel me ♪
♪ Touch me ♪
♪ Hear me ♪
CHORUS: ♪ Listening
to you I get the music ♪
♪ Gazing at you
I get the heat ♪
♪ Following you
I climb the mountain ♪
♪ I get excitement at your feet ♪
♪ Right behind you
I see the millions ♪
♪ On you
I see the glory ♪
♪ From you
I get opinions ♪
I get the story ♪
♪ Listening to you
I get the music ♪
♪ Gazing at you
I get the heat ♪
♪ Following you
I climb the mountain ♪
♪ I get excitement
At your feet ♪
TOMMY & CHORUS:
♪ Oh, right behind you ♪
♪ I see the millions ♪
♪ On you, I see the glory ♪
♪ From you, I get opinions ♪
♪ From you, I get the story ♪
♪ Listening to you ♪
♪ I get the music ♪
♪ Gazing at you ♪
♪ I get the heat ♪
♪ Following you ♪
♪ I climb the mountain ♪
♪ I get excitement at your feet ♪
♪ Right behind you
I see the millions ♪
♪ On you, I see the glory ♪
♪ From you, I get opinions ♪
♪ From you, I get the story ♪
♪ Oh, listening to you ♪
♪ I get the music ♪
♪ Gazing at you ♪
♪ I get the heat ♪
♪ Following you ♪
♪ I climb the mountain ♪
♪ I get excitement at your feet ♪
♪ Right behind you
I see the millions ♪
♪ On you, I see the glory ♪
♪ From you, I get opinions ♪
♪ From you, I get the story ♪
♪ Listening to you ♪♪
[THE WHO'S "LISTENING TO YOU" PLAYING]