- Yeah!
- Baby.
- You ain't caught nothin'.
- You'll have to move out of the way.
We don't want no cheap seaters
around the table.
If Kenny's moving, you've got to move.
All right.
Would you go if you had the chance again?
- Would I go? Yeah!
- I'd go to Sweden.
No, not to Canada.
- Would you go back to 'nam again?
- Yeah.
You would?
- You're a fuckin' psycho.
- No.
- You'd go back? You'd go back?
- Yeah.
- I went over there for a purpose, man.
- What was your purpose?
A lot of it was curiosity,
but another thing is...
Now you can't be curious, man.
I mean, you were there.
I said that was part of the reason.
Only part of it, man.
The other was a moral obligation.
Man, I feel that anybody...
Not for the country or anything like that,
for anybody.
Nobody's got the right
to tell anybody what to do...
Against their will if
they don't believe it.
That's what I went over there to fight for.
Do you know that they ran the French out
after 20 years?
Wait a minute, man!
You said that they're forced...
Shit, you call the draft not being forced?
I ain't saying the draft, our country.
I'm talking about another country...
That's having something
forced upon them.
It's our obligation
to go fight for somebody else?
I feel if you believe in it.
If you believe in it.
I can't see anybody saying
that after going and coming back...
To say that they would go again.
I just can't deal with that.
The reason I can see it is that some of us,
not all of us...
Some of us need to justify to ourselves
what the fuck we did there.
So if we come back to say
what we did was a waste...
What happened to us was a waste,
we can't live with it.
- So they'd do it again.
- So they say...
Inside themselves,
they're lying to themselves continuously...
Saying, "what I did was okay,
because this is what I got from it, man.
"I have to justify being paralyzed.
I have to justify killing people.
"So I say it was okay."
But how many guys can make the reality,
and say, "what I did was wrong...
"...and all this other shit was wrong," and
still be able to live with themselves...
Because they're crippled
for the rest of their fuckin' life?
Re-box all weapons.
Place your weapons on the firing line
with the dust covers up.
Grease up the brass.
Word is it's turned into
a hell of a war over there, captain.
We're going there, pal.
We're in 'nam, combat city.
I am ready, really ready.
I'll pop some rounds with you, captain.
Marine!
How's vi taking to your leaving?
Sometimes I think she hates
everything military...
But she stands behind me.
She knows I want it
more than anything else.
- How about Sally?
- She's okay.
I don't think she really understands
it all, but she accepts it.
You can't ask for a hell of a lot more
than that, now, can you?
American spokesman
reported a barrage of rockets...
Artillery, and mortar fire hitting...
Remember Jim hanson?
He got blown away in the middle
of the street, right in Saigon.
That's an embarrassment, you know that?
Makes us look like the goddamn "b" team.
Word is from on top
that Charlie shot his wad...
With this tet offensive,
and it's just a matter of a mop-up time.
I'll tell you, Earl, I've waited a long
time for an opportunity like this.
- You're going to make major.
- Yeah?
- Major?
- Major.
Major and Mrs. Robert Hyde?
I'll have to get my skirts lengthened
for that one.
Start wearing girdles.
- You'll have to watch your language.
- Right. Very reserved.
I'll tell you something.
I'm actually excited!
And I never thought it would get like this.
I have competitive nervousness.
I feel like I'm off to the olympic games,
representing the us.
Bob is very sexy.
In 13 months, I'm gonna throw you
the damnedest party you ever saw.
A side of beef, a case of Jack Daniels...
And maybe even
a couple of congressmen.
- How do you like that?
- Fantastic.
In the meantime,
I'll bring you back a souvenir.
- Like what?
- A commie ak-47.
Robert? I'm sorry,
I didn't mean to interrupt.
I wanted to pass along
the colonel's best wishes.
- Isn't he gonna be able to come by later?
- No. Tonight's his chess night.
Now, Sally, you be sure and keep in touch.
Let us know where you are.
I will, Mrs. vickery.
- She'll be staying with my mom.
- How nice.
Earl, your Kathy's doing
a wonderful job on the paper.
Don't let that go to your head, young lady.
I've got a lot of ideas
I want to call you about.
Call me tomorrow.
- May God be with you, Robert.
- Thank you, Mrs. vickery.
That was very nice.
Now hear this.
It is exactly zero hour minus six.
Your orders for the day are...
Go directly to the bedroom.
Do not pass go.
Do not...
Collect dinner.
Aren't you hungry?
Does a bear make big potty in the woods?
"From the halls of montezuma
"to the shores of tripoli
"I will fight
"my country's battles
"on land
"and in the air"
Bob?
What are you doing?
This darn thing wouldn't pop up.
You never know
when you're going to want some toast.
I got to start getting ready.
You don't need to be afraid for me,
you know.
I am afraid.
But I'm proud of you.
There's nothing I could do
here in California.
I know.
And that's where I belong.
I am a marine.
Left, right, and a left.
I got to go.
Pay the bar bill.
Once and for all, let's get the
generator in this thing fixed.
You can call my mom
and let her know when you're coming.
I bought you a present, sweetheart.
I don't have anything for you.
Sally!
It's a little wedding ring.
Look how outstanding that is.
- I like it.
- Yeah.
- You'll take it off when you go on liberty.
- No way!
I'll never take this off. That's a promise.
This will be my good luck charm.
That's right.
Sir, we're ready to move out.
Can I stow your gear?
- We're war.
- Yo.
Let's go.
When I get back...
We'll get a little condominium
right on the beach.
Tell brother Billy to take care.
And a garage filled up with a Porsche.
Be a good girl. No foolin' around.
Just come back.
You got it.
This is dink. My wife Sally.
Hi, Mrs. Hyde. Vi, capt. Hyde's wife.
- Hi, vi.
- Hi.
Be careful.
- You've got a spot on your tie.
- What are you talking about?
Don't wear your skirts so short.
See you around.
- Vi?
- Yeah?
Do you want a drink? I mean,
could I buy you a drink or something?
Where's open? No place is open.
There's the officers club.
Anyplace but there.
Yeah, I guess.
That's that.
I live just a couple of Miles down.
Want to come over?
- Yeah.
- Stay close.
Park in there. It's empty.
Okay.
Don't mind the mess.
Come on up.
Don't turn it off.
Okay?
Yeah, I'm sorry.
Just tonight, especially,
I sort of felt superstitious.
Whatever gets you through the night.
- Guess it was the way I was brought up.
- Me, too.
- Is a beer okay? That's all I got.
- Sure.
You going to stay on in officers quarters?
Are you kidding?
- I couldn't, even if I wanted to.
- That's spooky.
Bob moves off,
and I gotta move off the base.
You're the hole in the doughnut, and when
the doughnut goes, there's no hole.
They say, "if the marine corps
wanted you to have a wife...
"...they'd have issued you one."
Is that you?
Me and my kid brother.
He's cute.
He inherited the brains, the beauty,
the personality, the talent.
Then he got drafted.
He's the main reason I hang out here.
Not dink? Dink the kink?
He's part of it.
But the kid's in the va hospital,
psycho ward.
They sent him home without an ignition,
so I'm stuck with him.
God.
- Must be really hard on you.
- I see him every day.
I work in the hospital, in the kitchen.
Is he going to get better?
Who knows? They don't.
I don't.
- Pee wee.
- How you doing, Mr. Martin?
I'm just fine, pee wee. Just terrific.
I only stink a little bit.
- Smells like booze to me.
- I need a bath, man.
I just have two hands,
and too many assholes to clean.
That's what you're being
paid for, isn't it?
Mr. Martin, you get more from Uncle
for your disability...
Than me and my old lady get
put together.
Maybe they shouldn't
put you together then.
Guy, your radiator's blowing over.
- Yeah? So's yours.
- Guy, I'm serious, man.
You better watch it
before you pop your melon.
Shit. I'm filled up.
Where's corrine?
You'd better watch that booze.
Mess up your kidneys.
Look, watch where you're... goddamn it!
Shit.
My God!
Would you please give me my canes?
I'm sorry.
Goddamn it!
Nurses, interns and orderlies!
Fucking nurses and fucking doctors!
You treat us like nobodies
in this fucking hospital!
Goddamn it, where are you people?
- Give them hell, Luke.
- Corrine, you're fucking late!
There's something on the floor for you.
You stay where you are, digroot.
You come near me,
I'll break your fucking head.
You understand?
Where the fuck were you?
You're so goddamn slow. Can't you move?
Come near me. I want to hit ya!
I want to hit something
that can't even fucking move!
What am I saying?
What am I doing?
- Having a little problem today, Luke?
- Shit!
Doctor, for Christ's sake,
I can't get my piss bag changed.
You want me out of this fucking hospital?
Give him 50 of thorazine.
Put him in a room.
Take care of me!
I'll get the fuck out of here.
Just take care of me!
Fucking hospital!
Shit!
- Are you fleta Wilson?
- Yes.
I think I'd like to volunteer.
I mean, I don't think.
I do want to volunteer.
Damn! Sit down, please.
I'll be with you in a moment.
Hot stuff.
Do you have him, Jerry?
- Are you ready?
- Okay. One, two, three.
Yeah, I know what you mean,
but you'll get used to it.
One guy had "born to lose"
tattooed on his arm.
"LA vida loca. " The crazy life.
That's my favorite one.
I talked to a guy
who had a gold earring in his ear.
Yeah?
Not used to those hippie types?
Bob would flip out
if he ever saw those characters.
That about does it.
I feel like I've lived in base houses
all my life.
Should have had the government move us.
They do that for officers.
- Yeah?
- Yep.
I didn't realize that we'd accumulated
so much stuff.
Don't worry. My rates are cheap.
You know, I think I must have moved
at least 15 times since I left home.
I went back once when my old lady died.
Nothing's left, man.
They tore down my past
and built a shopping center.
- Want to see something funny?
- I'd love to.
My yearbook.
Look at that dress.
- It was a nice dress.
- It's cute.
There's another one here.
It's so funny looking at the way
we used to look.
Doggie in the window?
Look.
"Sally bender. Nickname: Sal.
"What is the one thing she'd want
on a desert island?
"A husband."
- I was so ambitious.
- And so original.
Know that guy we were just talking about?
- He's in here somewhere.
- Yeah?
Look. "Luke Martin.
- "Nickname: The Duke."
- He's cute.
"Co-captain of the football team.
"What one thing would he want
on a desert island?
"A mirror."
- This is asinine, pee wee.
- Here. Take some.
Don't you get the feeling
that this is kind of silly shit?
Shit. I'm not saying, man,
this isn't entertaining, pee wee.
I'm not eating, pee wee.
I'm not eating, pee wee. Come on, man.
- Give me my arms. I can feed myself.
- Try a little milk.
- This is bullshit. I'm not a child, man.
- Hello.
Juice and coffee!
Want some juice?
Excuse me,
do you want some juice or coffee?
Look at that brown-eyed chick, gang.
Come on, baby, light my fire.
Want to boom-boom?
- Short term?
- Like some juice?
I'm hard all over, sweet ass.
I'm a bargain in this ward.
Man, be cool. I told you.
We're playing cards. Get yourself together.
Want some juice?
Tits. Ass. You got it all, mama-San.
- Lay off, man.
- You have got it all.
- You shut up.
- Yes, sir, right away, sir.
You hear that, dummy?
You're disturbing these gentlemen.
- God!
- Can I kiss you? Can I sniff?
Luke?
Can I come in?
How you doing?
Do you remember me?
No.
I was at Lincoln high when you were there.
Sally Hyde.
I was Sally bender when I was there.
So?
- I just started volunteering today here.
- Terrific.
If I could get my hands loose,
I'd salute you.
You're a mess.
- Sally bender.
- Right.
- You were a cheerleader.
- That's right. Three years.
Were you wounded in 'nam?
Right.
When did it happen?
A long time ago.
- My husband just went over there.
- Poor bastard!
Sally?
Didn't we used to call you "bend 'er over"?
What? Who said that?
- "Bend 'er over." Everybody said it.
- They did not.
- Yes, they did, Sally.
- Come on! They did not.
What are you talking about?
Shit.
Sally, listen, can I ask
you for a big favor?
Sure.
Sure. How about...
How about unhitching me
from these things?
- No, I can't do that, Luke.
- Sure you can, Sally. It's easy.
No, I'm sorry. The doctor has to do that.
Come on. Please?
Please, Sally bender?
- Come on, just a little.
- What are you doing in here?
- I just was seeing if...
- We'll tend to Mr. Martin, Sally.
- You're needed on the ward.
- Okay.
Bender.
You almost got yourself a gold star.
Pee wee, I can crawl again.
'Morning.
I'm going to be feeding you this morning.
I'm a new volunteer here.
He ain't transistorized, honey.
You got to plug him in for sound.
Plug you in?
Is this going to hurt?
There. Is that okay?
- Thank you.
- Okay. Feel like some food?
Okay. There you go.
- God, I'm sorry.
- That's okay.
You want me to... here.
Here. There you go.
It's all energy. You understand?
- You don't understand, do you?
- Sure.
You give out energy, you get it back.
See me smiling?
Take a look at that smile.
You dig them pearly whites?
Now, I smile my ass off now.
Hell, I mean, sometimes
I think I'm the good humor man.
Everyone wants a piece of my action now.
They think I'm one of the beach boys.
- Sally, this is my brother bill.
- Hi, bill.
You see that?
Me and her just had a whole conversation
in smile contact.
- Vi, do you have a jumper cable?
- Sure. Bridges?
Watch. You watching?
You two just did it. You smiled at her,
"see what I put up with?"
She smiled back at you, "he's harmless."
- Are you on uppers?
- I don't know.
Come on, bill. How 'bout a game of chess?
My brother, a miracle of modern medicine.
Wait.
My God, what a day.
Is he usually like that?
Try it!
Is it charging?
No!
I like this one.
It's just beautiful. It's a convertible.
I don't know how you keep warm.
It's got a great sound system.
Blaupunkt.
- Why is this one so much less expensive?
- That's two years older.
"I'm so tired when I come home at night,
I just fall right asleep.
"I know you didn't want me to get a job."
Thanks.
"But this isn't really a job,
since I don't get paid or anything.
"I hope you don't mind."
And then there's sort of a sexy ending.
"Love, Sally."
That's nice.
But you didn't tell him
the house you rented was on the beach.
I know.
And you didn't tell him
about the new car you bought.
I figure I'm going to save that
for when he gets home.
I got one from dink this morning.
Yeah?
All he said was, "got you another ear."
Poetic, huh?
A captain? Shit, bender.
You didn't go out and marry
a fucking captain, did ya?
That's right. Why? What were you?
A sergeant.
So? Sergeants have a lot
of responsibility, don't they?
Yes. They sent me my stripes
on the hospital ship.
My reward for getting so fucked up!
Why are you so cynical about that, Luke?
What are you doing here?
Why aren't you on the golf course
teeing up balls?
Doing something you're good at?
I'm just trying to keep busy.
It gives you something
to talk about over Martinis...
How you're helping
out the poor cripples.
I don't think that I deserve that, Luke,
at all!
Maybe you're just getting ready for your
husband to come back in a body bag.
Read someplace else, man.
Luke?
Stop and listen to me!
What is the matter with you?
Why do you have to be such a bastard?
Kevin.
I thought you died Wednesday, man.
You can get paralyzed in a war
that doesn't even make sense...
And come back,
and they don't have the decent courtesy...
To ask you how you're doing.
You know, "can I do anything for you?"
I got a purple heart
from a goddamn second lieutenant...
That wasn't even in the damn war.
They don't tell you
how to manage your finances.
about going back into society.
Half the people today still can't.
What about your sex life?
They don't tell you anything about that.
I went out the first time
and didn't know what to do.
What happens if my gizmo busts?
What happens if I have a bowel movement?
What happens if I get there
and don't know how to react?
There's not enough beds,
there's not enough staff.
It's really crowded.
Guys have to wait in line.
They're not prepared for the number
of wounded guys that are being sent back.
I don't think we're really clear
on what you're asking us for, Sally.
It's what I said.
We could do an article in the paper...
Maybe using these photographs...
Interviewing some of the guys maybe.
Isn't it difficult for the men
to be around young women?
When I joined weight watchers,
I didn't want any candy around.
I don't think that that's our function.
It seems we're more a base gossip sheet.
- You know, fun and games for the fellas.
- I agree with you, Connie.
I'm sorry, Sally. I hope you understand.
What's next on the agenda?
We have the little league playoffs
and the officer-son baseball game.
That's the 25th and the 27th, isn't it?
I want to say that I'm really shocked.
I'm shocked that you'd rather
write about a goddamn home run...
Than about what's going on
in this hospital.
I mean, you wouldn't feel that
way if they were your husbands.
Well, that sure is a mind-blower.
That's the way it was done 150 years ago.
- Things have improved.
- They certainly have.
Now, picture this.
Picture yourself as a young man,
150 years ago...
Cuddling with one of the most beautiful
girls in the country.
There's a girl. You're crazy about her.
What's shaking, man?
One of them days, man.
I was flashing back
to when I got fucked up.
Get out of the way!
I hurt myself.
Senator Kennedy, would you comment
on the death of Dr. king?
I think he dedicated himself...
To justice and love
between his fellow human beings.
He gave his life for that principle...
And I think it's up to those of us
who are here...
It was a choice between
dealing with that or with...
This football game last week.
They just said, "it's not our function."
I mean, I don't know. Maybe I'm naive.
Naive? She wants to know if she's naive.
Man. Now, that's cold.
I'm a cold man.
You've done your duty
and served your purpose...
And so they just toss you into the heap
like used kleenex.
Yeah, that's the way it is. That's just it.
What is our function,
if it isn't to deal...
With the problems
that you guys face every day?
- God, the smugness! I can't believe it.
- Give 'em hell.
I'm sorry.
It's not gonna do any good,
but I'm rooting for you, bender.
Thanks a lot, Luke.
Seriously,
if they'd put something in the paper...
Bender, you're beautiful
when you're excited.
God only knows what he saw over there...
Or did.
I don't understand it.
He was only in 'nam for two weeks.
You know, I worry a lot about dink, too.
He's so funny, you know?
So uncomplicated.
He's more than just a roll in the sack.
I just hope he doesn't get totaled.
I got it.
Bender.
- You got a chair.
- You changed your hair!
You like it?
Yeah. It's very nice.
- You're mobile.
- I'll help you. Go ahead.
- Thanks, Luke.
- Hi, Rick.
- Luke, how you doing?
- Okay.
Congratulations.
Would you like to come over for dinner?
Wouldn't you like
to get out of here one night?
I'm a good cook.
Okay?
Beat 'em, bash 'em, that's our custom!
Come on, team, readjust them!
I hit him after the whistle, man!
What are you talking about?
I hit him after the whistle was blown!
He grabbed my chair!
Did you grab my chair?
I didn't grab his chair, man.
Can't you morons kick a field goal?
Field goal. Come on! Field goal, morons.
B-u-s-t! Bust 'em!
Beat 'em, bash 'em, that's our custom!
Come on, team, readjust 'em!
"Around about July 1,
my pa's mind would start wandering.
"He wouldn't give a damn about the cattle,
and that got us kids pretty excited.
"At the park, they'd have flags flyin'
and games of chance...
"...kissing booths and wrestling matches.
"But let me tell you,
that day was always too long for me.
"When it got dark, the band would play
the star-spangled banner...
"...and the fireworks would start.
"And I'd start thinking
about how brave those men were...
"...that fought in the revolution.
I'd dream about those men...
"...how they went to war for our freedom.
"I guess that's when
I decided to be a soldier...
"...seeing the sky lit
up with those rockets.
"I enlisted when I became of age.
I served in Europe in world war ii...
"...and was involved in the
liberation of dozens of towns.
"As I passed through them,
as I saw the faces of the people...
"...I realized I had fulfilled my dream.
"I had become one of those men
who had gone to war for freedom.
"I sure wound up doing
what I wanted to do...
"...and that's what July 4 means to me."
- I bet you can't do that.
- I can't do that.
Can you do this?
- No. I can't even...
- Go ahead, try it.
I can't do it.
Billy the kid, let's show these guys
what real talent is. Come on.
Give me your arm.
You know,
the duet we worked up just last night?
Billy, you going to play that thing?
Yeah, come on, Billy, play your guitar.
Come on. I love when you play the guitar.
"What is tomorrow?
"What is it we need?
"What will it give us?
"A new life we can lead
"will the wind crack the limbs
of a few dying trees?
"Will the branches unite
and bend in the breeze?
"Tomorrow is hope
"for it is something I've not seen
"tomorrow is a sunny day
"to live in a sunny dream"
come on, Billy, that sounded great.
I can't play my fucking guitar.
God!
It's all right, man.
It's going to be all right.
I think it really helped him,
having you there.
I really do.
Luke, are you okay?
Yeah.
Should we do the dinner another night?
No.
I think you were really wonderful with him.
I really do.
Boy.
Just come down here,
and hold the chair for me.
Thanks.
If you could pick my ankles up...
Thank you. That's good.
It's warm 'cause I've had the oven on.
I've got one of those timing devices...
That cooks your food
while you're at work.
Let me just move you around a bit.
- You like margaritas?
- Yeah.
I just happen to have some.
Let me just...
Do you get a chance to go out very much?
- To go to people's homes?
- No, I don't.
Let's go in the living room.
I think you can make it. Okay?
Let's see.
Wait a minute. What am I doing?
- What?
- What am I lighting a fire for?
The old girl scout instinct's coming.
Let's see. I've got a dip.
Sit down, bender.
Are you nervous?
Yes.
Why are you nervous?
This isn't
have-a-gimp-over-for-dinner night, is it?
You're not one of those weirdoes?
No, I'm not, Luke.
I know you're not.
I'm just very happy to be here.
I'm glad you're here.
How about some music?
I don't think you're going to like
my records very much.
You probably won't like
the way I dance either.
Do you know that when I dream...
I'm not in the chair?
I don't even have a chair in my dream.
I have legs.
When I was a kid,
I used to jump in my mother's kitchen...
And touch the ceiling.
She used to get pissed off...
'Cause I'd leave my handprints
on the ceiling, you know?
I still check the snow reports,
the conditions at mammoth.
I'm still the same person.
It's funny. People look at me...
They see something else,
but they don't see who I am, you know?
I think people have a real hard time
seeing who other people really are.
People don't see me like I really am.
People look at me, I think, and they see...
Cheery Sally, the captain's wife.
Sometimes I feel like
I'm becoming what people see.
You know,
I spend 95% of my time at the hospital...
Thinking about making love with you.
I've never been unfaithful to my husband.
Don't wake him up.
Doc.
Wake up.
We sail with the morning tide.
Doc, why don't you go to bed?
- Hi, Sally.
- Hi, doc.
- You think you can make it, doc?
- Sure.
- Smooth sailing, doc.
- Right.
Do you want a ride?
You sure I'm not heavy?
I wouldn't know.
- What are you doing?
- I don't know where to put my hands.
Put them in your pockets.
It seems strange to be here at night.
Not for me.
Thank you for the ride.
Thank you for the dinner.
Good night.
This just came.
Do you want me to stay?
I'll be in my office.
Vi?
- Vi?
- Here.
Orders from the front.
Would you believe we ate 200 gallons
of chicken noodle soup last week?
How do you feel about going
to Hong Kong for a week?
Are you kidding?
Bob and dink just got their r and r,
and they want us to catch the first plane.
- Hong Kong?
- Will you check the schedules?
I gotta get my hair done, go to the bank.
I think it's already tomorrow there.
A week?
Five days.
I can't go!
What am I supposed to do?
Walk out on my job?
Walk out on my brother?
I just can't, Sally.
Yeah.
I'm going to miss you. So's dink.
- I'll call you when I get back.
- Yeah.
- Give him a kiss for me.
- Right.
On the cheek!
He can dribble!
- How do you like that?
- Get out the way.
Great shot.
My best pass.
- Pick and roll.
- Okay, baby.
I got him!
Good shot!
You're out.
Okay, beanie, over your head.
Bender!
- All right!
- That's my best shot!
Good news!
I'm getting released on Thursday.
- I'm getting out!
- That's great!
- How you doing?
- Where you gonna go?
- You gonna stay with someone?
- Yeah, I've got my own place.
I'm going to have wheels.
I'll be in touch with you.
I owe you a dinner.
I wanted to tell you,
I'm not gonna be around for a while.
I just heard from Bob.
He's getting his r and r.
I'm going to be meeting him in Hong Kong.
- Have a nice trip.
- Yeah, I'll see you soon.
- Quarterback!
- Beanie!
The iceman returns again!
- Great shot!
- Come on, you buzzard, put it in the hole.
Here we go.
Hard over here. Over here.
There you go. Over this way.
Let's go, move it up. Put it down, man.
Down.
Good.
- How you doing, Sally?
- Vi!
Where is she?
Why did you have to go to work
in the hospital?
- Because I wanted to.
- But it's the pits!
You didn't have to do that.
I just don't want you to work.
I just don't understand it.
Five days, that's all I wanted.
I ask you, is that too much to expect...
From somebody that you've
been with for two years?
You know, like, women and dogs...
You got to have a license
to show you're the owner.
Yeah.
Thanks very much for all the advice.
I really appreciate it.
Listen, tell the head honcho over there...
That I'm going across the street.
I'll see him later.
- I'm sorry, dink.
- No. Thanks for everything.
Excuse me.
If you see vi,
thank her for me, too, will ya?
Make sure of that.
What the fuck is the matter with him?
Where's he going?
He's upset because vi didn't come,
and because I suggested...
That maybe he didn't have the right
to just order her over here.
We got to go get him.
No, Bob,
let's just be alone for a few minutes.
We are alone.
There's something wrong.
It's not you. It's just fucked up.
I can't get all this bullshit about 'nam
out of my head.
Why don't you talk to me about it?
I want to know what it's like.
I don't know what it's like.
I only know what it is.
A TV show is what it's like.
They sure as hell don't show what it is.
I got to find him.
Does she love me, Raul?
- She loves me, man.
- I wouldn't let you down, man.
- Those new heads will work real good.
- I appreciate it.
- Have a good day, Raul.
- Take her easy.
All right, man.
- How are my plants?
- They're fine.
Nah, they died.
- They died?
- Yeah. Sorry.
What?
- They died.
- Man, I only got two plants.
What do you think about
that Kennedy assassination?
What do you think about it?
Sally, listen, I made up my mind...
And you can tell the kid I'll marry her
if you want to.
You tell her.
Come on, give me a break.
I'm serious about this.
I put it down all in writing,
and what I wanted you to do is...
Kind of talk to her about it.
Okay, of course. I'll be glad to.
Okay!
Would you have married me
if I wasn't a marine?
- In a second.
- See, there?
What did I tell you?
Didn't I tell you the uniform
always used to mean something?
The entire structure
of the marine corps is changing.
It used to really mean something
to be a marine.
We're no longer the elite.
We're not even equal.
Excuse me.
Thank you.
Big hook.
Mister, can you walk?
No, I can't walk.
That's why I'm in this chair.
- What happened to you?
- Yeah, what happened?
I got in an accident. I had a bad accident.
I got a little piece of metal in my back.
And after that, I couldn't walk.
Mary, I'm going to go around.
- I don't believe you.
- You don't?
- What's wrong with kids today?
- We don't believe you!
- What's the matter with you characters?
- We don't believe you.
I want a ride!
Come on, I'll give you a ride.
Here we go.
Are you going to help me out here?
Pull that back. That's it.
I'll show you a way out.
It's all right. We got it.
I'll show you a way out
when you don't pay, so you can sneak out.
My first week in combat...
We took this little Hamlet.
I got this second lieutenant, this...
Fucking camp lejeune whiz kid.
He comes whipping right on up to me:
"Excuse me, sir, I'm sorry to bother you...
"...but do you think it would be okay
if we put the heads on the poles?
"You know,
that really scares the shit out of the vc."
My men...
Were chopping heads off.
That's what they were into.
They were dead.
Do you like tiger balm?
Makes you feel real cool.
Put some on your back.
Is that the way you massage
the basket cases at the hospital?
It's open.
Hi.
Where's adrienne?
Couldn't make it.
She asked me to take her place.
I was kind of counting on adrienne.
I've been around this part
of the pool before.
With a gimp?
Yeah.
A guy in Reno.
- You want a drink?
- I'd love a drink.
"Well, there aren't many days
"and not enough time
"bedlam is silence
"and the stillness is fury"
Luke.
Put him on the phone. I'll talk to him.
Luke?
Hey, Luke.
Man, listen to this.
"When I opened my eyes
"a few were gone"
if I have to go, is this going to be okay?
Sure.
"I've got too many days, Luke
"and not enough time"
fucking shit.
Could I use your phone?
I should call my service.
Sure. Do what you want.
Just close the door when you leave, okay?
It's not your fault. You're a pretty lady.
Fuck off, man!
Munson, open the door, man.
Open up.
Open up the door.
- Let's go. Come on.
- Munson!
Come on, man.
- He won't even look at us.
- Is he loaded?
Come on. Open up the door.
Where the fuck is the goddamn nurse?
Come on!
Open the door!
No!
What's going on?
Come on!
Take it out!
The man went out.
- Make a hole.
- Come on!
Where the fuck have you been?
He had a syringe.
Did he do himself in?
Tell us something.
What's happening, man?
Some kid just bought it
by shooting air into his veins.
Did he do it?
Doc!
Yeah, he's dead.
All right, out of here!
It's all right.
Get out of my way. I want to find out.
Yeah, I'm gonna find out.
I'll let you know in a minute.
Shit. He's dead, man.
Vi!
He didn't even fucking call me.
Little bastard just wasted his life,
you know?
It's a big fucking relief,
if you know what I mean.
I mean, this nurse calls me
and says he's dead.
I don't even know her.
I just got to get out of here. Let's go.
Wait a second. I got to take a shower.
Yeah, me, too.
Have some wine or something.
I'll be right back, okay?
Don't go away.
I won't.
What do you think I should do, Sally?
I think I'm going to say yes.
To dink?
Congratulations, Mrs. mobley!
- Here you go, ladies.
- Did you order some more?
- We didn't order any more champagne.
- Those gentlemen over there did.
You're not calling them over?
They want us to come over!
I'll take care of this. You get your stuff.
We're the boys from number 9.
What...
In the fuck are you doing?
- Shit!
- I'm so happy.
- We'll get a little light.
- Are we here?
This is your honeymoon cottage.
Take off your coat.
You're such a good horse.
What's the matter with you? You insane?
You know you're on a military base?
Where do you think you are?
What are you doing?
- Corporal, what's this all about?
- This guy seems to be tied up to the fence.
I don't know what your beef is,
and I don't care...
But I want this chain off the fence now.
Why don't you pay attention,
motherfucker?
Buddy, there's still time.
- We need some entertainment.
- The lady wants some music.
We need some entertainment.
Sally, come on!
Yes, got it!
Appropriate music.
It's very entertaining.
- You guys ever been to a go-go club?
- Tonight.
No. That was not a go-go club.
- What does a real go-go look like?
- I'm going to show you.
Show us!
It's high up here.
She's very good. What does she do?
She's one of the nutritionists
at the va hospital.
I think I see some flesh here.
Take it easy, now. Now, Bruce is here, vi.
Easy does it, vi.
Take it easy.
You didn't have to do that.
Are you all right?
Sally!
My brother!
What happened? What's wrong?
I think she freaked out.
Maybe we should have turned on the TV.
He identified himself as Luke Martin.
He said he was a sergeant
in the marines in Vietnam.
He was arrested after
he chained himself here to the west gate.
He said he wants to stop any others
from going to Vietnam.
The reason why I'm here
is because a buddy of mine...
Who'd been in 'nam
took his own life today.
- This is kind of a funeral service.
- It's Luke.
I'm here because I'm trying
to tell people, man...
If we want to commit suicide...
We have plenty of reasons
to do it here at home.
We don't have to go to Vietnam
to find reasons for us to kill ourselves.
I just don't think we should be over there.
I think that...
Do you think this is a way to stop it?
- I don't know, man.
- Get him outta here.
Police had difficulty
getting sgt. Martin into the police car...
Because he also was chained
to his wheelchair.
Let me take you home.
I'm not a very nice person.
You are to me.
I want to spend the night with you.
- Where's your car?
- Over here.
Yeah, they're out of the car.
Goddamn thing has a curtain.
Coming around the side.
Is she pushing him,
or is he going under his own power?
She's pushing.
Make yourself comfortable.
I have some things to do in the bathroom.
I should be just a few minutes.
Okay.
Could you pull that sheepskin
toward the center?
Put the pillow up.
Put the pillow up against the back.
Like that?
Turn the light on. I want to see you.
What do I do?
Everything.
I want you to do everything.
Where can I touch you?
Where can you feel?
That's nice. I'm real sensitive,
all the areas that I feel.
I'm real sensitive there.
- Can you feel that at all?
- I can't feel it, but I can see it.
I wish you could feel me.
I feel you.
I want you.
Softly.
You're so beautiful.
That's never happened to me before.
How much am I paying you?
Going to paint this?
We'll paint it to look like steps,
so no one will know I'm here.
Are you ready?
Okay.
This, strangely enough, is our barber.
For 25 cents, you get a massage,
your hair cut, and your ears popped.
Impressive?
The water buffalo didn't like us, either.
There's a tunnel. Look.
They had a sophisticated tunnel network.
They've been working on it since wwii
when they were fighting the Japanese.
Then they fought against the French
and built more tunnels. Now they got...
That's a buddy of mine, Willie.
He didn't make it.
Pretty people.
That's my smile.
My God!
Got a letter from Kathy.
Something about the newspaper.
That letter was from Bob.
How is he?
I don't know.
I didn't get a chance to read it.
I guess he's okay.
Whatever he says...
It's 100 times worse
than what he can tell you.
I'm so perverse.
I'm just jealous because I know
when that thing's over, man...
He's gonna come back to you.
We never manage
to talk about Bob, do we?
No, we don't.
I don't know what's going to happen...
With Bob and me, Luke.
It's very scary for me...
To think that maybe
it's not going to work out with him.
I know.
Because we've been together for so long.
It's going to be very hard for him...
And he's not going to like
the fact that I've changed.
And I have changed.
You know that I've never
been on my own before?
- You like that, sid?
- She's got a nice ass for a white girl.
You should have heard the tapes
we made at their pad.
- Do they get it on?
- I'll give him credit for that.
- You got a good angle?
- Yeah.
I don't know,
because everybody's different.
Don't you think so?
It's cool. It's all right.
Have a nice time.
- Two, please.
- Okay.
If dink saw you...
He'd probably think
you were a hippie faggot.
- Here's to dink, vi.
- A toast to the host.
Not here for a beer.
- Don't.
- If that motherfucker sends me an ear...
Are you listening?
I just made up a poem,
and you're not even listening.
Bye, guys. See you tomorrow.
Bye, Rita.
Hi.
It's from Bob. I opened it.
He's coming home.
- Is he all right?
- Yeah, he's all right.
He just got shot in the leg.
Nothing really too heavy.
He's all right.
Will you always be my friend?
Yes.
Say, "always."
Always.
I will always be your friend.
Good.
I'm going to miss you.
Hold on a second, will you?
Yeah?
Yeah, this is he.
What I have to say to high-school kids
they're not ready for.
Yeah, that was television.
I was angry. I was upset.
What the hell did you do to your hair?
I've stopped straightening it.
Where's all the demonstrators?
Some asshole on the plane...
Told us there was gonna be
some flower heads out here.
There's some kids out there,
but they can't come on the base.
- Does your leg hurt?
- No.
- What do you think?
- About what?
Our new car.
A speedster?
It's outstanding.
- Absolutely outstanding.
- I'm glad you're back.
One, two, three, four,
we don't want your rotten war!
Peace, brother.
Peace on you, too, brother.
You never told me
that you were this close to the beach.
I wanted to surprise you.
You're full of surprises.
Welcome back, hero!
- Vi, how are you?
- Great.
- So tell me, how's dink?
- Dink is fine.
- He's kicking everybody's ass, as always.
- Great.
No, ladies first,
but I'll have the number 2 one.
My God, does this look good.
Cheers.
Are you hungry?
I made some
Swedish meatballs to nibble on.
They go great with drinks.
You like it?
- How's the surf?
- It's good.
Why don't you sit down, sweetheart?
So, Bob, tell us about your foot.
It's not my foot. It's my leg.
And it's a goddamn bore.
Just like this whole fucking war is boring.
But, ladies...
Bob has got to tell you one thing
that is not boring.
That is the good old us of a Martini...
Of which I am going to partake
as much as I can...
As quick as I can.
Drink it up. I made gallons.
So, come on, Bob,
tell us the story about your leg.
What happened?
There's nothing to tell.
I'm a fucking hero.
They're going to give me a medal.
That's the story of my leg.
Nothin' to it, is there?
- Great.
- It ain't great.
How did it happen?
Look, it's just a boring story.
I mean, I'm on my way to the showers.
- Got an m-16 in one hand...
- On your way to the showers?
Yeah. I mean, why not?
Everywhere you go,
you better carry an m-16...
Particularly when you go to the showers.
There I am, like every other asshole...
Trucking on down the road
to the showers...
And I tripped and shot myself...
Right in the calf.
- My God.
- And that's it.
Dink should have thought of that.
I didn't think of that!
That's the way it happened!
- It was a goddamn accident!
- You don't have to get mad.
Yeah, but it was an accident.
Why are they decorating you?
- Where's the head?
- Right there.
I promised a guy from 'nam...
I'd have a drink with him
at the officers club, and I've got to go.
I'll be back for dinner.
Direct hit!
You couldn't have done it better
if you had your lights on.
Man, if you'd keep your lights on,
you wouldn't hit things like that.
It looks like
a fucking smithereen job to me.
I feel like that fucking...
Woman on the front of
the boats, you know?
Like the sss...
Sally, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, darling.
But, don't run out on me, you...
These are two friends of mine.
No, Sally, wait a sec.
My wife Sally.
This is... what was your name?
Monty.
I don't know them. Who are you?
- Usa.
- My wife Sally...
There's two things that smell like fish.
One of them's fish.
So go on already.
"Avoid loud and aggressive persons.
"They are vexations to the spirit."
I'm passing out.
"Keep interested in your own career,
however humble.
"It's a real possession
in the changing fortunes of time."
What is that tank for up there?
What's that turtle's name?
Let's give him a drink.
- No, don't.
- Don't pour the beer in there!
Wait! You'll kill the goddamn...
No, damn it! You ain't feedin' no turtle!
You nickel-dick, that's not even real.
That's a plastic turtle.
Don't look at that turtle.
I don't want you to look at that turtle.
Did you hear about the female peanut
walking down the street at night?
She was a salted.
That's the third time
he's told that joke tonight.
She was assaulted, and he was insulted.
- Capt. Hyde?
- Yeah.
The major's ready.
Maj. Mailer, capt. Hyde.
Capt. Hyde, this is Mr. ott.
- How do you do, sir?
- Mr. Roberts.
- Captain.
- They're with the FBI.
Would you like to have a seat?
No, thank you.
Captain,
what can you tell us about Luke Martin?
Aren't you going to park?
What are you going to do?
Drive.
I'll come with you.
No, I'd just...
Like to be by myself.
Please?
Are you going to be long?
No.
When that gun goes off,
you've got to uncoil like a spring...
You've got to come.
Just release.
Swimmers, take your marks.
I mean, you got to put
everything you have, you know...
Into that moment, right?
And get as far toward the...
I used to think about
the other end of the pool, you know.
You Luke Martin?
Depends.
I'm Bob Hyde.
Let's take a little break, mark, okay?
I told Sally I was going to do this.
You have a right to know
about the surveillance.
They were watching the house.
They got pictures. They got tapes.
Thanks...
For letting me know.
That's all I had to say.
The rest is up to Sally.
I guess.
See you.
Luke. What?
How am I taking what?
He didn't tell you?
I could have sworn that...
Listen, they probably had
some surveillance on me...
Because of the gate thing.
Yeah?
My God.
Listen, I'm going to be here.
If you need me, call me. I'm just here.
I wanted to talk to you.
You seem so far away from me
since you came back.
I've been scared.
I love you.
I do.
I'm not going to make excuses
for what happened.
It happened.
I needed somebody. I was lonely.
- Don't bullshit me.
- It's not... Bob, I was lonely.
Don't bullshit me.
It's not bullshit.
- It's bullshit!
- Bob, please!
Goddamn it, it's bullshit!
Everybody needs somebody,
for Christ's sake!
If it's over with us, it's over!
What are you saying?
That you won't even make the effort?
What I'm saying is,
I do not belong in this house!
And they're saying
that I don't belong over there.
- Who's they?
- The people that make the decisions...
About the war! That's who "they" is.
- I don't want to talk about the war.
- What should we talk about?
The fucking marriage? Think about that.
I can't talk to you when you're shouting.
I want to be your husband.
I just don't deserve to be your husband.
I don't deserve the medal
I'm getting tomorrow either.
How can they give you a medal
for a war they don't want you to fight?
- Now, who is that?
- Bob? Sally? Can I talk to you?
It's Luke. Let me tell him to go away.
What? Now, wait a minute.
You just wait right there.
I don't want to make anything
more complicated than it already is.
I just thought there might
be a few things that...
We should talk about.
They're not very complicated.
Actually, they're very simple.
I don't belong here.
You belong here.
I just wanted to get things straight...
What's going on with me...
So you know where I'm coming from
and what happened.
I know where you're coming from.
And I know what happened.
I've just got to figure out...
For myself...
What happened
and how I'm going to deal with it.
I can understand that.
- Bullshit!
- Don't!
- You Jody fuck! You get back!
- No, Bob...
Get back, slope cunt!
Now, you Jody motherfucker,
you explain to me...
How it is you understand anything.
I can understand because I'm a brother...
And I've been in the same
place you're at now.
That's why I feel so bad...
That I made it harder
for you than it is.
That's bullshit.
She's here because she loves you,
and there was never any question of that.
Don't tell me that, goddamn it!
It's true, what he's saying.
Bullshit!
If you give her a chance, she can help you.
She wants to listen to you...
And she wants to understand you.
Say something else, fuck.
I'm not the enemy.
Maybe the enemy is the fucking war.
But you don't want to kill anybody here.
You have enough ghosts to carry around.
Look at me.
My hand...
I was shaking, and I'm...
I'm sorry.
I'm fucked.
I just want to be a hero...
That's all.
I just want to be a fucking hero.
One day in my life, one moment.
I want to go out a hero.
That way, I would've
done something that was mine...
That I've done.
"Enemy forces captured
the north side of the bridge...
"...when lt. Roscoe charged forward,
firing his rifle.
"Lt. Roscoe's actions
so unnerved the enemy...
"...they withdrew from the position,
allowing him...
"...to secure the enemy position
until the rest of his company...
"...could move forward
and consolidate their forces.
"Lt. Roscoe maintained the position
against the repeated enemy attacks.
"Though wounded,
continued to inspire his men...
"...until reinforcements arrived
the following morning.
"Lt. Roscoe has upheld the highest
traditions of the marine corps...
"...and of the united
states naval service."
The marine corps builds
body, mind and spirit.
Thank you.
And now, with a different perspective,
we have Luke Martin...
Combat veteran of the marine corps.
- Sergeant, mind if I ask you a question?
- No, sir.
You can just call me sergeant.
That's what I was.
- Where were you stationed?
- Da nang.
I thought I'd go get some steaks
for a barbecue.
Would you like that?
It's been a long time
since you've lit a barbecue, hasn't it?
The charcoal's under the kitchen sink.
I'll see if vi wants to come with me.
I'll see you later.
You know, you want to be a part of it,
be patriotic, and go out and...
Get your licks in for the us of a.
When you get over there,
it's a totally different situation.
I mean...
You grow up real quick...
Because all you're seeing is
a lot of death.
I know some of you will
look at that uniform...
And remember all the films
and think about the glory of other wars...
And think about some vague...
Patriotic feeling
and go off and fight this Turkey, too.
I'm tellin' you, it ain't like the movies.
That's all I want to say.
I didn't have a choice.
When I was your age...
All I got was a guy
standing up like that
and giving me bullshit,
which I caught.
I was in good shape then.
I was the captain of the football team...
And I wanted to be a war hero.
I wanted to go out and kill for my country.
And now I'm here to tell you...
That I have killed
for my country, or whatever...
And I don't feel good about it.
Because there's not enough reason.
To feel a person die in your hands...
Or to see your best buddy
get blown away...
I'm here to tell you
it's a lousy thing, man.
I don't see any reason for it.
And there's a lot of shit
that I did over there...
That I find fucking hard to live with.
I don't want to see people like you
coming back...
And having to face the rest
of your lives with that shit.
It's as simple as that.
I don't feel sorry for myself.
I'm a lot fucking smarter now
than when I went...
And I'm just telling you...
There's a choice to be made here.
Subs By THIWANKA...