Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Hey, referee!
Why don't ya stop the fight?
Let's go!
Come on, hit him!
Throw in the towel!
Give the suckers some action.
You're fighting like a bum.
- You want some advice?
- Water.
Cold beer here!
Rocky, do you feel strong?
Absolutely.
You want some advice?
Mouthpiece.
Keep moving to your left.
Spider, get that bum
outta there!
Come on, Spider!
Kill the bum!
All right.
Next, a six-rounder
between local lightweights
Kid Brooks and Sugar Johnson.
Good form, champ!
Hey, you got a smoke?
You can have this one.
You're a bum!
You know that? You're a bum!
You really got lucky tonight.
Spider gets $40 less $ 1 5
locker and corner man,
$5.00 shower and towel, 7% tax.
Comes to 1 7.20.
You fought a good fight, Spider.
Balboa, you get winner's share.
$65 less $ 1 5 locker
and corner man,
$5.00 shower and towel,
and 7% tax.
Comes to 40.55.
When do I fight again?
Maybe two weeks.
Give me a call.
The doctor should be
about 20 minutes.
Here, boy. Here, boy.
Take me back
Doo-doo doo doo
I said, I been told by
Some people, and theyall
Said take me back
Doo-doo doo doo
Take me back like before
Now, I don't call it a reason
Ijust call it
believin' in myself
You guys get better every year.
What I saw before
I squeezedyou, and I heldyou
But I couldnot tell you
I lovedyou
Doo-doo doo doo
Take me back
Well, you put me down
Doo-doo doo doo
You put me down real nice
This love affair
Doo-doo doo doo
Has taken the longest slice
From my life as I see it...
Your old man
did pretty good tonight.
Why weren't you there?
You should have seen me.
You guys hungry?
There you go. There you go.
You want to see your friend
Moby Dick, huh?
How you doing, Moby Dick?
You miss me today?
Here you go. Say hi.
If you guys
could sing and dance,
I wouldn't be doing this.
And this turtle food I got here,
this turtle food
got more flies in it.
There's more moths
in it than flies.
Who the hell cares?
How you feeling this morning?
Fine.
How you doing, killer?
- How's the turtle food?
- Fine.
Me, I'm kind of aggravated.
I'm sorry.
It's not your fault.
Want to hear about it?
Here's somebody who don't.
The last turtle food I got here
had more moths than flies.
These moths get caught
in the turtle's throat.
I got to smack them
on the shell.
What do you think they get?
Come on.
They get shell-shocked.
You're starting
with bad jokes early.
Making jokes ain't
so easy sometimes.
That wasn't a joke.
How's my buddy today?.
Yo, Butkus.
Give me a kiss.
Adrian, clean the cat cages.
They're a mess.
You got to pay for that
turtle food, Rockhead.
Crime don't pay.
You know that, Gloria.
- Yo, Rock. How's your boss?
- Good.
Rock, you fighting again?
- We'll make some money soon?
- Yeah, a million dollars.
Hey, you, where you going?
Where you going?
Where you running?
- Don't hit the face!
- Shut up!
- Mr Gazzo wants the 200 now.
- I'm broke...
Mr Gazzo says I should get
the 200 or break your thumb.
- Please! Don't...
- What's your name again?
- Bob.
- Listen, Bob.
You want to dance, pay the band.
You want to borrow, pay the man.
I ain't emotionally
involved, understand?
Give me some money.
- There's 1 30 here.
- That's all...l'm broke...
Bob, you're still $70 light.
You don't have to break nothing.
Take my coat.
It's worth $50, $60.
Take the coat.
You should've planned ahead.
I'll tape the hand
like you broke the thumb.
You should have planned ahead.
Gazzo don't have to know.
He won't be wise to nothing.
Keep the coat. Keep...
He only had 1 30, but he's good
for the rest next week.
Sure, Rocky. Bob's good for it.
That's it for today.
Tomorrow, collect from Del Rio.
- He's late three weeks.
- Del Rio, three weeks.
How do you spell Del Rio?
- How'd you do last night?
- I did real good.
- Did you get the number?
- Of what?
The truck that run
over your face.
Pull over. I want to let
Rocky out and talk to him.
Why didn't you break his thumb?
- How do you know I didn't?
- Did I give you a job or not?
When you don't do
what I tell you,
you make me look bad, Rock.
I figure if I break the guy's
thumb, he gets laid off.
- He can't make the pay...
- Let me do the figuring.
These guys think
we're running a charity,
From here on in,
do what I tell you,
because it's bad
for my reputation.
- You got it, Rock?
- I got it.
How do you spell Del Rio?
Look in a dictionary.
I won't let that happen
no more - about the thumb.
You know.
So long, meatbag.
I should've broke YOUR thumbs!
Rock, heard you did
good last night.
- Absolutely.
- You ought to take a rest.
- My back is hurt.
- Your back?
- My back's hurt. You deaf?
- No. I'm short.
Yo, Mike, whose stuff
is this in my locker?
It's Dipper's.
Ain't your locker no more.
It's been mine for six years.
Where's my gear?
Mickey said bag it and hang it.
You put my stuff on Skid Row.
I been in that locker six years
and you put me on Skid Row?
Mickey tells me what to do.
- Where is he?
- Working with Dipper.
- He's in a bad mood.
- So am l.
Put your hands up. Watch it.
- Mick.
- Shut up!
To the body. That-a-boy.
Time.
What do you want?
- How you feeling today?
- What?
- How you feeling?
- Are you a doctor?
- You got a problem?
- What's YOUR problem?
How come I been
put out of my locker?
Because Dipper needed it.
He's a contender.
- You're a tomato.
- A tomato?
I run a business,
not a soup kitchen.
- Did you fight last night?
- Yeah.
- Did you win?
- K.O. in the second.
Who'd you fight?
Spider Rico.
He's a bum.
You think everybody
I fight is a bum.
Ain't they? You got heart,
but you fight like an ape.
You never got your nose busted.
Leave it that way,
and what's left of your mind.
I'm going to take a steam.
I did real good last night.
You should've seen me.
- Big deal.
- You should've seen me too.
- Ever think about retiring?
- No.
You think about it.
- Hey, lron Man.
- What?
I dig your locker.
Cold night.
Good night to catch pneumonia.
You need some help with that?
There's a good game
down at the Spectrum tonight.
Want to go
to a basketball game?
Tough day today.
They took my locker.
Had it six years.
It don't bother me.
People get the combination.
I must've had 20 bucks
taken out of there in 6 years.
It don't sound much,
but it adds up.
Doesn't matter. Who cares?
Whew. Cold night.
Hey, birds, look who's here -
the giant worm.
Don't these birds
look like flying candy?
Want to fly me home?
Need somebody to walk you home?
- No.
- It's a cold night.
If I was you, I'd take a cab.
Too many creeps around here.
Every other block,
there's a creep.
You can always tell a creep.
I'm going now.
I'll see youse later.
None of you guys get up.
You had a hard day at the cage.
So I'll go home, make up a joke.
- Good night, Adrian.
- Good night, Rocky.
No matter what happens...
Lefty, I got a friend
for you here.
- You seen Paulie?
- He's in the steamroom.
Rocky, what's with the eye?
- Been fightin'.
- Hope youse won it.
Yeah. Did real good.
The heavyweight
champion, Apollo Creed...
- Who'd you fight?
- Spider Rico.
Is he still around?
Yeah. He's doing
better than you are.
Paulie, did you lock the door?
I'd like to kill the moron
who broke the mirror.
Paulie, every day,
every night I pass by.
Your sister's giving me
the shoulder.
You can do better than her.
Every night I pass by,
I tell a joke.
Every morning I tell a joke.
- She just looks at me.
- Looks?
Like I'm a plate of leftovers.
I need a Cadillac
to connect with your sister?
She's a freakin' loser.
She gets me so crazy
I could split her head.
Don't get mental, man.
You're always in a bad mood.
Adrian is a loser.
She's pushing 30.
She'll end up dying alone.
- I'm 30 myself.
- And you'll die alone.
I don't see no crowd around you.
I'll kill whoever broke this.
Let's get out of this stink.
I want to talk to you.
- You still work for Gazzo?
- Yeah, sure.
Why don't you talk
to him about me?
I don't think Gazzo's
hiring right now.
Come on.
The girl's drying up.
If she don't start living,
her body will dry up.
Tomorrow's Thanksgiving.
Come over and talk to her.
Sure. Beer.
- You come for some bird.
- You got it.
I gotta go or she'll
call the hospital.
- Paulie!
- I got it.
..fight with Mac Lee Green
here in Philadelphia.
You're speaking of your
much-publicised fight.
The greatest sporting event
in the country's history.
I'll beat Green like
he committed a crime.
Take a look at that guy.
Where are the real fighters,
the pros?
All we got today are jig clowns.
- Clown?
- That's right, clown.
Apollo Creed will duplicate
the cracking of the liberty bell
by cracking Mac Lee Green.
You calling
Apollo Creed a clown?
Just look at him.
Stay in school, use your brain.
Be a doctor, a lawyer.
Forget about sports
as a profession.
Sports make you grunt and smell.
Be a thinker, not a stinker.
This man is champion
of the world.
He took his best shot
and became champ.
What shot did you ever take?
You're not happy
with your life, that's nice.
But I got a business.
I don't have to take no shots.
No one having gone more
than 1 2 rounds with him.
Stick that up your business.
What are you so insulted about?
You want me to take a shot?
I'll take a shot.
- There he goes.
- Rocky, how about a bottle?
- No wine.
- Just a little.
Buy us a Thunderbird.
Marie, your brother know
you're hanging out?
Screw you, yo-yo.
These guys teach you
to talk like that?
- Stuff it, man.
- Come here.
When I was your age,
only one girl in the
neighbourhood talked like that.
- That makes your teeth yellow.
- I like yellow teeth.
- It makes your breath garbage.
- Maybe I like garbage.
Nobody likes garbage.
This girl wasn't bad-looking,
but none of the guys
took her serious.
- Why?
- That's how guys are.
They laugh when you talk dirty,
but you get a reputation.
You get no respect.
I got to use a bad word.
Whore. You understand?
You use dirty words and maybe
end up becoming a whore.
Come on, Rocky, I'm just 1 2.
That don't matter.
You don't have to BE one.
Just act like one,
and that's it.
20 years from now,
people will say,
"Do you remember Marie,
"the little whore
at the hoagie shop."
"Oh, yeah, I remember her."
They don't remember YOU,
they remember the rep.
Hey, you got a boyfriend?
You ain't got a boyfriend.
Why don't you have a boyfriend?
'Cause you hang out
with them coconuts.
Hang around with coconuts,
you'll get nowhere.
Hang out with nice people,
you get nice friends.
Hang out with yo-yos,
you get yo-yo friends.
See, it's simple mathematics.
I hope you ain't...
You hope I don't become a whore.
Something like that.
- Goodnight, Rocky.
- Goodnight.
Screw you, creep-o.
Yeah. Who are you
to give advice, creep-o?
Are the doctor's
reports confirmed?
Definitely.
"Mac Lee Green has a
severely cracked metacarpal
"in his left hand."
Damn.
We can cancel the fight if
you're set on fighting Green.
What about all the time
Apollo's invested?
We can find a solution.
Find me another
ranked contender.
Apollo's already done
$1 million worth of publicity,
has contracts with
20 different organisations.
Ernie Roman's fighting
in France that week.
Get Buddy Shaw.
He's ranked fifth.
Went to California
and gained 50 pounds.
I got hold of every
worthwhile contender.
Five weeks isn't enough
time to get into shape.
Shape nothing. They're afraid.
Everybody in the world
will see this fight.
They don't want to be
the chump that gets whipped.
All I can say is
I'm a good promoter.
I've promoted fights
in every country in the world
but I don't know
what the hell else to do.
I do.
Without a ranked contender,
this fight needs a novelty.
This is the land of opportunity.
So Apollo Creed,
on January 1 st,
gives a local underdog
fighter an opportunity.
A snow-white underdog,
on this poster with me.
I'll tell you why -
because I'm sentimental.
So are a lot of other people
in this country.
They'd like to see Apollo Creed
give a local Philadelphia boy
a shot at the title.
That's the way I see it.
That's the way it's going to be.
Apollo, I like it.
It's very American.
No, Jergens, it's very smart.
What is it?
I just want to check.
Pick up 2 yards from Snyder
and a grand from Cappoli.
No, 2 yards from Cappoli
and a grand from Snyder.
- Write it down.
- I got it.
Who's this girl
you're going out with tomorrow?
- How'd you know?
- I hear things.
A lot of canaries
flying around the docks.
I'm going out
with Paulie's sister.
I hear she's retarded.
She ain't retarded. She's shy.
Take her to the zoo.
Retards like the zoo.
- This bum got to say that?
- Who you calling a bum?
Buddy's in a bad mood.
It's his prostate.
You ought to count
your blessings.
You're still healthy.
- Kiss my ass!
- Get out of the car!
Relax, relax.
You're driving me crazy,
both of youse.
Buddy doesn't like you.
Some guys, they just
hate for no reason.
Here's 50 bucks.
You and Adrian have a nice time.
Thanks. How'd you know her name?
You don't think I hear things?
Remember what I told you.
Take her to the zoo.
- More coffee, Mr Creed?
- No thanks, Shirley.
- What about Billy Snow?
- Fouls.
- How about Big Chuck Smith?
- He's too old and dull.
Bobby Judge is a good boy.
I don't feel heat
from that name.
Joe Zack's a good prospect.
Exactly what are you
looking for, Apollo?
This is what I'm looking for.
The ltalian Stallion.
"Rocky Balboa"?
Never heard of him.
It's the name, man -
"The ltalian Stallion"
The media will eat it up.
Who discovered America?
An ltalian.
Let's get it on
with a descendent.
I don't want you
messing with southpaws.
I'll drop him in three.
Apollo Creed meets
the ltalian Stallion.
Sounds like a monster movie.
What are you doing
with that bat?
- Your sister knows I'm coming?
- She's very excited.
Look at these swollen hands,
from carrying meat
in and out of the freezer.
- You ought to see a doctor.
- I need a different job.
What kind of turkey,
big or small?
Tell Gazzo I'm a good man
and nothing bothers me.
Busting bones don't bother me.
Big turkey, right?
Forget Gazzo. It's a bad job.
You got a match?
Go to him for me, as a favour.
Yeah. Last time I had a turkey,
they were having a $2.00
special at Horn Hardart's.
Your sister knows I'm coming?
Yeah, she's very excited.
Hey, forget about Gazzo.
I don't ask nobody twice.
You don't ask nobody twice.
Stay away, baby...
You sure your sister
knows I'm coming?
- Yeah, she's very excited.
- Yeah?
Paulie, you're late.
Did you call the hospital?
She calls the hospital
if I'm late.
Yo, how are you doing?
I told you she's very excited.
Why didn't you tell me
you were bringing him?
I'm not ready for this.
He's a friend.
He's taking you out.
I can't.
I want you out
of the kitchen now.
I won't.
I'm sick of seeing you
hang around like a spider.
- Go out and enjoy life.
- Paulie, I can't go!
Don't get wise with me.
I'm tired of you being a loser.
Don't call me that, Paulie.
Apollo Creed is shopping
for another victim
for the bicentennial
championship fight.
I'm not going to go,
Paulie. I won't go!
Why?
Paulie, it's Thanksgiving.
I got a turkey in the oven.
Oh, a turkey in the oven.
You want the bird?
Go in the alley and eat it.
I want you out of here!
Get outta here!
Enjoy your freakin' life.
You hungry, Rock?
Maybe we just better
forget all this.
Forget nothing.
Tell her something funny.
She's in a bad mood,
I'm in a bad mood.
- You want to go out with her?
- Yeah.
- I don't know what to say.
- Funny.
Yo, Adrian, it's me, Rocky.
Rocky, you know?
Listen...
I don't know what to say
'cause I ain't never
talked to no door before.
- Hey, forget it.
- You're doing fine.
I look like an idiot.
Keep doing what you're doing.
I know all about these things.
I feel like a jerk.
Yo, Adrian, it's Rocky again.
I know you ain't
too happy at this moment.
But could you do me a favour?
I got nobody to spend
Thanksgiving with.
So maybe we could
go out together,
get something to eat,
maybe laugh a little bit.
Would you like to...
Would you like to maybe,
you and me, go out together?
We'll have a good time,
a real good time, Adrian.
Thanks for the bird.
I'll turn the TV off.
I got a headache.
- What's your sister like to do?
- Ice skate.
Adrian, come on.
You're letting the heat out.
Listen, I don't want
no turkey anyway.
But it was Thanksgiving.
- It was what?
- Thanksgiving.
Yeah, to you.
But to me it's Thursday.
Yo, looks kind of quiet.
- I think it's closed.
- I think we're just early.
Yo! We're closed!
- What?
- I said we're closed.
Listen, I'm going
to smooth this guy out.
- We could go someplace else.
- It's OK.
You closed to the general
public or to everybody?
It's after 6.00.
It's Thanksgiving.
So do me a favour
and not stay here.
Could you do me a favour?
Hey, we're not operating.
This girl here
ain't feeling well.
Doctors say she should
go out and exercise.
What do you want from me?
If you could let her
on the ice, I'd appreciate it.
1 0 minutes, 1 0 bucks.
How about eight bucks?
Come on, it's Thanksgiving.
All right, nine bucks.
You'll have the ice
to yourself. 1 0 bucks.
Give me the blades.
Aren't you skating?
I ain't skated since I was 1 5.
That's when I started fighting.
Skating's bad for the ankles.
You're a pretty good
skater, are you?
Like I was saying,
fighting used to be tops
for me, but no more.
All I wanted was to prove
I could make a good pro.
You never got the chance?
I ain't crying about it
because I still fight.
- But I'm a southpaw.
- What's a southpaw?
It means you're left-handed.
Other guys,
it throws their timing off,
makes them look awkward.
You know where
southpaw came from?
A long time ago,
there was this guy fighting
around Philadelphia.
He was left-handed,
and his arm was facing
towards New Jersey.
That's south, so naturally
they called him south paw.
Southpaw, South Jersey,
South Camden, southpaw.
Things probably
worked out for the best.
Never got a chance
because you're left-handed?
That's absolutely true.
Watch out.
I just dislocated my finger.
Look at that.
It ain't your fault.
That's an old wound.
You see that?
It bends like that.
Push the button. Bong.
It works.
I'll show you something.
Seven minutes!
I keep pictures of my fights.
I done it in the
Baby Crenshaw fight.
I broke both my hands
on his face.
I lost that fight,
but that's a nice picture.
You having a good time?
You can see I ain't
too graceful.
I don't move well.
But I can really hit hard.
But nobody wants
to fight no southpaw.
You know how I got
started in fighting?
No.
Am I talking too loud?
Three minutes!
My father -
he was never too smart -
He says to me, "You weren't
born with much of a brain,
"so you better use your body."
So I become a fighter,
you know?
Why are you laughing?
- My mother said the opposite.
- What did she say?
She said, "You weren't born
with much of a body,
"so you better
develop your brain."
Yo! Time!
Can I ask you a question?
Absolutely.
Why do you want to fight?
Because
I can't sing or dance.
Don't fall!
I'm pretty good at this.
You like the way I skate?
Last fight I had, with Spider
Rico, he busted my head here.
Things get pretty rough
in the ring.
Some people are very shy
by nature, you know?
I suppose.
I say you're very shy
by nature, you know?
I suppose.
The bum from the dark.
Get a job.
Some people think
being shy is a disease,
but it don't bother me none.
Don't bother me, either.
Why did I bring it up?
Because I'm dumb.
We make a real sharp
couple of coconuts.
I'm dumb, you're shy.
Why would anybody
want to be a fighter?
You got to be a moron
to want to be a fighter.
You're almost guaranteed
to end up a bum.
I don't think you're a bum.
I'm at least half a bum,
but I'll tell you something.
Worst thing about fighting
is the morning after.
The morning after a fight,
you're like a large wound.
I feel like calling a taxi
to take me from the bed
to the bathroom.
Your hair hurts, your eyes hurt,
your face is busted up.
Look at this face... 64 fights.
See that nose?
That nose ain't
never been broken.
I had guys chewing on it,
twisting it, punching it.
These guys are hitting
my nose all the time.
Never broke. I'm proud of that.
- Why do it if it hurts?
- Why do you think?
'Cause you can't sing or dance.
Yeah, something like that.
Want to come inside?
No, I got to go.
Come on. I got these
very rare animals inside.
No, I got to go.
I got to go to
the bathroom. Come on.
No, I got to go.
Is this a face you can trust?
They ought to stick
this face on a stamp.
Come on. Come on in.
Come on.
Click.
Are you hungry?
No.
If you like soda,
some doughnuts or something.
I got a couple of cupcakes, huh?
I think I got some
chocolate in there. No?
Hot in here, you know?
I could go for some music.
These are the exotic animals.
These are my friends
Cuff and Link.
- I sold them to you.
- I know you did.
The first day you worked
at that pet shop,
I bought both these animals.
I bought this bowl
and I bought the animals,
some food, the marbles.
Remember that mountain?
I got rid of it
'cause it kept falling over.
Why don't you come
over here and sit down?
It's a nice couch.
I don't know.
There's big bugs there.
It's safer here.
You want to sit down?
These your parents?
Yeah, that's them.
- Is this you?
- Yeah. I was eight.
The ltalian Stallion as a baby.
Why don't you come on over
and make yourself comfortable?
Do you have a phone?
No. I had it pulled 'cause
people calling all the time.
Who needs the aggravation?
Who did you want to call?
I want to call my brother.
Why?
I think he might be worried.
I'll call your brother.
Paulie, your sister's with me!
I'll call youse later.
You don't like the room, do you?
- It's fine.
- It's only temporary.
It's not that.
What's the problem?
You don't like me?
You don't like the turtles?
- I don't think I belong here.
- It's OK.
I don't belong here.
Well, it's OK,
'cause you're my guest.
I don't know you well enough.
I've never been
in a man's apartment alone.
Well, they're all
the same, you know?
I'm not sure
I know you well enough.
I don't feel comfortable.
Yo, Adrian, I ain't
so comfortable, either.
- I should go.
- Don't go, please.
Do me a favour.
- What?
- Take off these glasses.
You have nice eyes, you know?
Do me another favour.
Why don't you
take off that hat?
I always knew you was pretty.
- Don't tease me.
- I'm not teasing you.
I just...want to kiss you.
You don't have to kiss me back,
but I want to kiss you.
- You got a fight coming up?
- Yeah, next month.
Come to the gym, man.
We'll get you in shape.
Rock, how are you doing?
Mick was looking for you.
- For me? You sure?
- Yeah, he was looking for you.
Your name's Rocky, right?
All right. Go on.
You got something for me?
Yeah, they need sparring
partners for Apollo Creed.
- Here's the card.
- When was they here?
About an hour ago.
They probably need
sparring partners.
I said that, you dumb dago!
For six years you've been
sticking it to me. How come?
- You don't want to know.
- I want to know.
- You want to know?
- I want to know!
OK, I'll tell you.
You had the talent
to be a good fighter,
not a leg-breaker
for some cheap loan-shark.
It's a living.
It's a waste of life.
Yes, may I help you?
You must be Mr Rocky Balboa.
Mr Jergens is expecting you.
Just a moment.
Mr Rocky Balboa to see you, sir.
Please go in, Mr Balboa.
- Can I have that?
- Certainly.
Thanks.
How are you? George Jergens.
Take a chair, please.
Thanks.
- Mr Balboa.
- Call me Rocky.
Tell me, Rocky,
do you have a manager?
Uh, no. Just me.
Well, Rocky, I've got
a proposition to make to you.
- About sparring?
- I beg your pardon.
I know you're looking
for sparring partners.
- I'm very available.
- I'm sure you are.
Sparring with the champion
would be an honour,
and I wouldn't take
no cheap shots.
You don't understand me, Rocky.
My proposition's this...
Would you be interested
in fighting Apollo Creed
for the world
heavyweight championship?
No.
Listen, Rocky,
Apollo's seen you fight.
He likes you.
He wants to fight you.
It's just that,
I fight in clubs.
I'm really a ham and egger.
This guy's the best.
It wouldn't be a good fight.
Thank you very much.
I appreciate it.
Rocky, do you believe America
is the land of opportunity?.
Yeah.
Apollo Creed does,
and he's going to prove it
by giving an unknown
a shot at the title,
and that unknown is you.
He picked you, Rocky.
Rocky, it's the chance
of a lifetime.
You can't pass it by.
What do you say?
We want to ask Apollo
a few questions.
How do you like the City
of Brotherly Love?
Just being in Philadelphia
makes me feel patriotic.
Beautiful people
and beautiful city.
I'm proud to be an American.
Apollo, why did you agree
to fight a man who has
no chance of winning?
American history proves
that everybody's
got a chance to win.
Didn't you ever hear
of Bunker Hill?
Apollo, is it coincidence that
you're fighting a white man?
Is it a coincidence
that he's fighting a black man?
Apollo, how do you feel
about your challenger?
Come here, Rock. My main man.
- Rocky, ain't you ltalian?
- Yeah, I'm ltalian.
If he can't fight,
I bet he can cook.
His lungs, punch out.
Rocky, how do you expect
to fight Apollo Creed?
Creed's the best.
I'll do the best I can.
Rocky, just between us,
where did you get
the name ltalian Stallion?
I invented that eight years ago
when I was eating dinner.
Rocky, your pay-day
will be $1 50,000.
Any comment?
You got no comment,
Rocky, right?
- No.
- No comment. Thank you.
I want to say "Hi"
to my girlfriend.
Yo, Adrian. It's me, Rocky.
Do you believe all this?
- Thank you, Rocky.
- Quit pushing, man!
He's making you out a fool.
I'd break his lips.
Don't bother me.
I guess you'll be looking
for people to help you out.
- Help what?
- Keep you living a clean life.
I do OK, you know.
You need someone
to help with the exercise
or stand by with a towel.
Who cared about me
yesterday?. Nobody.
I'll train myself.
Without good people to help,
you don't have
such a good chance.
Einstein flunked
out of school twice.
That so?
Yeah. Beethoven was deaf.
Helen Keller was blind.
Rocky's got a good chance.
Want me to get you a beer?
Want to do a good deed?
Keep out of my life!
- Did I say something wrong?
- You didn't say nothing.
Right! You didn't
say nothing at all!
I got to go.
Where's the freakin' pretzels?
Where's the pretzels?
Ain't we got any beer?
You were supposed
to pick up some beer.
How'd you like hearing
your name on TV?
I was shocked.
Why did you do that?
You're putting me on.
Absolutely.
What time should I expect you?
About 7.00.
You know how I said that stuff
on TV didn't bother me?
Yeah.
It did.
I want to know if you got
any money for training expenses.
- I got a few dollars.
- Put this in your glove.
- What's this?
- 500 bucks.
You ain't never had any luck,
but this time Lady Luck
may be in your corner.
Maybe. Thanks
for the money, Tony.
- Don't worry about it.
- Thanks a lot.
- Hey, wait a minute.
- What?
You're in training.
- Yo, Tony.
- What?
You coming to the fight?
Ringside.
I'll see ya.
Yeah?
Hello, kid. I seen
your light. Can I come in?
- Yeah, sure.
- Yeah, good.
This is a nice place.
All right, anyway.
I came to tell you
that what happened to you
is freak luck.
- Yeah, freak luck.
- Look at the other guys.
They're good fighters.
They're colourful.
They fight their guts
out for peanuts.
But you get a shot at the title.
Freak luck is a strange thing.
- Can I sit down?
- Sure.
- What the hell are those?
- They're domestic turtles.
One is Cuff
and the other is Link.
They make good soup.
Look, I'm here to warn you
to be very careful
about this shot you got,
because, like the Bible says,
you won't get a second chance.
Yeah. All right.
You thought of that?
Well, what you need
is a manager.
I know because I've been
in this racket for 50 years.
- 50 years?
- God, I've seen it all.
All of it.
You know what I done?
I have done it all.
You should have seen me knock
Guinea Russell out of the ring.
That's September 1 4th, 1 923,
the same night Firpo knocks
Dempsey out of the ring.
So who gets the publicity?
- Dempsey.
- Right, but why?
- 'Cause he was champ.
- No, 'cause he had a manager!
I had nothing.
I want you to look at my face.
I got 2 1 stitches
over this left eye.
I got 34 stitches over this eye.
I had my nose busted 1 7 times.
The last time was with
that fight with Sailor Mike.
I got the clipping here.
Want to read that?
Well, it doesn't matter.
Anyway, he put
this vegetation on my ear.
You kind of remind me
of the Rock.
- You really think so?
- Right.
You move like him,
and you got heart.
I got heart,
but I ain't got no locker.
Uh, anyway...
When I begun
in this business, kid...
Look, kid, I want
to make a suggestion.
Don't drink that piss
before a fight.
If you don't mind my saying.
When I started this racket,
us pugs were treated like dogs.
For 1 0 bucks, you got
to tear somebody's throat out.
One time, this son
of a bitch that I fought
put a nail right there.
- His thumb?
- Yeah, the glove.
He punched holes in my face.
I spat through my cheeks.
Can you imagine that?
I'll tell you what
I looked like in my prime.
I want you to look at something.
That's the way I looked
before these guys got at me.
You didn't take very good
care of the picture.
I never had no management,
that's the trouble.
I got all this
knowledge up here.
I want to give it to you.
I want to make sure all
the shit that happened to me
doesn't happen to you.
The fight's set.
I want to be your manager.
- You follow that?
- I don't need no manager.
You can't buy
what I'm gonna give you.
- I got pain and experience.
- I got that too.
Now, listen, kid...
- Hey, Mick.
- What?
I needed your help
about 1 0 years ago.
You never helped me.
If you wanted help,
why didn't you just ask me?
I asked, but you
never heard nothing.
I know l...l'm 76 years old.
Took him 1 0 years
to come to my house.
What's the matter,
you don't like my house?
My house stinks?
Right, it stinks!
I didn't ask
no favours from you!
Talk about your prime.
What about my prime, Mick?
At least you had a prime.
I ain't had nothing!
Legs are going,
everything's going.
Guy offers me a fight.
I'll fight the big fight.
I'm gonna go
and fight that big fight.
I'm gonna get that!
And you want to be
ringside and see it?
Want to see me
get my face kicked in?
Go on, fight the champ!
Yeah, I'll fight him.
Get my face kicked in.
You want to move
in here with me?
Come on! It's a nice house.
Come on in.
It stinks!
This whole place stinks.
Want to help me out?
Well, help me out.
I'm standing here.
It's only about 28 degrees.
We'll check that forecast.
I'm feeling very weird.
I got vinyl seats in my car.
When I hit those seats
this morning, I went, whoo!
If I'm up, everybody in the
Delaware Valley should be up.
At 4.03 in the morning,
what else can you do?
Mrs Kramer,
this is Don Cabot, WYBG.
You have a lot of nerve
calling me at this hour!
Goodbye.
We got Mrs Kramer up,
and it's a good morning.
28 degrees,
and it's cold out there.
Our high today
could possibly be 30.
Tonight, we're back down
in the 20-degree range.
Tomorrow, we may hit 40.
It's awfully chilly, so make
sure you have it bundled up.
It stinks in here, you know?
Yeah, I know.
Did you kill all these things?
No. Across the street.
Place is like an animal morgue.
It's a little cold, isn't it?
Yeah.
Who killed all these things?
Are you crazy?.
Pay Gazzo or end up on the hook.
- Gazzo's a good man.
- I know that.
Talk to him about me
and the collecting job.
Get me out of this freezer.
You should keep this job
because you eat better.
Does it ever snow in here?
You and my sister, how are you
getting along together?
- How you think?
- I'm not sure, Rock.
What's the story?
About what?
What's happening?
- You really like her?
- Sure I like her.
What's the attraction?
I don't know.
Fills gaps, I guess.
What's gaps?
She's got gaps. I got gaps.
Together we fill gaps.
You balling her?
Don't talk dirty
about your sister.
Are you screwing my sister?
That's why I can't
connect you with Gazzo -
because you talk too much.
- It's cold. I'm going home.
- It is cold in here!
It stinks, and you stink.
You're breaking the ribs.
Do that to Apollo Creed
and they'll put us in gaol.
See you tomorrow morning, OK?
- I turned the heat up.
- Thanks.
Your brother's a good man,
but he's awful pushy.
- Want me to rub you down?
- No, I'm just sore.
I'll just sit here.
- You sure?
- I'm sure.
Come on, no fooling around.
I'm tired.
I'm serious.
There's no fooling
around during training.
- You're not kidding.
- I ain't kidding.
- You sure?
- I'm sure.
Just make the meat, OK.
OK, I'll make the meat.
It's OK.
I'm sorry.
Underneath. Underneath.
Come on, come on!
Hold it, Rock!
You're driving me crazy.
You're sloppy because
you're off-balance.
Take this string
and tie it to both ankles.
- I never had good footwork.
- You're off-balance.
Marciano had the same problem,
and this string cured it.
If you can move and you can hit
without breaking the string,
you got balance
and become very dangerous.
You're looking good, Rock.
Thanks.
That's it.
- How about your autograph?
- Get outta here!
Don't interrupt me
while I'm conducting business.
Listen, kid.
Lay off that pet shop dame.
Women weaken legs.
Yeah, but I really
like this girl.
Then let her train you!
OK, no more fooling around.
OK, now hit it.
Women weaken legs, huh?
You look great.
- Really?
- Yeah.
You'll walk down the street
breaking hearts.
You look very sharp.
I got another surprise for you.
What?
Come here, kid.
To keep you company
when you run.
Come and meet the family.
The owner never come back?
He's yours if you want him.
Do I want him? What's he eat?
He eats little turtles.
Whose truck is this?
One call from me,
you're a celebrity.
You need exposure.
Don't breathe on me.
Don't I know about these things?
- No! What do they want?
- To watch you train.
- What's the matter with you?
- I'm doing you a favour.
You're embarrassing me
in front of your sister.
See this cigar?
Stick it in your ear.
You should've called me up.
Don't do that.
My sister really likes you.
I'll kill you one of these days.
Pretty baby!
Here's the next heavyweight
champion of the world.
We want a brief interview.
What about me?
I'm in charge of the meat.
Fine. Stand behind it.
I'm just going
to ask a few questions
about your unique
training method.
Folks want to know
how you got into this.
This isn't an everyday thing.
Rocky, turn around here.
Don't take no cheap shots.
No, I won't. Relax.
We're here with heavyweight
challenger Rocky Balboa...
The meat guy's
sticking his face in.
Let's try it again, Rocky.
We're here with heavyweight
challenger Rocky Balboa.
Mr Balboa has an unusual
method of training.
In a moment, he's going
to demonstrate that.
Rocky, why train in an icebox?
My friend there
let me in one day.
I hit the beef,
and I kind of liked it.
The owner don't mind.
Do other fighters
pound raw meat?
No, I think I invented it.
- Would you demonstrate?
- Sure.
Be sure to fly
my barber to Philly.
How much is being channelled
into closed-circuit advertising?
300,000.
Send the mayor's wife 200 roses
and make sure we get a picture.
Do you want to run
the radio spots in the midwest?
You could spend your money
better in Canada.
My friends in Toronto
could get you tax breaks.
George, I like your friends.
Champ, come look at this
boy you're gonna fight.
- Looks like he means business.
- I mean business too.
- Shirley, any more coffee?
- I'll get you some.
After the fight,
I may just retire.
The gross run
would be based on...
Diana Lewis in the meat house
with southpaw Rocky Balboa.
He called the reporters?
Threw my training schedule off.
He's trying to help.
It's just that
when reporters are around,
I get out of joint
'cause they take cheap shots.
Paulie keeps
asking me for a job,
but he don't know
nothing about fighting.
Are you gonna say anything?
I don't know
what he wants from me.
I don't want nothing from you.
This ain't no charity case.
- Get out of my house.
- It's not just your house.
You're no friend no more.
- Get out of my house,
- Don't talk to him like that.
Both of you get out of my house!
It's cold outside, Paulie.
I don't want you messing her,
and I don't raise you
to go with this bum.
Want to hit on me?
I'll break both your arms.
I'm not good enough for Gazzo!
You're a big-shot fighter,
you don't throw a crumb
to your friend Paulie.
- I even give you my sister.
- Only a pig would say that!
I'm a pig.
A pig gets you the best?
I don't get married
because of you.
You can't live by yourself.
I put you two together.
You owe me!
- You owe me!
- What do I owe you?
You're supposed
to be good to me.
What do I owe you, Paulie?
I treat you good!
I cook for you!
I pick up your dirty clothes.
I take care of you, Paulie.
I owe you nothing.
You made me feel like a loser.
I'm not a loser!
- You're busted.
- What?
You're not a virgin! You let
him take down your pants.
She's busted!
I can't help it no more.
You want a room-mate?
Absolutely.
OK, when you walk into the ring
with the number one
heavyweight of the world,
you'll be ready.
Why? Because I waited
for 50 years to make you ready.
You'll be able to spit nails.
You're gonna eat lightning,
and crap thunder.
You'll become
a very dangerous person.
Rock, I want you to meet
our cut man, AI Savani.
Take a look at his eye.
I've seen worse.
You ain't so bad yourself.
- Cover up.
- You cover up.
- Go and take a shower.
- I'll see you tomorrow.
You covered that
Whitmore fight, didn't you?
That's why you wanted me.
We got a winner here.
He goes to the body
like nobody you've seen.
You just stand by.
We're gonna win.
It's OK I talk to you?
OK you talk to me? Sure.
I figured some angle to make
some money off your name.
- My name? How's that?
- Advertising.
I know about that stuff.
What do you know
about advertising?
You can make money
off my name, make it.
I'm gonna take a shower.
- Help me off with these.
- Sure.
You're gonna kill him.
Rocky, what brings
you here tonight?
- The poster's wrong.
- What do you mean?
I'm wearing white pants
with a red stripe.
It doesn't
really matter, does it?
You'll give us a great show.
Try to get some rest, kid.
Good night.
I can't do it.
What?
I can't beat him.
- Apollo?
- Yeah.
I've been out there
walking around, thinking.
Who am I kidding? I ain't
even in the guy's league.
What are we gonna do?
I don't know.
You worked so hard.
Yeah. It don't matter
'cause I was nobody before.
- Don't say that.
- Come on, Adrian, it's true.
I was nobody.
That don't matter
either, you know?
'Cause I was thinking,
it really don't matter
if I lose this fight.
It don't matter
if this guy opens my head.
'Cause all I want to do
is go the distance.
Nobody's ever gone
the distance with Creed.
And if I can go
that distance, see,
and that bell rings
and I'm still standing...
I'm gonna know for
the first time in my life
that I weren't just another
bum from the neighbourhood.
Time, kid. Let's go.
I'll wait for you here.
How about I wait here
and you fight?
You're looking very great today.
I gotta go now,
but don't you leave town.
Wish me luck. I need it.
Good luck.
You don't think
this robe is too baggy?
Good luck.
Don't leave town.
Working the fight
with me tonight, Stu Nahan.
The electricity is
everywhere as Rocky Balboa...
What the hell is that?
You're not a billboard.
It's for a friend.
Paulie gets three grand.
I get the robe.
Shrewd.
You could quote a sports
magazine, which said
"Could be the cave man
against the cavalier."
Notice that buzzing.
The challenger getting ready
to enter the ring...
My date cost me $200.
I gotta work.
- How's the robe?
- A little baggy.
A 50-to- 1 underdog
living a Cinderella story.
He's captured people's
imaginations all over the world.
We love you, Rocky!
- Good luck, champ.
- Thanks for showing up.
His record, 44 victories,
38 by knockout.
and he's lost 20 fights.
Does he have the stamina
to last three rounds?
Las Vegas odds say no.
Rocky Balboa
climbing into the ring.
The ltalian Stallion.
Some meat sign
on the back of his robe.
A lot of noise
in the background.
There's the spotlight.
Is that the world heavyweight
champion Apollo Creed?
Is he supposed to be George
Washington? Obviously so.
Remember we talked about
Washington throwing a dollar?
In those days, it went farther.
He's taking off his blond wig.
The crowd is loving
every minute of it.
The world
heavyweight champion...
For you around the world,
he was dressed
as George Washington.
Uncle Sam himself!
I want you! All of you!
He looks like a flag.
- Is he talking to me?
- He's talking to you.
I want the Stallion!
"I want the Stallion."
During World War l,
there was a picture of Uncle Sam
with his finger pointed
like that, a recruiting poster.
"I want you" - that's what
he's doing the take on.
Creed in three.
What do you think
that outfit cost?
Ladies and gentlemen,
good evening.
A very happy New Year.
Welcome to Philadelphia.
Everybody who's anybody
is here tonight.
Time does not permit me
to introduce
the many luminaries of politics,
show business and sport
who are with us tonight.
But I would like to present
one of the immortals
of pugilism,
a champion in
and out of the ring,
Philadelphia's own Smoking Joe,
the beloved Mr Joe Frazier!
- How ya doing?
- How are you?
I'm fine.
Now he's coming
to talk to the champ.
- Hey, Joe.
- You been dumping on me...
- You next, Joe.
- You understand?
They must be friends.
Go, Frazier!
And now for the main event.
The challenger in white trunks,
weighing 1 90 pounds,
Philadelphia's favourite son,
The ltalian Stallion,
Rocky Balboa.
And on my right,
wearing red, white and blue,
weighing 2 1 0 pounds,
undefeated in 46 fights,
the Master of Disaster,
the undisputed heavyweight
champion of the world,
Apollo Creed!
You, chump! I want YOU!
No low blows.
Watch your heads. No butting.
Shake hands, come out fighting.
Put your hands up there, chump.
Rocky's just going over
and being calm.
There goes the big hat.
Never seen a fighter
that concerned about his hair.
There's the bell for round one.
Fighters come into
the centre of the ring.
Rocky looks like he's blocking
the blows with his face.
The champion doesn't look
the best he's ever been,
but he's moving.
The champion is smiling.
He's toying with this man,
giving the fans
their money's worth.
He's making a show of it.
Rocky looks ready
to challenge him now.
The champ is taunting him.
He's dancing around.
The champ is down!
Creed is down!
What a surprise this is.
It's the first time the
champion has been knocked down.
Holy Toledo.
He's giving him the count!
Let's go to work
right now, Rock!
Now Rocky coming back out.
He's like a bull
in a china closet.
And our champion's coming back.
That's the Apollo we know.
The champ is taunting Rocky
to come in for more.
Rocky's coming back now.
Rocky's got him on the rope!
There's no way he expected
this kind of hitting power.
Apollo driving him
against the ropes.
Rocky can hardly find his way.
I told ya!
Your nose is broke.
It's an improvement.
Quit jiving. Stick and move.
Go for the ribs.
Don't let him breathe.
The guy is great.
He doesn't know
it's a damn show.
He thinks it's a damn fight.
Finish this bum.
Stay to the body. The body!
Round two. Creed predicted
he'd win in three.
The champion's got him
backed in the corner.
Balboa's taking
a tremendous beating here.
His face is like
a punching bag.
What's keeping him up?
Stop playing around.
He says he wants more!
You folks with television,
you're watching a battle.
Balboa trying to fight back.
The champion can't
get out of there.
Balboa smacks him on the kisser.
They're ready to keep going.
This'll be a tough one.
What is keeping him up, Bill?
I don't know.
Can't even get his gloves up.
Stay down!
Apollo with his arms in the air.
Five...
Six...
Seven...
Eight... Nine...
Come on.
Apollo can't believe it!
The champion got
a left to the right rib.
- You OK, Champ?
- I'm OK.
I can't see. Open my eye.
Cut me, Mick.
- Don't want to.
- Cut me. Cut me.
Cut it!
I'm gonna stop the fight.
You ain't stopping nothing, man!
You stop this fight,
I'll kill you.
- I'm going.
- If you wanna go, go!
They look like
they've been in a war.
The champion really tagged him.
Apollo clearly protecting
his right side, his ribs.
Look at the blood coming out.
He's spitting up blood now.
Go for it!
He's got him against the rope.
Apollo the champion...
Ain't gonna be no rematch.
Don't want one.
You went the 1 5 rounds.
How do you feel?
All right.
Adrian!
- When the 1 5th round...
- Adrian!
Rocky.
Rocky!
You've had the privilege
of witnessing
the greatest exhibition
of guts and stamina
in the history of the ring.
We have a split decision...
Apollo Creed!
There won't be a rematch.
I've had enough of this
for one day! Adrian!
That's my friend. Rocko!
You're ripping the jacket.
Paulie?
- I love you!
- I love you.
I love you, Rocky.
I love you! I love you!
www.nieco.com
text nieco nieco