Where you headed, little lady?
Nowhere with you, numb nuts.
Buzz off!
See you Thursday, gorgeous!
It's a pretty day to hitchhike.
I've got a little VW
at Stinson Beach with a cracked block.
You wouldn't be going
to Mill Valley, would you?
Aren't we going to Mill Valley?
Got a couple bottles of
ice-cold beer up there.
You son of a bitch.
Okay, pile in!
How long you been with
Western Gas and Electric?
I can't remember how long.
How long I been in this?
Turn in here.
Climb up this road here.
I'll be right with you.
Hang a left here, Harry,
there's a jam on Bay.
What's with the citizen?
- Police officer, what's the problem?
- Thank God! He's inside!
Come on, it's a heart attack!
Wait here.
Make some room! Move aside!
Move aside.
This is an emergency!
Please move over!
Please give us room.
He's a police officer.
- Where's the ambulance?
- He had a heart attack.
He's still breathing, though.
Come on, get up.
Get up!
Get up, get up!
I say!
- Party's over.
- Thanks a lot, Harry.
Why are you squawking?
You got the free meal.
But I always enjoy
the ride in the ambulance.
Get out of here.
Harry, it's an all-units.
Marvelous.
My old lady will kill me.
She's doing a novena tonight
and I said I'd be home for supper.
Suspects are armed.
Code 33.
Inspector 71 responding to your 406.
What's going on?
Bastards held up that liquor store.
One of our guys stumbled in
and they shot him.
They have four hostages.
They'll shoot them
unless we give them a car.
What're you waiting on?
Lieutenant Brannigan.
He said to stall until he gets here.
- Don't let them kill me!
- We want the goddamn car right now!
Okay, but you get nothing
till I come and talk.
Lay your piece on that car's hood!
What about me? I'm your partner.
I move fast. I don't need
extra linguini holding me back.
You got a lot of class, Harry.
You get cute, I blow this nice lady
all over you. Let's go.
On the floor, motherfucker.
For God's sake, do like he says!
- This is my best jacket.
- Get on the floor, you son of a bitch!
Spreadeagle! Move it!
Get down there.
San Francisco's finest.
Mitch.
Roll him over.
He's clean.
Here's the story.
First, we want all the pigs
out of here.
Second, we want a car...
...with a police radio.
Deliver it right out there in front.
We're taking two hostages.
Both the women.
You don't do what I tell you,
we blow their fucking heads off.
- You got the picture?
- Yeah.
What are you waiting for?
Run, you jive-ass bastard.
- What do they want?
- They want a car.
What are you going to do?
Give them one.
You son of a bitch!
Why's a man crazy enough
to join the cops?
If you find out, you let me know.
$ 14,379.
- How's that?
- Want an itemized account?
You took out two doors,
one window, 12 feet of counter...
...plus damages to the stock.
Plus one city vehicle totaled.
And three hostages in the hospital
who will probably sue the city.
- Why?
- Excessive use of force.
For your information, Callahan...
...the minority community
hates this kind of police work.
By "minority community"
you mean the hoods?
So happens they're
American citizens too.
- The lady with the gun by her ear?
- I'm not debating this.
I've spoken to the mayor twice!
He went through the ceiling!
You mention the meeting?
- What?
- The meeting two months ago...
...when you said priority was
to run the hoods out.
Not with violence!
Should I yell "trick-or-treat"?
Come on.
I expect you
and everyone on this force...
...to be restrained
or turn in his resignation.
You're on notice, Harry.
That wild west show of yours
is exactly what...
...this department's
not going to tolerate!
Is that clear?
Yes, sir.
- Lf that's all, I've work to do.
- Not in homicide.
What?
You're transferred to personnel.
To personnel? That's for assholes.
I was in personnel for ten years.
Yeah.
That's it!
Report tomorrow to the oral
examining board, 9:00!
No, you haven't got the picture.
I'm the robber, you're the cop.
Now, I'm in a market.
You've just caught me.
A 211 in the act.
I'm coming out with a hostage:
A kid with a gun at his head.
There's no way to take me alive.
You have ten seconds to decide.
What do you do?
One...
...two, three...
- You're under arrest.
...four, five...
- Do something!
...six, seven.
Don't just stand there,
goddamn it, do something!
Bang, you're dead.
- You're late, Callahan.
- Sorry.
- Hello, Krause.
- Hi.
Okay, Bustanoby,
you'll be given your grade.
You were told 9:00.
We have 50 officers to test.
- For how many vacancies?
- Eight.
Five men and three women
promoted to inspector in this group.
- Three women?
- Do you object, inspector?
Now who might you be?
Ms. Grey, from the mayor's staff.
She's to monitor the exams.
- This is Inspector Callahan.
- Yes, I know something of him.
And I'd like to tell you...
...the mayor's plan is to bring
this department into...
...the mainstream of
twentieth-century thought.
How does he figure to do that?
For one thing...
...His Honor intends to...
...broaden participation
for women in the police force.
Well, that sounds very stylish.
He also said something about...
...winnowing the Neanderthals
out of the department.
Well, we better move along.
Next applicant.
- Officer Moore?
- Yes, sir.
This is the final stage
in the examination.
It's an informal test to measure
your ability to think on your feet.
Your reaction to stress, pressure.
Your ability to use the law
in a hypothetical situation.
Yes, sir.
How long on the force?
- Nine years.
- What department?
Mainly Personnel and Records.
- Personnel and Records.
- Yes, sir.
Have you any questions
for the applicant?
Questions...
How fast do you run the hundred?
Come on, you know
how this board functions.
All right, I'm sorry.
You know...
...if you're inspector under
the new guidelines...
...you might be out
riding in a police car.
Yes, sir, that's what I hope for.
Officer Moore, tell us about...
...your greatest felony arrest.
I've never made a felony arrest.
Well, tell us about
your best misdemeanor arrest.
I've never made a
misdemeanor arrest either.
What gives you the right
to be an inspector...
...when men have been
working 15 years!
Women stay home,
is that what you're saying?
You think it's an encounter group?
What will she do
if someone points a gun...
...and says, "Hit the deck"?!
You're trying to fail
this candidate, aren't you?
If she fails there,
she gets her ass blown off!
It's my ass!
And my hard luck.
Out there you'll have a partner.
You get blown away, he does too!
That's some price to pay
for being stylish!
Are you finished with the questioning?
Hypothetical situation, huh?
I'm standing on a corner
and Mrs. Grey propositions me...
...saying for $5.00
she'll put on a show...
...with a Shetland pony.
- Lf this is your idea of humor...
All right, what are you doing here?
Seeing if you know
what law's being broken...
...besides cruelty to animals.
That's a conspiracy,
title 7-182-1...
...of the California penal code.
Conspiracy to commit a misdemeanor...
...is a felony, and according to...
- Yes. Good answer.
Officer Moore,
you'll be given your grade.
After I get the guard's keys...
...we drive to the end,
warehouse 50-A. Lalo?
All right, now, that's...
...I drop you off at the small door
and go around...
...to the wharf side.
You open up the first big door.
I drive in and back up to
the compound on the right.
Karl and Tex?
Man, we grab
the M-16 automatic rifles.
Wanda?
Locate and take any explosives.
Dynamite, detonators, and plastics.
Right. Henry Lee?
I tote and load the ammo
for the M-16s, okay, man?
Miki?
Locate the L.A.W. Rockets.
They'll be in the back.
It's the most important item.
You sure of the location?
I sweated there for five years!
They're there, I promise!
All right, you guys.
- This is for the people!
- Right on, for the people.
Jesus, spare me.
- What is it?
- Gas company.
- Why?
- Major gas leak in the area.
We'll check underground pipes.
Don't smoke until we say it's okay!
I won't, I won't.
It's seeping down in the earth.
This whole damn block could go!
- Got a phone I can use?
- Right this way.
Let's go.
Charlie left the gate open.
Better check it.
Tony, call backup.
- I'll check around.
- Frank, watch yourself.
L.A.W.S. Rocket.
- Beautiful!
- Yes.
Lalo, get the rest of these loaded.
You'll blow us out of here!
You all right?
Let us get these.
Freeze.
Hold it right there!
Put those boxes down.
You back there.
Stand up so I can see you.
And drop that gun!
Put your hands over your head
and freeze!
- Now, wait a second.
- You shut up and listen.
You blink an eyelid
and I'll mail you home in a box!
All of you, against the fence!
Now!
You too, honey!
Oh, Jesus! Miki! Miki!
Oh, my God. Oh, Jesus.
Baby, I'll get you out.
I'll get you home.
Bobby, help get her up.
- You'll get us caught.
- No, we'll make it.
- She's dead.
- She's not dead!
The hell she isn't!
Come on, it's over.
Bobby.
Get it on there.
Lalo, get up in there! Come on!
Halt, police! Halt, or I'll fire!
I'll get this son of a bitch!
Goddamn it!
He said it looked like
a regular company truck.
I'm asking the
Marin County sheriff.
Might tie in with the two bodies
found there last week.
Yes, sir.
How's DiGeorgio?
Well, Irene's with him now.
Is that some kind of answer?
He's been given the last rites.
- Get what you can.
- I will.
Listen, I'm sorry.
Hello, Harry.
He's been asking for you.
How is he?
He's in and out.
I'll smoke a cigarette.
It's a war, isn't it?
I guess I never really
understood that.
Harry.
Frank, what happened?
I had them, dead bang. And then I...
Sorry.
Frank?
Something you want to tell him?
Harry, listen, the punk who cut me...
...I seen him before.
- Where?
I just can't make the name.
Where do you know him from, Frank?
That homicide...
...young hooker...
...in the Fillmore area.
The summer of '71.
- What about it?
- He was one of the pimps questioned.
Liked him for it, Harry.
We liked him real good.
We liked everybody
north of Market on that one.
He had one of them cute,
little-boy names...
...Charlie something, or Bobby.
I'll check Records.
They'll have your notes.
Ten-to-one they blow it.
Not this time, Frank.
Maybe you better get some rest.
- Do you have to go just yet?
- Not if you don't want me to.
Thanks, Harry.
Get Irene.
- Talk to Records?
- Not yet. That was McKay.
We got a tape from the bastards.
I'll see you in 30 minutes.
Code Blue, Intensive Care.
30 minutes.
One million dollars
or we blow things up.
People's Revolutionary Strike Force.
Remember Fessenheim.
"Fessenheim"?
It's being checked.
People's Revolutionary Strike Force.
They on your list?
Nothing.
- Think it's legit?
- Probably not.
Lieutenant Bressler in Homicide.
What are you doing
about those records?
What do you mean?
I just talked to you about them!
Homicide! Fillmore District!
Inspectors Callahan and DiGeorgio.
What do you mean, "written request"?
Well, who's got the keys?
I'm coming down there
in five minutes...
...you get those files open,
you pencil-pushing son of a bitch!
- You don't have to make threats.
- I'm gonna nail the guy...
...who carved DiGeorgio
on my own time!
That's unnecessary...
...you're back in Homicide
since 9, didn't you know?
I've been down in Records
looking up a homicide.
Any luck?
Well, I've got eleven names
of known pimps.
- I think our man's one of them.
- Judson, Maddox, Skidmore.
Shall I tell you my instinct on this?
- Black Militants.
- No, it's all hookers.
The girl shot in the warehouse?
Miki Waleska.
A known prostitute.
What we've got is a
well-organized group of militants...
...with enough explosives to blow
San Francisco away...
...including L.A.W.S. Rockets.
- L.A.W.S. Rockets?
The Army's giving a demonstration
at the firing range...
...in exactly 35 minutes.
I'd like everybody
on the case there...
...to see what you're against.
I've already been checked out
on the L.A.W.S. Rocket.
Your partner hasn't.
My partner?
Shit!
You know Inspector Moore?
Inspector.
I'll see you at the firing range.
Inspector?
Inspector, I know you aren't
overjoyed by this assignment.
- You don't think I'm up to it, do you?
- Right.
All right...
...let's get one thing straight.
I'm a woman.
I consider that fact irrelevant...
...because I don't expect
any special consideration.
Marvelous.
The L.A.W.S. Rocket: For all purposes...
...a one-shot disposable bazooka.
A fiberglass tube, 45 inches long...
...which fires a single projectile...
...designed to penetrate armor
three-quarters of an inch thick.
If you've all seen it,
I'll demonstrate how it works.
To fire the rocket, pull this pin...
...dropping the cover...
...then pull.
Front and rear sights spring up.
Got word from Pathology.
At noon they're posting the guard
that was killed. Check on it.
I'll be there.
- Captain?
- Go ahead.
Keep your eyes on that truck...
...I'll show how effective
this weapon can be.
Coming, inspector?
- Inspector?
- Yeah?
- 13.5 in my gym shorts.
- What?
My time in the hundred.
You asked me before.
- Think I was picking on you?
- Yes.
- It was nothing personal.
- Right.
I don't think you know
what Homicide does.
- I'll find out.
- I hope not the hard way.
How fast do you run the hundred?
Beats me.
I meant to say I'm sorry
about your partner.
He's not the first one.
Fanducci in '68 and Smith in '72,
but it wasn't your fault.
- How'd you know?
- Checked your records.
I don't want to get killed either.
What's the matter?
Black guy with the briefcase.
I know him.
- Tan suit?
- Yeah.
What did he do?
Can't remember. It's not important.
- Ever been to one of these before?
- No.
In that case, I'd suggest
you sit out here.
Don't concern yourself, inspector.
Hello, Harry.
Who's the pretty lady?
My partner, Inspector Moore.
- You missed most of it.
- We were at the firing range.
I have it on tape.
We finished the abdomen.
The wound matters.
The entry wound
was above the renal area...
...between ribs,
penetrating the chest cavity...
...piercing the lung.
There was also damage
to some other organs...
...pancreas, kidneys.
- What kind of knife?
- A long, heavy blade.
We're going in the skull now.
I'd say it was one of those
killing knives...
...a Marine Corps boy,
or Special Forces.
Bruises on the face?
The killer put his hand
over the mouth from behind.
- Professional?
- Textbook.
On first exam,
no exterior damage to the skull.
Subject brain shows no
contrecoup damage or clotting.
Jesus H. Christ, come look at this!
- It's the damnedest thing I ever saw.
- What?
It says "Eat at Luigi's!"
Welcome to Homicide.
What are you doing?
Excuse me, I'm with him.
I was coming down the hall
to take a leak when it blew!
Anybody in there?
- I don't think so.
- Where you going?
A group of kids, some are missing.
- Help him out.
- Me?
Great, just step out here, will you?
Well, we were lucky this time.
It's getting so you can't
even pee in peace.
- We got them, they're okay.
- Good.
You didn't...
...see anybody go in there, did you?
- No.
You sure? Black guy,
tan hat and suit, briefcase.
- I saw a guy like that.
- Short guy, about 5' 1 "?
No, this dude was six foot.
That's him.
It's a bomb. I saw who did it.
- Any idea?
- Looked familiar.
Just a minute.
You'd better check mug shots.
Honey, we're talking.
This is very important.
Better check mug shots,
we got another message.
They want two million.
- Two?
- I just saw him.
- Who?
- Tan suit, hat, and a briefcase.
- Where?
- Right down here.
- Why the hell didn't you tell me?
- Why the hell didn't you ask?
There he is, look!
Jesus!
Damn it.
What the hell's going on?
What are you doing here?
- Who are you?
- Police officer.
Speedy, you're under arrest.
God, this is a church!
What are you doing?
I'm a cop. He's under arrest.
Father, I did nothing!
This guy's rousting me!
Is it asking too much
to see a badge, officer?
He runs like a rabbit, I won't let go.
I'd like to see the badge now!
If you insist.
- Callahan, Inspector.
- Callahan...
...you're a disgrace to this city!
Okay! Nobody move!
Marvelous.
I think so.
Harry, wait, I'm talking to...
Jesus Christ!
Give him my best.
I'll call you back!
It's been disarmed
by the bomb squad.
It's the explosive from
the Hamilton Firearms works.
At times I can only
stand you as a human.
What about the punk?
- The suspect.
- "Suspect," my ass!
He won't talk, but we have a make.
He's Henry Lee Caldwell.
Member of a Black Militant group
called Uhuru.
- Pusseau, shelve that.
- Uhuru?
It's run by a guy called
Big Ed Mustapha.
Mustapha, in the Mission District.
I thought he was familiar.
Where's my partner?
She's in the can.
Been there since she found out...
...she was packing this thing
all over San Francisco!
Do me a favor. Go easy on her.
It's her first day
and it's been a long one.
She wants to play lumberjack,
she has to handle her end of the log.
I give up. What's this?
The Fillmore chapter of the V.F. W:
Very Few Whites.
Can I suggest you wait in the car,
inspector?
Don't concern yourself, inspector.
Well, if it ain't
Mighty Whitey and friend.
I'm looking for Big Ed Mustapha.
Sorry, honky, she can stay,
but you got to go.
Yeah, baby, we trying to keep up
standards, understand.
- You aren't making us welcome.
- You're welcome!
As welcome as a turd in a pool!
Well, look here, if it ain't the fuzz.
I'm looking for Ed Mustapha.
- You got a warrant, honky?
- What I got is Henry Lee Caldwell.
I never heard of him.
Let's see how fast you fuzz
can get your white asses out.
What is Henry Lee into now?
He's playing with dynamite.
You Mustapha?
Yeah, that's right.
Just come into my office here.
Just you.
Don't worry, pig,
she won't get lonesome.
That's mighty white of you.
Before we do anything uncalled-for...
...I'd like to point out
that I'm an officer.
Callahan.
Where do I know you from?
You don't.
I just know you.
Now, what's Henry Lee been up to?
Saying you don't know?
He don't come around here,
not for a long time.
Where is he?
He went white.
Why, he do something else foolish?
He and his friends helped
rip off the Hamilton Firearms.
I heard about that.
You wanna buy into that?
Four counts of murder,
aiding and abetting?
You got the wrong number, boy.
We don't deal in violence.
- What do you deal in?
- Waiting.
For what?
Waiting for all you honkies...
...to blow each other up
so we can move on in.
Talk about Henry Lee
and his friends.
Some dudes he met in Vietnam. Why?
Anybody on this list here grab you?
Hey, man, why should I help you?
I can talk to Robbery.
They'd be interested in this...
...elaborate furnishing.
What are you talking about?
"Room 401, Fairmont. "
"Rest at the Holiday Inn. "
Okay, okay, okay, so?
Maybe they're a little warm.
I tell you what...
...one of my boys got busted
on possession.
You get him off, and ignore
my interior decorator...
...and I'll see what I can do.
- That's a lot.
- You want a lot.
A thing like this can ruin my image.
I'll see what I can do.
What about the list?
Bobby Maxwell.
- He's the main man.
- You know him?
Stone waste of white.
Where can I find him?
I'll check around.
You do that. Much obliged.
Callahan, you're on the wrong side.
How do you figure that?
You put your ass on the line...
...for dudes who wouldn't
let you in the door any more...
...than they would me.
- It's not for them.
- Who, then?
You wouldn't believe me if I told.
...if I pull this piece...
- Having fun, inspector?
If you're done socializing,
we have work to do.
Son of a bitch.
If you have an objection
to how I handled myself...
...I wish you'd say so!
I thought I was doing all right.
Marvelous.
All right, Mustapha...
...this is Captain McKay
of the S.F.P.D.
Throw down your weapons
and come out peacefully.
You are totally surrounded.
Mustapha, do you hear me?
Come out with your hands raised
over your head.
I don't want to seem ungrateful...
...I just feel that
it might be better.
Well, I'm still a little confused...
...you and the S.W.A.T. Team
did it...
...but credit goes to
Moore and Callahan?
I felt it might be a better tactic...
...politically, with
the election coming up...
...to show the guidelines for
the police department worked.
Kind of "I told you so,"
if you know what I mean.
Yes, I see. It's an excellent idea.
What do you think, Jimmy?
I couldn't agree more.
You have proved to be an asset...
...to the force and
the administration.
Thank you.
The commendation presentation
starts in five minutes.
- We better get going.
- Thanks, Jimmy.
Off the record,
there will be changes...
...after the election,
and you'll figure greatly in my plans.
I'm sure you'll make
the right decision.
Can you comment on the
arrest of the Black Militants?
Later, Jim, later.
As mayor of San Francisco,
I want to make it official.
This is one hell of a cop!
And here come a couple more.
Hello. Right this way.
Lt. Bressler, Inspector Moore,
move to the stairs.
Mayor, would you join them?
We'll have some photographs taken.
- Is this all right?
- Yes.
Would you move in a little tighter?
Gentlemen, the inspectors who made
the Mustapha arrest.
This is Inspector Moore and Callahan.
How about one with
the mayor and Inspector Moore?
Captain McKay, switch places
with Inspector Moore?
Move in close.
Callahan, you get in there too.
We're ready.
Inspector Moore is one of
the first of her sex...
...to become a homicide investigator.
We're very proud of her
stunning professionalism.
Thank you very much.
Jimmy, give me time with these people.
Certainly. Can we move to the right?
I'll see you at the conference.
Anybody have the
letters of commendation?
- Jimmy?
- Yes, sir?
- Who's got the letters?
- Right here.
- Wait, what's this?
- Some form letters.
So you hand them
something for the cameras.
Well, all right.
Thank you, Jimmy.
The Mayor will introduce you,
hand you the letters...
...and then move
to the left off-camera.
I'll take this opportunity...
...to deliver a boot in the rear...
...to the people who think
the force has failed...
...under this administration.
Two minutes, Mr. Mayor.
Well, ready? Let's go.
- Just one minute, Mr. Mayor.
- Harry!
Can you tell me what these are for?
- Wait until after the broadcast.
- No.
All right, just watch it.
He has a right to know
what he's being commended for.
Specifically, it's for your part in
smashing the group of terrorists...
...who were trying to blackmail
the city out of two million dollars.
Let's look at...
If you mean Mustapha,
nobody smashed a thing.
I made a deal with Mustapha
to help me find them.
- Moore and I weren't there.
- What's he mean?
- No weapons or explosives were found?
- We'll find them!
They're still out there!
They'll blow the city!
You're saying how great we are.
Callahan, button your lip!
Don't jerk them off with me!
- You got yourself a 60-day suspension!
- Make it 90!
180! Give me your star!
Here's a seven-point suppository,
captain.
- What did you say?
- I said stick it in your ass.
- Mayor, you're on.
- I know, Jimmy, I know.
I'll have to go down there...
Go down there and jerk them off.
Inspector!
Inspector Callahan!
Damn it, Harry, slow down!
What's the matter?
Nothing!
Why aren't you getting
your commendation?
- Do you ever give up?
- Sometimes.
Not you.
What makes you think so?
Woman's intuition.
If you need anything or
if there's anything I can do...
...access to records or files...
...anything. Call me up.
I might just do that.
Fine.
Any time.
- Come on, take a walk.
- All right.
I wonder if I'll still have a job
when I get back.
What's the difference?
Why'd you want to be a cop, anyway?
Why don't you marry and have kids?
Why aren't you?
Nobody in their right mind's asking.
- Coitus interruptus.
- I beg your pardon?
Coit Tower.
It's vaguely phallic, don't you think?
Never thought of it that way.
I make up names for things.
You're "Cold, Bold Callahan"
with a great big. 44.
Every other cop is satisfied
with a. 38 or a. 357...
...why must you carry that cannon?
So I can hit what I aim at.
.357 is good, but I've seen 38s
careen off windshields.
No good in the city.
I see. So it's for the penetration.
Does everything have
a sexual connotation?
Only sometimes.
Want to go have a few beers?
You got a lot of nerve the way
you talk to the mayor, and McKay.
They're wrong and stupid.
They got the wrong guy,
but their egos won't admit it.
- You mean Mustapha.
- Yeah.
I had a deal with Mustapha.
He put me onto Bobby Maxwell,
the guy who knifed DiGeorgio.
- Where do we find Maxwell?
- We can't with Mustapha busted.
Maxwell's a prime candidate,
a tough cookie.
Was in Vietnam, likes combat.
He was busted out on a Section Eight.
We're good people.
Let's post Mustapha's bail.
Not a bad idea.
Question is, will he work with us now?
Want to have a few beers?
Why didn't I think of that?
All they had was apple juice.
- Anything's okay.
- Here.
I'm sorry.
You like fishing?
I have an Auntie Kate.
I'm called after her.
When I was a little girl,
she had a ranch in Oroville.
We used to fish.
I'd even bait my own hooks.
Is that what they call you? Kate?
That or Inspector Moore.
Inspector Moore, I don't
get friendly with partners.
I know. I mean, I understand.
Kate...
...whoever gets you as
a partner could do much worse.
I think if we want to beat
the crowds, we should leave.
Think so? You may be right.
I'll see you, Karl.
No need to come with us.
- Take over.
- Take it easy.
You hold on to this.
- Nice to see you!
- We're running late, sir.
All right, talk to me.
- He's on his way.
- Beautiful.
- Everything set?
- I'm ready.
Hi there.
Hello there, young lady.
What can I do for you?
Raise the bridge.
Raise the bridge?
Are you kidding?
When I tell you to.
I wish we could've stayed.
I think the Giants will finally win.
I don't know, mayor, looked like
it would end a no-hitter.
You have the testimonial tonight.
Oh, God, testimonials.
They never end, do they?
Give me the Taser gun.
Karl?
This looks like something from
James Bond.
Sure it'll work?
Karl, there's 25,000 volts
in this thing.
Even the fat boy will do
what we want once we zap him.
Okay, Tex.
Raise it.
What the hell? Get me out of this.
Don't hit the mayor, damn it!
- Who are you? What do you want?
- You.
Son of a bitch!
I'm not going anywhere with you!
The hell you aren't!
We're trying to get details,
and as they come in you'll get them.
They said the mayor was killed.
At first. Then we heard
he was kidnapped.
There's something going on
in China Basin.
I've got to go. Thanks for calling.
You're rapping with Bubba.
The mayor has been taken
prisoner of war...
...by the People's
Revolutionary Strike Force.
Everybody's a comedian.
Look, this is serious!
I'm leaving a tape of our demands
in the phone booth across the street.
Power to the people!
We'll do a little music and
I'll be right back!
Harry?
- What can I do for you?
- We've got to talk.
Go right ahead.
I want all the info that
you have on this case.
- Black Militants, remember?
- Come on, so we were wrong.
- I'll handle this one.
- No! We play as a team.
The last time we did that
I got the cue stuck in my ass.
We just got a tape.
Now they want five million.
Or they send back the mayor in pieces.
The negotiations are crucial now.
What will you do, pay the bastards?
The mayor's family is loaded,
they can afford it.
What about those who were killed?
Isn't that illegal?
We're not debating the point.
You're saying...
...anyone with the balls to take
hostages can walk away?
I'm saying you're out.
If I hear otherwise,
you're finished as a cop here.
I want all the information
you have on this case, every lead.
- May I speak, McKay?
- Go ahead!
Your mouthwash ain't making it!
Callahan...
...you got more surprises for me?
What do you mean?
Are you and McKay throwing another...
...paddy-wagon party for me?
Frigging McKay.
He's something, isn't he?
I want a line on this
Revolutionary Strike Force.
- You gots to be kidding!
- No, I'm not kidding.
If you don't,
I'll say you're an ear.
Hey, don't say that, not even joking.
Who's joking?
You really are a dirty bastard,
ain't you, Harry?
The dirtiest.
Word has it that Bobby Maxwell...
...and his chick Wanda...
...they're running around
calling themselves...
...the People's Revolutionary
Strike Force.
- "Calling themselves"?
- They don't believe in that shit...
...they're into the bread,
that's how they think.
Where do I find this Wanda?
She's a tall brunette, works at
Tiffany's on Broadway.
Thanks.
Callahan.
Do them in.
You can count on that.
Hi there!
- Is this Tiffany's?
- Like the sign says.
I'm Larry Dickman...
...my brother was here,
tall, balding?
Remember him well!
- Has a gold tooth in front?
- That's him.
You know what I bet you'd like?
I bet you want to learn
the love tussle.
That sounds swell,
but I'm looking for a certain girl.
We have many, warm and willing.
- Her name's Wanda.
- Anybody you want.
My brother says she's terrific.
Can I trust you?
Yeah.
What it is, is $ 75.
- $ 75?
- Of course, that includes...
We shouldn't do this,
because the heat's on.
Seeing your brother was here...
...the $ 75 includes
personal instructions...
...in 32 positions of lovemaking!
That many?
$ 75, you pay me first.
Oh, yeah.
Right this way.
What's this?
You've seen dummies.
It's the same principle.
For $ 75 you get to make it
with a rubber dolly.
Thirty-two ways!
Any objections?
Is there one where
the man gets on top?
That's 33!
Take your duds off.
I'll send the teacher in.
- Hi there.
- You're not Wanda.
These are the breaks. Needs air.
Can't hump a limp dummy, I say.
Speaking of limp dummies, strip.
Where's Wanda?
Beats the hell out of me, Tom.
I'll ask you just one last time.
- Where's Wanda?
- I don't know, I don't know.
She left a couple weeks ago.
Ask Buchinski!
He runs the whole street.
- Where's Buchinski?
- Down the hall to the right.
Yes, nearer my God to thee...
...so brother Bob's here.
Brother Bob will bring you to God.
Bring you to the Man
to save your soul.
Salvation is where it's at.
You're trespassing.
This is private property.
- You a lawyer?
- Yes, I am. Whoever you are...
I'm looking for a tall brunette,
Wanda.
I'll tell you something, punk.
It's a protected operation.
You'll end up with
your balls in spaghetti sauce.
You have clout with the syndicate?
I can blow you away with one call,
so get the hell out!
To me, you're just a maggot
who sells dirty pictures.
- Wanda! Where is she?
- Go to hell.
- One more time. Wanda?
- All right, all right.
She quit a few weeks ago,
it's all I know.
She got religion.
- What do you mean?
- Hanging by a church on Garvey.
Have you received another tape
from the People's Strike Force?
- Yes.
- Is the mayor all right?
We've been assured that he's
all right, but there'll be...
...no payment or transportation
until we have...
...seen the mayor.
- Then you're letting them go?
- That's the agreement.
- Any idea where they are?
- Not yet.
We should get one more
message this evening.
- Is Inspector Callahan off this case?
- Sorry, no more questions.
What do you have?
The priest, Father John Voss.
Militant, big in prison reform.
He runs rehab seminars in all
the prisons in this area.
Here's a list of the cons
that took it in San Quentin.
Bobby Maxell never missed a session.
- You wait here.
- Wait.
The new ransom tape
said "Fessenheim" again.
What does that mean?
Last year two bombs blew at a
nuclear plant in Fessenheim, France.
How about that.
The body of Christ.
The body...
Remember me, Father?
Yes.
- What is it you want?
- To talk about Bobby Maxwell.
Then get a warrant.
- Just a minute.
- I thought I made it clear to you.
I have nothing to say to you!
Why do you come here
and harass me in my church?
- Is that a confessional?
- You want to confess?
You first!
Where the hell's Maxwell?
God may forgive, but I...
Why do you protect them?
Many have died.
Sacrifices have to be made!
- The people are at war!
- So am I!
How dare you pull a gun
in the house of God.
If you don't believe in the sanctity...
I don't have time to argue
religion with you!
Look at her hands!
- There wasn't supposed to be killing.
- Is she dead?
I close my eyes to this.
Father in heaven, help.
You can't close your eyes anymore.
Now where's Maxwell?
Alcatraz.
A place to hole up.
It wouldn't do
any good to suggest...
Forget it.
No communications
were received since...
Nothing! You sure Wanda
got those tapes to the cops?
Bobby, I don't know.
I don't know.
I wasn't with her!
- Lf you didn't think she...
- Shut up!
- What're you doing?
- Having some coffee.
Get the hell out of here!
Christ, man, get your ass out there!
Lalo.
Get the mayor, bring him in here.
I'll get the bar.
Get him out of there.
Freeze!
All right, let him go!
Let him go!
Move over there, Your Honor! Fine.
Okay, now, I want you very slowly...
...to put down the weapon...
...then on the deck and spread them.
Are you kidding me?
Laugh at me, bastard,
and I'll shoot you where you stand.
Let's go, Your Honor. Let's go!
Let's get out of here. Now, speed!
Stay with me.
Hold it, hold it.
Just take it very easy.
You relax, do just as I say,
and I'll get you home, all right?
- Yeah.
- Take it slow.
Wait a minute.
Here we go.
Harry, look out!
Oh, Harry, I messed up.
You did just fine, Kate.
I'll get you out of here.
Don't concern yourself, Harry.
Get him.
You can count on it.
Maxwell!
You fucking fruit!
Get up there!
Go on, move!
Karl! Tex!
Karl!
Oh, God!
Callahan, you saved my life.
I can't thank you.
I can't tell you...
There'll be a letter of commendation
there for you.
Callahan! Callahan!
The chopper's here.
Don't you want a ride?
Maxwell...
...Bobby Maxwell,
this is Captain McKay speaking!
We have your money.
The plane's waiting at the airport.
We have acceded to all your demands...
...so release the mayor.
The helicopter will
fly you and your men to safety.