- Kurt, can you hear me?
- Go ahead, Sean.
At about 11 o'clock,
right in the middle of that herd
of wildebeest. See him?
- Now that's a good one.
- Let's go. Start out easy.
OK, Pockets.
This one must be a female, she can't
make up her mind which way to go.
Tell Kurt to let her run a while,
wear her down.
- Sean says give her some exercise.
- That's what we'll do.
Tell us when you want her.
Tell Kurt to take his time.
This is a mean one.
Take your time, Kurt.
Try her, Pockets, move in closer.
See what she's like.
Watch her, Pockets. Don't lose her.
The rhino got the Indian.
Swing around.
Bring the first-aid kit.
Are you trying to get a vacation?
- He hooked me good.
- He did, at that.
- Why didn't you shoot him?
- I didn't know he planned to ride with us.
- You can fix that up, Pockets.
- Big Band-Aid will do it.
- You all right?
- Want to stretch out?
Leave him here. Makes it easier
for me to work. Room, please!
Tough luck.
My fault. I messed it up.
- How is it your fault?
- I was driving, wasn't I?
- The Indian could have shot him.
- You find him again, I'll shoot him.
This tourniquet isn't working.
Better get him to hospital.
- Get him into the catching truck.
- Luis.
- Come on. Give 'em a hand.
- Hold it, buddy.
Easy.
Kurt.
Calling Arusha Control.
Arusha Control speaking. Go ahead.
This is Sean Mercer.
A man's been horned by a rhino.
He's bleeding pretty badly.
Tell Dr Sanderson we'll be at Arusha
hospital in about five hours. Over.
- Will do. Anything else?
- That's all. Over and out.
That hole looks very bad.
It don't look good.
After we get out of here,
push on ahead to the compound.
Pick up Brandy,
she'd want to be at the hospital.
You'll get there as quickly as we do.
- Arga! Where's Missy?
- In room.
No dinner. We're going into town.
The Indian bwana got hurt.
- Bad?
- I don't know yet. Get me some coffee.
Come in.
Hi, Kurt. You're back early.
- Is something wrong?
- Ja.
The Indian... Rhino gored him
in the leg. He lost a lot of blood.
They are taking him into hospital now.
- Must we hurry?
- I came ahead. There's plenty of time.
Thanks for coming for me.
Help me with my zipper, it's stuck.
Come over with me.
How did it happen? Was it
the same way as my father was killed?
No, we hadn't even put a rope on him.
How then?
It was my fault. I got too close.
The engine was spitting a little...
I took the chance and the Indian
was the one that got hurt.
You all take chances.
That's part of the job.
I know, but I shouldn't
have taken that one.
And to pull this thing up here...
I'm afraid of ripping something...
- Here you are.
- Thank you. I'll get a coat.
- How long does it take?
- As long as it takes.
You mean to tell whether
a man can live or not?
Patience, my boy, patience.
Sterling virtue. I wish I had more of it.
All we can do is wait.
Just don't start climbing the walls.
Who's got a cigarette?
- It's yours?
- Thanks.
- Which one is Sean Mercer?
- I am.
- I hear you've got a job open.
- What job?
They said in town
you'd be needing a man.
You're in a rush, aren't you?
Is he asking for the Indian's job?
- He's not dead yet.
- I know that.
I asked for the job
because I was afraid if I waited,
someone else might get it.
- You'd better get out of here.
- I'm not talking to you, I just...
Kurt, take it easy.
When a fellow's hungry... Cut it out!
Damp it! You can't whip us all.
- I can try.
- Bring your lunch.
What's going on here?
I have a patient already.
I don't want any more.
- How is he, Sandy? How's the Indian?
- Not good.
Did it have to be the Indian?
- What do you mean?
- We didn't arrange it.
You seem to take turns getting hurt.
I wish it was someone else.
You all have standard type blood
that's easy to match.
- The Indian has to be different.
- He needs a transfusion?
Plasma is not doing the job.
I need whole blood.
AB negative is not very easy to find.
I'll have to call on...
- What is that for?
- I was thinking...
...you were in a little too much of a hurry.
We are talking about blood type.
Exactly.
You mean, that is your blood type?
AB negative?
That's right.
Well, it seems the Indian's luck
hasn't run out.
- If you're willing...
- He is.
- I will?
- If you want that job.
I don't want anything from you,
including the job.
- You refuse to give him the blood?
- I didn't say that.
But I don't like to be told.
You are going to have to ask me now.
I ask you, please.
I'm sorry, Mademoiselle,
but he's going to have to ask me.
All right. I'm asking you.
This is the way you ask?
- Where do I go?
- In there. Tell the nurse...
- Wait. Tomorrow...
- He won't be going anywhere tomorrow.
When he's through with you,
we'll talk about that job.
I'll think about it. Mademoiselle...
Where did you say to go?
Second door on the left.
Tell the nurse to get you ready.
- Who's he?
- I don't know. I'm glad he's here.
Doc, how long before you can tell us
about the Indian?
Two or three hours. In the meantime,
would you do me a favour?
- Sure, Doc.
- Get out of here.
Leave me in peace. Go have a drink.
I think the Indian will be all right.
- We'll be at the Safari Bar. Coming?
- On the way.
Safari Bar. Yes, sir, they're here.
Hello, Doc. How's the Indian?
Did he have a tough time?
Everything OK? Nothing went wrong?
- He don't say anything.
- Give him a chance and shut up!
He what? Thanks, Doc.
The Indian sat up, asked for a drink
and made a pass at the nurse.
Thanks, Doc. We'll call you tomorrow.
- Youman! Another round.
- Yes, sir.
- Port!
- Port.
- Starboard!
- Starboard.
- Drop it!
- Drop it.
- Breakfast at six.
- It's a challenge we'll try to meet.
- Goodnight, everybody.
- Goodnight.
Goodnight, Brandy.
- Dead ahead, sailor.
- Aye, aye, sir!
Goodnight!
Before you go any further,
I should tell you, you're not alone.
I waited for you. The house boy
was gone and it was getting late.
Hi. I had to sleep somewhere
and I just picked a room.
I suppose I picked yours.
I hope you don't mind.
I don't mind... Who are you?
- Anna Maria D'Alessandro.
- What?
Anna Maria D'Alessandro.
And who are you?
I'm Sean Mercer, but...
What are you doing here?
- Trying to get some sleep.
- I don't mean that, I mean...
- You didn't expect me?
- I sure didn't.
- What's that for?
- I wanted to see if...
...if I was seeing things.
- You've been drinking a little.
No, ma'am. I've been drinking a lot.
Sean, I wanna talk to you about
tomorrow morning. Don't you think?
I wanna talk to you about tomorrow...
- Is there somebody in your bed?
- Yes, there is.
What did you want to say to me?
I had something important to say.
Can't remember what it is.
- Who is she?
- I don't know.
Sean. Do you have some?
I beg your pardon, I didn't expect...
He doesn't know who she is.
- Why is she in his bed?
- He doesn't know.
- I didn't say that.
- What did you say?
- I don't know.
- That's what you said.
- What?
- "I don't know. "
If you don't know,
why did you say so?
You get me mixed up, now. You said...
Look, you don't listen.
Let's start from the start...
Please, I had a long trip
and I would like some sleep.
- Wouldn't you?
- I certainly would.
No, no, no. Who are you
and why are you in his bed?
Why don't we leave the whole thing
until tomorrow?
She's right. We can face it
in the morning with clear heads.
- Yes, she is right. Goodnight.
- Goodnight.
Goodnight, Sean.
Thanks for the use of your room.
I didn't have much to say about it,
did I?
- Goodnight.
Anybody want one of these?
Black coffee.
Morning! Good morning, Sean.
- Jambo, Arga!
- Jambo!
What have we got for breakfast?
Bacon and eggs...
My favourite, codfish cakes.
Deep-fried with antelope fat,
I love it.
- Isn't anybody eating?
- Please, Pockets.
- Go away or shut up.
- Preferably both.
He's not human.
To drink that much and not feel it...
- We had a big night last night.
- You remember?
- Sean. I'm going on the wagon.
- Why?
I'm beginning to see things.
I thought I saw a girl in Sean's room.
You saw a girl.
That's what I said.
I thought I saw a girl.
Pockets, you did see a girl.
- I did?
- You did.
Good! Now, I don't...
- Well, who was she?
- I don't know.
- Don't start that again.
- What?
"I don't know. "
- Sean, he just said...
- Please!
Morning, everybody!
Morning, Pockets.
- Look what I found.
- What's this?
Cameras, lenses,
a real professional outfit.
Your room-mate.
- Professional?
- Photographer?
Didn't a photographer write to the Indian?
- From a zoo in Switzerland.
- Basle, wasn't it?
Yeah, but...
that was signed by a man, I think.
Well, go get the letter!
Sean, what does he mean,
"your room-mate"?
- The girl in my bed last night.
- Sean!
I didn't know her!
- What was she doing in your bed?
- I don't know.
Here it is. It's signed on the bottom.
A M D'Aless...
D'Alessandro.
- Good morning.
I don't think I have met everybody.
We'd better introduce ourselves.
They call me Pockets.
They tell me we met last night.
I remember you. Who wears
the other half of your pyjamas?
I do. My name is Kurt Mueller.
I know you. I covered the Le Mans race
three years ago.
You should have won.
That crash... Too bad.
I don't know... He walked away from it.
I'm Luis Francisco García López.
I don't wear pyjamas.
And this is our boss,
Miss Delacourt. We call her Brandy.
How do you do?
I'm not really their boss.
They were my father's friends.
Now we all work together.
I know of your father.
One doesn't work at the zoo long
without hearing of Frenchy Delacourt.
Kurt, Luis, will you help me
to check the motor on the truck?
Yes, boss.
- Will you have some breakfast?
- Thank you. Just coffee.
- Just coffee. Codfish cakes?
- No, thank you.
Miss... D'Alessander?
- D'Alessandro. "Dallas" is easier.
- Thank you.
- Did you sign this letter?
- Yes, of course. Why?
Because A M D'Alessandro
sounds like a man.
You mean because I'm a girl,
I can't do the job?
I mean we've got trouble enough.
Why not find out
what kind of girl I am before deciding?
- I wish I had the time...
- What about Miss Delacourt?
- She goes out with you.
- She was born and raised here.
She can drive as well as anyone here,
except Kurt.
She can shoot a gun as well as anyone,
except the Indian.
- Can you handle a gun?
- No.
Have you ever been hunting?
- Have you ever been to Africa?
- No...
Well, I'm sorry, Dallas,
about the misunderstanding.
We're short-handed, there isn't time to...
...take care of an amateur?
That's what I was going to say.
I'm sorry.
Well, I'm sorry, too.
I hate to do this.
I would prefer that you wanted me.
Here is a letter
from the director of the zoo.
I have a slight premonition
the boom is about to be lowered.
That zoo will buy
most of your animals this season.
And they want pictures of the catchings.
The boom has been lowered.
How long will it take to get your pictures?
As long as it takes to catch
your animals. I'm ready when you are.
That's a funny-looking work outfit,
but suit yourself. We're ready now.
- You won't give me five minutes?
- I can wait a few minutes.
- Thank you. I'll be right back.
- I can catch up with you, Sean.
What is it?
Did I say something wrong?
- I don't know.
- Nobody knows anything.
- Where are we going today?
- Manyara, I guess.
Are you gonna carry her stuff?
Don't start in by spoiling her.
Yes, bwana.
- Jambo!
- All set, Brandy?
- All set.
Let's get under way.
Pockets. Don't wait all day for her.
Yes, bwana! Yes!
- Dallas, let's go!
- I'll be right out!
Take my stuff, will you?
All aboard!
I'm coming!
- Hi.
- I'm sorry to keep you waiting.
Aren't we going? Let's go!
- Where are we going today?
- Yeah.
I said... Look out!
I didn't see that darned thing!
- How does the ground seem to you?
- Could be better.
- Some gullies over there.
- Yeah.
If we get after a good one,
stick around and hold him
if I miss the first time.
Will do.
- Give me that pad.
- Is it OK if I stand back there?
Stay inside, that ground's rough.
I'll be all right. I like to be
where I can move around.
You'll move around all right.
- What did you say?
- I told them to take care of you.
- Tell them I can take care of myself.
- OK...
Maybe.
Luis. Handle the pole.
Pockets, you pick me a big one
and I'll make you eat it!
Yes, bwana. I'll be very careful.
Start out easy.
Why don't they catch the big ones?
The last one tried
to get into Sean's lap.
Pockets thought he was coming through
the windshield and hit an ant-heap.
Take this one, Pockets!
Tell Kurt to let that one go.
The noose slipped.
Herding car... Let him go.
Sean's having noose trouble.
- Was that giraffe to your liking, bwana?
- Just get another one the same size.
- What happened?
- What?
- Nothing yet.
Knock on it!
Pockets!
You'd better stay there!
Take this one.
Get ready to shake hands with him!
All right...
Slow down easy! Easy!
Slow down easy!
Come on, hurry it up!
She's a handful of trouble.
- Get enough room to move around?
- Oh, shut up!
All right.
- Well, how is it?
- Terrible. I feel sore all over.
The best thing for you now
is a good hot bath. Come on.
- Thanks, Pockets.
- I'll put your things in the main building.
Brandy... I just want to say something.
You might not think so,
but I had a great day.
Only, I made a fool of myself.
I'm sorry, I apologise to all of you.
I would like to stay, if you'll let me,
but I don't want to force you, so...
...just forget about
the letter I showed you.
If you want me to go, just tell me. I'll go.
Thanks for listening.
Well, gentlemen.
Who's going to tell her to go?
Rhino, elephants, buffalo...
...and a greenhorn.
Well, if that's the way you want it.
Mamma mia!
Help!
Stand perfectly still. Don't move.
- I think I can save you.
- Thank you!
Get back! Back!
- OK. Get back!
- What the?
- What's going on here?
What's this Clyde Beatty routine?
What's he doing to you, Sonya?
Poking a chair at you!
Come on, get out.
You don't belong here anyway!
Here, that's my girl.
Pockets,
aren't you ashamed of yourself?
Dallas screamed,
I ran in, saw the cheetah...
It looked too good to pass up,
so I thought I...
- I was wrong.
- I think you're right.
- And stay out of here!
- Yes, ma'am.
Hi, Sonya.
Oh, nice!
- Shall I give you a hand?
- I just want to file these letters.
- Why don't you join the fun?
- I don't belong in there.
I've had all the fun
I can take for one day.
I've had bangs and bumps
on every part of my body, from...
...from bottom to top.
And I had a bath
with a cheetah and three men.
So I think I'll just sit for a while.
About not belonging...
They decided that
if you want to stay, it's all right.
I'm glad of that, because...
You said "they".
Did you vote against me?
I told you I thought
you'd be a damned nuisance.
Yeah, you did. And I was today, wasn't I?
You were. But at least you knew it.
Nice speech, but I don't think
you can talk your way out of it again.
- Hi. Care for some company?
- Yes, why not?
I wouldn't blame you if you didn't.
We were rough on you today.
- I had it coming.
- Would you like a drink?
- Just sit down and talk to me.
- Thank you, Sonya.
What'll we talk about?
My favourite subject?
- What?
- Me.
All right. We'll talk about you.
I noticed today that when everybody
was wrestling with the giraffe,
you were just sitting in the car,
laughing. Why?
Because the giraffe was out there.
- Why?
- The giraffe has spots.
The zebra has stripes...
and the lion is all one colour.
What are you talking about?
Dallas, any animal that has spots,
stripes, or is one colour,
any colour, I don't go near.
- You don't like animals.
- I like animals, I'm just scared of 'em.
But, Pockets, you drove right in
with all these giraffes around.
- What colour is a giraffe?
- Mostly yellow.
- What colour is a New York cab?
I drove a cab in Brooklyn. I pretend
it's rush hour in Flatbush and...
...in I go.
You people, you're all crazy!
Just gives me a chance
to do some of my old jokes.
You said you'd had a great day.
What was it that you liked?
Everything. The car going so fast,
the animals running...
It seems...
...a great way to make a living.
Well, crazy, but...
Pockets, tell me about things here.
Who are these men?
Where have they come from?
Well... You know about Brandy.
And Kurt. Let's see...
Luis, he's Mexican.
He started out as a bullfighter.
He told us he was pretty good.
I never saw him.
- Now, there's the Indian...
- The man who wrote to me.
Mister... Little Wolf.
Little Wolf! Wait till you meet him.
His folks didn't know what they had
when they called him Little Wolf.
- The Indian and I take care of Sean.
- Take care of him? How?
Sean's Irish and he gets mad.
If he takes his mad out on us,
nobody gets hurt. We don't mind.
- Pockets, why he doesn't like women?
- Why doesn't he like?
Dallas, I warn you, you are labouring
under a gross misapprehension...
- But why doesn't he like women?
- He thinks they're trouble.
Well, they are,
but who made him think so?
Well, that's a long story.
- He almost got married once.
- Well, that's possible.
He brought her here for a visit.
She hated the place, the animals,
everything and everybody.
She tried to get Sean to leave.
One day, she got on her broom and...
...just left town.
She was a fool.
You like it here, don't you?
Yeah, I like it.
I'm liable to like it too much.
Sean's got a way of...
You sure got it in a hurry, didn't you?
Pockets, tell me about him.
How does he treat you?
- You saw us all day.
- That was working.
You were with him a few minutes ago.
Was he nice to you?
No, he wasn't.
Well, lady, could be that you're in.
- What do you mean?
- I mean that's good.
If he were nice to you,
you wouldn't have a prayer.
Pockets, will you speak English?
- Bad is good, good is bad, I...
- OK, look...
If a man falls for a woman,
and gets his fingers burned,
so he won't be singed again,
what does he do?
I don't know. Tell me.
If he doesn't like you, he doesn't care
and he can be nice to you.
But if he does like you,
he doesn't want to get in any deeper.
So he acts mean. The more
he likes you, the meaner he acts.
- Doesn't that make sense?
- No.
Let's try a different way.
If you were me, what would you do?
If I were you, Dallas, I...
No, you wouldn't want me to answer that.
Pockets, make sense! What shall I do?
- Now you're making sense.
- What?
You said, "What shall I do?" That's it.
You're the one that has to do it. He won't.
- That's simple, that I can understand.
- You know, I think you do.
Come on. We've settled everything,
let's get a drink.
Dallas, one thing,
please, don't make him too mean.
- Why?
- I told you. He takes it out on me!
What's so funny?
We were talking about
that big giraffe you picked last year.
What a mess!
- He stepped over Sean.
- Landed on the hood.
After all that trouble catching him,
we had to let him go two months later.
- Why?
- We couldn't get him to Mombasa.
His neck was too long
for the railroad tunnel.
- Dallas, do you want a drink?
- No, thank you.
- E Flat.
- What?
E Flat.
- I told you, E Flat.
- You'd better be good.
At least I played it with both hands.
Arusha Control calling...
Arusha Control calling 505.
Do you read me? Over.
This is 505. We read you, over.
I have a transmission for you
from Dr Sanderson. Go ahead.
Hello 505. Can you hear me? Over.
Loud and clear, Sandy, go ahead.
Sean, you can have the Indian back
in three or four days.
I wish it was sooner. My nurses
are all worn out, dodging him.
That's good for 'em!
The exercise'll keep 'em thin.
If that Frenchman's up and around,
I'd like to talk to him. Over.
The Frenchman?
Didn't he come to your place?
He sure did not.
He left here early this morning,
with £ 15 he borrowed from the Indian.
- Where'd the Indian get £15?
- Borrowed it from me.
Did the Frenchman say
what he was using the money for?
No, just borrowed it and took off.
Over.
I guess that's that.
Put the £15 on our bill, Doc.
Tell the Indian
we're not sure he's worth it.
I've already done both those things.
Over and out.
- That's good news.
- Three or four days.
The Frenchman took off.
Too bad, we could've used him.
Better to work short-handed
than with the wrong kind of man.
How do you know
he was the wrong kind?
Didn't you hear it over the radio?
He took £15 from the Indian
for saving his life.
What kind of a man would do that?
- Lafayette is coming.
- What are you talking about?
The French blood bank
just turned in the gate.
- Hi.
- Hello.
The Indian said to tell you
he'd be back in a few days.
- We talked to the doctor.
- Did he tell you I was coming?
He said you borrowed £15
from the Indian.
And he said he hadn't seen you since.
- You thought I was going to skip out?
- You could have.
I've got something to do first.
Do you always carry that chip
on your shoulder?
That depends. I needed the money
to get my rifle from the gunsmith.
Without a rifle
I couldn't be much good to you.
Question is,
are you worth anything with it?
Why don't you try me and see?
Kurt is a pretty good shot.
Would you like to shoot against him?
I'd like that.
- Bring your gun down to the range.
- I'd like to go.
Me, too. Would an audience bother you?
If it does, he won't be much use to us.
- It won't make any difference.
- Hop in.
- Hey, where are you going? Wait!
- Dallas, come on!
All right.
Kurt, take the first bottle on the right.
And you... What is your name, anyway?
- Charles Maurey.
- Chalmo?
- Never mind. Chips will do.
You take the second one
and then alternate. Ready?
Go ahead.
There go my deposits!
Now shoot what's left of 'em.
That's pretty fair shooting.
- He's faster than I am.
- A little.
Reload, Chip.
We'll see how fast you really are.
Well, it looks like you're going to work.
I still have something to do.
May I have your gun, please?
- Sure.
- Thank you.
You still want me now?
You got the job.
OK.
But you've got a strange way
of asking for it.
- Kurt.
- Go ahead, Sean.
Our motor's a little hot.
We're going to get some water.
- Find a place in the shade and wait.
- OK, we'll be waiting for you.
- Holy smoke! What on earth is this?
- It's a well, a water-hole.
It belongs to the Masai tribe.
Nobody knows who built it
or how old it is. 2,000 years maybe.
You see how they raise the water
to the cattle.
Funny thing, they'll work all day
getting that water up.
But when it comes to repairs,
they won't touch it.
They hire another tribe to do the work.
They're cattlemen. Too proud to dig.
Can't you get any more speed
out of this thing?
Let's go, Pockets!
Oh, nuts! Don't slow down,
pass me the line.
Come on, hurry it up!
Some day, Pockets,
I'm gonna wring your neck!
Not today, bwana, not today!
Just shut up and drive!
We'd better get this one
or else he'll be awful mad!
The Lone Ranger rides again! Yahoo!
If he misses again,
stick your fingers in your ears.
Slow down easy! Easy!
Hold him! Let me see something!
Hang on to him!
Open the door!
Kurt, get out of there. He's hard to hold.
Come on out! Get the hell out, will you!
Get up!
Get him up!
I thought he was going
to take you clear to Arusha!
- You got another cage?
- No, thank you!
Let's break out the beer.
Cheeky!
Chewy!
- Bring him over here.
- OK.
He knows the way.
Come on!
See how he likes it?
- Want some?
- Brandy!
- Good morning.
- Morning.
I really twisted this thing yesterday.
Yeah.
What's the matter? You look liverish.
Too much sun?
Sean, how old is Brandy?
She's around... Let's see, she was 17...
Have you had a close look at her lately?
Holy smoke! She's all grown up.
I noticed that the other night
when I was zipping up her dress.
- When you what?
- Zipping her dress.
All of a sudden,
I stopped thinking of her as a kid.
- You did?
- I did.
That Frenchman isn't looking at her
like she was a child.
Anybody with two eyes can see that.
That's why you're green around the gills!
Spring comes to the bushveld
and the bucks start fighting.
- So what?
- So...
I can't answer that. But don't let it
gum up the work around here.
I won't. But I'm not going
to give him a free hand, either.
This is going to be great.
The Indian's knocked out,
we're stuck with a woman photographer,
now you break out in monkey bites.
- And we're a month behind already!
- So what?
So don't give him a free hand.
Come on!
Hey! It's the Indian!
- Welcome back, Little Wolf!
- We've missed you!
- Don't spoil him.
- Get the stretcher.
- Comment ça va?
- Frenchie, you've got good blood.
- We're blood brothers.
- Not till I give you some back.
It's like carrying an elephant!
Indian, this is
Signorina Anna Maria D'Alessandro.
- Molto piacere, signorina!
- Piacere!
- Where are you taking me?
- Bed. You're going to stay there.
- Pockets stood in the chair.
- No kidding!
All right, clear out.
Let him get some sleep.
- 'Night.
- Thanks, boys.
- Brought you some water.
- I've had that for days.
- Maybe this'll help.
- That's more like it.
Bring me up to date.
What's happened since I've been gone?
Frenchman's working out pretty good.
Quick. Pretty fair shot.
- Better than I am?
- Just as good. Moves fast.
Go on.
- We got a giraffe and a zebra.
- Go on.
The Frenchman and Kurt
got a thing going about Brandy.
- Well, good for Brandy! Go on.
- What do you mean, "go on"?
That Italian import out there.
Who does she belong to?
That Italian import out there
belongs to the Basle zoo.
That's A M D'Alessandro. Next time
you write to a photographer,
check what the initials mean.
- How come you let her stay?
- I had no choice.
- You haven't answered my question.
- What question?
- Who does she belong to?
- Oh, Indian!
If you need anything, holler.
I'll leave my door open.
Sean.
What about rhino?
They say there's plenty of them
around Longido.
- Don't do it.
- Why?
Let 'em alone.
First, it was that Belgian kid.
Then Brandy's father and then me.
- This was pretty close.
- Too close.
I'm beginning to think
we got the jinx on us about rhino.
- That's just because you got horned.
- No, it isn't.
Sure, I'm scared of 'em.
So is anybody with any sense.
You're right, there.
So just for this season,
let 'em alone.
Well, we'll wait
till we fill the other orders and then...
Don't lose any sleep over it
for a while. Goodnight.
'Night.
You didn't waste any time,
giving the Frenchman competition.
Competition? She was kissing
Uncle Kurt for giving her a present.
Has she thanked Uncle Kurt
that way before?
- No, she hasn't.
- Some present! What was it?
Oh, nothing.
One of those things women wear,
with laces on it
and some stuff around...
What business is it of yours?
The Frenchman was watching.
You got him worried, anyway.
- What's next?
- I was thinking of buffalo.
Got an order for three.
A male and a pair of young ones.
Semanjaro might be good.
I hear they are moving through there.
Could be all right.
Semanjaro's good country
for a lot of stuff we need.
Ought to be good, because it's so dry.
- Indian, do you like travelling?
- Sure, if I don't have to walk.
Tell Arga to get the stuff ready.
We'll go tomorrow.
- Enough for four or five days?
- That ought to do it.
Dallas, no trunk.
While I'm thinking about it,
no red shirt like you had on the first day.
Why?
Some people say animals
are colour-blind, but I don't agree.
- I had a bull chase me once.
- Really?
Sure it wasn't the other way round?
- Hi, Stan.
- How are you? Good?
Hello, Stan.
- What happened?
- She was a wild one, a real rogue.
Nearly killed a native three nights ago.
You can see what she started last night.
The family got out in time.
I had to shoot her.
- Can we help?
- Have you a radio set?
Could you tell headquarters
I'll stand by until they arrive?
- Sure.
- Thank you.
A calf. Did you know she had a calf?
- Not until now.
- Poor baby.
That's too bad.
What?
Dallas! Watch out!
- That thing can hurt you.
- He's not afraid.
You ought to be afraid of him.
Well, Stan. It's up to you.
I don't envy you your job.
We'll go on ahead.
I'll get your message to headquarters.
- Come, Dallas.
- Let's get out of here.
- I don't want to watch it.
- Watch what?
- It's the only way.
- What are you talking about?
That poor little fellow
hasn't been weaned yet.
He's hungry, that's why he isn't afraid.
In a couple of days, with no food,
he won't make it.
Lions and hyenas...
Better to get it over quick.
- You're going to shoot him?
- I'm not, Stan's the game ranger.
- That's my job.
- It's not a nice job.
- Come on, Dallas.
- I won't come!
I won't come unless you take him.
He's small, we've got plenty of room.
- How will you feed him?
- We'll find a way.
If he's hungry, he'll eat. Shoot him
and you'll have to shoot me, too.
Don't tempt me!
You know, Sean,
there are lots of goats around here.
- Goats!
- Goat milk is very nourishing.
- You see!
- How many goats to fill him up?
- What's a few goats?
- How will you get the milk into him?
Posho would be good.
- Mealie flour with milk.
- Like baby formula.
What are you grinning about?
Put your two cents' worth in, Indian.
- I was thinking...
- He's thinking you're gonna lose.
- I am, am I? And you're all for it?
- That's it, bwana.
Fine. You go get the goats,
I'll go ahead and make camp.
All you have to do is get the goats
and an elephant into the cars.
In your spare time, figure how to get
the milk into the elephant.
I'm going on to camp.
See you there, if you ever make it.
Well? What do we do?
First, we take up a collection for
the United Elephant Fund: $2 each.
I'll negotiate for the goats
while you get 'em all in the cars.
That's it! That's it!
Everybody contributes. See you later.
- You missed a lot of fun.
- Getting the elephant into the car?
That was easy.
Trouble was with the goats.
- Elephants and goats don't mix.
- How about the elephant?
Dallas climbed into the car
and he followed. Look.
Come, Tembo!
Take him out of here
while we get some milk.
He's getting hungry.
Brandy, find me some pails
to put some milk in, ja?
OK, Kurt.
Well, boys. Let's unload the goats.
Hey! Get them, boys!
I'll get this one right here!
Tembo! Come back!
Now, get him over here.
Come on. Get him out of here!
Think this is a mess?
Wait till they milk 'em!
It won't be easy!
Quiet, Tembo.
- Pockets! What are you trying to do?
- I'm trying to milk this goat.
That's the wrong kind of goat. It's a ram!
Come on, I'll show you. Turn around.
- That's the way you do it?
- That's the way.
Quiet, Tembo.
They're getting the milk for you.
Now, hold it quiet, so I can...
Stand still, baby. Good...
- That doesn't get us anywhere.
- We are just wasting milk.
- A goat only gives so much a day.
- He must eat!
Don't look at me!
Feeding him is up to you people.
So start thinking.
Wait, if we take a radiator hose
and shove it down...
...take a radiator hose
and shove it down his throat.
- Then pour the milk in?
- You'll strangle him.
Maybe if we cut a hole
in the bottom of a bucket.
Yeah, but it's still...
Oh, shut up!
He still has to swallow,
now he just chokes.
I seem to remember you started all this.
- Me?
- Yeah.
- You're confused. I just went along.
- Well, think of something!
I'm trying. If he'd shut up for a minute,
I might be able to...
Hey, he's not yelling.
That's the way, Tembo. Easy!
Yes. Oh, that's good!
Wonderful!
Yes, Tembo. Here!
Yes... No, stop it.
That's good!
It's easy. I just thought,
"How do you feed a baby?"
They never begin by pouring stuff
into them out of a bucket.
Here! Here, Tembo.
Oh, that's nice!
We ought to try Longido.
Seven Sisters is on the way.
We might find them there.
- Hi, Brandy.
- Hi.
Come on. Let's see
which one has to go to work.
Go on, Chips. Take a straw.
I don't understand. What is this for?
Oh, I forgot.
I'm going to the river to take a bath.
I can't carry a gun
and take a bath, too,
so someone has to come with me -
whoever gets the short straw!
- Not with this leg, Brandy.
- OK.
We've been doing this
since she's been this high.
- I have the short straw, Brandy.
- Let's go.
Sean, tell me something.
When we all drew straws
to see who'd go with Brandy,
you didn't have a short straw.
- I know it.
- Why did you say you did?
Didn't you tell me you'd discovered
that Brandy was all grown up?
That Frenchman doesn't look at her
like she's a schoolgirl.
- And I'm not so sure about Pockets.
- Three of us.
So I figured I'd better be the one.
I still think of her as a kid.
All right, Papa.
Can I give you a little warning?
It isn't exactly a fatherly gleam
in your eye when you look at Dallas.
- Oh, stop it!
- Don't act innocent with me.
Do you want me to answer this letter
from the San Diego zoo?
- All right, I'll do it.
- Do what?
Answer the letter
from the San Diego zoo.
Oh, sure!
I've run out of cigarettes.
I'll get some in my tent.
- Hey, Pockets!
- Hi!
- I thought you'd turned in.
- Got a minute?
Did Sean have anything more to say
about the baby elephant?
He didn't want to see it shot
any more than you did.
- Where is it?
- It's a he, Pockets.
I've been mixed up once before today.
He's tied up over there,
under the trees. He's asleep.
Don't miss his two o'clock feeding.
He'll start squalling.
Sean wouldn't like that!
And you can't walk the floor
with him, either!
By the way, how are you doing
with the big bwana?
I don't know. You heard him today.
He would like to shoot me, he said.
I know. I thought it was a good sign.
Good sign! If he really
gets to like me, I'm in danger!
Remember, he won't start anything.
You're gonna have to do it! Ciao!
Ciao.
Well...
Now is as good a time as any!
All right, see you in the morning.
- Hi, Kurt.
- 'Night, Dallas.
Watch it, Papa.
- Hi, Sean.
- Hello, Dallas.
I wanted to thank you
for letting me keep the elephant.
Why me? There were a lot of other
people on your side. Thank them.
Well, I'm sorry there was
so much trouble about the goats and...
That couldn't be helped.
Pockets trying to milk that ram
made it worthwhile!
- Dallas, will you have a drink?
- No, thank you.
This is the first time
you've been nice to me.
I was almost afraid to come in here.
Well, why did you come?
- I wanted to ask you a question.
- Go ahead.
Sean...
- How do you like to kiss?
- How do I like to kiss?
- That's what I said.
- What are you talking about?
The kiss. You know the kiss.
How do you like it? Slow? Quick?
Do you like to kiss the girl,
or the girl to kiss you?
- That's silly!
- Silly?
I ask how you like to kiss,
and you say it's silly?
- Have you never been kissed before?
- Of course I have.
Then why do you say it's silly?
It's silly to stand here and talk about it.
Of course it's silly to talk about it.
Let's do it. I'll show you.
You like this?
- There's a lot of people...
- Or slow, like this?
I think you like slow better.
Wanna try again to make sure?
Dallas, I've taken
about all of this I'm gonna take.
What are you going to do?
Sean, I was... I beg your pardon.
We ought to be in a railroad station,
then more people could come in.
- Sorry. I broke something up, didn't I?
- You managed. What do you want?
I was talking to Saidi.
He saw leopard tracks by the river.
- Big?
- You know the boys.
- It's the next thing to an elephant.
- We need a big one.
Well, I suppose
we'd better go talk to him.
- I'm sorry, Dallas.
- It's all right.
I mean...
Dallas, just out of curiosity...
- How did you get him started?
- I asked him how he liked to kiss.
- You just asked him...
... how he likes to kiss.
And you were just finding out when I...
If I ever get a problem,
may I come to you?
- Pockets!
- Yes, bwana.
Bring him in a little!
Watch it, Pockets!
- Bring us another head rope!
- All right!
Look out, he's loose!
All right, let's go! Don't lose me!
Our insurance rate just went up.
Drop that thing off of there!
Don't give him time to rest!
Lay it on! Over here!
Take the door, Kurt.
- All right, turn him loose!
- He's loose!
Take it off.
He's caught. Keep the rope tight.
Push him from behind, Luis.
All set.
The easiest one we ever got.
Well, we're stuck.
- I'll take the cable over.
- OK.
Look out, Kurt!
Thank you!
All right, Pockets. Take her away!
You know, this afternoon...
I don't like crocodiles,
especially when I'm in the water.
Anyway... Thanks again.
- A la tienne, mon pote.
- Prost!
I need some help.
The baby leopard is not eating good.
I'll get some milk and eggs.
Our girl looks pretty good tonight.
I'll flip you to see who goes with her.
Let's go together. I don't trust you.
Right, then give me my shilling back.
- Kurt, come here a minute.
- What's up?
- Somebody left the ostrich pen open.
- Here we go again!
Why don't you catch him, Kurt?
I'd better let the boys do it.
Hey! Let the females go! Keep the male.
The girls will come back
to the old man anyway.
Hold still, baby... There it is.
Pockets, got a pair of pliers?
He's got a thorn.
Easy now, easy.
She'll be better now.
Come, baby.
- Sean, look!
- What's all this?
I was taking Tembo to the bath,
and I found this one.
- Aren't they nice together?
- No.
- They can play together.
- It takes 20 goats...
Sean, don't speak...
- Listen first, don't speak!
- Why not?
- Don't make a fool of yourself.
- I'm a fool?
- Not yet. Just if you don't listen.
- Well, I'm listening.
I hired an African boy.
He's going to buy more goats.
He'll milk them and take care
of Tembo and his friend. No trouble.
- Aren't you glad you're not a fool?
- Dallas...
Yes, Sean?
Aw, hell!
Come on, baby. Let's have a bath.
You certainly won that one, bwana.
Some day, Pockets. Some day...
Here...
It's good!
Come, baby, come!
- Take a look, bwana.
- What?
It's worth your while.
Funny how good she is with animals.
She could even do it to me!
You could use it.
OK. That's enough!
Come, baby!
- Hi, Pockets.
- Hi, Dallas.
What are you doing out here,
all by yourself?
I don't know...
You said that if you had a problem,
you would come to me.
- Have you got one now?
- A problem? What about?
- Brandy?
- Brandy...
Aren't you in love with her?
Are you nuts? Me in love with Brandy?
That's the most...
- How did you know?
- The way you look at her.
- A woman can tell.
- She can, huh?
Then why didn't she notice it?
- Probably she has. How do you know?
- She never did anything about it.
So, as you told me, you've got to do it.
That's fine, but what do I do?
I can't ask her how she likes to kiss,
that's your stuff.
Dallas, what do I do?
Well... Did you ever dance with her?
- I don't remember.
- Do you know how to dance?
- As well as they can?
- Easy!
Come on, we'll show them!
I didn't know you could dance like that!
Go ahead, Pockets. Show her!
- Dallas?
- Yes?
- E occupata?
- Vengo!
- You've got visitors.
- Visitors?
- From the village. Can't you hear?
- I wondered about the singing.
They've made a song for you
and the elephants.
Really! How nice!
I'll come in a moment.
- What are they going to do?
- It's just a Warusha ceremony.
Hi, Sean.
What's the matter?
Sean, please help me! Sean!
We'd better go along and see
they don't get too enthusiastic.
It's not funny. They want to
shave my hair and take my clothes off!
- There was a man there.
- He doesn't speak English!
You're now a member
of the Warusha tribe.
They've given you a name:
Mother of Elephants, Mama Tembo.
You're supposed to dance with them.
- Roast beef! My favourite!
- Everything's your favourite.
- Arga, have you some red wine?
- Beer for me, please.
- Where's Mama Tembo?
- In her room.
The new member of the Warusha
is not coming to dinner.
She's been in the tub for hours,
scrubbing all the paint off.
- That stuff works like a dye.
- She says she has no skin left.
It was mean not telling her
what she was getting into.
- What do Italians like? Red wine?
- Any kind.
- Get yourself another bottle.
- Arga! Another one.
- Who is it?
- Sean. Are you decent?
- No, don't come in, please!
- Cover up, I'm coming.
Hello, Sonya. She's taken quite...
- Oh, brother!
- You make me mad!
When I look nice, you ignore me.
And now with this stuff on my face...
- You look all right.
- Oh, phooey!
- All right, you look terrible.
- So why don't you go away?
- How do you feel?
- I hurt.
I scrubbed and scrubbed.
I almost took my skin off!
- It gave you a good colour.
- How can you tell?
- I brought you a drink.
- Why?
Well, I don't know, the way you're acting.
But you were great today.
It meant a lot to that Warusha tribe.
Now they say Mama Tembo is rafiki,
which means friend.
Thank you.
And they also say that
you're mbali mbali.
If that means "covered with
cold cream" they are right.
- It means you're different.
- Yes, nice and greasy.
- Quit squawking.
- Well, look at me!
I am.
Come here!
You are a little slippery!
Wipe it off and we'll try again.
- I'm sorry.
- Women and their contraptions!
Now, you stop squawking.
Come and get it!
I brought you your dinner.
Now, Sean!
Sean, I didn't mean to do it!
Work 'em out onto the flats.
Sean says move 'em out onto the flats.
Make sure they know
that's where you want them.
- Let me know when you've picked one.
- I'm looking for one with blue eyes.
To the right, that bunch over to the right.
Where he goes, we go.
Hang on!
Where are you hurt? Easy, take it easy.
Shoulder?
- Just a dislocated shoulder.
- Just dislocated, huh?
I think she's right.
Hold still, I'll fix it.
- Better?
- Yes, great.
Let me have some of this water.
OK, Chip? OK?
My leg's hurt.
Pull him out of there.
Let's stand him up.
Put your weight on your leg.
Try. That's fine.
- It's not broken. It's all right.
- Get him out here and clean him up.
I'll take a look at this car.
Pretty lucky. We can tow this in
behind the green truck.
- We sure were lucky this afternoon.
- Yeah, when that car went over...
- Well, you never know, do you?
- Know what?
- Women.
- What?
- Or what they'll do.
- What do you mean?
Brandy! When the jeep flipped.
I'd have sworn she was in love
with one of those two Romeos.
- Well, isn't she?
- She sure didn't act like it.
I always thought... She didn't act
like she was in love, did she?
- Not to my way of thinking.
- Nor to mine, either.
- Rough trip?
- We never missed a bump.
- What happened?
- They flipped the herding car.
- Did they wreck it?
- It's OK.
They're going to be OK, too.
Need any help?
- We'll get cleaned up.
- I need a drink.
Let's get unloaded.
Pockets, give us a hand
with the wildebeest.
You know animals don't like me.
I won't be any good to you.
- You can get in their way.
- Sean!
You told me I wasn't
going to fuss with the animals!
All right, Sean.
He's hooked.
Here, Pockets, take this line...
What are you doing up there?
If he were up here, I'd be down there.
Take this line.
Pull him out when we open this door.
And keep the slack out of it,
so he won't get hurt.
Ready, Pockets? Watch out!
Don't fall in with those buffalo!
Thanks for the advice, Sean!
Pockets, darling!
Are you all right?
Speak to me please, darling.
Poor sweet baby!
- Pockets! Do something, Sean!
- What's the matter with him?
He's hurt. He doesn't speak,
he doesn't hear me.
Pockets, darling, please speak to me.
- Hello, Brandy.
- Are you all right?
I think so...
- No, you're not. You just say you are.
- Let me rest here a minute.
Sean, we have to get him into the house.
- I think you're right.
- Lift him carefully.
- Pockets, you'll be all right.
- It's nothing...
- What are you trying to do?
- I don't know, but I'm doing it right!
Shall I give you a hot bath?
Oh, no, Brandy... A hot bath?
- You just get his bed ready.
- Right away.
- Now?
- Now.
Thanks for coming in to patch us up.
- You'll make it.
- Dallas did a good job.
- How's the leg?
- A drink would help it.
- There's no ice. Arga!
- You're wasting your breath.
- Why?
- There isn't any ice.
- They'll know sooner or later.
- Might as well be now.
- What do you mean?
If you want the ice,
look in Brandy's room.
Go ahead! Take a look, both of you.
All right, we'll humour you.
- I think you're mean.
- They'll live through it.
- How do you feel now, darling?
- Wonderful, Brandy.
I was so frightened
when you fell off that fence.
He fell off a fence.
You nearly took a leg off,
I got a dislocated shoulder...
- And he gets the ice.
- Yeah.
Come on, I'll buy you a nice warm drink.
How did you get outside?
You bad boy!
Come back in, come on!
Oh, no! Three!
What would Sean say? I can't tell him.
- Tell him what?
- This one.
What's so unusual?
No... No! How did this happen?
It must have happened
when I was asleep!
- What do we do?
- How should I know?
By gosh, we got another one.
We're running an elephant nursery.
Mother!
That means that he can stay.
Well... You won another one!
Come on, baby. Let's go!
Come, baby, come!
Come in, don't be afraid!
Have you fellows any idea
what Pockets is doing in the workshop?
He won't let anybody in, he says
you promised him not to interfere.
- Another invention.
- Something for catching monkeys.
You know what he's been buying
to catch monkeys?
Listen:
"840 feet of three-eighths nylon rope,
"260 feet of one-eighth airplane cable,
"80 feet of one-and-a-half
OD aluminium tubing,
"1,200 square yards
of nylon fish net... "
Fish net? Must be planning
to run them into the river to catch them.
Just listen to this:
"100 Ibs black powder.
- "Twenty war-surplus rockets... "
- What!
For throwing ropes from ship to ship.
Then four firing switches "to be used
in missiles for second-stage boost".
Holy smoke!
Is he catching monkeys
or launching them?
We'd better have a little talk
with this gentleman.
Sean, I'd put out that cigarette.
- Hatari! Hatari!
- What are you talking about?
You're washed up!
Come on and get that hose!
Turn on the water. Come on, full force!
No! Don't put water on it!
You'll spoil everything.
- The place is on fire!
- What fire?
- It's just powder, it'll clear.
- Powder?
I thought you were trying
to catch monkeys.
That's what I'm doing.
See, the smoke's clearing.
- What are you doing?
- Wait!
- You said you'd leave me alone.
- I didn't expect Cape Canaveral!
You promised.
This place is restricted, off limits.
- You did promise.
- Yes, I promised.
Are you gonna break your promise?
Did you set that thing off
or did it go off by itself?
Did I?
Well, what happened, Sean, was...
You see...
- What?
- Well, I've heard...
I didn't feel that... You promised!
Get the roof fixed!
- Hi, Brandy.
- Hi, sweetie.
- What'll you have?
- Beer, if it's cold.
- How's that invention coming along?
- Fine!
How are you going to catch monkeys
with a rocket?
He's going to scare 'em
half to death, like he did me.
When they faint, we pick them up
on stretchers and carry them away.
- OK!
- How can you catch them with a net?
Look, I'm not going
to catch the monkeys.
I'm gonna get 500 monkeys
under that net for you to catch.
Some of them have got teeth
about an inch long.
- I've seen bigger.
- An inch and a half.
If I were you, I'd get some armour
to stop those monkeys
sinking their teeth
into some part of my anatomy.
I'll be ready in a few days.
If you don't think
the invention will work, forget it.
Forget that monkeys
have teeth this long, just don't bother.
- Goodnight, Pockets.
- Goodnight, Brandy. Folks. Rest well.
You don't suppose, by any chance...
Problem is, you can't depend on Pockets.
It might work.
What a thing to say!
I'm not going to get my ears bitten off...
- We'd better get busy.
- Let's have a look.
Hi.
Holy Muckya!
You look like a gasoline pump!
- Can you bend down in that thing?
- Sure.
Move around?
The man from Mars.
Take me to your leader!
Give me a hand with this, Dallas.
- Do you want your door closed?
- No, I can't breathe.
There's more over here! Back! Back!
Up, up you little devils!
All we need is about 200 more.
Ladies and gentlemen,
may I have your attention, please?
Thank you.
Three miles down the road,
past that little duka, is a tree.
There are lots of monkeys in that tree.
At 6.30 tomorrow morning,
I'll be ready to throw a net over them.
- The rest, my friends, is up to you.
- You got them up that tree?
- Yes.
- How?
The Warushas were helpful. I gave
them two cartons of your cigarettes.
That was very generous of you.
I hope they pleased them.
They would have liked filter tips...
What makes you think
the monkeys will be there tomorrow?
I tied Rover and Cyclone under
the tree, barking nicely when I left.
Have you got your armour ready,
King Arthur?
Sir Galahad? Black Knight, Red Knight?
And goodnight.
- Sleep tight.
- Thank you. You too... You'll need it!
- Rockets for Pockets.
- Everybody ready?
You think this'll work?
I've worked hard on this
and I'm a little nervous.
I understand.
I'm going to shoot the net over the tree.
There are at least 500 monkeys there.
You worry about the monkeys, OK?
I'll be watching you.
- The tree's over there.
- Sure.
The rocket's pointing away from it. Why?
I read books.
Vectors, trajectors,
centrifugal forces and stuff.
- You know what they are?
- No.
So you wouldn't understand
why it points that way.
But do you know?
I suggest you get behind that tree.
I'm about to light this thing.
I'm about to get behind a tree.
When the net is over the tree,
get in there fast,
and get those monkeys
before they get away.
It worked! Pockets, it worked!
- It did?
- All right, Luis. Get the cage truck.
Let's go get 'em!
It worked...!
It worked!
Timber!
Go get the monkeys! Come on!
- We're going great. Another box!
- We?
That's good! Get another cage!
OK, put 'em in. That's good.
Here comes Pockets. We'll have
to tell him again about the rocket.
Well, he earned it.
- Sean?
- Yes, Pockets.
Sean, the rocket was all right, wasn't it?
As I said, nobody can ever say
your inventions don't work.
Thank you, Sean.
I didn't see it. I was behind a tree.
- I had my hands over my eyes!
- I know.
- Tell me about it.
- He has, twice.
Tell me again, Sean!
The rocket went up,
just like you said it'd go.
Went over that tree
and took the net with it.
- Just like you said it would.
- Just like I said.
Did the monkeys get away, Sean?
- We got close to 500 of 'em caged.
- $6,000 dollars' worth.
Tell me about the smoke.
Well, I... Actually,
Kurt could see that better than I.
- What?
- Go on, tell him.
Well, there it was,
the great silver rocket...
It was red and blue!
The great red and blue
silver rocket, leaving a white trail...
...against the blue sky.
You never said that.
It must have been beautiful.
It was.
Sean, tell me again about the rocket.
It went just like you said it would. Gin!
I had my hands over my eyes.
- It's too bad you didn't see it.
- Tell me!
Pockets! Get me a drink, will you?
Left a white trail.
A white trail against the blue sky.
- Where's she going?
- She's taking the elephants for a swim.
Come on, baby!
Jambo!
Go get a gun and follow her, and see...
I don't think I can go fast enough,
big bwana.
Come, baby. Come!
That's good!
OK, baby! Let's go!
Come on, baby!
Hi!
What did I say about
leaving the compound
without somebody carrying a gun?
It wouldn't do me any good
to carry a gun, I can't shoot.
- It's a very short way.
- It's far enough to get you into trouble.
That "swimming pool" is a water-hole,
the only one around here.
- Everything comes here to drink.
- I won't bother them.
They might bother...
- What's that?
- Keep quiet.
Well, that does it.
Some of Tembo's grandfathers
are around. Here.
Keep walking.
Keep moving.
Get behind that tree and stay there.
You can come out now.
We're lucky. I think they've gone.
I was afraid you were going
to have to shoot him.
Him? That was a cow.
She was trying to tell us
to leave her baby alone.
She has one, you have three.
She figured you had enough.
So do I. Come on.
OK. Let's go, baby. Come!
- Just about wound up.
- I only see one order left to fill.
- That's right, Indian, the rhino.
- You're going to try them?
- You still believe in that jinx?
- I still can't walk good, but...
...I won't waste any more breath.
Do one thing to humour me.
- What's that?
- Use the power wagon for herding.
- It's slower.
- Fast enough.
And higher. A rhino can't climb into it.
I'll buy that.
- Is it working good?
- I'm the one who has to drive it.
All right. We'll use two ropes tomorrow.
Chips, you take a pole with Kurt.
We leave early so we'd better turn in.
We don't want any hangovers
or fuzzy heads in the morning, Pockets!
All right, goodnight!
Pockets, tell Sean
he's looking the wrong way.
You've got a visitor, right behind you!
Why don't you put the tailgate down
and let him climb in?
- We'll take this one.
- Kurt, we'll take this one.
Will do.
This is a big one. Don't be in a hurry.
I'll be very careful, bwana.
You're supposed to chase him!
Tell him that!
- Move in a little, Pockets.
- Moving in.
Watch that line, Saidi!
Take a dolly around that roller bar!
Hang on! Hang on, boys!
Hang on to the son of a...
All right, Luis. He's all yours.
Lay that loop over his head, Chips.
- Kurt, pull her forward a little.
- Say when.
When!
- Stand still, there.
- Jump the other one.
Keep those ropes taut.
I'm gonna try and move him.
Loosen this up a little.
- Fair day's work!
- Nice going, big bwana.
- That's the end of your jinx.
- Sure looks that way.
Kick him in the backsides
for old times' sake?
Don't get tangled in those ropes!
Hang on to him!
Look out! He's loose!
Well... Let's start over.
Get going again!
All right, move in a little closer.
Is that close enough?
Let's give it a try. He's tired.
Bwana, are we talking
about the same animal?
Bring him in a little!
Watch it, Pockets!
Watch it, he's gonna quit on you!
Get another rope around his head!
We're all right.
Watch that line on the catching car.
Take the rope.
Unload the crate and grab those lines.
Now, pull! Yank on it!
Look out!
All right, tip him over.
They got him now!
There you are, Indian.
He won't get away!
Easy, Sean, easy! This breaks the jinx.
I'll feel a lot better when he's delivered.
- Bring in that crate.
- He's a real nice one!
- Coming in.
- You got cleaned up in a hurry.
Good to be finished,
nothing to do in the morning.
We're not finished till we get those
animals to Mombasa, aboard ship.
That won't take long.
Marja Singh said he'd go with them.
He's a good man.
What'll you do till next season?
I had a letter from Bandini.
He's got a new car, wants me to drive it.
I thought you quit that?
I know, but... one more time won't hurt.
I hope you don't break your neck.
- The Frenchman is coming with me.
- Oh?
We'll go to Paris.
We found out we both know a girl there.
- One girl for the two of you?
- We'll go halves.
It's a good excuse for another fight.
- What's Dallas going to do?
- I don't know.
- Do you want an opinion from me?
- Looks like I'm gonna get it anyway.
It's like you got bit by a leopard
and now you see spots on everything.
I know all about that.
There's something about this girl.
I... I like her.
- What?
- I really like her.
It's gone that far?
Look, I don't know her
and she doesn't know me.
I've been busy. I haven't had time.
Only three months,
the whole hunting season.
- Are you pushing me?
- No! Take your time. She'll wait.
- Look, Kurt. This is serious.
- Ask her to come back next year.
She isn't very attractive.
She won't meet anybody like you...
More cracks and you won't need
a racing car to break your neck.
- Let's go to town.
- I don't think you should.
You shouldn't be with her all evening.
You might say something
you'll feel sorry about.
- Am I as bad as that?
- You ought to know.
- Who is it?
- Pockets.
Come on in.
Say, Dallas...
Hi, Pockets.
We're going into town...
...to celebrate. Are you ready?
I don't think I'll go,
I've got some work to do.
Dallas, this is Pockets.
What's the matter?
Isn't it going too good?
No, it's not going too good.
Probably my fault.
I messed it up a couple of times.
That didn't mean anything.
You didn't mess it up.
I didn't do it. She did it.
- Come again?
- That girl you told me about.
The one you said
made him burn his fingers.
When he looks at me,
when he touches me,
he likes what he sees
and what he feels just for...
Then she's there
and I'm not there any more.
- Well, couldn't you sort of?
- No, I couldn't.
It's all over.
I don't even know if I want him any more.
I was all right until you came in.
I just couldn't stand him looking at me
and wondering
if I was going to be like her.
I'd rather not have him.
It just wouldn't...
Oh, please, Pockets, go away!
Well, Dallas, if there's anything
I can do to help.
Please go away, go with the others.
All aboard! Bus now leaving
for 42nd Street and Arusha Square!
- Everybody here?
- Where's Dallas?
In her room. She's not coming.
Says she has work to do.
- Well!
- Well, what?
I'll see if I can get her
to change her mind.
You all go on ahead,
I'll see you in town.
Holy smoke!
What have you got in the third?
- Pretty good, eh?
- Smells good, too.
- This is business.
- Has it got a sister?
Two sisters?
Dallas? It's Sean.
Come in.
What's going on here?
- Please turn the light off, Sean.
- Sure.
What's the matter?
Why aren't you going with us?
I just don't feel like it.
You've been crying.
What if I have?
Can't somebody cry if they want to?
- What are you crying about?
- Nothing, nothing.
A girl doesn't cry about nothing.
It must be something.
It's because I... I got a scrotch.
- A what?
- A scrotch, going through the bush.
- Oh, a scratch!
- Scratch or scrotch, it hurts.
- What are you doing?
- Hold still!
No wonder it hurts,
the thorn is still in you.
There...
There's some iodine around here.
Never mind, just let it go.
It would be better with something on it.
You need iodine worse than I do.
- I need iodine?
- For your fingers.
- There's nothing wrong with them!
- Yes, there is!
I got all mixed up.
You don't use iodine on a burn, do you?
A burn? Make sense!
- How do you treat burned fingers?
- I guess you... put butter on them.
Yeah, then some day
you'll find somebody with butter.
I don't get it. Fingers, butter...
What are you talking about?
Go away! You always come
when I don't want you.
- Oh, Dallas, cut it out!
- Don't touch me! Leave me alone!
- Get out of here before I...
- OK!
Now, what the hell did I say?
First morning we can sleep,
those elephants...
What a racket!
Hasn't Mama Tembo
fed them this morning?
Mama Tembo has gone.
That's why they're yelling.
- "Gone"?
- She left a little while ago.
What do you mean, "left"?
- He may understand you, Pockets.
- I'll take a chance.
She has packed her bags
and departed from our midst.
- She can't do that!
- I found this letter under my door.
- Behave and I'll tell you what she says.
- Well, read it.
"Dearest Pockets... " That's me.
"I can't stand goodbyes, so
I'm having Saidi drive me into town. "
You notice she doesn't write
with an accent.
"Tell everybody that
I can't find words to thank them,
"that I'll never forget them,
that I love them. Dallas. "
- You believe now that she's gone?
- I'm gonna stop her.
You didn't want her to go?
- Of course I didn't!
- You asked her to stay?
- I was going to ask her, but...
- But what?
- She wouldn't let me. She ran me out.
- She's smart.
- What are you going to do?
- Find her.
Arusha's a big town,
if she doesn't want to be found.
- Tembo might find her.
- Get him on the scent.
- He's got a long nose!
- Hurry!
Right!
- What's this?
- She left that behind.
Make a good bandage for your fingers.
Friends! Tell the airport
not to let her on a plane.
- Shall we say why?
- Say she stole something. Money.
Tell the police to watch the Nairobi road.
- How much money?
- She robbed a bank.
Chips and I will check the taxi station.
I'll go with them.
I can go places they can't.
Hurry it up, Luis.
Why bring all three?
We can only use Tembo.
Get in there, get in!
Hold it!
Come on, Tembo!
What does she do to make him move?
Come on, get in. Come on, Tembo!
Come on!
This might work!
What is that?
Look, Tembo! Look, this is Mama.
Yes, Mama!
Bwana, you remember Mama, don't you?
Come on, take a good smell now.
- Yes, it's Mama!
- It's gonna work!
Wise child that knows its own mother.
Come on, there's no room for you.
Airport? If a girl about 5' 6" tall
with red hair shows up,
don't let her on a plane,
she robbed the Bank of England.
- Wait a minute, stop! Sean!
- Any luck?
She's not at the railroad station.
- She's been to the ticket office.
- What for?
Airline ticket, but she wasn't
at the airport. She must be in town.
- Where?
- I don't know.
- Tembo doing any good?
- Not a thing.
- Do those clothes belong to Dallas?
- Sure.
He's probably smelling them,
no wonder. Give them to us.
Sean, slow up.
I think he smells something.
He does smell something.
Come on, Tembo. Come on, baby.
There he goes...
He's going into Singh's. Come on.
Oh, no!
Go away!
You shouldn't have done it!
It's not... It's not fair!
I didn't want you to do this...
Why, why did you?
- Look, Dallas...
- What did you do that for?
Why didn't you just let me go?
Go away! It's all your fault.
Goodnight, Sean!
Before you go any further,
I should tell you you're not alone.
- What's your name?
- They call me Dallas.
What are you doing in my bed?
Sean, I wanna talk to you.
You know that girl Dallas
we were looking for? If we wanna...
Oh, Sean.
You know that girl we were
looking for this afternoon?
- She's in your bed.
- Pockets. Out.
- What's she doing in your bed?
- Get out.
We got married this afternoon!
Oh, no!
Go away! Go away, now!
Tembo, go away!
Tembo!
Go away!