Now, after years in the making,
Robert Altman brings to the big screen...
count 'em...
24 of your very favorite stars!
David Arkin, Barbara Baxley...
Ned Beatty in Nashville!
And the fabulous performances
of Karen Black, Ronee Blakley...
Timothy Brown in Nashville!
Along with the spectacular
Keith Carradine, Geraldine Chaplin...
with Robert DoQui in Nashville!
And the exciting appearances
of Shelley Duvall, Allen Garfield...
and Henry Gibson in Nashville!
And the fantastic Scott Glenn,
Jeff Goldblum...
Barbara Harris in Nashville!
Not to mention the terrific
David Hayward, Michael Murphy...
Allan Nicholls in Nashville!
And the all-time great Dave Peel...
Cristina Raines,
Bert Remsen in Nashville!
Plus the incredible Lily Tomlin...
Gwen Welles
and Keenan Wynn in Nashville!
Be the first on your block
to marvel at the magnificent stars...
through the magic of stereophonic sound
and living-color picture...
right before your very eyes
without commercial interruption.
Fellow taxpayers...
and stockholders in America...
on the first Tuesday
in November...
we have to make some vital decisions
about our management.
Let me go directly
to the point.
I'm for doing some replacing.
I've discussed
the Replacement Party...
with people
all over this country...
and I'm often confronted
with the statement...
"I don't want
to get mixed up in politics"...
or "I'm tired of politics,"
or "I'm not interested."
Almost as often someone says,
"I can't do anything about it anyway."
Let me point out two things.
Number one:
All of us are
deeply involved with politics...
whether we know it or not...
and whether we like it or not.
And number two:
We can do something about it.
When you pay more
for an automobile...
than it cost Columbus to make
his first voyage to America...
that's politics.
- That girl down there.
- Hold it! Hold it, everybody.
Honey, you gotta
get her out.
- Bob.
- Yes, sir.
I want to talk to Buddy.
Buddy?
Y-Yes, sir, Dad?
Buddy, who is that woman
in there with the hat on?
- She a friend of yours?
- Mr. Hamilton, I'm Opal.
I'm from the BBC, and I'm doing
a documentary on Nashville.
You know I don't allow no people
visitin' when I'm recording.
I want no recording equipment
in that studio.
- Buddy, escort the lady out.
- Yes, sir.
If she wants a copy of this record,
she can buy it when it's released.
No, darling, I'm sorry.
No strangers at all.
Mr. Hamilton,
I'll be waiting outside for you.
We'll have a little interview.
I want to do another one.
Jimmy, you count off.
I want to hear
a little more Haven in this one.
Ah, there we are.
This is Studio B right here.
- They're doing some gospel.
- Oh, how sweet!
A recording of some sort.
Glenn, how are you?
- Mind if we sit in?
- Come on in.
It's so little!
We'll be going down front
so we'll get out of their way.
It's so pretty! I've been
to all the recording studios in London.
They're always enormous
and very impersonal.
This is so cozy.
- Keep down so they can...
- Yes, of course.
So they can see
what's going on.
There we are.
This is a choir...
a black choir...
from part of...
from Fisk University here in town.
Good Lord!
- The lady singing is...
- Is she a missionary?
No, she's not.
She's a gospel singer.
She's the wife
of our attorney.
I was making
a documentary in Kenya...
and there was this marvelous
woman who was a missionary.
That's why I asked.
She was sensational.
She was converting Kikuyus
by the dozens.
She was trying to convert Masais.
Of course, they were hopeless.
I mean, they have
their own sort of religion.
Look at that.
That rhythm is fantastic.
You know, it's funny.
You can tell...
It's come down in the genes
through ages and ages...
and hundreds of years,
but it's there.
Take off those robes...
and one is in... in...
in darkest Africa.
I can just see
their naked, frenzied bodies...
dancing to the beat of...
Do they carry on
like that in church?
Depends on which church
you go to.
Hold it, everybody.
Damn it, Bob.
What's the name
of the piano player, Bob?
- That's Frog.
- "That's Frog." He plays like a frog.
We'll try it again.
Jimmy, you count off.
- Damn it to hell!
- Hold it, everybody.
- Bob.
- Yes, sir?
What did you say
the piano player's name was?
- Frog.
- Yeah.
When I ask for Pig, I want Pig.
Now, you get me Pig, and then
we'll be ready to record this here tune.
Yes, sir.
You get your hair cut.
You don't belong in Nashville.
This is Bill Jenkins
on special assignment...
for Channel Two News
here at Metro Airport.
We are awaiting
the arrival of Barbara Jean...
who has been away for treatment
at the Baltimore Burn Center.
Already, prior to her arrival,
around 3,000 Barbara Jean fans...
and supporters are here.
They are being held inside
the terminal by security police.
Ma'am, excuse me.
Am I late for Barbara Jean's plane?
- I don't think so, but they're
not gonna let you out there.
- Thank you, ma'am.
Members of the Chamber of Commerce
and other fans are on the way.
Also, it's reported Haven Hamilton
will make an appearance here.
There is no question about being involved.
The question is,
what to do?
It is the very nature
of government...
to strain at a gnat
and swallow a camel.
As loyal citizens,
we accept our take-home pay...
understand
most of the deductions...
and even, to a degree,
come to expect them.
However, when a government
begins to force its citizens...
to swallow a camel...
it's time to pause
and do some accounting.
Her plane has touched down.
It's down the taxiway...
and will be turning
onto the ramp area...
directly here in front of us
at Metro Airport.
Could you pass me
the crackers, please?
- There you go.
- Thank you.
- Miss, may I have...
- Hi!
A caramel sundae, please?
Honey, we ain't got
no caramel sundae.
- Butterscotch?
- We ain't got no butterscotch sundae.
- Got a strawberry.
- Strawberries are always in season.
Fine, fine.
- That's fine. Thank you.
- Good for you too.
Thank you. Then I'll have
a strawberry sundae, if I may.
- You got it.
- Thank you.
- Sueleen, did you see what he did?
- One strawberry sundae!
Did you see
what he just did?
He took the thing off the salt
and threw it up in the air.
Why'd you do that?
What are you doin'
in Nashville?
- Oh, I live here.
- You do?
Hey, fellas, come here.
I want you to see somethin'.
My wife and I...
- My wife is sick, unfortunately.
- I'm sorry to hear that.
Oh, it's just one of those things
that happens.
- Happens in the best of families.
- Yeah.
I wrote me this real hot song.
You wanna hear it?
It's called
"I Never Get Enough."
Okay, listen. All right?
At any moment, Barbara Jean will be
stepping out and will be greeted...
by the Chamber of Commerce,
as well as Mr. Sperry.
Mr. Sperry making his way
to the aircraft now with a big wave.
Of course, he's the president
of Barnett Enterprises.
- We'll be talking with Mr. Sperry...
- How you doin'?
John Triplette?
- You looking for me? I'm John Triplette.
- Oh!
- How are you?
- Hey, John. How are you?
Those kids
in those uniforms are terrific.
- Hello.
- What's your name?
- Del Reese. I'm sorry. Forgive me.
- Thanks for coming out.
- It's a great idea.
- You mean the girls in the costumes?
Barbara Jean's
still on the aircraft. We'll be awaiting...
Thousands of people
have turned out at Metro Airport...
to greet Barbara Jean
on her arrival.
Haven Hamilton has just arrived,
typically dressed in white...
his white Jeep being driven
today by his son, Bud.
Members of the Chamber of Commerce
are going over to meet Haven Hamilton.
He's greeting some of his old friends,
business acquaintances.
Autograph seekers are now
making their way over.
Barbara Jean still
is aboard the aircraft...
- Hello, Martha.
- Hi.
- How are you, Martha?
- I'm okay, but, uh...
- Pardon me?
- Listen, uh, I've changed my name.
- Okay.
- It's L.A. Joan from now on.
Let me get some cigarettes.
Your Aunt Esther wants to see you.
- She's in the hospital...
- Wait a minute.
- And she'd like to see...
- This guy's a rock star. Hang on.
Can I get your autograph?
You're Tom, aren't you?
Tom, Bill, and Mary?
Jesus, you ought to stop that diet
before you ruin yourself.
Do you believe this? They have
our album here. Hey, how's it selling?
- What's that?
- Bill, Mary, and Tom.
A little slow,
but we sell mostly country.
I'm the handsome one in the front.
I don't have my glasses on
in the picture, but I...
Wait a minute! Hal Phillip Walker
looks exactly like Connie White.
Now, Del, I like...
I like the idea of bands.
I want you to listen
to those little kids, honey.
I want you to know
they practiced...
every day after school
for two hours...
for a whole month
just for this event.
- Yes, that's so nice.
- Isn't that cute?
I think that'll cheer her up.
Pearl, shut up.
- Just like your mama, son.
- Yes, yes, I'm sure he is.
... tragically burned
in an accident involving a fire baton.
She has now fully recovered.
However, she's required to take...
- Excuse me, Barnett.
- I got no time right now!
Jesus!
I just think they're so cute,
Buddy.
Hello, hello. Testing.
I wonder if this thing's on.
Hey, wait. Are you Tom
of Bill, Mary, and Tom?
- Yeah. What's your name?
- Jamie.
You thought of voting
for Walker for president?
- I don't vote for nobody.
- Oh, come on.
Just read it.
He's got a fantastic platform.
How you doin', Sarge?
Ya kill anybody this week?
Did you ever see
such pretty girls in your life?
Someday you're gonna be
big girls like your mommies...
and you're gonna be lookin'
for a nice, young, handsome man.
Come on, Buddy.
You say hello.
My son Buddy, he just graduated
from Harvard Law School...
and we're tryin' to give him
all the breaks we never got.
- Buddy, say hello to the people.
- Hi.
Thank you, Buddy.
And thank you again for comin' here
and makin' us all feel so at home.
Here she comes!
Our Barbara Jean!
Come on.
Get on the other side.
Here's our own Barbara Jean!
May I have a word, Barnett?
None of that shit.
Come on. Come on.
Get up there.
Come on.
Who do you think
you are? Marlon Brando?
Barbara Jean, ladies and gentlemen!
- Hi!
- Ah, look at that!
Thank you so much.
Hi, sweetie, darling!
Hi, Bill. Hi, Mary.
Where's Tom?
- Take my bag?
- Sure.
- You were supposed
to meet us at the gate.
- Then let's go meet at the gate.
- Norman, let's go to the limo.
- The limo is just outside.
Barbara Jean, for you.
- Thank you, Haven.
- Right here for the photographer.
Thank you, Tennessee Twirlers,
for coming out today...
and thank you,
Franklin High School Band.
I think you kids
get better every year.
Oh, little beauty!
Thank you so much!
Are you gonna ride into town
with me or not?
Go on without me. I'm gonna wait,
'cause I think she's gonna sing.
Her? She ain't gonna sing.
She don't sing unless she get paid.
I'd like to thank you...
for coming out
to greet me today.
It's great to be home.
It's hot as a firecracker.
What's so funny about that?
Me and the boys are gonna be
out at the Opry this week...
and like my granddaddy
always used to say...
if you're down to the river,
I hope you'll drop in.
Oh! Yes, that's sweet.
Who writes your material, darlin'?
Barnett, who are
all those people inside?
It's just airport security,
'cause of all the hijackers.
- Did they come to see me?
- They can see you pretty good.
Then I'd like to go in
and say hello.
I believe
Barbara Jean wants to go inside...
- Barnett, I'm sorry, darlin'.
- To see the fans who were not able...
to make it out here.
This was a little bit unscheduled.
She's on her way down there...
probably to greet
some fans inside there.
- Stepping down the walkway with Barnett.
- Watch out for the water.
Right behind, Haven Hamilton...
and all the other friends,
members, and, uh...
She's fallen! Harold, come on!
She's fallen somewhere
down there.
If we can get down there...
if we have enough cable.
Don't know how far
we can make it.
Who do you think is running Congress?
Farmers? Engineers?
Teachers? Businessmen?
No, my friends.
Congress is run by lawyers.
A lawyer is trained for two things
and two things only:
To clarify... that's one...
And to confuse...
that's the other thing.
He does whichever
is to his client's advantage.
Did you ever ask a lawyer
the time of day?
He told you how to make
a watch, didn't he?
Ever ask a lawyer how to get
to Mr. Jones's house in the country?
You got lost, didn't you?
Congress is composed
of 535 individuals.
Two hundred and eighty-eight
are lawyers.
And you wonder
what's wrong in Congress.
No wonder we often know
how to make a watch...
but we don't know
the time of day.
No wonder it takes six or seven years...
What the hell
is the matter with you?
Yes, I'm talking about replacement.
Replacing this lawyeristic,
red-taped...
and blank-taped government...
with the yes-and-no language
of farmers and teachers...
engineers and businessmen.
I'm not pessimistic
about this country.
She finally collapsed here
on the sidewalk. Sort of a faint.
That's all we've been able
to determine at this moment.
We interviewed Mr. Sperry.
He said the same thing.
Haven Hamilton
said the same thing as well.
That's about it for the moment
from Metro Airport.
For Channel Two News,
this is Bill Jenkins reporting.
Let's consider our national anthem.
Nobody knows the words.
Nobody can sing it.
Nobody understands it.
Yee-haw!
I suppose
all the lawyers supported it...
because a lawyer
wrote the words...
and a judge wrote the tune.
Careful, Buddy.
- Read it carefully.
- Watch out for that truck.
And I say "read it"
because I know you can't sing it.
Read all four verses, and you'll
understand what I'm talking about.
Yes, sir, I would support work
and vote for replacement.
- Change our national anthem back
to something people can understand...
- This is terrific, Norman.
Back to something that would make
a light shine in their faces.
Hey, man, get off my car!
Don't lean on my car!
I just got this goddamn thing fixed,
so don't lean on it.
Oh, Jesus Christ. Oh, God.
Hey, man,
get the hell off my car!
You almost made me fall!
Great, thanks.
Can I have one too?
Thanks a lot. Just keep those
cards and letters comin' in, folks.
- I feel faint.
- I'm gonna get us a Popsicle.
Just a minute. Hello?
- All those mangled bodies.
- Would you go to that Popsicle truck...
and get us a couple sweet ices?
There must be 20 cars piled up,
one on top of the other,
some of them upside-down.
- Come on.
- I saw a leg sticking out.
This is gonna be a mess.
I don't know how long it...
Can you just pull on through
where the ambulance went?
You want to try it?
- What's the matter, son?
- It's stalled.
- What did you want? Popsicle?
- I wish my cameraman had been here.
He's never around. I need something
like this for my documentary.
I need it.
It's... It's America.
Those cars
smashing into each other...
and all those
mangled corpses...
Just a minute.
Well, it's hard to really say.
You see...
after they opened her up, they figured
they ought to do an exploratory.
You know,
give her kind of an overhaul.
- Twenty dollars?
- Twenty dollars.
- I'll give you five.
- No, I'll take 15.
You'll take 15?
I'll give you ten.
I can think
of no sensible reason why New York...
must of necessity have 12,000...
major crimes committed...
for every 1,000
committed in Tokyo.
- Excuse me.
- Yet these are the true victims.
Some very funny notions
have developed in American politics.
Um, let me see.
Um, have you any children?
Yes, I have two children.
I have a boy and a girl.
Oh, isn't that nice!
How old are they?
Twelve and 11.
Do they want to be singers
like their mummy?
Um, well,
my children are deaf.
They're... They are deaf.
They were born deaf.
Oh, my God, how awful!
- It's so depressing.
- Now, just a minute. That's not so.
- I wish you could see my boy.
- Oh, I couldn't.
- He has the most incredible personality.
- It's the sadness of it.
What happened is, he made
a million dollars on a flyswatter...
because it had
a red dot in the center.
- Flyswatter?
- That's right. Just a red dot.
He was sittin' in a buffet,
and he was eatin'...
and he saw a woman,
and she was swattin' flies.
And, uh, she...
He said...
"What makes
the difference in flyswatters?"
'Cause it has to do
with the Industrial Revolution.
The thing with these country people is
they have a real grassroots appeal.
- Well, hell, they got fans.
- And they're the people
that elect the president.
- We're gonna do everything we can.
- You line up a lot of movie stars...
I think people here feel that
movie stars are eccentric and crazy.
- Communists.
- Well...
- A lot of 'em are.
- It's been said, now.
- Then I want to go to the Grand Ole Opry.
- Forget that.
- 'Cause I have to have my record...
- I don't like music.
- I'm gonna go see what's goin' on.
- I have a gold record...
- and it needs to be signed.
- Get the hell away from my truck!
- Goddamn it! Sons of bitches!
- Shit!
I say, could I please speak
to Mr. Tommy Brown?
- What?
- I'm sorry.
Is it possible to have a few words
with Mr. Tommy Brown?
I'm from the BBC. I'm doing
a documentary on Nashville.
What is the BBC?
- British Broadcasting Company.
- Oh, English.
It was called
"Wanda, Wander."
No, that song was called
"Wonder, Wanda."
- I don't really know.
- Thank you, thank you.
- Goddamn it, it was "Wanda, Wander."
- It was "Wonder, Wanda."
"Wanda, Wander"! What difference
does it make? It was a hit!
There's no breathing space.
What we need,
first and foremost...
is a commonsense approach.
Nothing complicated.
Is Mr. Brown going to...
Will he be here soon?
Yeah, he's in the back changin'.
He has to put his makeup on.
Whenever he's going to have
an interview, he puts his makeup on...
and likes to get
all prettied up, you know?
That's nice.
He must be
a marvelous person...
to have all you lovely people
working for him.
I know the problems in the South.
I mean, I've heard of them.
Well, yeah.
- He's a very liberal guy.
- That's lovely.
By the way, I'd like for you
to meet his wife. This is Joy.
- Mrs. Brown?
- Yes.
Today in America...
with its unmatched resources...
it is exceedingly ridiculous...
a total absurdity...
that any citizen with any ailment...
mental or physical,
should go medically unattended.
We're settin' up
everything for you.
- We got pictures the right height.
- Oh, the little bird again.
Isn't that beautiful?
I remember when you gave that to me.
I remember I almost threw it out.
Good afternoon, girls.
I'd like you to wait
outside the room a while...
because I know Aunt Esther
would like to fix herself up a little.
I want my dog.
Where is my dog?
- I just need one shot.
- I'm sorry.
- Could you excuse us?
- Come on in, sir.
- How you doin', Howard?
I'm sorry.
No press allowed.
We'll put
these pictures above your head.
- Delbert, I got no time.
- I know.
I just stopped by
to see Barbara Jean.
How you doin'?
How's lawyerin'?
Nobody pays me no mind.
I'm just like another flunky.
- Would you mind crankin' me up?
- More white carnations!
If I told him once,
I told him twice.
Bud, this is a hospital!
This ain't no construction site!
- I am not the press.
- Go build another chair!
Goddamn it!
I am not the press.
I am from the BBC.
Damned if I don't
keep my pledge.
- Look who's here... Mr. Brown.
- Glad you're here, but cut it short.
How do you do?
Nice to see you.
You look as beautiful
as a big, black butterfly.
I'm gettin' jealous.
- You better get out of here.
- He's gettin' mighty jealous.
I gotta sit myself up a bit. Hi.
- I need to talk to you.
- You got it.
All right, everybody.
Doctor's gotta talk turkey.
Barnett, there's somebody
I want you to meet.
- John Triplette from California.
- John Triple?
- Triplette.
- Okay. All right.
- He's a killer.
- Give us some good news.
Excuse us, please.
- Are you a relative?
- What? No, no.
- Can you tell me how she is?
- She's fine. It's her husband
I'm concerned about.
- Now, say somethin' good.
You got two seconds.
- Fair.
- Can I have a light?
- Excuse me?
- Yeah, sure.
The incident you described
just now is very similar...
to what you have here
for your second admission...
- when it was diagnosed as some kind of intestinal disorder.
-  - What's your name?
Bud Hamilton's my name.
Esther's awake,
and she's dying to see you.
I'll be there in a minute, okay?
I'm talking to someone right now.
- I'm talking to someone.
- I beg your pardon.
- That's my uncle.
- Your uncle?
I've got a sick aunt
down the hall.
I just got in from Los Angeles
a few hours ago.
- I'm L.A. Joan.
- L.A. Joan?
What do you do?
Well, I know it sounds arrogant...
but I'm on my way to town,
if I ever make it...
to become a country-western
singer or a star.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
What are you gonna do
if you don't?
If I don't? I don't know.
I could always go into sales.
- Like ladies' clothes?
- I don't know.
Well, I know all about trucks,
so I'd go into trucking, I guess.
- You're kiddin' me.
- No, I'm not kiddin' you.
I'm in a truck enough.
And I know
how to fix motors and all that.
- Nobody'd buy trucks from a girl.
- I been fixin' motors a long time.
They'd buy 'em from me
'cause I know all about motors.
Why do you say that?
Because now...
See, what's happenin' is, if I can't
sell trucks and I can't go...
- Nobody'd buy a truck from a girl.
- I knew this would happen.
Don't say you saw me.
Hey, you haven't seen
my wife, have ya?
- She's sort of an ordinary-lookin' lady.
- Huh-uh.
- Are you going into town?
- You're not one of them
country singers, are ya?
- No. Can you give me a ride?
- All right, get in.
- Thank you.
You look like a guy
I was in the navy with.
He wouldn't take a bath. We had
to pee in his bed to get him discharged.
Hi.
My name's Sueleen Gay...
and I'm here to sing you all a couple
of songs tonight that I wrote.
And I sure hope
you're gonna enjoy 'em, honey...
'cause I know I'm gonna
enjoy singin' 'em to ya.
The first one I'm gonna sing
tonight is called...
"Let Me Be The One."
Let's go.
Oh, what about your...
your aunt and uncle?
Oh, it's cool.
I can see them anytime.
- What kind of car you got?
- I have a little... Here.
Martha!
And, uh...
that... that being true...
I would suggest,
on the basis of the first account...
How come you're not
wearing the blue dress?
Because I didn't want to.
You're supposed to wear
the blue dress when I wear this.
- I don't want to dress
like twins anymore.
- We're not twins. We're a trio.
Hi, young stud.
Come on in, sit down...
right over here.
Yeah! Whoo.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry to...
That's okay.
He looks like Howdy Doody.
Okay, this is, uh...
Right here at Deemens Den.
- Hi, everybody. My name's Sheila.
- And my name's Patti.
And we're
the Smokey Mountain Laurel.
Come on, Becky, let's go.
It's gettin' late.
I gotta get up and go...
Sorry. Oh! Tom!
- Yeah?
- Tom, hello.
Another one of his girlfriends.
I was looking for you.
This chap told me you were in here.
- Who are you?
- I'm Opal from the BBC. Hello.
Good evening, ladies.
You don't mind
if I sit down for a little bit.
All right.
I want to hear it some more...
for my Misty Mountain Boys!
I got a couple announcements
I wanna make.
We got some stars here tonight.
- Can't be us.
- And one of 'em is...
Tommy Brown's back in town!
Tommy Brown,
stand up and show it all off!
Oh, ain't he beautiful!
Tommy Brown's
the whitest nigger in town!
It's gettin' late.
- I'm very sorry.
- That marshmallow!
He oughta drink some
of that milk! It fits his personality!
This is not typical of Lady Pearl's
parlors, you understand.
It's not typical of Nashville.
I hope you'll tell the other ones.
Hey, he's leavin'!
The Oreo cookie's leavin'!
Calm down.
You're drunk.
I'm drunk, but shit, he's still
the whitest nigger in town...
and I ain't gonna change my mind
about that, I'll tell you right now.
Shit! Hey, where you goin',
Tommy Brown?
Come on back here!
Hey, get your hands off...
Listen, boys!
I got two guns here!
- How'd we do, Trout?
- Not bad, girls.
Go sit down.
I'll talk to you in a minute.
Send over a couple of beers.
Bear, how about a couple beers
for the ladies, huh?
- Honey, what's your name?
- Sueleen.
- Sueleen?
- Sueleen Gay.
Sueleen Gay,
you're on next.
Come on, Bunkie.
One, two, three, four.
Un, deux, trois, quatre.
Testing. Testing.
I gotta go to the bathroom.
Wait for me here.
The kind of guys
that go for this Hal Phillip Walker...
longhairs and smoke
cigarettes that look funny.
I heard this guy's
an admitted homo.
and I'm here to sing y'all
a couple songs I wrote.
First one I'm gonna do is called
"Let Me Be The One."
That's awful.
- You want a beer?
- No, thanks. This is business.
See, what I was wonderin'...
I'm makin'
a demonstration album...
at a recordin' studio...
- and, uh...
- Winifred!
- What? You...
- Goddamn it, come back here!
- Deemens Den.
- Is Trout around there?
- Yeah, this is Trout.
- Listen, this is Del Reese.
We're gonna have
a little fundraiser...
and we need
some help with some...
- Talent?
- Yeah, talent. Right.
I tell you what I'm gonna do.
The fella I'm working with is here.
I'm gonna put him on.
Maybe he can tell you
exactly what we need.
- John Triplette's his name.
- All right.
Uh, Trout.
This fella's name's Trout.
- Trout?
- Yeah.
- Hello, Trout?
- Hey, John, how are you?
- Fine. How are you?
- Fantastic.
- As Del told you,
we're putting a smoker together.
- Right.
I think next Monday night,
hopefully.
What we need is a young lady
to entertain the troops.
Hey, babes.
And then...
- What are you tellin'? Huh?
- Mm-hmm.
Set the table, please.
Hey, babe, I'm sorry...
you got stuck in that big
traffic jam out there today.
I have got
a saucy, saucy redhead...
- Saucy?
- Who is dynamite.
Why, in fact, her name
is "Suelynn" Gay.
Well, if she's half as provocative
as her name, we're home free.
I'm sorry I sprang
this dinner on you.
I asked the man
if he wanted to come to dinner...
- and he said yes.
- And then one boy pushed me out.
- Were you out there by yourself?
- Wasn't it hot?
- Thought I was gonna burn up.
- It was terrible.
We got in the car,
and I turned on the air conditioner.
Coach said, "Go in the water."
I said, "Okay."
- What you tellin', Jimmy?
- Talkin' 'bout swimming class.
- He's telling me about swimming class.
- Oh.
Did you swim today?
Did you learn anything?
- Huh?
- Hush! Let him tell it.
Then the coach said, "Ready?"
I said, "Yeah. Oh, boy."
Then I went down
to the diving board...
Whoo!
And touched bottom.
And I kept going through.
Walked on the bottom.
And then I come out.
Then I get two cards:
"Goldfish" and...
and "Passed the test."
How about that?
They call you Goldfish?
Goldfish. That's it.
Oh, dynamite! Dynamite!
Sueleen,
I'm so proud of you, baby.
- Thank you.
- You knocked 'em out up there.
- Oh, excuse me. I'm sorry.
- All the people were goin' crazy!
Darlin', you're outta sight!
You are outta sight! Oh, my goodness.
Oh, that's beautiful.
Honey, it takes an attitude to be a star.
- What can I tell you?
- Do I get the job, then?
Honey, I got you a job
while you were singin'.
- You did? Oh!
- A friend of mine called.
Very heavy.
There's a party Monday night.
Listen, the pay is not much...
- because it's a low-budget thing.
- I don't care about the money.
- It's only $10.
This must be
some sort of amateur night.
- You're gonna be a star.
- I gotta make a phone call.
I'll be right back.
They are good, babe.
- I can get that.
- You want me to get it?
- That's all right. Go on.
- Where you goin'?
- Telephone.
- Oh.
Mm! Hello.
- Hi. Linnea?
- Mm-hmm.
- I'm here.
- Who is it?
This is Tom.
Just a minute. I have something
in my mouth. I was eatin' dinner.
You haven't changed a bit,
have you?
- Now, who is it?
- Tom. Don't you remember?
No, I don't believe I do.
We met in the control room
at the recording studio...
about two months ago.
- Oh, yes. How are you?
- I'm fine. How are you?
I'm just fine.
What are you doin' in Nashville?
I'm gonna do some recording.
I'm here for a couple weeks.
I'd really like to see you.
Why don't you come out to the house?
The children would love to meet you.
It's not exactly
what I had in mind.
- Well...
- Look, I find you very attractive,
and I'd like to see you.
Well, I think it'd be fine if we had
dinner some night here at the house.
You've never met
my husband, Del, have you?
I see. You can't talk now.
I'll call you later.
I'm going home now.
I'll call you when I get there. Bye.
Uh, I'd like to...
Um...
Well, all right. I'll talk to you later.
Thank you for calling.
- He's done well in those primaries.
- He sure has.
That's the key to it.
Excuse me.
Who was it, babe?
Oh, down at
the recording studio.
I left some,
uh, music down there.
- What kind of a gun is it?
- A.38 Smith & Wesson police special.
Uh, this particular gun's
a stainless steel gun.
Did you ever have to shoot it?
Of course, we have to shoot it
to qualify on the range...
but I've never had
to kill anyone with it.
'Course, there's been occasions
where I have had to use it to...
See ya later, alligator.
- Am I too late?
- Well, Esther's asleep now.
She's looking forward
to seeing you in the morning.
If the chairman
of the board of your company...
had been running your business...
the way Washington
has been running our business...
you'd be asking
a lot of questions...
and you would find out
what you already know:
We have some problems
that money alone won't solve.
Now, I know something
about money.
Anybody who grew up without it
knows a lot about money.
I know more about money
than some of the rich...
because I never had any
until I was 27.
I know something
of what money can do...
and more important...
I know something
of what it can't do.
Does it make sense
to let the petroleum industry...
boost their prices at will...
- adding to an already staggering profit...
- Watch where you're going!
But tell the little filling station
owner in his khakis...
- he can't charge one penny more?
- What's wrong with you, you dope?
To tax the salaries of people
on poverty-level income...
- I don't need that shit, you stupid...
- then turn around...
and give back in food stamps...
twice the amount of the tax.
If there's any cleaning up
to be done...
we're going to have to do it.
The Lord is not going
to do the replacing...
and the powers that be...
are certainly not going
to replace themselves.
That old truth remains:
There is no such thing
as a free lunch.
- Hello.
- If the books are to be balanced...
we're going to have
to balance them.
- Yes, sir?
- You've got a room for rent?
Yeah, I'm Mr. Green.
That's me. I'm Mr. Green.
- I'd like to see it.
- What's your name again?
- Kenny. Kenny Fraiser.
- All right, sir, right this way.
Right in the back.
Go right through.
That's your room
straight ahead there, Kenny.
My wife's been in the hospital...
so the house is a little dusty,
but there's clean sheets on the bed.
It's fine.
It's like my room at home.
- The toilet's down at the end of the hall.
- Fine.
- You a musician?
- Yeah.
Well, now, my niece
is interested in music.
Martha!
This here is Kenny.
This is Martha.
- Hi!
- Hi.
She's from California.
- Uh, $13.50?
- That's right. $13.50 a week.
And you can have breakfast
with me if you want.
- Of course, you'll have
to help wash the dishes.
- That's fine.
Let me put this down,
and I'll pay you.
Good mornin'.
Barbara Jean, time to get...
- Excuse me.
I must have the wrong room.
- Who are you? I think you do.
Come on, Barbara Jean.
Time to get up.
Come on. Hi.
- Good morning, Louise.
- Did you have a nice rest?
Yeah.
I was just having a dream.
I know the political positions
are laughing...
but not quite as loud today
as they were yesterday.
Del, are you...
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
You want me
to fry you an egg?
No, honey, I'm gonna
hard-boil me a couple eggs.
All right.
I was there
for about a year on a kibbutz.
I was feeling very romantic...
about that kind
of socialism at the time.
I thought I'd like
to have a bash at it.
- Hello.
- Can I talk to Linnea, please?
- Del, I'm on the phone. This is Linnea.
- Okay.
How are you? Listen,
I'm sorry I didn't call sooner, but...
- Who is this?
- This is Tom.
Tom who?
Oh, come on.
- Who is this? Tom who?
- This is Tom. Listen...
I don't know who you are,
why you're calling, and I want you to stop.
- Honey, you know you want to see me.
- I never said any such thing.
Don't you ever call here again,
and I'm not foolin'.
I mean it. Don't you ever call here again!
What's goin' on?
Hello? Linnea?
Hello?
Who was that, babe?
Just some crazy person
been callin' here.
Next time, get on the phone
and tell him you're gonna get the police.
Okay.
Come on.
Yeah, he wants that
in the cadaver room.
How do you get outside, please?
- You dial "9."
- Hi, Mr. Green.
Look at those flowers.
Did you grow those?
Esther and I did, yes.
My niece here picked 'em.
She's from California.
Oh, that's good.
They're so healthy.
Let me check and see if she's awake.
- I see no reason
why I can't use the phone.
- May I see your credentials?
- I'll be happy to show them to you.
- Hi.
Holy dog shit!
Will you look at that?
Must be some friends of Buddy's.
- Uh, Little Women.
- Little Women?
Ever since that Easy Rider movie,
that's the bike everybody's been drivin':
Long, low,
laid-back in the front.
- They're so dangerous, aren't they?
- They are.
Over here at the Baptist Hospital,
there's a whole ward of young boys...
the cutest, best-lookin' boys
you'd ever want to see...
just paralyzed
from the waist down.
Oh! Excuse me.
Thank you for the ride, darling.
- Break a leg.
- Have you passed the bar yet?
- Oh, yeah.
- Not that bar.
No, I know. Excuse me.
- Well, well, well. Young Hamilton!
- How are you?
- Fine, fine.
Give us a kiss, love.
You're a shy young man,
aren't you?
- Is your dad around?
- Uh, yes, but...
- Do you think I could have...
- Later.
A little chat with him?
He's kind of tied up right now,
but maybe you could...
- Is your mum around?
- No, as a matter of fact,
my mom is in Paris.
- This is Bergman!
- I like it. It's kind of nice.
Pure, unadulterated Bergman!
It's beautiful!
- Do you live here?
- Yeah, we do.
We've been here
for quite a while.
Lucky you! It's so gorgeous.
I've never seen...
- Of course, the people are all wrong
for Bergman, aren't they?
- Oh, yeah.
Well, I suppose
you're interested in horses.
Yeah, I like horses. Sure.
Honey, you should arrange for him
to visit one of our horse shows.
Haven breeds those famous
Tennessee Walkers you've heard about.
- Oh, really?
- Oh, Mr. Triplette knows all about walkers.
That is not the kind of walker
I had in mind.
- That's very fast.
- We have to be.
She had this most
horrible accident.
- Hi, Marie. How are you?
- How are you?
And she got a lick on the head
gettin' into a car...
one of those tiny cars,
her daughter's car.
This happened
almost a year ago.
No one had any idea this was gonna
develop into such a horrible thing.
Mr., uh, Triplette...
I'm real sorry
ole Delbert told you...
Haven would appear
at the political rally.
He knows better than that.
We never let Haven Hamilton
take sides politically.
You understand we give
contributions to everybody.
And they are not
puny contributions.
Only time I ever went
hog-wild around the bend...
was for the Kennedy boys.
Tsk.
But they were different.
- Yes, ma'am, they were.
- That's a fact.
Excuse me a minute.
Thank you, Brenda.
Is this party
somebody's birthday, or...
No, this is, uh...
I'm sure you've seen Haven Hamilton.
- No, I never heard of him.
- He's been a country-western star...
Do we get out here?
Let me, uh...
Let me get that door.
Listen, I wanted to ask...
Would it be all right
if I asked Mr. Gould a question?
- You want to ask me something?
- We're gonna be riding back with you.
Could we wait until then?
I just wanted to know
what you were doing in Nashville.
Just coming to a party.
What are you doing here in Nashville?
- I'm stuck here.
- Oh, yeah?
We'll see you in a bit.
Haven is singing tonight
at the Grand Ole Opry...
and this is just
a previous sort of party...
- Oh, yeah?
- For his friends.
He's got
a lot of photographers here.
What are you doing here, anyway?
I came on a date, and now I'm goin'
to the Grand Ole Opry.
How you gonna go
to the Grand Ole Opry?
- "How"?
- Yeah. You came with a date.
- Is he gonna take you?
- Huh? No.
They left.
No, I'm promoting a movie,
but I'm not making one.
- Are you a personal friend
of Mr. Hamilton's?
- Yeah, we're very good friends.
No, I'm not a singer.
I'm a businessman.
I take care
of all Dad's business.
- You're a businessman?
- Yeah.
With that face?
You can't be a businessman.
Yeah, I... I work with,
uh, Dad's company.
I take care of his records
and all of his business.
Anything that comes in
comes through me.
- Do you like it?
- Yeah, it's great. It really is.
Dad's wanted me
to do that all his life.
Haven, listen,
I'd be the last guy in the world...
to try and change your mind
about something you don't want to do...
but I'd like to explain a couple things
about what we're trying to do...
in this campaign
before you discount it altogether.
And somehow the blood...
began to drain
into behind her eyeball...
and the pressure caused
her eye just to bulge out.
It was all red.
It was just awful-lookin'.
Everybody thought
she was gonna lose her eye.
We still don't know
how it's gonna come out.
I don't know how
you're gonna feel about this...
but, uh...
Walker thinks that...
you'd make
a fine governor in this state.
He thinks the time's right.
He thinks the people
of Tennessee love you.
He knows they do.
He knows how you feel about them.
And he wants you
to know that...
should the time come
you want to run...
he'll be there with his organization
to back you all the way.
Elliot Gould,
Delbert and Linnea Reese.
- Del Reese.
- Mrs. Reese.
And Mrs. Dorster.
Elliot Gould.
You gonna be
at Opryland tonight?
Well, I...
I hadn't thought I would be.
Well, I'm gonna be
at Opryland tonight.
Oh, well, sure, I'll be there.
Sure.
Yes, I guess you will.
And that's when
I'll give you my decision.
Well, thank you so much
for thinking about it.
Terrific.
- Is Haven around?
- Yeah, right around the corner.
Would you check and see
if it's all right if we come?
- Yeah.
- I see him with other people.
Thank you, Del.
Do you want to be a singer?
Look at me.
- Look at me.
- I think everybody...
Dad wouldn't hear of it.
He really wouldn't. He...
But you want to be a singer.
- I know him. That's Elliot Gould.
- This guy?
- He's a really well-known actor.
- Oh, yes, with the curly hair.
Yeah. He was married
to Barbra Streisand.
- He's grossin' real big.
- You gotta be kiddin' me.
No. That girl that sang "People."
I just shook the man's hand
like he was somebody off the street.
- Delbert! Go over there
and bring him on over.
- Yes, sir.
- Oh, Delbert!
- We all walk on the street, Delbert.
Oh, Delbert.
Listen, you all come over.
Haven wants to meet you right away.
I didn't realize who you were
when we first were introduced.
You wrote a song?
Yeah, I wrote one song
in my life, and, uh...
- I'd love to hear it.
- Are you sure?
- Mm-hmm.
- Okay.
It's Elliot Gould!
Well, let me meet the movie star!
Lady Pearl, Elliot Gould.
- Haven Hamilton.
- Well, how do you do, Mr. Gould?
So nice to meet you. Welcome
to Nashville and to my lovely home.
- Elliot! Elliot Gould!
- What brings you here?
- Oh, hello.
- Hello!
- I'm just, uh...
How are you?
You look marvelous!
- Is this another unexpected guest?
- I'm Opal from the BBC.
Remember
the Cannes Film Festival?
No, of course you wouldn't.
How silly of me.
What are you doing...
- What am I doing in Nashville?
- Excuse me. I'm sorry.
- I'm doing this documentary...
- Excuse me, but Mr. Gould
does not give interviews.
I don't know who you are
or what you're doing here...
but I will not tolerate rudeness
in the presence of a star.
Two stars.
Just take her, Delbert.
Thank you very much. Good-bye.
- Mr. Hamilton!
- It's gonna be all right.
- No, listen...
- Who are you?
Well, that's the price
of success, I guess.
Certainly is.
Go get a Goo Goo,
friends, and settle back...
for 30 of the goodest
minutes in radio...
the Goo Goo Grand Ole Opry!
It's sent your way
by the makers of Goo Goo...
the goodest candy bar
in the world...
and King Leo pure stick candy,
the candy that roars with flavor.
Now a big welcome, if you please,
for the Goo Goo man of the hour...
Tommy Brown!
Okay, this is it.
- This is it, all right.
- Yeah, all right.
- It's the new one!
- Yeah, I know.
- It's the new one, all right.
- Have you got the time?
Sure. Yeah. It's, uh...
All right!
I'm Del Reese, and I'm goin' back
to Haven Hamilton's group.
- Remember me?
- This young lady's with me here.
I'm being interviewed by her...
and I really gotta go
to the bathroom.
Oh, yeah! Thank you!
Thank you, Tommy.
Beautiful job, as always.
Say, Harold Weakly,
have you been on vacation yet?
Gosh, no.
I've been busier than a puppy...
in a room full of rubber balls.
And if you're like me,
all that hustling and bustling...
makes you want to sit down
and let the world go by...
while you enjoy
a Goo Goo candy cluster.
- Hey, Steve. She's with me.
- Excuse me. Can I help you?
- I'm with these people here.
- Do you have a backstage pass?
A pass?
They didn't need a pass.
You need a pass
to go backstage.
Go get a Goo Goo, the South's
favorite piece of candy for 62 years.
- You ready to do the song?
- Right.
- Okay.
I wouldn't worry
about killin' 'em. They're already dead.
- Yes, thank you.
- You're lucky to be alive.
Haven Hamilton!
Yeah.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
Well, I want to thank you
for that wonderful, warm welcome.
And I'm sure
you meant to share it with...
with Bud Hamilton,
my son, who's here.
Stand up, Bud.
Isn't he somethin' else?
Yes, indeed. Yes, indeed.
God bless you, and thank you
so much for that warm welcome.
- How tall is that guy?
- Who?
- Today I'd like to do
a special treat for you...
- Haven.
- A brand-new song.
- Don't ever ask him that, John.
That's funny, because...
Oh, there's Connie White!
How are you, honey?
You know what?
You remember you signed my album?
Well, thank you
for coming to the show.
I have a song I wrote.
I'll give you a call tomorrow.
- That's fine.
- We'll just chat, you know, and...
You remember what I wrote on
the program? Will you remember?
- "I'm your friend. Connie White."
- I like your dress. I'm gonna get one too.
But I like the gold one
with the be...
you know, when you...
when you have no waist.
Thank you. Thank you.
- He's got the entire galaxy
on the back of his shirt.
- Thank you so much.
And now I'd like to do
a special old favorite...
the song that got me started
in this business...
that's been so kind to me...
a song you've loved
through the years...
and one I'm sure
you're gonna love tonight.
Thank you.
Well, now, Wilton's goin'!
Come on, Wilton!
Let's hear it for Wilton!
You gettin' ready, Joe?
Now everybody's goin'!
Yes, sir!
Well, thank you.
Thank you, and God love you.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
Of course, we want to send
very special wishes...
and greetings
to our own Barbara Jean.
I know most of you read...
that she collapsed
out at the airport.
She's in the hospital.
She's in Vanderbilt Hospital
recuperating...
and Barnett tells me
she really cried real tears...
because she couldn't
be here with you tonight.
But I hope you'll send some letters
and best wishes and prayers to her.
That's Vanderbilt Hospital,
Nashville, Tennessee 27322.
And you tell her
Haven told you to write.
Now, as a special
stand-in for her...
we have her dear friend
Connie White...
who got out of the dentist's chair
this morning...
where she was having
some root-canal work...
and came all the way out here
to sing for you.
Miss Connie White, who's a friend
not only of Barbara Jean's...
but a friend
of yours and mine.
A wonderful singer
in her own way...
Miss Connie White!
Come on out, Connie!
- Hi, Del. How are you?
- I want you to meet John Triplette.
You look so good.
Wonderful!
Isn't she lovely, folks?
Isn't she beautiful?
We might want to talk.
- We'll talk about it later.
- Nice to see you.
Well, who do we have here?
- What is your name, honey?
- Paul Harris.
Paul Harris.
He's 13, he said.
And what's your name, honey?
Last time I saw a dress like that,
I was headin' for the junior prom.
You boys havin' a good time tonight?
The girl fell out of the car.
I want you to study real hard,
because just remember...
any one of you can grow up
to be the president.
Turn that off.
Okay.
One more minute, darlin'.
- Right now.
- She'll be through in a moment.
I want you
to turn it off right now!
It bothers me.
It bothers me too,
but I gotta listen, don't I?
- Why?
- Come on, now, honey.
I gotta go to the King of the Road
and thank her for you.
- Thank her?
- I gotta know what songs she sang.
You can ask anybody.
You can call.
You can send flowers.
You can send a message.
Come on.
Don't get upset, now.
You're makin' me ruin
my nail-polish job.
Do I tell you how to sing,
darlin'? Hmm?
Have I ever told you
how to sing a song?
That ain't the point.
I know why you're goin' over there.
Don't tell me how to run your life.
I've been doin' pretty good with it.
You go... Wh...
Let's calm down.
We're gettin' on each other's nerves.
You're goin' to the King of the Road
so you can hobnob with everybody.
- So I can do what? "Hobnob"?
- I ain't got no friends.
I gotta sit here
in this goddamn hospital.
- They're all gonna talk
about how I'm a nut.
- I ain't doin' no hobnobbin'.
Now, whoa, whoa, whoa.
"Barbara Jean had another collapse."
You know what?
While you're at it...
why don't you take her
some of my flowers?
- Are you through?
- No, I ain't through.
- Are you through, darlin'?
- Take her this nice black one.
That'll cheer her up.
- Why don't you try these?
- Are you through?
- And these.
- I said, are you through?
And why don't you try these?
And this...
Are you through, I said?
Are you through...
Are you goin' nutsy on me?
'Cause I won't stand for that,
Barbara Jean.
Huh? You havin' one of them
nervous breakdowns again?
- Huh?
- No.
You could've fooled me,
'cause it looks like you're ready for it.
You just settle down and shape up.
You understand?
The only reason I'm goin' over there
is 'cause I love you.
I don't love to go over there
and hobnob with them phonies.
Why do you make me
raise my voice to you?
Why do you put us both
through this?
Are you all right?
Come on, now.
Let's have a little smile for Barnett.
- I'm tired of this place.
- Come on, now.
Come on, now.
Get up.
You help me, I help you.
All right? Come on, now.
Come on.
Now, where's Barnett goin'?
Where am I goin'?
Hmm?
- King of the Road.
- And why am I goin' there?
- To see Connie.
- And why am I doin' that?
To thank her
for singin' at the Opry.
- Who am I doin' that for?
- You're doin' it for me.
That's right.
Now, I'm walkin' out now.
What do you say?
You say "bye-bye."
Bye.
- Bye-bye.
- Bye.
Barnett?
- Hello, Ben.
- Hi.
Aren't they wonderful?
So marvelous.
What are you upset about?
She's really late.
- Well, she's not that late.
- No, she's late.
- Thank you.
- He's right over there.
I thought you were
very, very good tonight.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
She sounded beautiful.
She looked beautiful.
Well, Sue,
I didn't expect to see you.
- I wanted you to meet Julie Christie.
- Well, excuse my back.
- So nice to see you.
- Did you see Doctor Zhivago?
- She the one that got off the train?
- Will you be here a while?
- No, just passing through.
- Please sit down.
- Do sit down and have a drink with us.
- We're not staying.
You're English, aren't you?
I could tell.
Look at her.
Isn't she lovely?
- This is such a coincidence.
- I'm Del Reese.
Yes. I was talkin' about
the Christy Minstrels just this mornin'...
and now we have
Julie Christie here.
- I met you with Peter Finch.
- Oh, yeah?
- You won't sit down and stay?
- No, thank you.
- Julie has a friend at the Exit/In.
- I hope your stay is very nice...
and I hope you'll remember what film
facilities we have in Nashville.
- Oh, yeah, sure.
- Thank you. Good to see you.
- Have a lovely evening. Good-bye.
- Bye-bye.
Nice to see you.
Well, isn't that an honor?
- What a surprise. Julie Christie.
- Who's Julie Christie?
"Who's Julie Christie?"
She's a famous star.
She's won the Academy Award.
- Oh!
- No, I'm not kiddin'.
She got it for one of those pictures.
I don't know which one.
- She's done so many.
- Isn't he a gem?
- He's got the worst sense of humor.
- No, she's lovely.
Come on.
She can't even comb her hair.
Oh, you've got
a Hal Phillip Walker button.
No, it's Kennedy.
Isn't that rather ancient?
How strange! I thought everybody
in the South didn't go for Kennedy.
It's John Fitzgerald Kennedy.
Well, he...
he took the whole South...
except for Tennessee,
Florida, Kentucky.
And there's a reason
he didn't take Tennessee.
But he got 481,453 votes...
and the asshole
got 556,577 votes.
I just can tell.
It's something...
It's the way she looks at me.
You know that feeling you get
that there's somethin' else going on?
And if I do a performance
when I'm too tired, it doesn't have...
- Hey, y'all.
- Hi, Barnett.
- How are you, Connie?
Now, the problem we got here...
is anti-Catholicism.
These dumbheads
around here, they're all...
Baptists and whatever,
I don't know.
Even to teach 'em
to make change over the bar...
you gotta crack their skulls...
let alone teach 'em
to vote for the Catholic...
just because he happens
to be a better man.
Here, this is just somethin'...
somethin' that Barbara Jean
told me to pick up for you.
- You shouldn't have.
- I know, but she told me.
- I told her I shouldn't have.
- Did you get the flowers we sent?
Thank you.
Appreciate it.
Thank you very much.
As most of you might have noticed...
we have a celebrity
with us tonight.
If we get our hands together,
we might can get a song.
- Miss Connie White.
- From the goodness of her heart.
What do you want, a few bucks?
Huh? You holdin' out
for somethin' better?
She's a real sweetie pie.
Thank you very much.
That's what I love about this place.
Can you see me? I can't see you.
- That was a nice gesture.
- I'm gonna sing something y'all know.
- What was a nice gesture?
- Join me on the choruses.
Don't seem to be
appreciated, do it?
"Rolling Stone."
Thank you.
Everybody!
And all I remember
the next few days was...
I was just lookin'
at that TV set and seein' it all...
seein' that great
fat-bellied sheriff...
sayin',
"Ruby, you son of a bitch."
And Oswald...
and her in her little pink suit.
Here's the best.
Here's Vassar.
And then comes Bobby.
Oh, I worked for him.
- Don't you think we...
- I worked here.
I worked all over the country.
I worked out in California,
out in Stockton.
Bobby came here and spoke,
he went down to Memphis...
and then he even went out
to Stockton, California...
and spoke off the Santa Fe train
at the old Santa Fe depot.
Oh...
he was a beautiful man.
He was not much like...
uh, John, you know.
He was more puny-like.
But all the time
I was workin' for him...
I was just so scared.
Inside, you know?
Just scared.
Haven, do you think we could
get Connie out to the rally?
Connie White and Barbara Jean never
appear on the same stage together.
Connie can replace Barbara Jean,
but that's it.
As for Haven Hamilton, well...
I'll appear wherever
Barbara Jean appears.
I got a good mind to take you outside.
With my wife in the hospital,
you puttin' that shit on me?
Calm down, Barnett.
Calm down, enjoy the show.
- Barnett's angry.
- Okay.
I think she's having an affair here.
I really do.
You are way, way off.
Are you kidding?
I love you.
And on the profession
of your faith...
I baptize you, my sister...
in the name of the Father
and of the Son...
and of the Holy Ghost.
Amen.
is on the same floor
with Barbara Jean.
in the service too.
- Yes, sir.
- Oh, not the army. It was the navy.
We lost him in the South Pacific.
We don't know how.
Sorry to hear that, sir.
- World War I I.
- Yes, sir.
I'm wandering in a graveyard.
The dead here have no crosses...
nor tombstones, nor wreaths
to sing of their past glory...
but lie in rotting, decaying...
rusty heaps...
their innards ripped out...
by greedy, vulturous hands...
their vast, vacant skeletons...
sadly sighing to the sky.
The rust on their bodies...
is the color of dried blood.
Dried blood.
I'm reminded of...
of an elephant's
secret burial ground.
Yes.
Cet air de mystre.
Cette essence de I'irrel.
These cars
are trying to communicate.
O cars, are you trying
to tell me something?
- Are you trying to convey some secret...
- What? What? Excuse me?
Oh, excuse me.
I thought
I was completely alone.
How embarrassing!
Oh, you're a musician!
A round of applause
for Miss Daisy Hoy.
Miss Albuquerque.
Hi, Frog.
This is with gestures.
Miss Jill Brown
on the track in number 78.
You wanna talk
about yesterday?
Get up, goddamn it!
You fucker!
You wanna talk
about yesterday?
Do you wanna talk about yesterday
or not? What are you...
Shit.
Come out of there!
You leave me alone!
Come on!
Look, I know what's...
For Christ's sake, what...
Now...
What are you doing?
You wanna talk about yesterday or not?
Oh, that's terrific.
Hey, that's great. Hey, terrific.
It's great. Oh, thanks.
My turtle. Thanks a lot.
Look, just relax!
Look, I know what's goin' on.
Great.
House detective.
Bill, hi.
I'm John Triplette.
Am I early?
I called you this morning.
- Oh, the guy from TV.
- Yeah. How are ya?
- Come on in.
- Thank you.
- Sure.
Just... We're just
cleanin' up here.
- You know, the...
- Sunday morning blues.
- Would you hold this?
- Sure.
Thanks. Let me just
move this over here.
- Is this your new album?
- Yeah. That's our only album.
It's a very good one, though.
I've heard it.
- Oh, thank you.
- It's terrific.
- I'm really sorry about the mess.
- That's all right.
You oughta see my room.
We had a little party last night.
Had a pretty good time too.
- Uh...
- I wanted to, um...
tell you about what we're trying
to do with this show.
- Can I get you a drink?
- No, thanks.
- I could call down.
- I don't want to take up your time.
I just want to tell you a little bit
about what we're trying to do.
I know you're astute politically,
and I'm certainly not here
to sell you a bill of goods.
- Don't care. Don't care about politics.
- No politics? Okay, great.
Let me tell you, then,
I've got a problem...
that I think could work
to your advantage.
As you know, this redneck music
is very popular right now...
and I've got an awful lot
of these local yokels...
on the bill singing...
- Your basic country folk.
- Country crapola. Right.
So I think, uh...
What I'm going for
is a broader appeal.
- Which is where we would fit in.
- More than just this Southern thing.
And I think that
a really hip group like yours...
could walk off with the evening.
Yeah. Probably the only
rock group on the...
- Absolutely, yeah.
- Sounds good.
- Sounds inviting.
- Yeah.
And I think
you do get a lot of...
a big audience
from these country guys.
Is this just network, or is it...
It's better than network.
It's syndicated.
They'll be showing it
for a year and a half.
- Your glasses, sweetheart.
- Oh, thanks.
This is my wife, Mary.
This is John Triplette.
Sit down, dear. Go ahead.
He's, uh... he's the fella
from the television show...
that they're doing
for Hal Phillip Walker.
That political thing going on.
He's offered us a spot.
You're doing some great promotion
on that guy. All those buttons and...
- Thank you. I'm trying.
- And bumper stickers.
Anyways, we got
a great time spot on this gala...
and we're gonna walk away
with the show, John says.
We can't vote for him
because we're registered Democrats.
And besides,
he's a little crazy, isn't he?
Well, they're all a little crazy.
- I'll drink to that.
- That's the name of the game.
But I think the thing
you should consider is your future.
It would give you a great shot.
But it doesn't make any difference.
We're registered Democrats.
Well, I'm a registered Democrat!
The only reason
we're registered Democrats...
is because your father's
a registered Democrat...
and his father's
a registered Democrat.
Tom's a registered Democrat,
and he wouldn't do it.
- Hi, Tom.
- Hi, Norman. How you doin'?
Good. I'm sure glad you called.
Is there anything I can...
- Sit down.
- Okay.
- You don't have
any speckled birds, do you?
- What? Oh.
You know,
LA turnarounds. Uppers.
Uh, no, no, I, uh...
But I know where
to get some grass.
- No, thanks. I don't need any grass.
- Okay.
- Uh, can I ask you a question?
- Mm-hmm.
Is there something...
Are you angry at Bill?
- No.
- Oh.
'Cause I, uh...
You know, I, uh...
Bill and Mary
and you and, uh...
Well, Bill...
I mean, Bill seems to be, um...
Uh...
- I'm just confused.
- Mm.
Uh...
- Here, why don't you write yourself a hit?
- Okay.
- Hello.
- Hi. Can I talk to Cherry, please?
She's in bed with R.Y.
You wanna talk to R.Y?
- I'd rather talk to her, if I could.
- Who is this?
- This is Frank,
one of the cooks at the restaurant.
- Are you a Jehovah Witness?
Does it make sense that the churches...
should remain untaxed
on their vast holdings of land...
and corporate investments?
Does it make sense that
a multimillion-dollar income...
should go untaxed
year after year?
No, all will not be easy...
but we will bask
in the satisfaction...
of having done
what we should have done.
And if we don't
get it done today...
we may run out of tomorrows.
The buses!
The buses are empty...
and look almost menacing...
threatening,
as so many yellow dragons...
watching me
with their hollow, vacant eyes.
I wonder how many little
black children and white children...
have yellow nightmares...
their own special brand of fear
for the yellow peril.
I can't have...
I can't start...
Damn it!
It's got to be more... positive.
No, more negative.
Start again.
Yellow is the color
of caution.
No.
Yellow is the color
of cowardice.
of sunshine.
And yet I see
very little sunshine...
in the lives of all the little
black children and white children.
I see their lives, rather,
as a study in grayness...
a mixture of black and...
Oh, Christ, no.
That's fascist. Oh!
Yellow, yellow, yellow.
Yellow fever.
I think we'll be able to talk about it.
They're checkin' out now.
- Get together with him before he leaves.
- What about the place?
- It's not bad at all.
- Think it'll work out?
Yeah. It's got this bizarre stage
that drops out of the ceiling.
- I know.
- Have you seen it?
They're gettin' out this mornin'.
- The place is very confused.
- Bye-bye!
Wait a minute.
Here we go. Uh, Barnett?
- Yes?
- Phone's for you.
- Is it important, or what?
- Bye, girls.
- Hello.
- Hello, Barnett. John Triplette.
Oh, are you...
Are you going...
Mr. Green, how are you?
I'm goin' home.
- I'm glad to hear that.
- Thank you. How is Mrs. Green?
She's fine, and she's gonna be
thrilled I saw you again.
Give her my very best.
And is she takin' her vitamin E?
- Got 'em right here.
- All right. Good for you.
- You take care, darlin'. Bye-bye.
- Unbelievable.
All right, come on.
Let's get her on there.
We got to go with those
white horseshoes, huh?
We're gonna live
with those for infamy.
Take that on the other elevator.
Didn't the doctor
get ahold of you?
I'm really sorry
I have to tell you this.
Mrs. Green expired
this morning.
What?
Mrs. Green died this morning.
Wait right here.
Let me go get the doctor.
Mr. Green?
Mr. Green, you know,
my mama saved her life.
They used to live
next door to each other.
My mama put out the flames.
She always loved Barbara Jean
more than anything.
She's still keepin'
a scrapbook on her.
The only thing she said to me
when I joined up was...
"Son, when you're doin' your travels,
I want you to see Barbara Jean.
Don't say nothin' about me.
Just see Barbara Jean."
So that's what I been doin'.
Now I'm gonna go over
to Opryland and hear her sing.
Give my best to your wife, now.
Let me turn this...
Wait a minute. Don't laugh.
I... Let me... Just...
I have a theory
about political assassination.
You see, I believe
people like Madame Pearl...
and all these people here
in this country who carry guns...
are the real assassins.
Because, you see,
they stimulate other people...
who are perhaps innocent...
and who eventually
are the ones who pull the trigger.
- Mom?
- Kenny? Where are you, Kenny?
- I'm in Nashville. How are you?
- I've been so worried.
- There's no reason to worry.
- I haven't been able to sleep.
I had to take some NyQuil
so I could go to sleep, you know?
- Puts you right out.
- Did it help?
Yeah, it did.
Where are you staying in Nashville?
- I'm staying at a rooming house.
- Who you talkin' to?
- To my mother.
- Who are you talking to, Kenny?
- A girl that lives in the rooming house.
- A girl that lives...
- Who owns that rooming house?
- Her uncle.
A man owns the rooming house?
It can't be very clean.
- Don't be silly.
- I bet the sheets aren't clean.
In the South
you can pick up this parasite...
- Joan, put that down, please!
- Kenny, listen...
- Just a minute.
- Just wanted to look at your fiddle.
Kenny! You can get
this parasite fungus in the South.
It's difficult to get rid of.
When are you coming home?
- I don't know. A couple of weeks.
- You left your blue suit in the closet.
- I don't need my blue suit.
- I would really like you
to get home as soon as you can.
- I'm... been a little...
- Mother, just listen to me.
Kenny, don't you talk to me
in that tone of voice.
I love you too, Mama.
I really do.
I'll see you soon.
Bye-bye.
Let's find Barnett.
I hope he's not in a bad mood.
- Hey, Barnett.
- I'm obliged to you, but...
- What do you want now?
This guy wants her to do four shows.
What do you want?
Don't let her do too much.
How you hangin'?
- You feelin' better she's better?
- Yeah, I feel swell.
We gotta talk to you.
We're gonna do a show.
Okay?
John's doing this show.
Haven's gonna do it.
We want Barbara Jean to headline it.
- Unbelievable.
- Now wait a second.
I wish they wouldn't rush us.
Get a shot.
It's for this candidate,
Hal Phillip Walker.
We don't want her to make
any political statement at all.
What do you think
her bein' there's gonna be?
- Ain't that a political statement?
- People haven't seen her.
No! No, fellas.
Don't take it personal.
No. No politics,
no government, no nothin'.
- All right? Okay?
- All right.
- I heard you all out.
- Hello, boys. How's it goin'?
I believe I met you before
in the hospital.
Look at that. Didn't Jewel
show you how to do her hair?
- Come on, darlin'.
- How's it goin'?
- No pictures.
- I'm all excited. A little rushed, but...
- How do you feel?
- Great.
I told the band you're gonna
start off with the cowboy song.
- Forget it.
- No, just leave it to me.
He's crazy.
He can take a flying leap.
I'm gonna stay after him
like a rodent, man.
Thank you. Thank you.
Have you been in Vietnam?
Yes, you have.
I can tell by your face.
Was it awful?
It was...
It was kind of hot and wet.
Thank you.
I want to tell you all a little secret
you might not know...
and that is that last night
I thanked my lucky stars...
that I could be here at all
to sing for ya.
I heard on the radio
this cutest little boy, nine years old...
and you know how
a deejay'll play a tune...
and ask everybody
to phone in how they like it?
I was listenin' to it,
and they asked for callers to call in.
This little nine-year-old called in.
The song had voices in the background...
like the way they use
backup voices these days...
soundin' like little munchkins?
The deejay said,
"How old are you, son?"
The boy said, "I'm nine,
and I think it's gonna be a hit."
The deejay said, "Why?"
"Because it had those chipmunks in it."
And I thought that was so cute
because I can sing
like a munchkin myself...
and I'm real fond
of The Wizard of Oz.
Plus, I live, you know,
just a ways out here...
off of Interstate 24
on the road to Chattanooga...
so you can see
why I kinda related to that.
I think me and the boys are gonna
strike up another tune. Let's go, boys.
Three, four, one, two.
I think there's a storm.
Seems like it's a-brewin'.
That's what my granddaddy
used to say all the time...
Once he got deaf...
he never talked much no more.
Except sometimes
he'd say, "Oh, gosh"...
or "Oh, durn it" or "My word."
My granny, she'd go around
clickin' her teeth to the radio all day.
Boy, was she a lot of fun,
and cooked always...
my favorite, roast beef,
and she was a sweetheart.
She raised chickens too.
She, uh...
In fact, did you ever hear
a chicken sound?
You know how chickens go?
Here, chick, chick, chick, chick.
Anyway, I guess we'd better strike up
this tune before it's too late.
- Okay, boys.
- Three, four, one, two.
I ever really got
was when Mama...
My grandma... she's the one who
clacked her false teeth to the radio.
She taught my mama how to sing,
and Mama taught me.
One time she took me, 'cause
we was gonna get a new Frigidaire.
She took me to the Frigidaire store
where the man was advertisin'.
This record was goin' 'round...
and my mama told him
I knew how to sing.
He said, "If she learns this tune,
I'll give y'all a quarter."
So Mama and I went home...
And then what happened?
Let's see, I think... Uh, yeah.
We went home...
and I learned both sides
of the record in half an hour.
We went back and pranced in real fancy
and told him I'd learned 'em...
and he said, "Let me hear"...
so I sang him both sides
of the record instead of one.
So he gave us 50 cents, and we went
across the street and had us a soda.
Ever since then,
I been workin'. I don't...
I think ever since then
I been workin' and doin' my...
- Come on, come on.
- Supportin' myself.
- Anyway...
- Hey, hey. Hey, hey.
- Am I all right?
- I'm gonna get you some lemonade.
- You're fine. It's the microphone.
- I ain't done.
- I know.
- Go get some... glass of water.
Boys, help her off.
You'll come back. Okay, darlin'?
Thank you!
All right. Watch the wire.
All right. Okay.
Aw, come on.
Have a heart, now.
Thank you!
Come on, now.
It's just too soon.
All of you must know...
Come on.
You didn't mean that, did you?
That little girl's just come
out of the hospital.
You know that girl
just come out of the hospital.
I'm sorry. That little girl's
in there cryin' her eyes out...
'cause she didn't want
to disappoint you.
Y'all show up at Centennial Park
tomorrow at the Parthenon.
You'll see her for free
as our guests. How's that?
All right?
Okay, let's hear a welcome.
A get-well welcome for Barbara Jean.
Let's hear it. Come on!
Ingrates.
All they are is ingrates.
I got trapped out there,
and you guys know it.
- I want some ground rules right now.
- You name it.
- She's gonna sing first, right?
- Right.
She's gonna be off
before that man even shows.
Fine. Whatever you want.
- Never should've brought her here.
- Any way you want it.
No paraphernalia, no literature
being circulated. You understand?
And never, at any time, is she to be
associated with Hal Phillip Walker.
- Hello?
- Hey.
Guess who.
- Linnea?
- Yes, it's me.
Hi. This is Tom.
Listen, I'm playing a gig tonight downtown.
You want to come and meet me?
It's at a place called the, uh...
No Exit, or the Exit...
Exit Out, or somethin'.
Anyhow, it's right across the street
from Friday's, on Church Street.
You know where that is,
don't you?
Anyhow, I'll be there
at 8:00, and, uh...
why don't you
meet me there?
- Okay?
- Um...
Driver, could I have
a wee bit more champagne?
- It's Norman.
- Oh.
Norman, yes.
Norman. Of course.
He doesn't like
to be known as a driver.
Oh. Thank you so much,
Norman.
- Have you ever been
to the ladies' restroom here?
- No.
I'm stuck here at the Exit/In
with no place left to go.
- I'll have a cider.
- Apple cider?
- Yes. Thank you.
- Put it on my bill.
- On another bill?
- Yeah.
Uh, all right. And would you
put it in a wine glass, please?
Put it in a wine glass
and put it on my bill.
Traveling
in cozy, close quarters...
I mean, you sort of
have to camp in one room.
- Well, Mary and I camp in one room.
- Obviously, yes...
- Tom camps in a lot of rooms.
- I shouldn't...
My name's Wade Coolidge.
What's yours?
Um, Linnea is my name.
Well, shall I say
that Tom and I, um...
- You sang together?
- No, I mean...
we sort of got to know
each other, um...
in the biblical sense,
shall we say.
- You went to church?
- I'm sorry.
No, I'm sorry.
This is dreadful.
But he is so attractive,
I was wondering...
I shouldn't be asking you.
I should really be asking Mary.
You went to bed
with him, right?
Oh, yeah.
I thought you understood that.
Well, I shouldn't...
Where did you go
to bed with him?
Listen, we got
a special treat tonight.
A friend of mine
is in town cuttin' an album.
- That's you.
- Tom Frank is in the audience.
Tom? Speak of the devil!
He's agreed to come up
and do a couple of numbers.
Let's make him feel at home.
Tom Frank!
Come on!
Right.
Goddamn it!
- I haven't seen him for more than two minutes in three days.
-  - Thank you.
- As y'all may remember,
I used to be part of a trio.
- "Used to be"?
I been hidin' from 'em all week,
but they found me tonight...
so we might as well have
them up here too.
- Bill and Mary.
- Lovely!
Yes, you must!
I've been watching it all week.
Thank you, thank you.
We don't need to sing at all.
You guys can do it for us.
Mm!
When this is all over, I'm gonna
be taking them back to someplace...
and we could drive around.
I can show you
a little bit of Nashville...
and I can tell you things
that'd send you around the corner.
I'm not kidding.
I know, for instance...
- Uh... What is your name?
- Norman.
Yeah, Norman.
Please, Norman, I...
I make a point never
to gossip with servants.
Thank you.
Okay, fellas,
I think you know...
we've got a good man
to get behind.
I don't wanna take a lot of your time,
'cause we do have
entertainment for ya.
Uh, you got pledge cards
on the table there.
You can pledge
anything you want to.
I'll make sure... I'll make you pay,
whatever you put down there.
If you got a check,
don't be afraid to write it.
I'll get that to the bank quick,
before you can stop it.
Any cash, anything at all.
Don't anybody
be humble or shy.
That's all. And while you're writin',
so you don't get bored or anything...
Just keep your eyes up,
'cause good things come from above.
- Hi, y'all.
- Hi!
My name's Sueleen Gay...
and I'm here to sing you a song
about a girl that never gets enough.
She's the worst singer
I ever heard.
She cannot sing a lick,
can she?
Hey, you forgot your jacket.
Excuse me.
I gotta go to the bathroom.
If you want more,
it's gonna have to be me alone...
'cause it seems
I just been deserted.
I'm gonna play
somethin' that, uh...
I wrote just recently...
- and came here to record.
- All right!
I'm gonna dedicate this to someone
special who might be here tonight.
This is a song called
"I'm Easy."
Do it to me.
- Hi.
- Hi!
I'm gonna sing you all
a song Barbara Jean wrote.
Just wanna get comfortable.
It's called, uh,
"One, I Love You."
Boo! Come on, now!
Boo! Come on! Take it off!
- Did you tell Trout what you wanted?
- Did I? It was your job.
- I know.
- I assumed he knew what...
Well, I didn't think
it was gonna be any problem.
Come on! What is this?
Come on back here, baby!
- What's the matter, honey?
- I don't understand what's goin' on.
Didn't Trout tell you
you're supposed to strip?
I'm a singer!
Listen, go finish the show
like you told Trout you'd do...
and I'll set it up
so you can sing in the Parthenon.
- Huh?
- I'll set it up for you so you can sing
in the Parthenon with Barbara Jean.
- Go finish the show...
- I'm gonna get to sing with Barbara Jean?
Yes, you are. Yes, you will.
I'll take care of it.
Go finish the show
like you told Trout you'd do, okay?
These fellas really like you, honey.
- Okay?
- I'm gonna be as big a star
as Barbara Jean is one day.
I know you are.
You can't miss.
- Go on, now.
- Come on, let's have the show!
Whoo! Hey!
All right! All right!
You're my mama!
All right!
Whoo! Hey, hey, hey!
Want to learn how to say
something in sign language?
Yeah.
How do you say "I love you"?
Well, you could say...
Shorthand for it is...
This is shorthand.
Or you could say, "I"...
you could say, "love you."
- "I love you"?
- Mm-hmm.
Or you could just say,
"I'm happy I met you."
- I'm happy I met you.
- Right.
Phew.
How can you smoke
those things?
It's easy.
- Do you smoke?
- No.
What do you wanna
do that for?
- Doesn't look good.
- No?
- Hm-mmm.
- So what?
- Tom, I have to go.
- Aw.
- Can't you just call him,
tell him you're hung up?
- No, I can't.
- Couldn't you just stay another hour?
- No, no.
I just can't.
Long-distance operator.
You want this charged to your room?
- Yeah, please.
- Your room number, please?
One-twelve.
- Hello?
- Hey.
- How you doin'?
- Oh, wow.
Listen, I'm real sorry
I left the way I did.
Oh, wow.
It's really nice to talk to you.
It's okay.
It's nice to talk to you too.
- What are you doing?
- I'm thinkin' about you.
You are? Wow.
Can you come down here?
- When?
- Tonight.
- Oh, Tom, I can't do that.
- Why not?
We have an opening at the museum
tomorrow. I can't leave my job like that.
Why don't you quit?
I'm makin' bread here.
We've tried that before.
It doesn't work.
I need to be busy.
I'll wait for you here.
When are you coming back?
About a week.
Okay, well, just come on back.
Move back in. It's fine.
I miss you.
I really do.
New York's really been nice.
It's missed you too.
The weather's been terrific.
I went sailing.
- Yeah.
- What's that?
That's just room service.
There's 50 cents on the desk there.
Just pick it up.
- Big tipper.
- Yeah, well, times are hard.
Right, all that money.
You can afford to bring me
down there, I see. Hmm.
- Yeah. Well, never mind.
See you in a week.
- I love you, Tom.
This it, honey?
Be careful gettin' out.
Hey.
Hey!
Hey, wait just a minute.
Just hold it, will ya?
Now...
I know you don't do that
all the time. I...
I want to tell you
that I just... I mean...
Me personally, boy, I...
I'd just like to kiss you all over,
every place.
You know what I'm telling you?
- I think you...
- Sueleen?
You okay?
Shit, man.
Didn't your mama
teach you no manners?
Who was that?
What's the matter with you?
Ain't you gonna talk to me?
Did it go all right?
- Oh, Wade.
- What?
I had to do me a striptease tonight
in front of all those men...
to get to sing at the Parthenon
with Barbara Jean.
Oh, shit! Sueleen, I...
That's dreadful!
That's terrible, girl!
I mean...
I been meanin'
to tell you this for a long time:
You can't sing.
You may as well face the fact
you cannot sing.
You ain't gonna never be no star.
I wish you'd give it up.
They gonna kill ya. They gonna tear
your heart out if you keep on.
They gonna walk
on your soul, girl.
- I don't know
what you're talkin' about.
- You can't sing.
- Do you understand that?
- Yeah? You wanna make a bet?
You wanna come to the Parthenon
and watch me sing with Barbara Jean?
- I am leavin' for Detroit Wednesday.
- You just come and watch.
I'm leavin' for Detroit,
and if you wanna go, come on.
- They gonna kill you in this town!
- You come and see.
- They gonna use you. You know that.
- Bye, Wade.
Dumb bitch!
I don't know why I stick around.
She makes me
so goddamn mad I could spit!
Little more than a year ago,
a man named Hal Phillip Walker...
excited a group of college students
with some questions:
Have you stood
on a high and windy hill...
and heard the acorns
drop and roll?
Have you walked in the valley
beside the brook...
walked alone
and remembered?
Does Christmas
smell like oranges to you?
In a commencement speech,
such questions were fitting, perhaps...
but hardly the material with which
to launch a presidential campaign.
Even those who pay
close attention to politics...
probably saw
Hal Phillip Walker...
and his Replacement Party...
as a bit of frost on the hillside.
Summer, if not late spring,
would surely do away with all that.
Well, now that summer,
along with presidential primaries,
is heavy upon us...
and the frost is still there,
perhaps we should take a closer look.
Hal Phillip Walker is,
in a way, a mystery man.
Out of nowhere, with a handful
of students and scarcely any pros...
he's managed to win
three presidential primaries...
and is given a fighting chance
to take a fourth: Tennessee.
A win in that state would
take on added significance...
for only once
in the last 50 years...
has Tennessee failed to vote
for the winning presidential candidate.
No doubt many Americans,
especially party-liners...
wish that Hal Phillip Walker
would go away...
disappear
like the natural frost...
and come again
at some more convenient season.
But wherever he may be going,
it seems sure...
that Hal Phillip Walker
is not going away...
for there is genuine appeal...
and it must be related
to the raw courage of this man...
running for president,
willing to battle vast oil companies...
eliminate subsidies to farmers...
tax churches,
abolish the electoral college...
change the national anthem...
and remove lawyers from government,
especially from Congress.
At this point, it would be wise
to say most of us...
don't know the answer
to Hal Phillip Walker.
But to answer
one of his questions...
as a matter of fact,
Christmas has always smelled...
like oranges to me.
You may have
to sit out here an hour or so.
All right. It'll give me time
to work on my speech.
Okay, thank you.
Hi. How are you?
Good to see you.
How are you?
- Delbert. How are you?
- Hey, John. How are you?
- Can I say hello?
- He's working on his speech.
- We'll do that later.
- Right.
- He's gonna wait back there, huh?
- He'll sit out there a minute.
- Anybody here yet?
- Yeah, some of the people.
- Barnett?
- I haven't seen him yet,
but he ought to be here quick.
This building
was originally here...
It was made out of lumber
and plaster of Paris.
- Oh, yeah?
- This whole big building.
See, they built it
for a centennial celebration...
and people liked this,
and they didn't want it torn down.
Nashville got to be called
"Athens of the South."
- They sort of took to that.
- Because of this building?
- Yeah, right.
- That's good!
Then they had to rebuild it.
This one was originally just...
this was built back up
right before I was born.
Whoo!
Gonna be a scorcher.
- Will the park police control all this?
- Right.
What's all these chairs?
Hey, Triple, Delbert, come on.
We don't need all these chairs.
- This ain't no band here, right?
- What's the matter, man?
I don't...
I don't believe it!
What's the matter?
Are you guys jerkin' me around?
Do you see what I see, or am I...
What the hell is that sign
doin' up there, Triple?
We had some ground rules.
Am I right?
No political signs,
no advertisements, no noth...
- What the hell are you doin', huh?
Go about your business.
- We'll take care of it.
I have abided by all the ground rules
you laid down, Barnett.
I have Walker sitting out
behind this place like an idiot!
Well, he can sit out in the sun
and parch for all I care!
My wife ain't well! I brought her
out of a hospital bed to be here!
You gave me some truth!
You're full of it, just like your man!
- I have abided by every ground rule.
- Except what?
What is that up there?
She ain't gonna appear here
with that sign up there!
- I have busted my ass for you!
- I'm gonna bust your ass too!
I'm through with it!
Take your wife and take a walk!
I'll tell these people
she's not going to appear again!
- Go on and do it!
- Okay, take a walk, and I'll do it.
You'd do that, huh? You'd put
a knife in my wife's back like that?
You're putting the knife
in her back, buster. You're doing it.
I have not got time
to take the goddamn sign down
and put it back up again!
What are you hollerin' about?
You tryin' to embarrass me?
- I'm tryin' to be heard.
- Get these chairs off, and we'll talk about it.
- Okay. I'll take care of it.
- Chrissake! Delbert... where is that rat?
What are you hiding for,
you little rat?
And grant us
so to serve thee by day...
that we may find
eternal fellowship with them...
through him who died
and rose again for us all...
Jesus Christ, our Lord.
Amen.
- Mr. Green, it's not over.
- I'm going to find Martha.
- What for?
- She owes some respect to Esther.
And now, ladies and gentlemen...
Barbara Jean
and Haven Hamilton.
I'll find her.
Thank you.
For Mama and Daddy.
Thank you so much,
ladies and gentlemen.
- Thank you.
- Wonderful! Wonderful!
Let's hear it for Barbara Jean!
Get that gun!
I'm all right. You get her.
- Dad?
- Bud, help her off. I'm all right.
- Get Walker out of here!
- Get off your asses!
- Watch her head!
Y'all take it easy now.
This isn't Dallas, it's Nashville.
This is Nashville.
You show 'em what we're made of.
They can't do this to us
here in Nashville.
Okay, everybody, sing!
Come on, somebody, sing!
No, I'm fine. You sing.
You stay here and play.
- Somebody sing.
- You've been hurt.
- I'm gonna get somebody to help you.
- Somebody sing. Sing.
Sing!
I think you've been hurt.
Watch your step there.
- Come on, easy, easy.
- I can't stop that blood, man!
Excuse me.
Have you got a car or somethin'?
Can you please tell me
what's happened?
except Clorox bottles
and plastic flyswatters...
Come on, everybody!
Ain't gonna be nothin'
left in our graves...
except flyswatters
with red dots on 'em.
I ain't gonna be worried.