[ Thunder Rumbling ]
[ Chattering ]
[ Ship Horn Blaring ]
Be careful.
[ Speaking Greek ]
- Crete.
- [ Continues In Greek ]
Uh, excuse me--
[ Continues In Greek ]
He says, big storm.
Ship must wait.
- How long?
- I don't know.
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
[ Rain Pattering ]
[ Man Coughs ]
- [ Gurgles ]
- [ Man Coughs ]
You are traveling.
- Where to, with your permission?
- Crete.
And you stay there long, no?
How do you know?
I watch you
with all the boxes in the rain.
Very funny.
[ Laughs ]
I like you.
Take me with you,
will you?
Take?
- Why?
[ Tsks ] Will no man ever do something
without a why...
just like that,
for the hell of it?
- Well--
- All right. Take me as a cook.
I make soups like--
You like soups, no?
- Well--
- Of course you do. You're English, no?
- Half.
- Half?
My father was Greek,
but I was born in England.
Ah, same thing.
With your permission.
Hey.
''Virginia.''
- Oh, no, thank you.
- Please.
All right.
- Keep the packet.
- Only one.
- Are you a cook?
- If you need one, I am.
What I meant was,
what work do you do?
Listen to him. I got hands, feet, head--
they do the jobs.
- Who the hell am I to choose?
- [ Chuckles ]
Well, then,
what was the most recent?
Oh. In the mine.
I am a good miner.
I have a clever nose
for the metals.
But I beat up the boss, and they kicked me out.
[ Laughs ]
-[ Laughter Continues ]
-[ Baby Crying ]
I'm getting awfully nervous about the boat.
I think I'll, uh--
If you like,
I go ask.
No, thank you.
It's all right.
Maybe we could go together,
then you could ask for me.
Sure. Give me.
No, thank you.
I-I can manage.
He says 1 0:00.
Well, that's three whole hours.
Damn.
- Are you in big hurry?
- No.
Then it's all right.
Come.
&&[ Greek Folk ]
[ Greek ]
- Roumi. That's rum.
- Oh, I'll have some tea, if you don't mind.
Tea?
[ Greek ]
And you, mister,
what do you do?
Me? Well, I'm a writer.
Excuse me,
but you look it.
What do you write,
love stories?
No. Uh, poetry, essays.
What's that?
Essays.
Tsk, tsk, tsk. No, you think too much.
That is your trouble.
Clever people and grocers,
they weigh everything.
Me, if I was you, I would look at me straight
and I would say...
''Zorba, come,''
or ''Zorba, don't come.''
- Zorba?
- That's me.
Alexis Zorba.
I have other names,
if you are interested.
-Oh, I am.
- ''Spaghetti,'' because I am long...
and ''California,''
because I've been to America.
And ''Epidemic,'' because everyplace I go,
people say I louse things up.
Your health.
[ Chiming ]
[ Chattering ]
Listen to that bitch,
the sea.
That maker of widows.
What have you got
in there, clothes?
[ Laughs ]
You ask such sensible questions.
- It's my santouri.
- Your what?
My santouri.
&&[ Strums Note ]
Makes the best music.
It goes with me...
always.
And you, mister, what do you go
to do in Crete? With your permission.
I have some land there.
It belonged to my father.
And you go to write?
- Not exactly.
- What, exactly?
I haven't written anything
in months.
- On this land, there's an old mine.
- Oh?
- Lignite.
- Lignitis. I know.
- It's been idle for years.
- Why?
Because I let it.
And now...
you want to make it work.
If I can. Yes.
I must.
[ Whistling ]
- Which way is it going?
- What?
The weighing machine.
Zorba up
or Zorba down?
- Oh, well, I was thinking.
- Ah.
- That mine.
- Uh-huh?
I'm not very rich,
and I will need someone with experience.
- So I--
- And so?
Well, although I--
I-I don't really know you very well.
[ Exhales ]
[ Chuckles ]
Um, what I'm doing is probably mad.
It's yes.
Yes?
Yes.
[ Laughs ]
Shake.
Thio roumia.
Mister, you are
a lucky man.
When Zorba goes to work,
no mine stands a chance.
It'll be wonderful
to get down to some real work.
Also, it'll be very good for the village.
I understand it's rather poor.
Ah, we make everybody happy.
[ Laughs ]
- And we'll have fun, too.
- Yeah.
We'll swim,
and we'll drink wine...
and you'll play
the santouri.
What's the matter?
It's about the santouri.
We make a bargain,
or I cannot come.
In work,
I am your man...
but in things like playing
and singing...
I am my own.
How do you mean?
I mean free.
You, uh--you sign?
I sign.
Ah.
[ Greek ]
- Here.
- Oh, I don't drink rum.
This time you will.
Why start with the wrong foot?
Well, Zorba, God bless.
And... the devil, too, boss.
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
You like her, boss?
No.
[ Wind Blowing ]
[ Whistling ]
- Are you all right?
- Sure.
- [ Whistling ]
- Here.
Thanks, boss.
Your friend in there
will be looking for you.
Incidentally, you never told me--
are you married?
Am I not a man,
and is not a man stupid?
I'm a man,
so I married.
Wife, children, house, everything.
The full catastrophe.
What happened?
Be a pal, boss.
Don't make me talk.
And you?
No. I'm single.
I guess too many books.
Look. Look.! A dolphin.!
- Oh, yes.
- What kind of a man are you?
Don't you even
like dolphins?
[ Ship Horn Blows ]
[ Lamb Bleating ]
[ Greek ]
[ Continues In Greek ]
American!
[ Shouting ]
[ Woman Speaking French ]
[ Continues ]
I hope we find
somewhere to stay.
Sure. Have you never heard
of Cretan hospitality?
[ Cheering ]
Now, Mr. Epidemic,
you behave yourself.
We don't want to
start another war.
Boss, if there is a widow around,
don't worry.
[ All Greeting ]
[ Clamoring ]
- What are they all saying?
- They all want us to stay with them.
- Madame Hortense?
- Who's that?
- Who's Madame Hortense?
- A Frenchwoman.
She has hotel.
I am Mavrandoni.
So you come at last.
- I welcome you.
- I'm very glad to meet you.
- You got my letter?
- Yes.
Mr. Mavrandoni has been
looking after our land.
This, uh, madame,
she's, uh, a widow?
How many hairs
on my head?
- She's a widow of the same number of husbands.
- [ Both Laugh ]
&& [ Humming ]
[ Children Cheering ]
[ Dog Barking ]
Bonjour.!
Bonjour.
- Welcome, gentlemen.
- [ Children Laughing ]
This is a great pleasure,
madame.
- [ Giggles ]
- [ Children Whistle ]
Two beds, madame.
Without bugs.
Monsieur, Madame Hortense
has not the bugs.
You got to admit, boss, it is big,
but she shakes it well.
Plop, ploof.
This way.
- [ Needle Scratching ]
- && [ Woman And Man Singing In French ]
&& [ Singing With Record ]
[ Laughs, Clears Throat ]
They say it was
my grand succes.
You may not believe it, monsieur,
but I was a very famous artiste.
- Oh?
- I appear in all the most chic cabarets.
I slept in the silk sheets
with real lace.
- Boss, ask her to dance.
- What?
- Make a pass. Pinch her.
- No.
It's only polite.
What?
- He would like to dance with you,
but, uh, he is shy.
- [ Laughs ]
- Perhaps madame is tired.
- She is not.
Are you?
Come on.
[ Madame Hortense Giggles ]
[ Laughs ]
Whoa-ho!
[ Children Giggling ]
[ Screaming ]
These Cretans!
They are so ungrateful.
Don't cry,
my little chouchou.
They would be dead-- all dead--
if there was not me.
I know, I know.
- No hands.
- Madame.
Hey.
Boss, match?
- Madame?
- && [ Slow ]
- Merci.
- Pas de quoi.
You know how
I came to Crete?
With the British fleet.
Yes, monsieur.
I was in love
with the admiral...
and where he go, I go.
It was here that I met
the other three.
- What other three?
- Admirals, of course.
The French,
then Italian...
and the Russian.
Oh, how lovely they was,
my four admirals--
with their golden epaulet
and all those feathers...
like big, beautiful cockerels.
And what beards--
so soft and curly and perfumed.
Fortunately, each has
different parfum...
so it was no mistake, even in the dark.
[ Raucous Laughter]
- [ Coughing ]
- Oh, my little chouchou, here, here.
My darling queen,
please continue.
Yes.
Alors...
me and my admirals,
we sit on the bed...
dressed very informal.
And we discussion politics...
very serious.
All the time, they pour champagne over me
to make me fresh.
It was summer,
you know, very hot...
and in this time
in Crete...
it was big trouble--
[ Grunts ]
revolution or something.
With my binoculars...
I could see
the poor little Cretans...
running in mountains
with their flags.
My four admirals...
they want to open the fire...
but I throw myself
in the middle.
I pulled an Italian
by the beard--
You know, I was
more familiar with him--
and I cry, ''Stop it!
''You-- You can't kill them!
Please, Canavaro,
Canavaro mio, no boom-boom!''
Canavaro?
What the hell is that?
What do you
think it is?
Himself.
Canavaro.
Canavaro mio.
Go on, my chouchou.
Again and again,
I stopped the boom-boom.
And what do you think
I get in the end?
- What?
- What? Tell me.
Tell me. What?
Nothing!
- No medals. Nothing!
- Please, no more boom-boom.
-Alors--
- [ Stifled Laughter]
You are laughing.
No.
- At me.
- No, of course not.
D-Don't-Don't go!
That was a very
bad thing we did, boss.
The poor, weak creature.
Where are you?
Bouboulina?
- Where are you?
- [ Muffled Sobbing ]
My Bouboulina.
[ Sobbing ]
Bouboulina.
Ohh.
Go away.
It's me, your Canavaro.
Fine Canavaro you are--
no feathers...
- no beard.
- Oh.
Here.
Blow, my Bouboulina.
[ Sniffing ]
Who was that-- Bouboulina?
She was a big hero
in the war against the Turks.
- Huh, boss?
- Yes, madame.
She was like you...
a great sea dog.
You see?
Yes. Me, too.
I fought
breasts to breasts...
but then came
the bad times.
- They make the peace.
- Tsk. Aw.
And the ship
must go away.
''And me, what will become of me?''
I cried.
- ''Four times a widow.''
- Oh.
[ Groans ]
So they laughed, monsieur.
You men are so cruel.
And then they were sorry for me,
so they undressed me...
they filled the bath
with champagne...
and...
they dropped me.
Then they sit all around.
You understand that now
that we was all very familiar.
[ Laughing ]
And they drank all the champagne...
all, from the top
to the bottom.
Then?
And then...
they put out the light.
When I waked up...
I smelled so good--
all their perfume,
one on top of the other.
But they was gone.
Men are so cruel.
[ Parrot Chatters ]
Canavaro.
[ Mouthing Words ]
[ Whispers ]
What is it?
[ Continues Mouthing ]
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
[ Both Moan ]
[ Thunder Rumbles ]
Oh!
[ Man In Greek ]
[ Greek ]
Shh.! She's here.!
[ Whistles ]
- [ Whistles ]
- Look.
Boss, a big, beautiful,
wild widow.
- [ Goat Grunts ]
- [ Men Laughing ]
[ All Whistling ]
[ Whistling, Laughter Continue ]
[ Spits ]
[ Whistling ]
- Pavlo!
- [ Continues Whistling ]
[ Quietly ]
Look at Mavrandoni.
- He is burning.
- Why?
His son is crazy in love
with the widow...
but she spits him
in the eye.
The more she spits...
the more he wants her.
Look.
Look at the faces
of all these.
They all want her...
and they hate her because
they cannot have her.
Only one man here...
can.
Who?
You.
Really?
I saw her eyes
when she looked at you.
Zorba, don't start.
Listen.
God, who is a clever devil...
- today put in your hands a gift from paradise.
- Don't be silly.
Boss, why did God
give us hands?
To grab.
Well, grab!
[ Knocking ]
[ Greek ]
- Boss!
- Yes?
Boss. Listen, you go.
You knock.
You say, ''I have come
for my umbrella.''
- She will say, ''Please, please come in.''
- No.
Boss, boss,
don't make me mad.
I don't want
any trouble.
Boss, life is trouble,
only death is not.
To be alive is to undo your belt
and look for trouble.
Well?
No.
[ Whistling ]
&& [ Singing In Greek ]
&& [ Singing ]
&&[ Singing Continues ]
&&[ Continues, Distant ]
[ Hammering ]
[ Greek ]
[ Banging ]
[ Explosion ]
Zorba!
What?
For God's sake, boss,
will you go back to your papers?
Zorba?
[ Creaking ]
Get out!
[ Rumbling Fades ]
Zorba!
[ Coughing ]
You bastard mountain,
I'll eat your guts!
[ Continues In Greek ]
What is it, Zorba?
They left their axes inside, that's what.
They are so brave.
Every time they hear a noise,
they mess their pants.
Poo!
[ Continues In Greek ]
- Zorba, leave them alone!
- Axes cost money.
I know, and I don't care. Right now
I'm just glad that nobody's hurt. That's all.
- [ Scoffs ]
- And what's more...
I think you should
let them go for today.
Boss, you better
make up your mind.
Are you or are you not
a gosh-darn capitalist?
- [ Laughs ]
- I'm hungry.
We got to find
some strong trees...
to make beams
for the galleries!
[ Greek ]
&&[ Men Chanting In Greek ]
[ Church Bell Clanging ]
[ Screaming ]
- [ Screams ]
[ Shouting ]
[ Bell Clanging ]
[ Chattering, Laughing ]
[ Sighs ]
Damn.
[ Creaking ]
Hello.
You're late.
What is it, Zorba?
Out with it.
Boss...
do you trust me?
- Yes, I do.
- Why the hell do you?
- Because you're you.
- But you don't understand.
My brain is not
the right weight.
It-It gives me
such crazy ideas.
I might ruin you.
I'll take that chance.
Say that again, boss.
Give me courage.
I'll take that chance.
- Boss.
- Hmm?
- Boss!
- What?
- Do you dance?
- Dance?
Uh, no. No.
Oh. Then get out of the way.
I-I may knock you down.
- [ Panting ]
- Opa!
Ha!
[ Hissing ]
Opa.! Opa.!
Opa.! Opa.! Opa.!
[ Grunts ]
[ Hissing ]
&&[ Folk::Dance ]
Opa.!
Zorba!
That's enough!
Stop. Stop!
- && [ Stops ]
- Go!
Hey.
[ Panting ]
[ Breathing Heavily ]
Zorba. Zorba.!
- Are you all right?
- [ Panting ]
Now--
Now I can--
I can talk again.
What on Earth
came over you?
When a man is full,
what can he do?
Burst.
When my little boy
Dimitri died...
and everybody was crying.
Me...
I got up,
and I danced.
They said,
''Zorba is mad.''
But it was the dancing--
only the dancing that...
stopped the pain.
You see, he was my first.
He was only three.
When I'm happy,
it's the same thing.
Come inside.
You'll catch cold.
With your permission.
Now...
will you tell me what
this is all about?
- I got a plan.
- What plan?
- A great big crazy plan.
- Well, what?
- I cannot tell you.
- Why?
I got many things to be figuring:
trees, monks, machines.
Tomorrow, maybe.
Tonight, we celebrate!
Come on!
Don't be delicate!
- Boss.!
- What?
Come and see.
Remember that plan
I could not tell you about?
Here it is.
What is it?
It's a mountain.
That one.
Oh, yes.
Look.
That's the way
we'll get the trees down.
- An overhead cable? You're mad.
- Why?
Well, to begin with,
that forest doesn't belong to us.
Well... it doesn't
and it does.
What does that mean?
It belongs
to the monastery...
the monastery
belongs to God...
and God belongs
to everybody.
You agree?
- No, I certainly don't.
- All right.
- You will pay them something, but not much.
- How do you know?
They are friends of mine.
Hey, if it works...
we'll bring down
the whole forest.
First we get
the mine going...
then open a timber factory,
we get stinking rich...
then make our own ship
and sail around the world.
Aren't you going
a little too fast?
Do you know
how old I am?
Ah, never mind.
That's a secret.
But I have got
to go fast.
You know,
they say that age...
kills the fire
inside of a man...
that he hears death coming.
He opens the door and says,
''Come in. Give me rest.''
That is a pack
of old damn lies.
I've got enough fight in me
to devour the world.!
So... I fight!
Well, do we?
Or do we
let the mountain win?
Tell me what you need.
I will need some strong wire,
hooks and things.
I will have to go to town.
I still have to figure out
the angle.
If it's not perfect,
it will be catastrophe.
How long will it take you?
- Oh, uh--
- The way things are going,
it better be soon or not at all.
I'll give you until Christmas.
[ Bells Ringing ]
[ Children Shouting ]
[ Chattering ]
[ Laughing ]
&&[ Zorba Humming ]
Hey, boss.
[ Sniffs ]
Rose water.
- Boss!
- Well, what news?
I made a great discovery.
Stones... are alive.
Oh, that's fine.
I wish, instead, you'd discover
your famous... angle.
I'm trying, boss.
Look. Your umbrella.
Never mind.
Just let me remind you
that tomorrow's Christmas.
I know.
Wh-Where are you going?
I need some wire.
Where the hell
did I put it?
Won't this string do?
Tsk.
Excuse me.
Look! A melomakarouno.
- A what?
- A Christmas cookie.
Well, what's so strange
about that?
Nothing.
But many melomakarouno
inside an empty trunk is very strange.
An umbrella under a bed
is also strange.
All right, all right.
She came here!
No. She sent them.
Now you have the proof.
Now it is very simple.
Tonight,
after Bouboulina's party--
Get on with your work!
Boss! You want me
to beat you an egg?
It's good for the strength.
Boss, now I can
tell you a secret.
All these days,
I couldn't work, I couldn't sleep.
And you know why?
Because of the widow.
Don't get me wrong.
I know she's too good for these old bones.
But to think of her
without anybody.
That was too much.
All right, laugh.
But remember this:
If a woman sleeps alone,
it puts a shame on all men.
God has a very big heart...
but there is one sin
he will not forgive:
If a woman calls a man
to her bed...
and he will not go.
I know because a very wise
old Turk told me.
A Turk?
And you, a Greek, believed him?
I'm going to wash.
I thought the Greeks
and the Turks never talked.
They just fought.
Don't tell me
you never went to war.
I don't like that kind
of stupid talk.
What's so stupid
about fighting for your country?
Excuse me, boss.
You talk like a teacher.
You think like a teacher.
How can you understand?
Of course I can.
With your head, yes.
You say, ''This is right.
This is wrong.''
But when you talk...
I watch your arms,
your legs, your chest.
They are dumb.
They say nothing.
So how can you understand?
You're just making up excuses.
I don't believe you give a damn
about your country.
Don't you talk to me
like that!
Look here, here, here!
Nothing on the back.
I have done things
for my country...
that would make
your hair stand.
I have killed, burned villages,
raped women.
And why?
Because they were
Turks or Bulgarians!
That's the rotten
damn fool I was.
Now I look at a man,
any man...
and I say he is good,
he is bad.
What do I care
if he's Greek or Turk?
As I get older, I swear
by the bread I eat...
I even stop asking that.
Good or bad?
What is the difference?
We all end up the same way:
food for worms.
[ Laughs ]
And as for women...
you make fun of me
that I love them.
How can I not love them?
They are such poor,
weak creatures...
and it takes so little.
A man's hand on their breast,
and they give you all they got.
[ Zorba ]
Where are you, Bouboulina?
Canavaro is here.!
Buon giorno, buona sera,
mangaite macaroni.
Chouchou.
Look what I brought you.
- Merci.
- Happy Christmas.
I made it myself
to make her feel good.
[ Laughing ]
Oh!
- It's me?
- Yes.
Merry Christmas,
madame.
And also for you.
What is that extraordinary smell
coming from the kitchen?
It is a big,
fat Turkish.
- A Turkish?
- Oh, mon Dieu.!
I hope he's not burning.
Do not worry.
Sit down.
We will start from the center,
the belly.
Then we will take care
of the other parts later.
Yes.
[ Coughing ]
Merci.
Aren't you feeling well?
In my age, monsieur,
one is never well.
Especially on the holidays.
I drink to your health...
my beautiful
chouchou mermaid.
May you grow new teeth...
and new skin...
and throw away these stupid ribbons
you wear to hide your neck.
[ Cats Screeching ]
May the great powers
come back to Crete.
And when you rise
out of the waves to greet them...
may all their
damn ships crash...
on these round,
hard rocks!
[ Both Laughing ]
I wish it could happen, what you say,
but it is too late.
Ah, no, no.
No, it is not.
- [ Cats Screeching ]
- Oh!
- Meow!
- [ Squealing ]
[ Both Laughing ]
No! No!
[ Squealing ]
Are you all right?
You see, it is... too late.
Up, up, up.
[ Sighs ]
Oh, don't be sad,
my little Bouboulina.
I have heard
of a new doctor in Europe.
He makes... miracles.
You take what the hell ever he gives you--
drops or powders--
and you become 20 again,
maybe 25.
I will get you some.
- You will?
- Sure.
A big bottle?
A whole barrel.
[ Sighs ]
What are you thinking?
Alexandria, Beirut, Istanbul--
how they loved me.
Who?
Everybody.
Belebe, Mustafa and Aspacher...
Suleyman, Pasha.
Especially Suleyman.
[ Cats Screeching ]
Those damn cats.
- [ Banging ]
- [ Cats Continue Screeching ]
- Well, I--
- Shh.
What?
She's asleep?
Yes.
Oh, let her.
She's 20 again.
She's strolling around
Alexandria, Beirut.
Look at her--smiling.
Silly old bitch.
Come on.
We can't go and just
leave her alone like that.
She's not alone!
She's with Suleyman, Pasha--
Having hell of a time.
Dirty old cow.
[ Bell Ringing ]
[ Bell Continues Ringing ]
[ Villagers Chattering ]
She's in. Go.
And God bless you.
- Hey, where are you going?
- To church.
- What--
- I've never been to a Greek Christmas.
- Oh, boss--
- No! Don't you understand?
Understand what?
I understand you are young and full of energy...
- and I don't understand
what the hell you're doing with it!
- [ Greek ]
I've had enough of this.
Why don't you leave me alone?
- Because I love you and I want the best for you.
- Don't shout!
Who's shouting?
There she is.
She is waiting.
- Cigarette?
- This is ridiculous.
- I'm not going to stand here arguing.
- But, boss, she--
she is waiting for you!
Let's just say
that I'm different...
and I've got to go
my own way.
If God went your way,
there would be no Christmas.
He did not go to church.
He went to Mary.
And Christ was born.
He went that way.
Mary is the widow.
- [ Shouts In Greek ]
- Cigaro.
On a deaf man's door,
you can knock forever!
[ Laughs, Mutters ]
&& [ Singing ]
- Now here's the money.
- Thank you.
And remember,
it's all I can afford.
Well, boss, I know.
Just buy what we need for the cable
and come straight back.
- Of course.
- And don't get stuck anywhere on the way.
I will be quick
like the wind.
Five days.
You-You promised.
Boss, I promise.
Good-bye, boss.
Zorba! Zorba! Zorba!
What do you want?
Don't forget me.
Yes. Yes. Good-bye.
Don't be sad.
He's coming back.
They all say that.
[ Chattering ]
[ Horn Honking ]
&&[ Ragtime ]
&& [ Ragtime Continues ]
Garcon.! Champagne.!
Goochie-goochie!
Goochie-goochie-goochie!
&& [ Tango ]
[ Giggles ]
That's it.
&&[ Ragtime Resumes ]
[ Coughs ]
[ Laughing ]
''I shall not describe you...
''the continuation...
''except to say...
''that it was long...
and very wild.''
[ Laughs ]
[ Greek ]
Very, very wild.
Uh--
[ Chuckles ]
Next afternoon--
Next afternoon...
I wake up.
And... what do I see...
next to me... in bed?
The female sex...
in person.
Soft...
and warm...
and sweet-smelling.
So I say to myself...
''Zorba...
''you are in paradise.
''Enjoy it.
Don't move. ''
[ Zorba's Voice ] Imagine what luck--
There's a restaurant opposite.
And they send us food,
splendiferous food--
caviar...
steaks, baklava, everything.
We eat, and back to work,
and back to sleep...
and so on, et cetera.
Antoni!
So this is my good news,
darling boss.
And don't you worry. I think of your business
also. But I ask you, why push things?
Every day my head
becomes more clear...
and I shall be able
to make the best deals.
I kiss you friendly.
Me, Zorba.
P.S., I forgot to tell you.
Her name is Lola.
[ Greek ]
[ Panting ]
Monsieur!
Pardon.
They told me
you have a letter.
It's from him?
It's from him.
What does it say?
Read it yourself.
I cannot.
My eyes.
He says...
he's very busy.
There is
something for me?
Oh, of course.
Oh. Read it.
Please.
''Please tell Bouboulina
that I miss her.''
Go on.
''Tell her...
''that every night
I go back to my little room...
and I pray to God
to send me back to her... quickly.''
''For without my Bouboulina...
''I feel so damn miserable...
''that when I see her again, I--
I'll--''
What?
''I'll kneel before her...
and ask her
to be mine forever.''
Forever?
Yes. Forever.
That's what he says.
All right.
Tell him that I accept.
And please write
that he brings me...
five meters
of white satin...
and a voile.
You see,
I cannot find here.
I understand.
You are very kind.
Oh!
One thing more.
You know, Zorba and me,
we like you very much.
Will you be
our witness?
It will be an honor.
&& [ Singing In Greek ]
[ Dogs Barking ]
&&[ Strums Chords ]
&&[ Strums Chord ]
[ Knocking ]
- [ Greek ]
[ Greek ]
[ Whispering ]
[ Sobbing ]
[ Sobbing Continues ]
I'm sorry.
Oh! Oh.
[ Greek ]
No!
[ Woman Wails ]
[ Greek ]
- [ Men Laughing ]
- [ Screaming ]
[ Laughing Continues ]
[ Shouts In Greek ]
&&[ Zorba Singing ]
&& [ Singing Continues ]
- Mr. Zorba.
- Boss!
[ Laughs ]
Oh, boss.
- You stink of perfume, Mr. Zorba.
- Yes, I know.
I scrubbed my skin for two hours,
but it still smells.
It's funny.
Isn't it?
- [ Chuckles ]
- Yeah.
Well, what's all this?
- Presents.
- Presents? Who the hell for?
Barba Antoni,
Yianni.
This is for poor
little Bouboulina.
I hope
it's a wedding dress.
A what?
Well, you heard me.
Boss, what have you
been cooking up?
Well, she was here
when your letter came.
I couldn't very well
read to her what was in it...
could I?
That was not
a very good joke, boss.
What about the stuff
for the overhead cable?
I got everything.
Don't worry.
Oh. A gift for you.
A box of...
English chocolates.
- Thank you.
- It's all right.
Hey, no more
fooling around.
Not in this place.
Now we'll pull up our pants
and we'll make some money, a pile of money.
[ Laughing ]
You are incorrigible.
I don't know what
that means, but here...
with my compliments.
Good God! What have you
done to your hair?
- I painted it.
- Why?
For pride.
So I could go out with Lola
without making her ashamed.
[ Laughing ]
[ Laughs ]
Ah, he laughs.
But listen.
You know what?
I became young
like my hair.
[ Laughs ]
Stronger than a bull.
You ask Lola.
And you know that, uh,
pain in my kidneys?
That's gone. Hah!
Figure that out!
By the way, boss,
I come in last night and you are out.
Where the hell are you?
&&[ Playing Instrument ]
&& [ Singing In Greek ]
&& [ Singing Continues ]
&&[ Men Chanting ]
[ Whistles ]
&& [ Chanting Continues ]
[ Whistling ]
[ Men Shouting ]
[ Shouting Continues ]
[ Whistling Continues ]
[ All Shouting ]
Oh!
[ Shouting In Greek ]
[ Shouting Continues ]
Zorba! Zorba!
[ Shouts In Greek ]
[ Whistling, Shouting Continue ]
[ Shouting Stops ]
[ Grunts, Screams ]
[ Sobbing, Whimpering ]
[ Greek ]
&&[ Chanting Continues ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Shouts In Greek ]
[ Grunting Continues ]
[ Woman Screaming ]
[ Wailing ]
[ Wailing Continues ]
I... couldn't help.
[ Zorba ]
Why do the young die?
Why does anybody die?
Tell me.
I don't know.
What's the use
of all your damn books?
If they don't tell you that,
what the hell do they tell you?
They tell me...
about the agony of men...
who can't answer
questions like yours.
I spit on their agony.
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
Who's that?
It's me.
My God! Get her
inside quickly.
Hey.
Did you get drenched?
You are cruel!
Why you abandon me?
I will make some coffee.
The whole village,
they are laughing at me.
Where is my white satin?
Where is my wedding dress?
In Crete, uh, you don't find
the, uh, real good satin.
No!
So, uh, I ordered some.
From Athens.
Yes?
Also some white candles with--
with silk ribbons...
and pink bonbonnieres.
[ Laughs ]
Oh.
Our wedding, my dear Bouboulina,
will be so splendiferous...
it will blind the world
with glory.
Yes.
I can no longer
keep it a secret.
I have engaged
the best tailors in Athens...
to make for you a dress
like nobody has seen in the East.
Or the West.
Twenty meters of white satin
covered in pearls...
with the sun on one breast
and the moon on the other...
in pure gold.
Gold.
Me too.
I have a secret for you.
What's that?
Open it.
- I'll have some coffee first.
- No! Now.
[ Whispers ]
You see what you've done?
Where the hell
did you get these rings?
I had them made for us...
from two golden sovereigns
the English admiral gave me.
I was keeping them for my--
For what?
My funeral.
- Zorba.
- Hmm?
Please, we become
fiances now.
- But, uh--
- We have the witness. We have the rings.
Please.
- But we have no priest.
- I don't mind.
God is watching.
No?
All right. We'll go outside
where God can see us better.
- [ Laughs ]
- Hey, hey. You-- You get ready.
Witness, come on.
What do we do?
- Can you sing?
- Certainly not.
Never mind. I can.
Weddings, baptisms, funerals--
I know them back to front.
I was a boy chanter.
&&[ Zorba Chanting In Greek ]
&& [ Chanting Continues ]
[ Praying In Greek ]
[ Coughing ]
It's nothing.
Just a cold.
Tomorrow you'll feel better.
Next Sunday, we'll go out,
have a hell of a time.
It's Easter, you know.
- Easter?
- Yes.
You need some sun
to cheer you up.
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
Now, my beautiful,
we pull everything away.
Listen to that beautiful noise.
[ Pops ]
[ Chuckles ]
Eh?
- [ Popping Continues ]
- Like kissing.
Oh, very sexy.
I'm jealous.
&&[ Folk::Dance, Distant ]
- [ Shouting In Greek ]
- [ Hitting Door]
[ Greek ]
[ Both Shouting In Greek ]
&& [ Continues, Louder]
[ Villagers Chattering ]
[ Chattering Continues ]
[ Whimpers ]
Shh.
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
- [ Door Closes, Distant ]
- [ Footsteps Approaching ]
[ Villagers Chattering, Distant ]
[ Whispers ]
Exo.
- Exo.!
- [ Gasps ]
- Oh! I-- I don't want--
- No, no.
- [ Sobbing ] I don't want--
- No. It's okay. It's all right.
- [ Sobbing Continues ]
- [ Villagers Chattering, Approaching ]
[ Chicken Clucking ]
- [ Men Yelling ]
- [ Footsteps Running ]
[ Running Continues ]
- Exo.! Exo.!
- [ Whispering, Indistinct ]
Peace.
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
[ Greek ]
[ Gasps, Muttering ]
Mon Christ.
[ Breathing Heavily ]
Je ne veux pas.
[ Whispering In French ]
[ Whispering Continues ]
[ Squawks ]
Canavaro.
[ Women Wailing ]
Maman.! Maman.!
- [ Greek ]
- Exo.! Exo, exo.!
- Exo.!
- [ Yelps ]
[ Groans ]
It's me-- Zorba.
Don't be afraid.
[ Women Yelling In Greek ]
- [ Yelling Continues ]
- [ Villagers Chattering ]
&& [ Folk: Fast ]
[ Laughing ]
[ Greek ]
He asks us
to drink to her soul.
[ Chattering Continues, Distant ]
[ Parrot Chirps ]
[ Villagers Chattering ]
Zorba, what about
the funeral?
There will be
no funeral.
Why?
She was a Frank.
She crossed herself
with four fingers.
But I don't understand.
The priest will not bury her
like everybody else.
- But that's dreadful.
- Why?
She is dead.
It makes no difference.
[ Men Cheering ]
Hey, boss! Boss!
Come on!
We are nearly ready.
Hey, Canavaro, you want to come
and watch too, huh?
[ Yelping ]
Come on!
&&[ Chanting In Greek ]
[ Both In Greek ]
[ Gunshot ]
[ Wheels Clattering, Whirring ]
[ All Chattering ]
[ Wheels Whirring Faster, Louder]
[ Whirring Continues ]
- [ Impact ]
- [ Platform Creaking ]
[ Wood Splintering ]
- [ Crowd Chattering ]
- It's nothing. It's nothing!
The first time
it always does that.
[ Greek ]
Hey! Hey!
[ Gunshot ]
[ Wheels Whirring ]
[ Crowd Yelling ]
[ Splashing ]
[ Splashing Fades ]
[ Crowd Murmuring ]
Boss? Where are you, boss?
It's nothing!
[ Greek ]
[ Continues In Greek ]
- [ Gunshot ]
- [ Yelling ]
[ Wheels Whirring, Approaching ]
[ Creaking ]
- [ Squawks ]
- [ Clattering ]
[ Yelling ]
[ Yelling Fades ]
[ Rustling In Birdcage ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Muttering, Squawking ]
Hey.
[ Greek ]
Hey, Canavaro.
How are you, eh?
- The lamb!
- What?
It will burn!
You know, people tell the future
from this.
Can you?
- Everything's fine. We will live a thousand years.
- [ Chuckles ]
Oh, I see a journey.
A big journey to a city
with big houses.
How soon, boss?
I don't know.
A few days.
What will I do
without your company?
Cheer up.
We'll get together again.
No. You'll go away
and stay...
with your books.
To your health.
Yours, Zorba.
[ Chuckles ]
Damn it, boss,
I like you too much not to say it.
You've got everything
except one thing-- madness.
A man needs a little madness,
or else--
- Or else?
- He never dares cut the rope and be free.
Are you angry with me?
Teach me to dance,
will you?
Dance?
Did you say... ''dance''?
Come on, my boy.
[ Snapping Fingers ]
Together.
Let's go.
Up!
[ Chuckles ]
Again. Up!
Down.
Yiasou, Levendi.
Boss, I have
so much to tell you.
I never loved a man
more than you.
[ Snapping Fingers ]
Up!
[ Laughing ]
Hey, boss...
did you ever see
a more splendiferous crash?
[ Laughing ]
Hey. Hey.
You can laugh too, huh?
- Hey! You laugh!
- [ Both Laughing ]
You saw--
You saw how they all ran!
Especially the-- the--
the monks!
The third time--
The third time
was the best!
Nothing left!
Hey!
Faster!
Up! Up!