Born of cold and winter air.
And mountain rain combining.
This icy force both
foul and fair.
Has a frozen heart
worth mining.
So cut through the heart.
Cold and clear.
Strike for love and
strike for fear.
See the beauty
sharp and sheer.
Split the ice apart.
And break the frozen
heart Hup, ho.
Watch your step Let it go.
Hup, ho.
Beautiful Powerful.
Dangerous Cold.
Ice has a magic Can't
be controlled.
Stronger than one.
Stronger than ten.
Stronger than a hundred men!
Om.
Born of cold And winter air.
And mountain rain combining.
This icy force both
foul and fair.
Has a frozen heart
worth mining.
Cut through the heart.
Cold and clear.
Strike for love and
strike for fear.
There's beauty and
there's danger here.
Split the ice apart.
Beware the frozen heart.
Come on, Sven.
Elsa. Psst!
Elsa!
Wake-up. Wake-up. Wake-up!
Anna, go back to sleep.
I just can't.
The sky is awake, so I'm awake.
So, we have to play.
Go play by yourself.
Do you want to build a snowman?
Come on, come on, come on!
Do the magic!
Oh...
- Ready?
- Uh-huh.
This is amazing!
Watch this!
Hi, I'm Olaf,
and I like warm hugs.
I love you, Olaf!
Olaf...
Tickle bumps!
Oh!
Hang on!
Catch me!
Gotcha!
Again!
Wait!
- Whoo-hoo!
- Slow down!
Whoo!
Anna!
Mama! Papa!
No, no...
You're okay, Anna. I got you.
Elsa, what have you done?
This is getting out of hand.
It was an accident.
I'm sorry, Anna!
- Oh. She's ice cold.
- I know where we have to go.
Ice?
Faster, Sven.
Sven!
Please! Help! It's my daughter.
It's the King.
- Trolls?
- Shush!
I'm trying to listen.
Cuties. I'm going to keep you.
Your Majesty.
Born with the powers, or cursed?
Born. And they're
getting stronger.
Here, here.
You are lucky it
wasn't her heart.
The heart is not
so easily changed.
But the head can be persuaded.
Do what you must.
I recommend we remove all magic.
Even memories of
magic, to be safe.
But don't worry.
I'll leave the fun.
She will be okay.
But she won't remember
I have powers?
It's for the best.
Listen to me, Elsa. Your
power will only grow.
There is beauty in it...
But also great danger.
You must learn to control it.
Fear will be your enemy.
No!
We'll protect her.
She can learn to control it.
I'm sure.
Until then...
We'll lock the gates.
We'll reduce the staff.
We will limit her
contact with people,
and keep her powers
hidden from everyone.
Including Anna.
Ah.
Elsa?
Do you wanna build a snowman?
Come on, let's go and play.
I never see you anymore.
Come out the door.
It's like you've gone away.
We used to be best buddies
And now we're not.
I wish you would tell me why.
Do you wanna build a snowman?
It doesn't have
to be a snowman.
Go away, Anna.
Okay, bye.
The gloves will help.
See? Conceal it.
Don't feel it.
Don't let it show.
Do you wanna build a snowman?
Or ride our bike
around the halls?
I think some company
is overdue.
I've started talking To the
pictures on the walls.
Hang in there, Joan.
It gets a little lonely
All these empty rooms.
Just watching the
hours tick by
I'm scared.
It's getting stronger!
Getting upset only makes
it worse. Calm down.
No! Don't touch me!
Please, I don't
want to hurt you.
See you in two weeks!
Do you have to go?
You'll be fine, Elsa.
Your Highness.
Elsa?
Please I know you're in there.
People are asking
where you've been.
They say "Have courage"
And I'm trying to.
I'm right out here for you.
Just let me in.
We only have each other
It's just you and me.
What are we gonna do?
Do you wanna build a snowman?
All ashore!
Welcome to Arendelle!
Watch your step, please.
The gates will be opening soon.
Why do I have to wear this?
Because the Queen
has come of age.
It's Coronation Day!
That's not my fault.
What do you want, Sven?
"Give me a snack."
What's the magic word?
"Please."
Uh! Uh-uh-uh. Share.
I can't believe they're
finally opening up the gates!
And for a whole day!
Faster, Percy!
Arendelle, our most
mysterious trade partner.
Open those gates so I may unlock
your secrets and
exploit your riches.
Did I say that out loud?
Oh! Me sore eyes can't wait
to see the Queen
and the Princess.
I bet they are
absolutely lovely.
I bet they are beautiful.
Princess Anna?
- Princess Anna?
- Huh? Yeah?
Oh. Sorry to wake you, ma'am.
No, no, no, you didn't.
I've been up for hours.
Who is it?
Still me, ma'am.
The gates will open soon.
Time to get ready.
Of course.
Ready for what?
Your sister's coronation, ma'am.
My sister's corneration.
It's Coronation Day!
The window is open!
So's that door!
I didn't know they
did that anymore.
Who knew we owned
8,000 salad plates?
For years I've roamed
these empty halls.
Why have a ballroom
with no balls?
Finally They're
opening up the gates!
There'll be actual,
real, live people.
It'll be totally strange.
But wow! Am I so ready
for this change!
'Cause for the first
time in forever.
There'll be music.
There'll be light.
For the first time.
In forever.
I'll be dancing
through the night.
Don't know if I'm
elated or gassy.
But I'm somewhere in that zone
'Cause for the first
time in forever.
I won't be alone
I can't wait to meet everyone!
What if I meet The One?
Tonight Imagine
me gown and all.
Fetchingly draped
against the wall.
The picture of
sophisticated Grace.
I suddenly see him
standing there.
A beautiful stranger.
Tall and fair.
I wanna stuff some
chocolate in my face!
But then we laugh and
talk all evening.
Which is totally bizarre.
Nothing like the life
I've led so far.
For the first time in forever.
There'll be magic
There'll be fun.
For the first time in forever.
I could be noticed by someone.
And I know it is
totally crazy.
To dream I'd find romance.
But for the first
time in forever.
At least I've got a chance!
Don't let them in.
Don't let them see.
Be the good girl.
You always have to be.
Conceal.
Don't feel.
Put on a show.
Make one wrong move.
And everyone will know.
But it's only for today.
It's only for today.
It's agony to wait.
Tell the guards to open up.
The gate.
For the first time in forever.
Don't let them in
Don't let them see.
I'm getting what
I'm dreaming of.
Be the good girl.
You always have to be.
A chance to change.
My lonely world.
Conceal.
A chance to find true love.
Conceal, don't feel
Don't let them know.
I know it all ends tomorrow.
So it has to be today!
'Cause for the first
time in forever.
For the first time.
In forever.
Nothing's in my way!
Hey!
I'm so sorry. Are you hurt?
Hey.
Uh... No, no, I'm okay.
Are you sure?
Yeah. I just wasn't looking
where I was going.
But I'm great, actually.
Oh... Thank goodness.
Oh! Uh...
Prince Hans of the
Southern Isles.
Princess Anna of Arendelle.
"Princess"? My Lady.
"UN."
- Whoa.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa...
- Um...
- Whew.
Hi. Again.
Oh, boy!
This is awkward.
Not "You're awkward," but
just because we're...
I'm awkward, you're gorgeous.
Wait, what?
I'd like to formally apologize
for hitting the Princess of
Arendelle with my horse.
And for every moment after.
No! No, no. It's fine.
I'm not that Princess.
I mean, if you had
hit my sister Elsa,
it would be... Yeesh!
Because, you know...
Hello.
But, lucky you,
it's just me.
"Jus" you?
The bells. The coronation.
I better go.
I have to go. I better go. Uh...
Bye!
Oh, no. Oh!
Your Majesty, the gloves.
Queen Elsa of Arendelle.
Queen Elsa of Arendelle!
Princess Anna of Arendelle.
Oh. Here? Are you sure?
Because I don't think
I'm supposed to...
Oh. Okay.
Hi.
"Hi" me? Oh...
Um... Hi.
You look beautiful.
Thank you. You look
beautiful-ler.
I mean, not "Fuller."
You don't look Fuller.
But more beautiful.
Thank you.
So...
This is what a party looks like.
It's warmer than I thought.
What is that amazing smell?
Chocolate.
Your Majesty.
- The Duke of Weaseltown.
- "Weselton"!
Duke of Weselton, Your Majesty.
As your closest partner in
trade it seems only fitting
that I offer you
your first dance as Queen.
One-two, and jump.
Uh...
Thank you. Only, I don't dance.
Oh...
But my sister does.
- What?
- Oh! Lucky you.
Oh, I don't think...
If you swoon, let me know.
I'll catch you.
Sorry.
Like an agile peacock.
Ow! Ow.
Speaking of, so great
to have the gates open.
Why did they shut them
in the first place?
Do you know the reason? Hmm?
- No.
All right. Hang on!
They don't call me the
"Little Dipper" for nothing!
Oh-ho!
Like a chicken with the
face of a monkey, I fly.
Let me know when you're ready
for another round, Milady.
Well, he was sprightly.
Especially for a man in heels.
Are you okay?
I've never been better.
This is so nice.
I wish it could be like
this all the time.
Me, too.
But it can't.
- Why not?
- It just can't.
Excuse me for a minute.
I'd be honored.
Glad I caught you.
Hans.
Oop.
I often had a whole parlor
to myself to slide!
- Oh!
- Oops.
Sorry.
Your physique helps,
I'm sure, too.
Ah.
What's this?
Uh, I was born with it.
Although, I dreamed I
was kissed by a troll.
I like it.
Yeah, the whole thing.
You got it.
Okay, wait, wait. So, you
have how many brothers?
Twelve older brothers.
Three of them pretended
I was invisible,
literally, for two years.
That's horrible.
It's what brothers do.
And sisters.
Elsa and I were really
close when we were little.
But then, one day, she
just shut me out,
and I never knew why.
I would never shut you out.
Okay, can I just say
something crazy?
I love crazy.
All my life has been A
series of doors in my face.
And then suddenly
I bump into you
I was thinking the same
thing, because, like...
I've been searching
my whole life.
To find my own place.
And maybe it's the
party talking.
Or the chocolate fondue.
But with you.
But with you I found my place.
I see your face.
And it's nothing like
I've ever known before.
Love is an open.
Door!
- Door.
"BOTH". Love is an open door.
- With you.
- I mean, it's crazy.
- What?
- We finish each
other's Sandwiches.
That's what I was gonna say!
I've never met someone.
"BOTH". Who thinks
so much like me.
Jinx! Jinx again!
Our mental synchronization Can
have but one explanation.
- You.
- And I.
- Were.
- Just.
"BOTH". Meant to be.
- Say goodbye.
"BOTH". To the
pain of the past.
We don't have to
feel it anymore.
Love is an open door.
Love is an open.
- Door.
"BOTH". Life can
be so much more.
- With you.
"BOTH". Love is an open.
- Door.
Can I say something crazy?
Will you marry me?
Can I say something
even crazier?
Yes!
Coming through. Excuse me.
Oh...
Pardon. Sorry. Oh!
Can we just get
around you there?
Thank you. Oh! There she is.
Elsa!
I mean, Queen. Me again. Um...
May I present Prince Hans
of the Southern Isles.
Your Majesty.
We would like...
Uh, your blessing...
Of our marriage.
- Marriage?
- Yes!
I'm sorry, I'm confused.
Well, we haven't worked out
all the details ourselves.
We'll need a few days
to plan the ceremony.
Of course, we'll have soup, roast
and ice cream. And then...
Wait. Would we live here?
- Here?
- Absolutely!
- Anna!
- Oh!
We can invite all 12 of your
brothers to stay with us.
What? No, no, no.
- Of course we have the room.
- Wait, slow down.
No one's brothers
are staying here.
No one is getting married.
Wait, what?
May I talk to you, please?
Alone.
No. Whatever you have to say,
you can say to both of us.
Fine. You can't marry
a man you just met.
You can if it's true love.
Anna, what do you
know about true love?
More than you.
All you know is how
to shut people out.
You asked for my blessing,
but my answer is no.
Now, excuse me.
Your Majesty, if I
may ease your...
No, you may not. And I
think you should go.
The party is over.
Close the gates.
- Yes, Your Majesty.
- What?
Elsa, no, no! Wait.
Give me my glove!
Elsa, please, please.
I can't live like this anymore!
Then leave.
What did I ever do to you?
Enough, Anna.
No, why? Why do you shut me out?
Why do you shut the world out?
What are you so afraid of?
I said, enough!
Sorcery.
I knew there was something
dubious going on here.
Elsa.
There she is!
Yes! It is her!
Queen Elsa.
Our beautiful Queen!
Your Majesty? Are you all right?
No.
There she is! Stop her!
Please, just stay away from me.
Stay away.
Monster. Monster!
{SHUDDERS)
Elsa!
Wait, please!
Elsa, stop!
Anna!
No.
The fjord.
- Snow!
- Snow?
Yes, snow.
- Are you all right?
- No.
Did you know?
No.
Look, it's snowing.
It's snowing!
The Queen has cursed this land!
She must be stopped! You
have to go after her.
Wait, no!
You! Is there sorcery
in you, too?
Are you a monster, too?
No, no. I'm completely ordinary.
That's right, she is.
In the best way.
And my sister is not a monster.
She nearly killed me!
- You slipped on ice.
- Her ice.
It was an accident.
She was scared.
She didn't mean it. She
didn't mean any of this.
Tonight was my fault.
I pushed her.
So, I'm the one
- that needs to go after her.
- What?
- Bring me my horse, please.
- Anna, no.
It's too dangerous.
Elsa is not dangerous.
I'll bring her back, and
I'll make this right.
I'm coming with you.
No, I need you here to
take care of Arendelle.
On my honor.
I leave Prince Hans in charge.
Are you sure you can trust her?
I don't want you getting hurt.
She's my sister.
She would never hurt me.
The snow glows white On
the mountain tonight.
Not a footprint to be seen.
A kingdom of isolation.
And it looks like
I'm the Queen.
The wind is howling.
Like this swirling
storm inside.
Couldn't keep it in
Heaven knows I tried.
Don't let them in
Don't let them see.
Be the good girl You
always have to be.
Conceal, don't feel
Don't let them know.
Well, now they know.
Let it go! Let it go!
Can't hold me back anymore.
Turn away and slam the door.
I don't care.
What they're going to say.
Let the storm rage on.
The cold never
bothered me anyway.
It's funny how some distance
Makes everything seem small.
And the fears that
once controlled me.
Can't get to me at all.
It's time to see
what I can do.
To test the limits
and break through.
No right, no wrong.
No rules for me.
I'm free!
Let it go!
I am one with the
wind and sky.
Let it go! Let it go!
You'll never see me cry.
Here I stand.
And here I'll stay.
Let the storm rage on.
My power flurries
through the air.
Into the ground.
My soul is spiraling
in frozen fractals.
All around.
And one thought crystallizes
Like an icy blast.
I'm never going back.
The past is in the past.
Let it go! Let it go!
And I'll rise like
the break of Dawn.
Let it go! Let it go!
That perfect girl is gone.
Here I stand.
In the light of day.
Let the storm rage on!
The cold never
bothered me anyway
Elsa!
Elsa, it's me, Anna,
your sister who didn't mean to
make you freeze the summer.
I'm sorry. It's all my fault.
Of course, none of it
would have happened
if she had just
told me her secret.
She's a stinker.
Whoa!
Oh, no. No, no, no! Come back!
No, no, no!
Okay.
Snow. It had to be snow.
She couldn't have
had tropical magic
that covered the fjords
in white sand and warm...
Fire!
Cold, cold, cold, cold, cold.
Ooh. "And sauna"!
- Yoo-hoo.
- Hmm?
Big summer blowout.
Half off swimming suits, clogs,
and a sun balm of my
own invention, yah?
Oh. Great. For now,
um, how about boots?
Winter boots and dresses?
That would be in our
winter department.
Oh. Um...
I was just wondering.
Has another young woman...
The Queen perhaps, I don't know,
passed through here?
The only one crazy enough
to be out in this storm
is you, dear.
You and this fellow.
You-hoe.
Big summer blowout.
Carrots.
Huh?
Behind you.
Oh! Right. Excuse me.
Oh. A real howler in July, yes?
Wherever could it
be coming from?
The North Mountain.
North Mountain.
That Will be 40.
Forty? No, 10.
Oh, dear, that's no good.
See, this is from
our winter stock,
where supply and demand
have a big problem.
You want to talk about a
supply and demand problem?
I sell ice for a living.
Ooh. That's a rough business
to be in right now.
I mean, that is really...
That's unfortunate.
Still 40.
But I will throw in a
visit to Oaken's sauna.
Yoo-hoo. Hi, family.
Yoo-hoo!
Ten is all I got. Help me out.
Okay. Ten will get you
this and no more.
Okay, just tell me one thing.
What was happening on
the North Mountain?
Did it seem magical?
Yes!
Now, back up while I deal
with this crook, here.
What did you call me?
Okay, okay. I'm out.
Whoa!
Bye-bye.
No, Sven, I didn't
get your carrots.
But I did find us
a place to sleep.
And it's free.
I'm sorry about this violence.
I will add a quart of lutefisk,
so we have good feelings.
Just the outfit and
the boots, yah?
Uh...
Reindeers are
better than people.
Sven, don't you
think that's true?
"Yeah, people will beat you
And curse you and cheat you.
"Every one of them's
bad, except you".
Aw. Thanks, buddy.
But people smell
better than reindeers.
Sven, don't you
think I'm right?
"That's once again true
For all, except you".
You got me Let's
call it a night.
"Good night".
Don't let the frostbite.
Bite.
Nice duet.
It's just you.
What do you want?
I want you to take me
up the North Mountain.
I don't take people places.
Let me rephrase that.
Hey.
Take me up the North Mountain.
Please.
Look, I know how to
stop this winter.
We leave at Dawn.
And you forgot the
carrots for Sven.
Oops, sorry.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I didn't...
We leave now. Right now.
WheW!
Hang on! We like to go fast.
- I like fast.
- Whoa! Whoa, whoa, whoa...
Get your feet down.
This is fresh lacquer.
Seriously, were you
raised in a barn?
Ugh!
- No, I was raised in a castle.
- Hmm.
So, uh, tell me,
what made the Queen
go all ice-crazy?
Oh. Well...
It was all my fault.
I got engaged, but
then she freaked out,
because I'd only just met
him, you know, that day.
And she said she wouldn't
bless the marriage, and...
Wait. You got engaged to
someone you just met that day?
Yeah. Anyway, I got mad,
and so she got mad,
and then she tried to walk away,
and I grabbed her glove...
Hang on!
You mean to tell
me you got engaged
to someone you
just met that day?
Yes. Pay attention.
But the thing is, she wore
the gloves all the time,
so I just thought, maybe she
has a thing about dirt.
Didn't your parents ever
warn you about strangers?
Yes, they did.
But Hans is not a stranger.
Oh, yeah? What's his last name?
"Of the Southern Isles."
- What's his favorite food?
- Sandwiches.
- Best friend's name?
- Probably John.
- Eye color?
- Dreamy.
- Foot size?
- Foot size doesn't matter.
Have you had a
meal with him yet?
What if you hate
the way he eats?
What if you hate the
way he picks his nose?
Picks his nose?
And eats it.
Excuse me, Sir. He is a Prince.
- All men do it.
- Ew.
Look, it doesn't matter.
It's true love.
It doesn't sound like true love.
Are you some sort
of love expert?
No. But, uh, I have
friends who are.
You have friends
who are love experts?
I'm not buying it.
- Stop talking.
- No, no, no. No, no.
- I'd like to meet these...
- No, I mean it.
Sven, go.
Go!
- What are they?
- Wolves.
Wolves?
- What do we do?
- I got this.
You just... Don't fall
off, and don't get eaten.
But I want to help!
- No.
- Why not?
Because I don't trust
your judgment.
Excuse me?
Who marries a man she just met?
It's true love!
Whoa!
VVhoa. VVhoa!
Christopher!
It's "Kristoff"!
Ow!
Duck!
You almost set me on fire!
But I didn't.
Get ready to jump, Sven!
You don't tell him what to do.
- Hey!
- I do!
Jump, Sven!
Phew!
But I just paid it Off.
Uh-oh. No. No.
No!
Ah! No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
Grab on!
Pull, Sven. Pull!
Whoa.
I'll replace your sled,
and everything in it.
And I understand if you don't
want to help me anymore.
Of course I don't want to
help her anymore. In fact,
this whole thing has ruined me
for helping anyone ever again.
AN NAl It's this way?
"She'll die on her own."
- I can live with that.
- Here we go.
"But you won't get your
new sled if she's dead."
I think, actually, it's up.
Sometimes, I really
don't like you.
Hold up! We're coming.
You are?
I mean, sure. I'll
let you tag along.
Arendelle.
It's completely frozen.
But it will be fine.
Elsa will thaw it.
Will she?
Yeah. Now, come on.
This way to the North Mountain?
More like this way.
I never knew winter
could be so beautiful.
Yeah.
It really is
beautiful, isn't it?
But it's so white.
You know, how about
a little color?
I'm thinking maybe some
crimson, chartreuse.
How about yellow?
No, not yellow. Yellow and snow?
No go.
Am I right?
- Hi.
- You're creepy.
- Whoa!
- I don't want it.
- Back at you.
- Please don't drop me.
- No.
- Come on, it's just a head.
All right. We got
off to a bad start.
Ew, ew, ew, the body!
Wait, what am I
looking at right now?
Why are you hanging off
the earth like a bat?
All right, wait one second.
Oh. Uh...
Oh!
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Now, I'm perfect.
Well, almost.
It was like my whole life
got turned upside down.
Oh! Too hard. I'm sorry!
- Head rush!
- I was just... Are you okay?
Are you kidding me?
I am wonderful!
I've always wanted a nose.
So cute.
It's like a little baby unicorn.
But... Hey! Whoa!
Oh.
I love it even more.
All right, let's start
this thing over.
Hi, everyone.
I'm Olaf.
And I like warm hugs.
Olaf?
That's right. Olaf.
And you are?
Oh. Um...
I'm Anna.
And who's the funky-looking
donkey over there?
- That's Sven.
- Uh-huh.
And who's the reindeer?
Sven.
Oh, the... Oh. Okay. That
makes things easier for me.
Aw, look at him trying
to kiss my nose.
- I like you, too.
- Olaf.
- Did Elsa build you?
- Yeah. Why?
Do you know where she is?
- Fascinating.
- Yeah. Why?
Do you think you could
show us the way?
Yeah. Why?
How does this work? Ow!
Stop it, Sven. I'm
trying to focus, here.
- Yeah. Why?
- I'll tell you why.
We need Elsa to
bring back summer.
- Summer?
- Mmm-hmm.
Oh. I don't know why,
but I've always loved
the idea of summer.
And sun, and all things hot.
Really?
I'm guessing you don't have
much experience with heat.
Nope.
But sometimes I like
to close my eyes,
and imagine what it would be
like when summer does come.
Bees will buzz Kids will
blow dandelion fuzz.
And I'll be doing Whatever
snow does in summer.
A drink in my hand.
My snow up against
the burning sand.
Probably getting
gorgeously tanned.
In summer.
I'll finally see
a summer breeze.
Blow away a winter storm.
And find out what
happens to solid water.
When it gets warm.
And I can't wait to see.
What my buddies
all think of me.
Just imagine how
much cooler I'll be.
In summer!
The hot and the cold
are both so intense.
Put them together It
just makes sense.
Winter's a good time
To stay in and cuddle.
But put me in summer
and I'll be a...
Happy snowman!
When life gets rough.
I like to hold on to my dream.
Relaxing in the summer sun
Just letting off steam.
Oh, the sky.
Will be blue.
And you guys will
be there, too.
When I finally do.
What frozen things
do In summer!
- I'm gonna tell him.
- Don't you dare.
In summer!
So, come on! Elsa's this way.
Let's go bring back summer!
I'm coming!
Somebody's gotta tell him.
No, no. You've got the
bark facing down.
The bark needs to be face-up.
- Bark down is drier.
- Bark up!
Bark down! Papa!
Cloak? Does anyone need a cloak?
Arendelle is indebted
to you, Your Highness.
The castle is open.
There is soup and hot
glogg in the great hall.
Here, pass these out.
Prince Hans!
Are we expected to just
sit here and freeze
while you give away all of
Arendelle's tradable goods?
Princess Anna has
given her orders.
And that's another thing!
Has it dawned on you that your
Princess may be conspiring
with a wicked sorceress
to destroy us all?
Do not question the Princess.
She left me in charge
and I will not hesitate
to protect Arendelle
from treason.
Treason?
VVhoa! VVhoa!
Whoa, boy. Easy.
Easy.
It's Princess Anna's horse.
So, where is the Princess?
Where could she be?
Where is she?
Princess Anna is in trouble.
I need volunteers to go
with me to find her.
- I'll go.
- I volunteer.
I volunteer two men, My Lord.
Be prepared for anything.
And should you
encounter the Queen,
you are to put an
end to this winter.
- Do you understand?
- Hmm.
So, how exactly are you
planning to stop this weather?
Oh. I am gonna
talk to my sister.
That's your plan?
My ice business is riding on
you talking to your sister?
Yep.
So, you're not at
all afraid of her?
- Why would I be?
- Yeah.
I bet she's the nicest,
gentlest, warmest person ever.
Oh. Look at that.
I've been impaled.
What now?
Mmm...
It's too steep.
I've only got one rope and you
don't know how to climb mountains.
Says who'?
Hmm?
What are you doing?
I'm going to see my sister.
You're gonna kill yourself.
I wouldn't put my foot there.
- You're distracting me.
- Or there.
How do you know Elsa
even wants to see you?
All right. I'm just
blocking you out
because I gotta
concentrate, here.
You know, most
people who disappear
into the mountains
want to be alone.
Nobody wants to be alone.
Except maybe you.
I'm not alone. I have
friends, remember?
You mean, the love experts?
Yes, the love experts.
Ah...
Please tell me I'm almost there.
Does the air seem a bit
thin to you up here?
Hang on.
Hey, Sven?
Not sure if this is gonna
solve the problem,
but I found a staircase
that leads exactly
where you wanted to go.
Ha-ha! Thank goodness. Catch!
Thanks. That was like a
crazy trust exercise.
Whoa.
Now, that's ice.
I might cry.
Go ahead. I won't judge.
All right, take it easy, boy.
Come here.
I got you.
Okay. You stay
right here, buddy.
Flawless.
Knock.
Just knock.
Why isn't she knocking?
Do you think she
knows how to knock?
Huh. It opened.
That's a first.
Oh. You should probably
wait out here.
- What?
- The last time I introduced her to a guy,
she froze everything.
But, but... Oh, come on!
It's a palace made of ice.
Ice is my life!
Bye, Sven.
You, too, Olaf.
- Me?
- Just give us a minute.
Okay.
One, two,
- three...
- Four...
Whoa.
Elsa?
It's me, Anna.
Anna.
Whoa. Elsa, you look different.
It's a good different.
And this place...
It's amazing.
Thank you.
I never knew what
I was capable of.
I'm so sorry about what
happened. If I'd have known...
No, no, no. It's okay.
You don't have to apologize,
but you should probably go.
Please.
But I just got here.
You belong down in Arendelle.
So do you.
No, Anna, I belong here.
Alone.
Where I can be who I am
without hurting anybody.
Actually, about that...
- Sixty!
- Wait. What is that?
Hi! I'm Olaf and I
like warm hugs!
Olaf?
Yeah. You built me.
Remember that?
And you're alive?
Um... I think so.
He's just like the one
we built as kids.
Yeah.
Elsa, we were so close.
We can be like that again.
Catch me! Slow down!
Anna!
No.
We can't. Goodbye, Anna.
Elsa, wait.
No, I'm just trying
to protect you.
You don't have to protect me.
I'm not afraid.
Please don't shut me out again.
Please don't slam the door.
You don't have to keep
Your distance anymore
'Cause for the first
time in forever.
I finally understand.
For the first time in forever.
We can fix this hand in hand.
We can head down this
mountain together.
You don't have to live in fear
'Cause for the first
time in forever.
I Will be right here
Anna.
Please go back home.
Your life awaits.
Go enjoy the sun And
open up the gates.
- Yeah, but...
- I know.
You mean well But leave me be.
Yes, I'm alone.
But I'm alone and free.
Just stay away And
you'll be safe from me.
Actually, we're not.
What do you mean, you're not?
I get the feeling
you don't know.
What do I not know?
Arendelle's in
deep, deep, deep.
Deep snow.
What?
You kind of set off an
eternal winter everywhere.
Everywhere?
Well, it's okay, you
can just unfreeze it.
No, I can't. I don't know how.
Sure you can. I know you can.
'Cause for the first
time in forever.
Oh, I'm such a fool!
I can't be free!
You don't have to be afraid.
No escape from the
storm inside of me.
We can work this out together.
I can't control the curse!
We'll reverse the
storm you've made.
Anna, please you'll
only make it worse!
Don't panic There's
so much fear!
We'll make the sun
shine bright.
You're not safe here!
We can face this
thing together.
No!
We can change this
winter weather.
And everything
will be all right.
I can't!
Anna!
Are you okay?
I'm okay.
I'm fine.
Who's this?
Wait, it doesn't matter. Just...
You have to go.
No, I know we can figure
this out together.
How?
What power do you have
to stop this winter?
To stop me?
Anna, I think we should go.
No, I'm not leaving
without you, Elsa.
Yes, you are.
Stop! Put us down!
Go away.
Heads up!
Watch out for my butt!
It is not nice to throw people!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, feisty-pants.
Okay, relax.
- Just calm down! Calm down!
- Okay! All right!
- I'm okay.
- Just let the snowman be.
- I'm calm.
- Great.
Oh! Come on!
Oh. Look, see? Now,
you made him mad.
I'll distract him. You guys go.
No, no! Not you guys!
This just got a
whole lot harder.
Look out!
Run! Run!
What are you doing?
I got him!
Whoa! Stop!
It's a 100-foot drop.
It's 200.
OW!
- What's that for?
- I'm digging a snow anchor.
Okay. What if We fall?
There's 20 feet of fresh
powder down there.
It'll be like landing
on a pillow.
Hopefully.
Okay, Anna. On three.
Okay. One...
You tell me when.
I'm ready to go.
- Two...
- I was born ready! Yes!
Calm down.
Tree!
What the... Whoa!
That happened.
Man, am I out of shape.
There we go. Hey, Anna!
Sven! Where did you guys go?
We totally lost
Marshmallow back there.
Hey! We were just
talking about you.
All good things,
all good things.
No!
This is not making much
of a difference, is it?
Olaf!
Hang in there, guys!
Go. Go faster!
- Wait, what?
- Hey!
Ow!
Kristoff!
Don't come back!
We won't.
Hey, you were right.
Just like a pillow.
Olaf!
I can't feel my legs!
- Those are my legs.
- Ooh!
Hey, do me a favor,
grab my butt.
Oh. That feels better.
Hey, Sven! He found us.
Who's my cute little reindeer?
Don't talk to him like that.
You're tickling me.
Here.
Whoa!
Are you okay?
Thank you.
- How's your head?
- Ah! Ooh!
It's fine. Uh...
Uh, I'm good. I've
got a thick skull.
I don't have a skull.
Or bones.
So, uh... So, now what?
NOW What?
Now what?
Oh...
What am I gonna do?
She threw me out.
I can't go back to Arendelle
with the weather like this.
And then there's
your ice business.
Hey, hey. Don't worry
about my ice business.
- Worry about your hair!
- What?
I just fell off a Cliff.
You should see your hair.
No, yours is turning white.
White? It's... What?
It's because she
struck you, isn't it?
Does it look bad?
- No.
- You hesitated.
No, I didn't.
Anna, you need help, okay?
Come on.
Okay! Where are we going?
To see my friends.
The love experts?
- Love experts?
- Uh-huh.
And don't worry, they'll
be able to fix this.
How do you know?
Because I've seen
them do it before.
I like to consider
myself a love expert.
Get it together.
Control it.
Don't feel. Don't feel.
Don't feel.
Don't feel!
Look, Sven, the sky is awake.
- Are you cold?
- A little.
Uh... Wait. Come here.
Huh?
Ooh.
So, uh, about my friends.
Well...
I say "friends"...
They're more like family.
Anyway, when I was a kid,
it was just me and Sven.
Until they, you know,
kinda took us in.
- They did?
- Yeah.
I don't want to scare you.
They can be a little
inappropriate and loud.
Very loud.
They are also stubborn at times,
and a little overbearing.
And heavy. Really,
really, heavy.
But you'll get it.
They mean well.
Kristoff, they sound wonderful.
Okay, then.
Meet my family.
Hey, guys.
They're rocks.
You are a sight for sore eyes.
He's crazy.
Rocko's looking sharp, as usual.
Clay, whoa... I don't
even recognize you.
You lost so much weight.
I'll distract him
while you run.
Hi, Sven's family!
It's nice to meet you.
Because I love you,
Anna, I insist you run.
I understand you're
love experts. Ooh!
Why aren't you running?
Uh...
Okay. Well, I'm gonna go.
- Go.
- No, no, no. Anna, wait.
Kristoff!
Whoa!
Hey!
Kristoff's home!
- Kristoff's here!
- Kristoff's home!
- Wait, "Kristoff"?
- Uh-huh.
Ah, let me look at you.
Take off your
clothes, I wash them.
No! No, I'm going to
keep my clothes on.
Look, it's great to see you all,
but where's Granpabbie?
He's napping.
But look, I grew a mushroom.
- L...
- I earned my fire Crystal.
I passed a kidney Stone.
Kristoff, pick me up.
You're getting big.
Good for you.
Trolls. They're trolls!
He's brought a girl!
A girl!
- Whoa!
- Is that a real girl?
She's like a little cupcake.
What's going on?
I've learned to
just roll with it.
Let me see. Bright
eyes, working nose,
strong teeth!
Yes, yes. She'll do
nicely for our Kristoff.
Wait, wait, wait. Oh, um, no.
- No.
- You've got the wrong idea.
No. That's not why I
brought her here.
Right. We're not... I'm not...
What's the issue, dear?
Why are you holding
back from such a man?
Is it the clumpy way he walks?
- What?
- Or the grumpy way he talks?
- Oh, no.
- Or the pear-shaped, square-shaped.
Weirdness of his feet?
Hey!
And though we know
he washes well.
He always ends up
sort of smelly.
But you'll never meet a fella.
"BOTH". Who's as
sensitive and sweet.
That's nice, but...
So, he's a bit of
a fixer-upper.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa...
- So, he's got a few flaws.
"TROLL 1". Like his
peculiar brain, dear.
TROLL '2'. His thing
with the reindeer.
That's a little outside
of nature's laws.
This is not about me!
So, he's a bit of
a fixer-upper.
But this we're certain of.
You can fix this
fixer-upper up.
- With a little bit of love.
- Um...
Can we please just stop
talking about this?
We've got a real,
actual problem, here.
I'll say. So, tell me, dear...
Is it the way that
he runs scared?
Or that he's
socially impaired?
Or that he only likes
To tinkle in the woods?
I did not need to know that.
Are you holding
back your fondness.
Due to his unmanly blondness?
Or the way he covers up
That he's the honest goods?
He's just a bit
of a fixer-upper.
He's got a couple of bugs.
- No, I don't!
- His isolation is confirmation.
- Of his desperation for healing hugs.
- Aw.
So, he's a bit of
a fixer-upper.
But we know what to do.
The way to fix up
this fixer-upper.
Is to fix him up with you.
Whoa!
Stop it, stop it, stop it!
Enough!
She is engaged to
someone else, okay?
So, she's a bit
of a fixer-upper.
That's a minor thing.
Her quote "engagement"
Is a flex arrangement.
And by the way, I
don't see no ring.
So, she's a bit
of a fixer-upper.
- Hey! Whoa, watch it!
- Her brain's a bit betwixt.
Get the fiance out of the way.
And the whole thing
will be fixed.
We're not saying
you can change him
'Cause people don't
really change.
We're only saying
that love's a force.
That's powerful and strange.
People make bad choices.
If they're mad or
scared or stressed.
But throw a little
love their way.
Throw a little love their way.
And you'll bring
out their best.
True love brings out the best.
Everyone's a bit
of a fixer-upper.
That's what it's all about.
- Father!
- Sister!
- Brother!
- We need each other to raise us up.
And round us out.
Everyone's a bit
of a fixer-upper.
But when push comes to shove.
The only fixer-upper fixer.
That can fix a
fixer-upper is...
True, true.
True.
Love!
Love, love, love.
Love True love.
True.
Do you, Anna, take Kristoff to
be your trollfully wedded...
- Wait, what?
- You're getting married.
Love!
Anna?
She's as cold as ice.
There is strange magic here.
- Granpabbie.
- Come, come. Bring her here to me.
Anna, your life is in danger.
There is ice in your heart
put there by your sister.
If not removed, to solid ice
will you freeze, forever.
What? No.
But you can remove it, right?
I cannot.
I'm sorry, Kristoff.
If it was her head,
that would be easy.
But only an act of true love
can thaw a frozen heart.
An act of true love?
A true love's kiss, perhaps?
Something's wrong.
Are you all right?
Anna, we've got to get
you back to Hans.
Hans.
Pull us out, Sven.
Olaf, come on!
I'm coming!
Let's go kiss Hans!
Who is this Hans?
We are here to find
Princess Anna.
Be on guard, but no harm
is to come to the Queen.
Do you understand?
Yes, Your Grace.
The Queen.
Go, go! Come on!
Duke'S THUG 22 There!
Duke'S THUG 12 Up there!
Come on!
We got her.
No. Please.
Go around. Toss it.
Stay away!
LOOK out!
Duke'S THUG 21 Fire! Fire!
Get her!
Ah!
Come on!
Grab his arm.
Duke'S THUG 22 Aim...
SOLDIER 11 This way, this way!
SOLDIER 23 Whoa!
Queen Elsa!
Don't be the monster
they fear you are.
Oh, no. What have...
What have I done?
Why did you bring me here?
I couldn't just let
them kill you.
But I'm a danger to Arendelle.
Get Anna.
Anna has not returned.
If you would just
stop the winter.
Bring back summer, please.
Don't you see?
I can't.
You have to tell
them to let me go.
I will do what I can.
Just hang in there.
Come on, buddy, faster!
Oh, boy!
Whoa! I'll meet you
guys at the castle!
Stay out of sight, Olaf.
I will!
- Hello!
- It's alive!
It's Princess Anna!
Are you gonna be okay?
Don't worry about me.
Anna!
- You had us worried sick.
- My Lady.
Get her warm. And find
Prince Hans, immediately.
We will. Thank you.
Make sure she's safe.
Oh, you poor girl,
you're freezing.
Oh, let's get you inside
now and get you warm.
I'm going back out to
look for Princess Anna.
You cannot risk going
out there again.
If anything happens to her...
If anything happens
to the Princess,
you are all Arendelle has left.
He's in here.
Prince Hans.
Anna.
You're so cold.
- Hans, you have to kiss me.
- What?
- Now! Now!
- Slow down.
We'll give you two some privacy.
What happened out there?
Elsa struck me with her powers.
You said she would
never hurt you.
I was wrong.
Anna.
She froze my heart,
and only an act of
true love can save me.
A true love's kiss.
Oh, Anna.
If only there was someone
out there who loved you.
What?
You said you did.
As thirteenth in line
in my own kingdom,
I didn't stand a chance.
I knew I would have to marry
into the throne somewhere.
What... What are
you talking about?
As heir, Elsa was
preferable, of course.
But no one was getting
anywhere with her.
- But you...
- Hans!
You were so desperate for love,
you were willing to marry
me just like that.
I figured after we married,
I would have to stage a
little accident for Elsa.
Hans! No. Stop.
But then, she doomed herself,
and you were dumb
enough to go after her.
Please.
All that's left now
is to kill Elsa,
and bring back summer.
You're no match for Elsa.
No, you're no match for Elsa.
I, on the other hand,
am the hero who is going to save
Arendelle from destruction.
You won't get away with this.
Oh...
I already have.
Please, somebody, help.
Please. Please.
It's getting colder
by the minute.
If we don't do something soon,
we'll all freeze to death.
Prince Hans.
Princess Anna is...
Dead.
What?
What happened to her?
She was killed.
By Queen Elsa.
No!
Her own sister.
At least we got to say
our marriage vows
before she died in my arms.
There can be no doubt now.
Queen Elsa is a monster,
and we are all in grave danger.
Prince Hans,
Arendelle looks to you.
With a heavy heart,
I charge Queen Elsa of
Arendelle with treason.
And sentence her to death.
Hurry up!
She's dangerous.
- Move quickly.
- Careful.
- It won't open!
- It's frozen shut.
Put your back into it!
Come on! Push!
What is it, buddy?
Hey, watch it.
What's wrong with you?
I don't understand you
when you talk like that.
Stop it! Put me down!
No, Sven!
We're not going back.
She's with her true love.
What the...
Anna!
Come on! Come on, boy.
Help.
Anna!
Oh, no.
Olaf?
Olaf. Get away from there.
Wow!
So, this is heat.
I love it.
Ooh! But don't touch it.
So, where's Hans? What
happened to your kiss?
I was wrong about him.
It wasn't true love.
But we ran all the way here.
Please, Olaf, you can't
stay here. You'll melt.
I am not leaving here until
we find some other act of
true love to save you.
Do you happen to have any ideas?
I don't even know what love is.
That's okay, I do.
Love 'vs
putting someone else's
needs before yours.
Like, you know, how Kristoff brought you
back here to Hans and left you forever.
Kristoff loves me?
Wow, you really don't know
anything about love, do you?
Olaf, you're melting.
Some people are
worth melting for.
Just maybe not
right this second.
Don't worry, I've got it.
We're gonna get through...
Oh, wait.
Hang on, I'm getting something.
It's Kristoff and Sven!
They're coming back this way.
They... They are?
Wow! He's really moving fast.
I guess I was wrong.
I guess Kristoff doesn't love
you enough to leave you behind.
Help me up, Olaf. Please.
No, no, no! You need to stay
by the fire and keep warm.
I need to get to Kristoff.
Why?
Oh, I know Why!
There's your act of
true love right there!
Riding across the fjords like a
Valiant, pungent reindeer King!
Come on!
Look out!
"OW.!"
Uh... Back this way.
We're trapped.
On...
Whoa!
Slide, Anna!
We made it!
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
Come on, buddy, faster.
Kristoff!
Keep going!
Come on!
No.
Whoa!
Sven... Sven!
Good boy.
Kristoff.
- Kristoff...
- Anna...
Anna!
Elsa! You can't run from this!
Just take care of my sister.
Your sister?
She returned from the
mountain weak and cold.
She said that you
froze her heart.
No.
I tried to save her,
but it was too late.
Her skin was ice. Her
hair turned white.
Your sister is dead.
Because of you.
No.
Kristoff.
Anna!
Elsa?
No!
Anna!
Oh. Anna!
No, no!
Please, no.
Anna?
Oh, Elsa.
You sacrificed yourself for me?
I love you.
"An act of true love will
thaw a frozen heart."
"Love Will thaw."
Love. Of course.
Elsa?
Love!
I knew you could do it.
Hands down, this is the
best day of my life.
And, quite possibly, the last.
Oh, Olaf! Hang on, little guy.
Oh, Oh, Oh!
My own personal flurry!
Uh-uh-uh-uh.
Anna?
But she froze your heart.
The only frozen heart
around here is yours.
Wonderful!
Setting course, Sir.
I will return this
scoundrel to his country.
We shall see what his 12 big
brothers think of his behavior.
Arendelle thanks you, milord.
This is unacceptable.
I am a victim of fear.
I've been traumatized.
Ah! My neck hurts.
Is there a doctor
that I could see?
And I demand to see the Queen!
Oh. I have a message
from the Queen.
"Arendelle will
henceforth and forever"
"no longer do business of
any sort with Weaseltown."
"Weselton."
- it's Weselton!
- Let's go.
Come on, come on, come on!
Okay, okay, here I come.
- Pole!
- Whoops! Sorry.
Okay, Okay-
Here we are. Oh!
I owe you a sled.
- Are you serious?
- Yes!
And it's the latest model.
No, I can't accept this.
You have to. No returns. No
exchanges. Queen's orders.
She's named you the Official
Arendelle Ice Master and Deliverer.
- What? That's not a thing.
- Oh, sure it is.
And it even has a cup holder.
Do you like it?
Like it? I love it!
Whoa.
I could kiss you!
I could. I mean, I'd like to.
I'd...
May I? We me. I mean, may we?
Wait, what?
We may.
Mmm.
Summer!
Ooh...
Hello.
{CHUCKLING)
Are you ready?
Ice!
Ooh! Whoo-hoo...
Swing me.
Ooh...
I like the open gates.
We are never closing them again.
Oh, Elsa, they're beautiful,
but you know I don't skate.
Come on! You can do it!
Look out. Reindeer
coming through.
I got it, I got it. I don't
got it, I don't got it.
Hey, guys!
That's it, Olaf.
Glide and pivot. And
glide and pivot.
Go.
Oh!
Subtitle by: EJSUB