I'm singing in the rain
Just singing in the rain
What a glorious feeling
I'm happy again
Whoa!
Let the stormy clouds chase
Everyone from the place
I'm laughing at clouds
So dark up above
The sun's in my eyes
And I'm ready for love
Come on, bring on that rain
I'm happy again
Come on with the rain
There's a smile on my face
I'm dancing with worms
Whoa!
A permit? Damn! How do you say "permit"?
I have a permit.
- Dr. Niko Tapopopolis?
- It's Tatopoulos.
Kyle Terrington.
I'm with the U.S. State Department.
- What are they doing?
- You're being reassigned.
My work here isn't finished.
It is now.
What did you see, old man?
That's affirmative.
Hey, where you going
with my stuff?
Hello?
Hello. That's very delicate.
Thank you.
Dr. Niko Topodopeles?
- It's Tatopoulos.
- Whatever.
Get these people off the pier.
- Sir, what am I doing here?
- Watch your step and don't talk.
Get them off the damn pier!
- Is this some kind of spill?
- Something like that.
I work for the
Nuclear Regulatory Commission...
but accidents and spills
are not my field.
We know.
Do you know you've interrupted a study
of the Chernobyl earthworm?
Yeah, you're the worm guy, right?
Radioactive contamination in that area
has mutated the earthworm's DNA.
- You know what that means?
- No, but I'm about to find out.
It means that because
of a man-made accident...
Chernobyl earthworms are now
17% larger than they were before.
17%, huh?
Sounds pretty big.
They're enormous.
That's what I'm trying to say.
I'm a biologist. I take
radioactive samples and I study them.
That's great.
Here's your sample.
- Study it.
- What sample?
- You're standing in it.
- I don't see it.
Where is it?
I don't see it.
Colonel! Colonel!
That was a footprint!
I was standing inside of a footprint.
That's right.
There's no animal in the world that
makes footprints like that, is there?
I told them this is not your field,
but they never listen to genius.
Nick, this is Elsie Chapman of
the National Institute of Paleontology.
She's your boss.
- Those were footprints, right?
- Yes, they were.
- Anybody see what made them?
- Actually, no such luck.
It happened so fast, nobody knew
what hit them until it was over.
- Elsie?
- Yeah?
Tape's in.
The French finally released it.
This is a Japanese cannery ship that was
attacked and sunk near French Polynesia.
We believe it's connected.
Dr. Craven, have you met the "worm guy"?
Oh, sorry. Summer cold.
Come on, come on ! All right?
Have a nice day.
Oh, wait, wait, wait!
- It's supposed to rain all week.
- What's with the bags?
Caiman's groceries.
Oh, girl!
- Speak of the devil.
- What?
This is the midget version. This makes
me look like a trained professional.
Can we put this on the 5:00, please?
- Think I should ask him?
- No!
- I'm gonna ask him.
- I will.
- Audrey.
- Did you talk with Humphries?
- This is not the place.
- Tell me. Did you talk with him?
- He's considering you and Rodriguez.
You serious? He's gonna consider me
for the job? What else did he say?
Why don't we talk about it
over dinner tonight? Your place.
You're married.
Yes, and you're beautiful.
Have I told you before?
Mr. Caiman !
I've been doing research for you after
hours and weekends for over three years.
This is a very important job to me.
I'm too old to be your assistant. I need
to know this job is going someplace.
So, have dinner with me tonight.
I can't.
It's your choice.
- Okay, let's go.
- Charlie?
Say hello to your new co-anchor,
Ms. Desireé Pon.
Welcome aboard.
- Mark, can I have a pillow, something?
- In five. Four.
Three. Two.
Hello, New York. At 5:00 we'll ask
Fat Pat, "When will this rain end?"
So three years digging up worms
in Chernobyl?
How did Mrs. Tata-polis
handle that?
It's Tatopoulos.
I'm not married.
Really? A girlfriend?
No. Perhaps I work too much.
There's no one who holds
a special place in your heart?
No. Not for a long time now.
You may be the wrong man for the job...
but I think you're cute.
Oh. Thank you.
She thinks I'm cute.
Who are they?
Get those people out of there.
- They're with me.
- Is that right?
- Who are you?
- Casualty and Property Insurance.
- We're preparing our report.
- You're damn fast.
That's our job.
Your people are getting in the way
of my job.
What could've done this?
Mr. Roaché, get your people
out of here...
or I will.
- Captain's getting a cup of coffee.
- Don't take too long.
- Then he'll come and kick your ass.
- Yeah ! I'm in for a buck.
What is that dope-head doing?
Artie!
- Artie, why are we slowing down?
- I don't know. She's at full throttle.
Maybe she's heavy in the net.
Yo! How come we stopped?
Are the nets full?
I don't think so.
We must be caught on something.
Bring in the nets.
Pull 'em in now.
- What's going on?
- We're bringing them in !
The engines are heating.
- Should I shut them down?
- No! Keep pulling!
Come on! Bring 'em!
I'm trying. I'm trying!
Cut 'em loose! Cut the net!
Look out!
Cut loose now!
Hurry! Hurry!
Jump!
Abandon ship!
Let her go!
You hear that?
Excuse me, sir. Got a report
of three fishing trawlers going down.
- What makes you think it's related?
- The trawlers were pulled under, sir.
Jesus Christ!
It's 200 miles off the Eastern American
seaboard and we don't know what it is.
- It's Theropoda Allosarus.
- What?
Some type of enormous reptile we believe
died out in the Cretaceous Period.
Where's it been hiding
the last 60 million years?
What about the traces of radiation?
The radiation isn't an anomaly.
It's the clue.
This animal is much too big
to be some kind of lost dinosaur.
Don't tell me what it isn't,
tell me what it is.
What do we know?
It was first sighted...
off the French Polynesian Pacific,
right?
That area has been exposed to dozens
of nuclear tests over the past 30 years.
Hence the radiation.
No, more than that.
I believe this is a mutated aberration.
A hybrid caused by the fallout
on these islands.
Like your earthworms?
Yes. Yes.
We're looking at a completely
incipient creature.
The dawn of a new species.
The first of its kind.
My lite sucks.
Oh, please! Your lite doesn't suck.
- His lite sucks.
- 'Cause I'm married to you.
I cannot believe he put the moves on me
after everything I've done for him.
He is scum! As far as he's concerned,
you're a pair of breasts that talk.
Hey, there's an image.
He is dirt!
He's a douche bag, gutter slime,
dog crap, puke chunks.
You don't see I'm eating?
Audrey, you're too damn nice.
That's your problem.
Nice gets you nothing in this town.
It's dog eat dog. You gotta be a killer
to get ahead. Know what I'm saying?
I'm sorry, baby,
but you just don't got what it takes.
- Do you think that's true, Animal?
- Pretty much.
You're a nice person.
Nice guys finish last.
- I can be tough if I want.
- Yeah, sure.
I can!
- I can.
- No, yeah.
Whatever.
Oh, my God!
Could you turn that up, please?
- It's Nick!
- Who is he?
He was my college sweetie.
He looks so handsome on TV.
There seems to be an unusually
tight security around the crash site...
possibly because of the highly sensitive
military cargo on the plane.
Fellas, you want to unload this, please?
I'm getting soaked!
Come on, will ya?
Joe, gonna catch one of them
little fish in the East River?
I hope so.
You never know.
I mean, today could be my lucky day.
The only thing you're gonna catch
is a cold!
I got a bite!
Boy, do I have a bite!
Hold on, Joe. You got a big one, baby.
Hold on to it now.
You wanna fight?
Here he is, ladies and gentlemen,
the man you've all been waiting for.
Yours for a safer New York.
Your mayor, Mayor Ebert!
Thank you!
I want to thank all of you for coming
on this beautiful New York City day!
When I first came into office
four years ago...
people didn't think
that I would reduce crime.
But I did!
Oh, my God!
Move it! Let's get out of here!
I am grateful
we're getting a new set.
It represents a commitment
on the part management.
What I don't understand
is why we're the only station...
that doesn't have
the Korean grocery holdup as our lead.
What's our lead?
Rain ! Again!
Mom?
Sorry. I don't give a rat's ass
about a war...
in some country whose name
I can't even pronounce!
How about a real story?
Sir, I think your story
just walked by the window.
What?
Maybe we can get in
the Korean grocer's hospital room.
Did this Romeo have a name?
Nick Tatopoulos.
- Jesus! Is that why you dumped him?
- No.
How long did you guys go out, anyway?
Nearly tour years.
Girl, I'm surprised
he didn't ask you to marry him.
That's the problem.
He did.
Tell me that's not another parade.
I don't think that's a parade.
Please stand by.
What the hell is that?
Are you all right?
Are you cut?
Victor!
- Don't be stupid!
- Oh, my!
Jesus, Mary and Joseph!
That is really--
That is large.
Oh, my God!
Come on, you bastard!
Jeez!
Victor, get back here,
you retard!
Somebody do something!
Sergeant O'Neal, sir!
Any word from the mayor's office?
Yes, sir. They've agreed to evacuate the
city and called out the National Guard.
Wait. Evacuate Manhattan?
That's over three million people.
- Has that been done before?
- I don't think so.
- Where is he now?
- We lost sight of it, sir.
You want to run that by me again?
After its initial attack...
he disappeared.
Secretary of Defense Burk
is on the line.
I don't understand. How could
something so big just disappear?
- We're not sure, but we're scanning--
- He probably returned to the river.
I don't think so.
I mean, look at it.
It's perfect.
An island, water on all sides,
but like no other island in the world.
This is a place
where he can easily hide.
He's in there someplace.
Channel 12 caught it on tape.
Hello. I'm Charles Caiman
in the WIDF News Center.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we New Yorkers like to think...
we've seen it all, but what you
will see will shock you beyond belief.
This is footage we have
that indicates...
that there is a dinosaur loose
in Manhattan.
WIDF's exclusive footage
was shot barely half an hour ago.
WIDF cameraman Victor "Animal" Palotti
survived unharmed.
Great stuff, Animal.
Weren't you scared?
Yeah. Thought Lucy was gonna kill me.
Damn right, you crazy wop!
Okay, people, we have to be
completely relocated...
to the New Jersey station
for the 10:00 broadcast.
Animal!
You're riding in the chopper
with Caiman. Let's go. Lift off.
You going to be all right?
Audrey's going
to spend the night with us.
Cool. A threesome. That's excellent.
I'm a little tired--
Dozens of people are reported killed,
thousands of others injured.
Civil defense stations
are being set up throughout Manhattan.
In addition, city, military...
and health officials
are setting up a command post...
on the Jersey shore
in anticipation of an evacuation.
My bag. My bag!
Mr. Caiman, wait.
I've got a lead.
- I know a guy who's on the inside.
- Not now.
You don't understand.
I can get us inside information.
This is when the big boys go to work.
Okay, honey? Bag.
This is crazy! Come on, let's go.
Wait up.
- Can we get a cab?
- Audrey, what are you thinking?
Go, go!
In what city officials are describing
as the worst act of destruction...
since the World Trade Center bombing...
hundreds of thousands of people
have jammed the streets...
in the largest evacuation
in this city's history.
And many people, many, many people
are not happy about it.
Among those unhappy citizens
are the managers of the stores...
along pricey Fifth and Madison Avenue.
The Warner Bros. and Disney stores
have been cleared out by looters.
And the streets are jammed.
Traffic is at a standstill.
Emergency vehicles cannot have access
to any emergency that may develop.
And there is a slow but steady stream
out of the city...
as if Long Island or New Jersey
were any refuge in this time of crisis.
This is great!
If I'm wrong on this evacuation, they'll
string me up from the Liberty torch.
Didn't we agree that we weren't to have
any sweets until after the election?
Back off, Gene.
- Mr. Mayor.
- Who are they?
Building owners and business people
from the community.
- I don't have time for this nonsense.
- Campaign contributors!
Ladies and gentlemen,
I share your concerns.
I want to get this city back in business
as soon as possible. Please.
La Rochelle Insurance. We represent
13%% of the buildings in your city.
You can count on our emotional
and financial support.
Thank you.
What do you plan to do?
- Coming through.
- Where's your I.D.?
- What's the matter?
- You need press I.D.
I've got l. D.
I had a badge on my bag.
I don't know if this is a good idea.
What are you talking about?
You stole it.
Finally you got a little chutzpah.
Don't wimp out on me.
What if Caiman finds out?
How often will you have an ex-boyfriend
on the inside of a major story?
This is a once-in-a-lifetime
opportunity.
If I could just stick this thing.
You got any glue?
I'm sorry. I left my forgery kit
at the office.
No croissant?
Ah, you call this coffee?
I call this America.
I'm sorry, Mr. Mayor,
but that's where we are.
Now hold on. Hold on.
You're saying that in an election month
I've evacuated this city for nothing?
Do you realize what this evacuation
will cost the people of this city?
We have been monitoring the waters
around the island.
- As far as we can tell, it hasn't left.
- But you don't know for sure.
We have a strong reason to believe
it may be hiding...
inside one of the buildings
within the restricted area.
- But you don't know for sure!
- Mr. Mayor.
We cannot give the "all clear"
until each building has been checked.
- What is it?
- Excuse me, sir.
That may be more difficult
than we originally projected.
Terrific! More good news.
We've run into a problem.
- Do you believe this?
- I don't know what's going on.
- You never know what's going on.
- Thank you.
- Here, sir.
- Fall in.
Let's go, people.
Fall in downstairs.
Lieutenant Anderson and his men
found this this afternoon.
We were checking the office building
above when we found the floor was gone.
When we discovered he could burrow
through the tunnels, we realized...
he could be outside
the quarantine zone.
Holy Christ!
How many tunnels lead off the island?
Only 14. We've checked them all.
He hasn't used any of them.
- Have them all sealed up.
- Yes, sir.
How? How would we do that, sir?
Fill them with cement. Brick them up.
Put land mines in them, bombs.
I don't care! Make sure the damn thing
doesn't leave the island!
Yes, sir.
You know, he's not some enemy
trying to evade you.
- He's just an animal.
- What are you suggesting?
When I had to catch earthworms...
the best way to get them was not
to dig them out, but to draw them out.
All we need to do
is to find out what he needs...
and he'll come to you.
Where are they now?
Delta Niner, what is convoy position?
Command, they have
just entered the city.
I have no radio contact with the convoy.
I'm expecting ground confirmation now.
- Convoy ETA ten minutes, sir.
- We've got to hurry.
Man your positions now.
Ten minutes to ETA.
Go, go, go!
All systems go!
Is it good?
Let's go! Come on, coming through!
Put it down.
You said this was French Roast!
More cream.
Bring 'em in!
Bring 'em back.
I hope this plan of yours works.
I'm hoping that myself.
- Did you give approval for this?
- They just appropriated it.
Twelve city dump trucks? Would you like
to tell me what's going on?
Actually, no, I wouldn't.
And don't touch anything.
- How's O'Neal doing?
- Everything is on schedule.
- You sure you didn't know about this?
- No one told me anything.
Why do I keep you around?
Dump!
Very clever.
Let's pile it on
and let's get out of here.
That's a lot of fish.
Come on, you bastard,
it's supper time.
Look at all that frigging fish.
Is this gonna work?
We gotta get these manholes uncovered.
We want him to smell the bait.
Come on !
Let's go! Let's go!
Come on, guys.
Get those lids off. Go!
What the hell is he doing?
Okay, this way.
- Come on.
- You heard him. Let's go.
Come on! Over there!
This one.
Give me the crowbar.
Set up here.
It's your best shot.
This is 6-Alpha Charlie.
We can't stay put!
We gotta move!
We need bigger guns.
- We've lost communications.
- Get us back on-line.
Fire at will !
- Fire at will.
- Fire, fire!
O'Neal, what the hell
is going on?
He's gone, sir.
Echo unit in pursuit.
Follow my lead.
- All systems armed.
- Echo 4 armed.
We're doing 80 knots,
and he's pulling away, sir.
I've got him locked on.
- Target is locked on, sir.
- Fire the damn missile.
- Echo, fire at will.
- Fire sidewinders.
Damn!
That is a negative impact.
I repeat, that is a negative impact.
- Negative impact, sir.
- Negative impact?
That's the goddamn Chrysler Building.
He had it locked on.
We had you locked on.
The heat seekers can't lock, sir.
He's colder than the buildings.
Freddie!
- What?
- Let's go before we get caught.
Jimmy, you know that bad feeling I get
when something bad is going to happen?
- Yeah.
- I'm getting that feeling right now.
Descend to 300 feet.
All systems armed.
Target, 11 :00.
Where'd he go?
Echo Flight, get it together, guys.
Prepare to fire.
Echo 4, ready.
Echo 2, ready.
Fire!
I think we got him.
- We've lost Echo 1 and 2, sir.
- God!
Echo 4, where is target?
Jesus! He's right on my tail, sir!
I can't shake him!
Oh, I think I lost him.
We've lost Echo 4, sir.
What the hell is the matter with you?
You've caused more damage
than that goddamn thing did!
-Calm down. Have some candy.
-I don't want any candy! Leave me alone.
I can't believe it.
He did all of this
and we did nothing to him.
That's not true.
We fed him.
Here at Command Center in New Jersey
there is no new information to report...
because the military has clamped
a total media blackout...
on whatever is going on
out here.
Officials are not saying anything
about their attempts to contain...
or control this creature.
Okay, the situation is under control !
It is under control.
We have containment.
Don't wait for me. I'm okay.
- Can I help you, young man?
- Yes.
Do you have any
at-home pregnancy tests?
Especially ones that look
for gonadotrophic hormones...
or clomiphene citrate?
I don't know.
This is all we've got.
I'll take all of them.
You must have some harem.
Oh, my God. Is that you?
What are you doing here?
Hi. Hello.
- Wow. How much is that?
- $46.
God, you look-- Wow!
- How have you been?
- It's good to see you, Nick.
- So you made it.
- What?
You're a reporter.
That's good.
That's what you always wanted.
I'm happy for you.
Really. I am.
Thank you.
You're still mad at me?
Well, you left without a phone call,
letter, nothing, all this time.
Yeah. I guess I am
still a little mad.
That was eight years ago.
Some people change.
Most people don't.
I'm sorry you feel that way.
You're right.
Eight years is a long time.
Can I make you a cup of tea?
Sure. That'd be nice.
I still can't believe it.
How does a guy go
from anti-nuke activist...
to working for
the Nuclear Regulatory Commission?
When you and I went
to rallies together in college...
we helped to create awareness.
But now, from the inside...
I'm able to effect real change.
And exactly what changes
are you trying to effect?
I'm preparing a census
for the government.
I'm cataloging new species created
as a result of nuclear contamination.
- Is that what you think created this?
- Yeah. I found a blood sample earlier.
- How close did you get to the thing?
- I got pretty close.
What else did you find out?
We know he eats tons of fish.
He's amphibious.
He's a burrower.
And...
he's pregnant.
He is?
He! A very unusual he.
Obviously these tests
weren't designed for this...
but fundamentally they look for the same
hormonal patterns to indicate pregnancy.
I don't get it. It he's the first
of his kind, how can he be pregnant?
Doesn't he need a mate?
Not if he reproduces asexually.
Where's the fun in that?
I kept thinking,
why would he travel so tar?
But it makes perfect sense.
Lots of animals travel
great distances for reproduction.
That's what he's doing in New York.
He's nesting.
- Nesting?
- Yes.
Do you realize
that a lizard can lay...
up to 12 eggs at a time?
- Think of it.
- I didn't know that.
Forgive me.
I have to get this to the lab...
see it I can confirm all this.
I'll be right back.
Come on, Joey.
There's nothing down here.
I'm telling you, man,
I heard something.
You heard nothing.
It's a dead end.
Anything?
No. Nothing down here.
Nothing at all.
This is why, in this case, all the
king's horses and all the king's men...
may not be able to put
the Big Apple together again.
Audrey Timmonds. WIDF News.
- Yes!
- That's it. You owe me a beer.
You like it?
I should've worn my hair back.
- No, it looks great.
- You liked it? Good.
Can I ask you something?
How did you get ahold of this material?
It's like you said.
"Nice guys finish last."
- Thank you. I love you.
- Yeah, sure.
Murray!
Come here a second.
Hold on a second?
What is it?
I've got exclusive footage
of other places this thing has attacked.
You do?
Whose story is that?
Mine.
If we can lure him into a more open area
such as this portion of Central Park...
I think we can take him down.
Last time you didn't even scratch it.
That's not true. Our worm guy,
I mean Dr. Tatopoulos, has found blood.
Yes, I did.
We need to get him out
into open terrain...
and use weapons that don't rely
on heat-seeking technology--
Excuse me, sir. I think this situation
has become more complicated than that.
The blood that I collected...
revealed that the creature is either
about to lay eggs or already has.
Are you trying to tell us that there's
another one of those things out there?
No, Governor.
I don't believe so.
Wait a minute.
Then how can it be pregnant?
What is this, the virgin lizard?
No. It reproduces asexually.
That's why we have to find the nest
as soon as possible.
Otherwise up to a dozen
are going to be born...
each one capable of laying eggs
on its own.
Very quickly we could be looking at
an enormous population.
After we kill the creature,
then we'll search for the nest.
I think it might be too late by then.
These eggs will hatch very quickly.
How do you know?
The fish that we found
on the subway.
He's not collecting all this food
just for himself.
He's preparing to teed his young.
Stay tuned for our special report.
Would you excuse us, please?
Where you been?
They just promo-ed your spot.
It's up right after this.
Turn it up?
Yo! Can you turn it up, please?
The TV!
If Dr. Tatopoulos is right, we must act
quickly before this problem escalates.
So you want to divide our efforts
based solely on some wild theory?
Sir, Nick's come through for us before.
If he feels--
Come through for you?
Colonel, your campaign's a disaster.
You weren't even able to keep this thing
from coming to Manhattan.
Excuse me, gentlemen,
but I think we should see this.
Look at the methods and motivations
of Manhattan's newest unwanted pest.
Godzilla.
That's what Japanese sailors
called him in song.
A mythological sea dragon
who filled their hearts with fear.
- He stole my report!
- I know.
That myth has become reality,
our modern-day terror.
I don't believe it!
Who is this Godzilla?
Where did he come from? Why is he here?
And it's Gojira, you moron !
A direct path can be traced
from Manhattan to French Polynesia...
where nuclear tests have been going on
for more than two decades.
Research team member
Dr. Nick Papadopoulus believes....
the creature may be nesting...
using Manhattan as ground zero
to cultivate the species.
This despite the fact
that the combined might...
of the United States military
has been unable to subdue--
You went to the press with this?
- No! I haven't talked to anyone.
- They mentioned you by name!
Yeah. Yeah !
You gave them the tape?
No, I didn't give them the tape.
It's in my tent right now.
Oh, my God! She took it.
Pack your stuff, mister. You're
officially off this project as of now!
We're leaving.
I'm so sorry.
Make sure that Hicks finds that nest
before it's too late.
I'll try.
He's not there? A second ago
you told me he was on the other line.
Please. It's urgent. I really need
to talk to him. Yes, Nick Tatopoulos.
You're leaving?
Why?
Is it 'cause of me?
'Cause of the story?
What did you think
was going to happen?
You never said it was off the record.
I shouldn't have to. You were supposed
to be my friend. I trusted you.
There's something I have to tell you.
I lied to you.
I'm not a reporter.
When we broke up,
and I first came out to New York...
I was so sure I'd make it.
But I haven't.
That's why I needed the story so bad.
I couldn't tell you
I'm a failure.
And you thought that made it okay
to steal my tapes?
It was a terrible thing to do.
I never should've done that.
Good luck with your new career.
I really think you have
what it takes.
Newark Airport.
I'm sorry.
Yo! Give her a break, will ya?
Excuse me, is this the best way
to the airport?
Sir, where are you going?
Hello?
Okay, stop.
Stop the car right now!
Let me out of here!
I'm afraid I can't do that.
I know you, don't l?
Yeah, you're that insurance guy.
Agent Philippe Roaché, D.G.S. E.
Direction Générale
des Securité Extérieure.
Sounds big.
The French Secret Service.
Your American friends have decided
not to look for the creature's nest.
What? Are you sure?
How do you know that?
- We know. Trust me.
- Trust you?
You hijack me and you expect me
to trust you?
- Yes.
- Why should l?
Because you are the only one who wants
to find the nest as much as I do.
How did you get all this stuff
into the country?
This is America.
We can buy anything.
Why all the secrecy? Why aren't you
working with the U.S. military?
I'm not permitted
to speak of such things.
You said you needed my trust.
Then I need yours.
I am a patriot. I love my country.
You understand that?
Sure.
It is my job to protect my country.
Sometimes I must even protect it
from itself...
from mistakes we've made.
Mistakes we don't want the world
to know about.
- The nuclear tests in the Pacific?
- Yes.
This testing done by my country
left a terrible mess.
We're here to clean it up.
We know how to get into the city.
We just don't know where
to start looking.
Here. This is the 23rd Street
subway station.
That's where we first found the fish.
That'd be a good place to start.
So you're in?
Yeah. Yeah, I'm in.
I always wanted to join
the French Foreign Legion.
- Hello.
- How's it going?
Excuse me. Pardon me.
Sorry.
- Honey?
- Hi, sweetie.
- Who are all these people?
- What?
I couldn't just let them
sleep on the street.
Where's Audrey?
In the bedroom crying her eyes out
because of you.
What did I do?
That "you gotta be vicious" stuff
you tilled her head with.
- Get out of here!
- Go talk to her right now.
I was agreeing with you.
Excuse me.
Contrary to frivolous reporting...
we have absolutely no information
whatsoever to make us believe...
that there are any eggs of the creature
in the city.
There's no need for panic.
Repeat. There's no reason to panic.
It's all my fault.
What have I done?
What have I become?
Look at me. This isn't me.
I don't do stuff like this.
You made a mistake. It happens.
Well, I totally screwed up with the
only man who will ever care about me.
If I told you you could make it all up,
would you?
Of course I would.
So get this.
After he left you in the street,
I kinda followed him.
Figured I'd talk some sense
into the guy, you know?
Next thing I know,
he pulls into this warehouse...
with all these French wackos
in military outfits.
They want to sneak back
into the city tonight.
They're going after the nest.
If he finds it, I think you should be
the one that lets the world know...
that this guy was right all along.
You want me to follow him
into the city?
Yeah. We both will.
Come on. It'll be fun.
I don't know. I've already made
such a mess of everything.
Yeah, you did, Audrey.
I'm goin' after him.
You can come with me or not. Okay?
What are you doing?
Can't let Lucy know.
She'll hurt me.
What's with the gum?
Makes us look more American.
Really?
Just let me do the talking.
All right?
It's not in gear.
Follow me. This way.
- You okay?
- I'm okay.
- Come on.
- What is this place?
It's a vent that leads to
the subway tunnels underneath here.
It should take us to
the 23rd Street station in Manhattan.
You've got to be kidding me.
Aren't there rats and stuff down here?
I'm more concerned about lizards
at this point.
Big, ugly, nasty, large lizards.
Who you with?
We're with the 3-2, sir.
I didn't ask you, soldier!
Sergeant O'Neal just called down for us.
He wants us to join him now, sir.
Thank you.
- You got a problem talkin'?
- No, sir. I'm tine.
Let's go!
Keep it movin'.
Thank you very much.
Elvis Presley movies.
He was the King.
Sir, O'Neal on-line.
Do you read me?
Call for O'Neal!
How are we doing?
So tar so good.
We're right on schedule.
We're good.
- Oh, my God!
- Yeah. There they are.
Kill your light.
How do we get down there?
We're gonna lose them.
- How did they get down there?
- I don't know.
You don't think
they climbed down this thing?
Jesus!
Careful.
- Gimme your hand.
- I got you.
The gutter.
- Do you hear that?
- What?
Animal, come on!
I guess we go this way.
Sir, we spotted him in section 5.
Combat positions! Here we go.
Combat!
Target's heading north
to section 5.
Do not fire until he has cleared
the buildings and enters the park.
Wait until he enters the park.
Come on.
He's leaving!
Fire away!
Damn!
Fire!
Raven Flight. Evasive maneuvers.
Target is in the clear. He's headed
toward the Westside Highway.
Don't worry. The navy
has something waiting for him.
- Stations manned for battle station.
- At ordered depth, sir.
We've got him on sonar.
Utah closing in.
Make final preparations.
Prepare to fire.
Manned and ready.
Torpedo room reports
manned and ready.
- Final bearing in chute.
- Are we locked on?
- Aye, sir.
- Locked on, Captain.
- Number one, stand by. Fire.
Torpedo 1 left the tube.
Indiana and Anchorage closing in.
- What's the status?
- We're locked on and closing in.
Fire one.
- The target's heading right at us!
- All back full.
Aye, sir. All back full.
Stand by for impact in ten seconds.
Six. Five.
Four. Three.
Two. One.
We've lost the Anchorage, sir.
He's shitted course.
He's heading back towards Manhattan.
Full ahead. Close in and lock on.
Prepare tubes 3 and 4 and lock on.
- Stand by, 3. Fire.
- Torpedo 3 left the tube.
Impact in eight seconds.
Seven. Six.
Three. Two. One.
- Direct hit!
- Got him.
Congratulations, sir.
Good job.
Well done.
What's up there?
This is a good smell.
Yeah.
Look at this.
He trashed the Garden.
Oh, man!
Now I'm pissed.
Is that them?
Yeah.
Three eggs.
I thought there'd be more.
And you were right.
Oh my! Wow!
There's gotta be more
than 20 eggs here.
Way more!
Start counting.
- Could you help me?
- You all right?
What the hell are they doing?
We have a problem.
Oh, my God! God!
Come on, let's go.
One second, all right?
This is unbelievable.
- Don't we have enough already?
- I just want--
That's good for me.
That's plenty.
We should-- Let's--
Let's not startle him.
We smell like the fish.
- I think we should leave now.
- I think that's a good idea.
Run! Come on!
- Everybody outside now!
- Come on, quickly!
Lock the doors now!
We have to keep them contained inside.
Come on, let's go!
- You see that?
- On three.
Three!
This is where the Knicks
get showered and everything.
Now what do we do?
I'm standing just outside the
Jersey entrance to the Lincoln Tunnel...
where thousands of angry refugees are
demanding to be let back into the city.
All major arteries into the city
are clogged with jubilant Manhattanites.
Yes, I understand.
- Your office is swamped with calls.
- I know.
Do you have any idea what's going on out
there? Phones are ringing off the hook.
People are screaming
to be let back into the city.
We're sending divers in
to retrieve the body.
What are you waiting for?
Colonel, we've got to start a search
for the nest.
We've been through this already.
What if Nick is right
and we blow this whole thing?
This could be the only chance we have
to do something about it.
Captain, organize a search party.
I want a sweep of the entire city
and the subway.
You don't have the authority
to do that.
Try and stop me.
Contact the military.
Get them to send a bomber
to blow up this building.
- How do I do that?
- 555-7600.
Tell them it's a Code Dragonfly.
That should get you through.
What are you waiting for?
- 555 what?
- 7600.
- All circuits are busy right now.
- It's busy.
Try again!
What did they say?
I can't get through.
I don't know what's wrong.
We secured the doors.
- Where is Jean-Philippe, Jean-Pierre?
- They didn't make it.
My men and I will hold them here.
You'll have to go and get help.
Can we tit up there?
Only one way to find out.
Boost me up.
This is not good.
Come on.
Wrong floor.
Why don't we go this way?
- It's me. It's me.
- What happened?
They're loose. They're all over
the place. I couldn't get out.
- Who are you?
- Audrey!
Here.
- You all right?
- I think so.
No cameras.
Yeah, all right.
Very good.
Do you have a radio, walkie-talkie,
anything to contact the outside?
- What about the phones?
- It's no good. Circuits are jammed.
Wait. I know a way. I know how
we can get a message to the outside.
This way.
The tape!
Come on !
Come on.
- The broadcast booth is over here.
- How do you know that?
Our network covers the Rangers games.
- It's locked.
- Wait. There's a code.
Come on !
I was just about to get it.
The network is on an intranet. It's
a direct teed into our computer system.
Your station won't have an easier time
reaching the military than I did.
Did they monitor
all the news broadcasts?
Yeah, they did.
All right, we'll go live.
We'll broadcast right from in here.
Hopefully they'll see it.
I'll try to get a message through.
Let's not forget in our rush
to return to the city...
that many people have had their lives
changed forever.
No one in the city has been untouched
by the tragedy.
The sick, the displaced,
the injured--
There's no Ranger game on tonight.
Ed, if you're seeing this,
will you please put us on live?
It's urgent.
I know this sounds crazy,
but you have to do it.
Trust me.
I'm not putting you on live.
- I don't think he'll do it.
- Yes, he will.
All right, Ed? Come on!
See that? They'll be all over the city
if we don't stop them.
Give me a second.
The time has come to return
to our homes and pick up our lives.
- These are the last three.
- Our fears have been allayed.
Thanks to the heroic efforts
of our boys in uniform--
Are we on?
This calculator--
Yeah, you're on.
Yes, you're on. Go!
We're live inside
Madison Square Garden...
where Dr. Niko Tatopoulos
has discovered the beast's lair.
Doctor, can you tell us
what's happening here?
- That's you, yes. Go, go.
- Thank you.
Well, we've discovered
over 200 eggs.
Go get Hicks.
Which a few moments ago began hatching.
The creatures just hatched are over nine
feet tall, and they've begun feeding.
When their food supply runs out here...
they will attempt to hunt down food
of their own outside of this nest.
Oh, my God!
If they get out, they'll multiply
and soon a new species will emerge.
One that could replace us as
the dominant species of this planet.
Each one of these amazing reptiles...
are born pregnant.
Adaptive and cunning, these 200
could become 40,000 within this year.
If the military is listening
to this broadcast...
they have to destroy this building
immediately...
before these creatures
can escape.
So far they're all trapped
inside this building...
but I don't think
we can contain them for long.
They're very strong, agile...
and they're looking for food.
So your theory of the creature nesting
turned out to be correct after all.
Regardless of what happens to us,
the most important thing...
is that this building be destroyed
immediately before they escape.
Reporting live
from Madison Square Garden...
this is Audrey Timmonds
for WIDF News.
Thanks, Audrey.
Sure.
That's affirmative.
Let me spell it out for you.
I want you to blow up
Madison Square Garden.
The good news is they got that message.
The bad news is we've got
less than six minutes to get out.
Party's over.
Time to leave.
Anyone care to join me?
- Where did you find this guy?
- He's from France.
Stallion 1-5s I.P. inbound.
You okay?
Guys, this way. Come on.
Oh, my God! The fish.
Nick, come on!
They've eaten all the fish.
Come on, Nick! This way.
Not this way! Back that way!
- The escalators.
- Hurry!
Stallions, check master arms on.
Two, three.
I think I lost them.
Stallion 1-5 showing a good laser track
on top of the Garden. Selecting L.G.B.
How much time do we have left?
Less than 30 seconds.
Let's go!
Let's go! Come on!
Come on !
Save your Mavericks.
Two away.
Lead has good hits.
Are you all right?
Yeah.
Somehow I never thought your life
was this exciting.
You'd be surprised.
I'd like to find out.
How ya doin'?
You all right?
I could use a coffee.
He looks angry.
What do we do?
Running would be a good idea.
Let's go!
Come on !
- Get in!
- What are you doin'?
You better step on it, Mr. French.
Take 57th Street
and cut up the Westside.
Are you crazy?
Take the FDR.
- The FDR in the rain?
- Got to be a map.
He's gettin' larger!
Take the Westside Highway!
- I got one.
- The Westside's got construction.
This is a subway map!
- Broadway?
- Make up your minds!
Take Broadway!
We're traveling down Broadway.
Make a right on 34th Street.
That was O'Neal.
Is everybody okay?
Is everybody all right?
- Turn around. Do it!
- What? Why?
Command center, come in.
This is O'Neal for Hicks.
- What's going on?
- He's back, sir.
Godzilla is still alive.
Lieutenant Rodgers,
are those F-18s still in the air?
Yes, sir.
They're heading back to the base.
Turn 'em around.
- Here it is.
- What are we looking for?
Every cab company keeps a record...
of each of its cab's
radio frequencies.
Bingo!
He's getting closer!
In there. Go in the tunnel.
They've got it blocked.
- Now where would you like to go?
- Turn off the lights.
Nick, are you there?
Nick?
Nice trick with the cab I.D.
Where the hell are you?
You have to help us.
We're in the--
Park Avenue Tunnel.
He's got us trapped in here.
You guys have got to lure him
out into the open...
so we can get a clear shot at him.
No problem. You want us
to wash him up, too?
- Where's the nearest suspension bridge?
- Brooklyn.
- Let's go.
- How would you like us to do that?
This thing have high beams?
Now!
He's headed toward the Brooklyn Bridge.
Target is heading toward
the Brooklyn Bridge, sir.
Direct the F-18s
to the Brooklyn Bridge.
- He's not following us!
- Really?
You gotta be kiddin' me.
We're in his mouth.
You're goin' the wrong way, man!
Will you shut up?
Gun it! Go, go!
Go, go!
Move it!
O'Neal, it worked!
He's caught in the suspension cables.
Do it!
- Now!
- Roger.
Stallion 1-5, tally one on the bridge.
Fire at will.
Two away!
Hurry up, go!
Direct hit,
but the target is still moving.
Circle around and fire again!
That's my husband!
I'm gonna kill him!
Oh, my.
Oh, God. Oh, no!
Wait. Wait.
We can use this.
"The mayor who destroyed Godzilla."
I don't think we should exploit this.
It could backfire.
Listen, idiot. I do the thinking
around here. It's a magnificent idea.
You know what I think about you
and your campaign?
Where are you goin'? I need you.
O'Neal, do you read me?
Yes, sir.
That is one hell of a job, soldier.
That's one hell of a job.
Roger that, sir.
Sorry folks.
I've already promised my story...
as an exclusive to another reporter.
We did it!
We got the exclusive!
You're beautiful.
We did?
I don't think so.
Remember you work for me.
Not anymore, Chuck.
I quit.
She quits.
All right, folks,
let's keep it movin'.
- You take the tape out of the camera?
- No.
- I couldn't have just lost it.
- Where's Philippe?
Hello?
- Hello?
- It's Philippe.
Where are you?
Tell your friends I will send the tape
after I've removed a few items from it.
- I understand.
- I wanted to say au revoir.
Thank you for your help, my friend.
Wait. Hello?
Who was that French guy anyway?
Just some insurance guy.
Did he say anything about my tape?
Yeah, he said something
about your tape.
- Does he have my tape or not?
- Yeah, he has your tape.