Hey, look, over there!
Wow!
Their ship is so big.
Wish ours was that fancy.
I'd be so happy if
ours was that fancy.
- 'Cause then...
- Why is that?
'Cause is looks better?
This boat has seen us
through many a storm.
It may not look like much but,
it has something
theirs never will.
What? Wood rot and rats?
Are the children learning
something, dear?
It is unclear.
All right, sit, children.
I think it's time
that I told you the story
of Aladdin, the Princess,
and the lamp.
What's so special about a lamp?
Oh, this is a magic lamp.
Maybe if you sing.
It's better when you sing.
No, no. No singing.
It's been a long day.
♪ Oh, imagine a land
It's a faraway place ♪
♪ Where the caravan camels roam ♪
♪ Where you wander among
every culture and tongue ♪
♪ It's chaotic, but hey,
it's home ♪
♪ When the wind's from the east
and the sun's from the west ♪
♪ And the sand in the glass is right ♪
♪ Come on down,
stop on by ♪
♪ Hop a carpet and fly ♪
♪ To another Arabian night ♪
♪ As you wind through the streets ♪
♪ At the fabled bazaars ♪
♪ With the cardamom-cluttered stalls ♪
♪ You can smell every spice ♪
♪ While you haggle the price ♪
♪ Of the silks and the satin shawls ♪
♪ Oh, the music that plays ♪
♪ As you move through a maze ♪
♪ In the haze of your pure delight ♪
♪ You are caught in a dance ♪
♪ You are lost in the trance ♪
♪ Of another Arabian night ♪
♪ Arabian nights ♪
♪ Like Arabian days ♪
♪ More often than not ♪
♪ Are hotter than hot ♪
♪ In a lot of good ways ♪
♪ Arabian nights ♪
♪ Like Arabian dreams ♪
♪ This mystical land ♪
♪ Of magic and sand ♪
♪ Is more than it seems ♪
♪ There's a road that may lead you ♪
♪ To good or to greed through ♪
♪ The power your wishing commands ♪
♪ Let the darkness unfold ♪
♪ Or find fortunes untold ♪
♪ Well, your destiny lies in your hands ♪
Only one may enter here.
One whose worth lies far within.
A diamond in the rough.
♪ Arabian nights ♪
♪ Like Arabian days ♪
♪ They seem to excite ♪
♪ Take off and take flight ♪
♪ To shock and amaze ♪
Seek me out.
The diamond in the rough.
♪ Arabian nights ♪
♪ 'Neath Arabian moons ♪
♪ A fool off his guard ♪
♪ Could fall and fall hard ♪
♪ Out there on the dunes ♪
What's your monkey's name?
Abu.
He's a lovely monkey.
Mm, that's a lovely necklace.
So, where does Abu come from?
He, uh... Oh!
I think this... belongs to me.
Good day, ladies.
Okay.
How'd we do, Abu?
Good monkey.
Stop right there, Aladdin.
Whatever it is you stole today,
I don't want it.
Whoa, whoa,
I didn't steal anything.
It's a family heirloom
that's worth a lot of...
I'll give you a bag of dates
for it, nothing more.
Zulla, we both know it's
worth at least three bags.
Take a bag of dates
and get out!
Here you go, Abu.
Shh.
Hello.
Hi.
- Are you hungry?
- Mm-hmm.
Here, take some bread.
Hey. Hey!
You steal from my brother.
Stealing? No, I...
You pay or I take bracelet.
Sir, I don't have any money.
- Let go of me!
- No.
Take it easy, Jamal.
Khalil walks away from the stall,
and this one... this one...
she steal the bread!
Those children were hungry!
- I...
- Okay, give me a minute.
You keep your little
street rat nose
out of it! Huh?
Do you have any money?
- No!
- Okay.
Trust me.
- Here you go.
- Wait!
- This is what you wanted, right?
- Eh! Thank you.
Okay, and an apple
for your troubles.
- Nice.
- That was m...
I'm not leaving
without my bracelet!
You mean, this bracelet?
Come on.
♪ Nay nay nay na-na-nay ♪
♪ Nay nay nay nay nay... ♪
Aladdin!
Thief, Aladdin!
Are we in trouble?
Only if you get caught.
Aladdin!
Down that alley.
Monkey knows the way.
Abu.
Cute butt.
You'll be fine.
- Over there!
- Hey, you!
You looking for this, Jamal?
Aladdin, you street rat!
♪ Gotta keep ♪
♪ One jump ahead of the bread line ♪
♪ One swing ahead of the sword ♪
♪ I steal only what I can't afford ♪
Stop!
♪ And that's everything ♪
♪ One jump ahead of the lawmen ♪
♪ That's all, and that's no joke ♪
♪ These guys don't appreciate I'm broke ♪
♪ Riffraff! Street rat! Scoundrel! ♪
♪ Take that! ♪
♪ Try a different tact, guys ♪
♪ Rip him open ♪
♪ 'Round the back, guys ♪
♪ I can take a hint
Gotta face the facts ♪
♪ Could really use a friend or two ♪
♪ Oh, it's sad,
Aladdin's hit the bottom ♪
♪ He's become a
one-man rise in crime ♪
♪ I'd blame parents,
'cept he hasn't got 'em ♪
♪ Gotta eat to live,
gotta steal to eat ♪
♪ Tell you all about it
when I got the time ♪
Hey!
There are stairs, you know.
Where's the fun in that?
♪ One jump ahead of the slowpokes ♪
♪ One skip ahead of my doom ♪
♪ Next time gonna use
a nom de plume ♪
Hey, get back here!
♪ One jump ahead of the hitmen ♪
♪ One hit ahead of the flock ♪
♪ I think I'll take a stroll
around the block ♪
♪ Stop thief! ♪
♪ Vandal! ♪
♪ Abu! ♪
♪ Scoundrel! ♪
♪ Let's not be too hasty ♪
♪ Still I think he's rather tasty ♪
♪ Gotta eat to live,
gotta steal to eat ♪
♪ Otherwise we'd get along ♪
♪ Wrong! ♪
No, no, no, no!
Together on three.
Together on three?
- We jump.
- We jump?!
Why are you repeating
everything I say?
The pole.
One, two, three!
Sorry!
I can't.
Look at me.
You... can do this.
- Oh.
Nicely done.
Thank you.
♪ One jump ahead of the hoofbeats ♪
♪ One hop ahead of the hump ♪
♪ One trick ahead of disaster ♪
♪ They're quick, but I'm much faster ♪
♪ Here goes
Better throw my hand in ♪
♪ Wish me happy landing ♪
♪ All I gotta do is jump! ♪
Oh, dear.
Come on. I know
somewhere we'll be safe.
Here comes the Master.
You bring me the rough
but never a diamond.
Take them away.
Majazeer, perhaps this
diamond in the rough
does not exist.
He is out there.
But we've searched for months.
I do not understand
what could possibly
be in that cave
that could help a man
as great as you.
You are already second
only to the Sultan.
Second! Uh-oh.
Who's in trouble now?
And you think second is enough?
Of course.
You were not born to be sultan.
Not smart.
Do you know what I had to do
to get the power that I have?
The sacrifices that I've made?
The bodies that I've buried?
The five years spent
in a Sherabad jail?
People need to understand
that they will pay
for underestimating me.
Second is not enough!
And it will never be enough!
That's why I need the lamp.
And why I no longer need you!
Tea?
Thank you.
And thank you for
getting me out of there.
Aladdin, isn't it?
Uh, you're welcome...
Um, I'm Dalia.
Dalia.
From the palace.
How could you tell?
Well, only someone
from the palace
could afford a bracelet like that.
And that silk lining
is imported, too.
It comes from the merchant
boats straight to the palace.
But not to servants.
At least not most servants.
Which means you...
are a handmaid to the Princess.
Impressive.
You think that's impressive.
You should see the
city from up there.
Agrabah.
It's so beautiful.
I should get out more.
You should tell the
Princess to get out more.
The people haven't
seen her in years.
They won't let her.
Ever since my...
The Queen was killed,
the Sultan's been afraid.
So she's kept locked away.
Seems everyone's been
afraid since then.
But the people of Agrabah
had nothing to do with that.
The people loved her.
They did, didn't they?
Is this yours?
It's kind of... borrowed.
My mother taught me that song.
Mine too.
It's all I remember of her.
And what about your father?
I lost them both
when I was young.
Been on my own ever since.
It's all right, it's just...
What?
It's a little sad...
having a monkey as the only
parental authority in your life.
We get by.
Every day, I just...
think things will be different,
but it never seems to change.
Just sometimes,
I feel like I'm...
Trapped.
Like you...
can't escape what
you were born into?
Yes.
I have to get back to the palace.
Now?
It's just another prince
coming to court the princess.
Yes, and I have to
get her ready.
Oh, do you have my bracelet?
Sure.
I'm sure I put it in here.
Somewhere.
Abu, did you take it?
That was my mother's bracelet.
Yes, it's beautiful.
You are a thief.
No. No. Yes, but...
I was so naive.
Excuse me.
Wait. Wait. Wait!
Wait, it's not like that!
Street rat, get out of the way.
Who do you think you're
calling a street rat?
Are you talking back to me?
You were born worthless
and you will die worthless.
And only your fleas
will mourn you.
Come on, Abu.
Let's go home.
♪ Riffraff ♪
♪ Street rat ♪
♪ I don't ♪
♪ Buy that ♪
♪ If only ♪
♪ They'd look closer ♪
♪ Would they see a poor boy? ♪
♪ No, siree ♪
♪ They'd find out ♪
♪ There's so much more ♪
♪ To me ♪
Abu.
There's a time that we do steal,
and a time we don't.
This was definitely a don't.
Welcome, Prince Anders.
We trust you had an
enjoyable journey.
Oh, wow.
Prince Anders, my daughter...
Princess Jasmine.
S-So...
Why did no one tell
me of your beauty?
No one mentioned yours, either.
Oh, thank you.
They say that in Skånland.
Ya, right?
It's... It's very, very amusing.
- Is it?
- Ya.
We have that same title yet are
never described the same way.
Mm-hrm... Jasmine.
Ya.
Oh.
What is that?
Don't. Don't tell me.
It's a cat... with stripes.
He likes you.
I know.
'Cause in Skånland, cats love me.
Here, puss-puss.
Hey, puss-puss.
Hey, puss-puss, puss...
My Sultan...
Our enemies grow
stronger every day,
yet you allow your daughter
to dismiss Prince Anders
and a possible military alliance.
Which enemies?
Sherabad continues to amass.
Sherabad is our ally.
Was our ally.
You would drag us into
a war with our only...
Yet you would allow your
kingdom to sink into ruin,
for mere sentiment!
Jafar!
Remember your place.
I apologize.
Forgive me, my Sultan.
I went too far.
But...
if you would only reconsider,
I think you would see
that invading Sherabad
is the right thing to do.
Invading Sherabad is...
Invade Sherabad?
Why would we invade
Mother's kingdom?
We would never invade Sherabad.
But an ally in Skånland would
improve our situation.
Yes. If you
consider giving
Prince Anders a chance.
To rule?
Baba, Rajah would
make a better ruler.
My dear, I'm not
getting any younger.
We must find you
a husband and...
we are running out of kingdoms.
What foreign prince can
care for our people as I do?
I could lead, if only...
My dear, you cannot be a sultan.
Because it has never been done
in the thousand-year
history of our kingdom.
I have been preparing for this
my whole life.
- I have read every...
- Books?
But you cannot read experience.
Inexperience is dangerous.
People, left unchecked, will revolt.
Walls and borders, unguarded,
will be attacked.
Jafar is right.
One day,
you will understand.
You may leave now.
Life will be kinder
to you, Princess,
once you accept these
traditions and understand
it's better for you to be seen
and not heard.
♪ Here comes a wave
Meant to wash me away ♪
♪ A tide that is taking me under ♪
♪ Broken again
Left with nothing to say ♪
♪ My voice drowned out in the thunder ♪
♪ But I can't cry ♪
♪ And I can't start to crumble ♪
♪ Whenever they try ♪
♪ To shut me or cut me down ♪
♪ I can't stay silent ♪
♪ Though they wanna keep me quiet ♪
♪ And I tremble when they try it ♪
♪ All I know ♪
♪ Is I won't ♪
♪ Go speechless ♪
Open the gates!
You know what to do, Abu.
Close the gates!
Tacky monkey.
Remember your place, Jafar.
Remember your place.
If I hear that...!
One more time.
Sorry, Master.
Another petty insult
from that slow-minded fool.
He sees a city
where I see an empire.
Such vision.
Once that lamp sits in my hand,
then I shall sit on his throne.
Thief! Thief in the palace.
Thief in the palace?
That's what I said.
Thief.
What have you seen, lago?
Diamond in the rough.
Who's a clever boy?
But Dalia, there has to be
something I can do.
A handsome prince
wants to marry you.
Oh, when will life get easier?
It's not that I don't want to
marry, it's just...
You want to be sultan.
But why?
You remember my
mother used to say,
"We would only ever be as happy
as our least happy subject."
If she saw what I saw today,
she would be heart-broken.
She would also want
you to be safe.
And clean. I'll draw the bath.
Jafar's guards on every corner.
Soon he'd have them
invading our neighbors,
risking lives, for what?
I can help!
I know I can.
I was born to do more than
marry some useless prince.
If you had to marry
a useless prince,
you could certainly do
worse than this one.
He's tall and handsome,
and yes, he's a little dim but,
you're just getting married.
It's not like you
have to talk to him.
But you'd prefer that
boy from the market.
Can I help you?
- Tea?
- You.
You! What are you doing here?
Get in here, now.
I... came back to
return your bracelet.
My bracelet? Where is it?
On your wrist.
What?
Not bad!
I like what she's
done with the place.
How did you get past the guards?
That was challenging.
But, I have my ways.
While the Princess is out,
would you like to go for a stroll?
Have a little chat?
You're unbelievable.
You cannot just
break into a palace
and walk around like
you own the place.
If you don't have anything,
you have to act like
you own everything.
So, what do you say?
I did find your bracelet.
You did not find it,
you stole it.
Correction, the monkey stole it.
He's your monkey.
He's still just a monkey.
Who ordered the tea?
Uh...
I did.
For you,
Princess Jasmine.
Your Majesty!
Why are you being weird?
Oh, I'm... the Princess... Yes!
Mm-hmm.
And it is good to be me
with all my
palaces and...
wagons of gold... things...
and dresses for...
every hour of the day.
Now it is time for
my cat to be cleaned.
She doesn't get out much.
Mm-hmm. Clearly.
Aren't you supposed
to be in the bath?
This cat isn't going
to clean itself.
But don't cats clean themselves?
You have to go now.
Oh, okay, but I'm coming
back tomorrow night.
What? No, you can't.
Meet me in the courtyard
beside the fountain.
When the moon is
above the minaret.
To return this.
I promise.
Can you believe it, Abu?
The most heavily guarded
place in all of Agrabah.
Evening.
Guards are behind me.
Hello, boys.
Where am I?
In a world of trouble, boy.
That bracelet. Is that
what this is about?
Because I-I didn't steal it.
The handmaid...
What was the handmaid doing
wearing the Queen's bracelet?
The Queen?
No, no. She said that
- it belonged to...
- Her mother.
Well, at least she told
the truth about one thing.
A-Are you saying that
was the Princess?
- I was talking to the...
- She was toying with you.
It amuses her to meet commoners.
Did you actually
think she liked you?
What do they call you?
Aladdin.
People like us
must be realistic.
Us?
You see, I was once like you.
A common thief.
Only I thought bigger.
Steal an apple,
and you're a thief.
Steal a kingdom,
and you're a statesman.
Only weak men stop there.
You're either the most powerful
man in the room, or you're nothing.
You. You stumbled
upon an opportunity.
I can make you rich.
Rich enough to impress a princess.
But nothing comes for free.
What would I have to do?
There's a cave nearby.
And in it, a simple oil lamp.
Retrieve it for me,
and I will make you
wealthy enough to
impress a princess.
You're nothing to her.
But you could be.
Your life begins now, Aladdin.
Still waiting?
No. No, I... came out to...
He promised.
I'll be upstairs if you need me.
Good night, Dalia.
The Cave of Wonders.
When you enter,
you will see more riches
than you've ever dreamed of.
Gold, diamonds...
and... the lamp.
Bring it to me and I will
make you rich and free.
But take no other treasure,
no matter how sorely
you are tempted.
And you will be tempted.
Only one may enter here.
One who's worth lies far within.
A diamond in the rough.
Remember...
take nothing but the lamp.
Abu, don't touch. Remember?
Whoa.
Abu.
This is a magic carpet.
These really do exist.
Hello, carpet.
Let's see what we can do
about your situation here.
Oh, hey!
Don't mention it.
Abu, keep your little
monkey hands to yourself.
Abu! No!
You have touched the
forbidden treasure!
Now, you will never
again see the light
of day!
Carpet!
Abu, jump!
Could you give me a hand?
First, the lamp.
- No, no, first, your hand.
- We don't have much time.
Give me the lamp.
Your hand!
Second no more, Master.
Now, your hand!
How about my foot?
No!
Get off me, monkey!
Dirty monkey.
Aaahhh!
We're alive.
I think.
Thank you, carpet.
Abu.
How did you...?
You cunning little monkey.
Now, all we need's a way out.
Hey, carpet, do you know
a way out of here?
The lamp?
What is that?
Oh, great one who summons me.
Terrible one who commands me.
I stand by my oath.
Loyalty to wishes three.
I said... oh...
great...
Excuse me.
Boy, where's your boss?
Help me out here,
where's your boss?
If I was gonna talk to myself,
I coulda just stayed in the lamp.
Hello!
Um...
Use your big boy voice.
I'm... talking...
to a smoking blue giant?
No!
I am not a giant.
I am a genie.
There's a difference.
Giants are not real.
- Where's your boss?
- Um, my boss?
Look, kid, I've been doing
this a long time, all right?
There's always a guy, you know.
He's cheated somebody
or buried somebody or...
I mean, you get my point.
Where's that guy?
I know that guy.
He's outside.
So...
it's just...
you and me down here?
And a monkey.
That's your personal business, but
we gonna need to talk
about that monkey later.
Such a pretty little monkey.
So, you rubbed the lamp?
Uh-huh.
O... kay.
Hey, do you mind if I just
stretch it out over here?
Do you mind?
Uh, are you asking me?
You're my master.
I'm your master?
Downward dog!
No, no, no. You look like
you should be my master.
Right, but that's not
quite how it works, though.
How long have you
been trapped in here?
'Bout a thousand years.
A thousand years?
Kid, is it me, or does, like,
everything surprise you?
So, you really
don't know who I am?
Genie, wishes, lamp?
None of that ringin' a bell?
Wow.
Well, th-th-that's a first.
Monkey!
Oh, you don't need to
worry about him, he's fine.
♪ Well, Ali Baba, he had
them forty thieves ♪
♪ Scheherazade had
a thousand tales ♪
♪ Well, master, you're in luck
because up your sleeve ♪
♪ You got a genie that never fails! ♪
Whoo!
I'm the best.
Yeah.
Not enough, huh?
I'm kidding. Watch this.
Here I go!
Unh, ooh, woo!
Back up!
Uh-oh!
Watch out!
You done wound me up!
'Boutta show you what
I'm workin' with, unh!
♪ Well, Ali Baba, he had
them forty thieves ♪
♪ Scheherazade had
a thousand tales ♪
♪ But, master, you're in luck
because up your sleeves ♪
♪ You got a brand of magic
never fails ♪
♪ You got some power
in your corner now ♪
♪ Heavy ammunition in your camp ♪
♪ You got some punch,
pizazz, yahoo, and how? ♪
♪ All you gotta do
is rub that lamp ♪
♪ And then I'll say ♪
♪ Mister-Man, what's your name?
Whatever ♪
♪ What will your pleasure be? ♪
♪ Let me take your order,
I'll jot it down ♪
♪ You ain't never had
a friend like me ♪
♪ Life is your restaurant ♪
♪ And I'm your maitre d' ♪
♪ Come, whisper to me
whatever it is you want ♪
♪ You ain't never had
a friend like me ♪
♪ We pride ourselves on service ♪
♪ You the boss, the king, the shah! ♪
♪ Say what you wish,
it's yours! True dish ♪
♪ How about a little more baklava? ♪
♪ Have some of column A ♪
♪ Try all of column B ♪
♪ I'm in the mood
to help you, dude ♪
♪ You ain't never had
a friend like me ♪
Oh!
Unh!
It's the big part
Watch out!
Oh!
♪ Can your friends do this? ♪
♪ Can your friends do that? ♪
♪ Can your friends pull this ♪
♪ Outta they little hat? ♪
♪ Can your friends go ♪
♪ I'm the genie of the lamp ♪
♪ I can sing, rap, dance,
if you give me a chance, oh! ♪
♪ Don't sit there buggy-eyed ♪
♪ I'm here to answer
all your midday prayers ♪
♪ You got me bona fide, certified ♪
♪ You got a genie
for your charge d'affaires ♪
♪ I got a powerful urge
to help you out ♪
♪ So what's your wish?
I really wanna know ♪
♪ You got a list that's
three miles long, no doubt ♪
♪ All you gotta do
is rub like so ♪
♪ - Mister? Yes!
- Aladdin ♪
♪ One wish or two or three ♪
♪ Well, I'm on the job,
you big nabob ♪
♪ You ain't never had a friend,
never had a friend ♪
♪ - You ain't never
- Never ♪
♪ - Had a
- Had a ♪
♪ - Friend
- Friend ♪
♪ - Like
- Like ♪
♪ Me! ♪
♪ You ain't never had
a friend like me ♪
You can clap now.
Puh-domp.
No, no, no, no.
Please, please, please, please.
You can thank me outside.
I-In the sun.
When you wish us out.
So, how does it work?
You're... kidding, right?
The whole song...
was th-the instructions!
Obviously you can't dance
and listen at the same time.
So here's the basics:
Step one. Rub the lamp.
Step two. Say what you want.
Step three. There is no step three.
See? It's that easy.
You get three wishes. They must
begin with rubbing the lamp
and saying "I wish". Got it?
- I think so.
- A couple other rules.
You can't wish for more wishes.
Three is enough.
Now, I can't make
anybody love anybody.
Or bring anybody
back from the dead.
Feel free to interrupt me
anytime you don't understand.
I'm kidding. Don't ever interrupt me,
no matter what.
Now, I usually don't have
to go through all this
because by the time
the guy gets to me,
he pretty much
knows what he wants
and it generally has to do with
tons of money and power!
Do me a favor,
do not drink from that cup.
I promise you, there's not
enough money and power on earth
for you to be satisfied.
Good?
So, what's your first wish?
Mm, well...
I have to think about it.
I mean, if there are only three.
Why are there only three, anyway?
I don't know! Who cares?
You don't know.
I thought you were all-knowing?
That's 'cause you don't listen.
I never said I was all-knowing.
I said I was all-powerful.
The most powerful
being in the universe.
Look, whatever I don't know,
I know I can learn it.
Side in the sun.
Why you playin' hard to wish?
I know you can't tell,
but I'm very pale.
This is sky blue.
My natural pigmentation is navy.
Give us some sun!
Okay, Genie.
I wish for you
to get us out of this cave.
Oh, yeah!
He has made his first wish!
Thank you for choosing
carpets, camels and caravans.
Please don't forget to tip
your genie on the way out.
Hold yourself, kid!
Whoo!
Whoa.
Man, look at this world.
It's so... big.
Inside the lamp,
everything's like, brass!
Brass! Brass! Brass!
Like, ooh, is that some copper?
Nope! Brass!
Sorta the problem with the
genie life.
Phenomenal cosmic powers,
but itty-bitty living space.
So, is this magic?
Or are you magic?
Eh, kind of a package deal.
Can you warn me
before you do that?
Oh, you'll get used to it.
Right.
So, do I have to make
all my wishes here?
I mean, if I take you back to
Agrabah, won't people...?
No, no, no, no, no.
I can look totally normal.
Right. Totally normal.
Still blue.
Do we need the top knot?
That's my little cherry on top.
Okay, okay.
So...
What are you gonna wish?
Oh, I-I haven't
thought about that.
Mm. You really are not that guy.
Okay.
So what would you wish for?
No one's ever
asked me that before.
An easy one though.
I wish to be free.
To not have to say,
Can I help you?
What would you like?
Welcome to the lamp.
May I take your order please?
Freedom.
I wish to be...
To be human.
Why don't you just
set yourself free?
Carpet!
Did you hear
what this boy said?
Why don't I set myself free?
Only way a genie
gets to be free is if
the owner of the lamp
uses one of his wishes
to set him free.
And the last time
that happened was, like,
the fourth of Never-ary.
I'll do it.
I've got three, right?
Actually, you have two left.
You used one to get out
of the cave, remember?
Did I? Or did you?
I thought I had to be
rubbing the lamp?
Okay, little street boy.
Let's rewind the tape.
Okay, Genie.
Oooh!
The old
monkey-with-the-lamp trick.
Never seen that one before.
Keep my eye on you.
At least now I can use my
third wish to set you free.
Here's the thing about wishes.
The more you have,
the more you want.
That's not me.
Hmm.
We'll see about that.
- But there is something.
- Uh-oh.
Seen that face before.
Who is she?
Who's the girl?
She's a princess.
Aww, aren't they all?
Treat your woman like a
queen, I always say.
No. No, she's
an actual princess.
Well, I already told you.
I can't make anyone
love anyone, so.
No, no. We had a connection.
Did they?
She is smart and kind
and so beautiful.
But she has to marry a...
Hey, can you make me a prince?
There's a lot of gray area
in "make me a prince".
I could just... make you a prince.
Oh, no.
Right, you'd be snuggled up with
that dude for the rest of your life.
Yo, you all seen my palace?
Be specific with your words.
- The deal is in the detail.
- Got it.
Which I don't really understand
because if she already
likes you, why change?
I told you she
has to marry a prince.
I just wanna go home, man.
Okay. I can do that.
An official wish this time,
for those of us
who are counting,
which now, I am one.
Genie... I wish...
Lamp?
Oh. Sorry.
All right.
Genie...
Don't hurt him, Genie.
I wish...
to become...
a prince.
Back up, boy,
I need some room to work.
I'm about to fabulize you.
Genie?
A little head-spinning.
Better though, right?
I think I'm...
getting used to it.
Okay, a prince, a prince.
Obviously, the ghetto-chic
is not gonna work.
I'm feeling a periwinkle.
Wh-What's periwinkle?
No. Chartreuse.
- The lines are all wrong.
- What is this?
The color clashes
with your skin tone.
The silhouette is confused.
This is a big hat.
No, that is not a big hat.
Come on, Genie,
gotta beat the door down.
Gotta go bold!
Gotta... gold!
Aah, no!
- We've gone too far.
- Genie! You slippin'.
It's gotta be neutral
for the desert.
Ivory, beige, bone, Albion.
It's a little heavy.
Oh!
And the crowd goes wild!
Oho!
The Genie! The Genie's on fire!
The Genie's on fire, folks.
Somebody cool me down!
Somebody put me out!
I'm too much!
So what do you think?
I like it.
Of course you like it, boy.
I made it.
I think that's me.
Strictly speaking, it... it's me.
I mean, I did most of the work.
You was just standing there.
But I hear you.
But won't people recognize me?
Nobody will recognize you.
That's how genie magic works.
People see what
they're told to see.
Right.
- Who am I?
- Who...
Prince... Ali.
- From?
- Duh.
From Abuvwah.
A-bab-wah?
You're not listenin'.
Ababwah.
- Is that a real place?
- Yeah.
Like, everybody knows about it.
It has a brochure.
A little hot in the summer,
temperate in the fall.
I-I'll let you read it en route.
How are we gonna get there?
I guess you can't ride a chimp.
Don't you just love
a moonwalking monkey?
Uh-uh, hold it there, Abu.
Donkey. Too small.
No. Too obvious.
We need something robust.
Relax, Abu.
It's just for a minute.
Whoa.
Prince Ali...
of Ababwah.
And now, for your entourage.
What?
What's happening?
Genie?
Clear the way!
Clear the way! Clear the way!
♪ Make way for Prince Ali! ♪
♪ Say hey! It's Prince Ali! ♪
♪ Hey! Clear the way
in the old bazaar ♪
♪ Hey you! Let us through!
It's a brand new star ♪
♪ Oh come, be the first on
your block to meet his eye! ♪
♪ Make way! Here he comes! ♪
♪ Ring bells! Bang the drums! ♪
♪ You're gonna love this guy ♪
♪ Prince Ali! Fabulous he!
Ali Ababwa ♪
♪ Show some respect,
boy, genuflect ♪
♪ Down on one knee ♪
♪ Now, try your best to stay calm ♪
♪ Brush up your Friday salaam ♪
♪ Then come and meet his
spectacular coterie ♪
♪ Prince Ali! Mighty is he!
Ali Ababwa ♪
♪ Strong as ten regular men ♪
♪ Definitely! ♪
♪ He's faced the galloping hordes ♪
♪ A hundred bad guys
with swords ♪
♪ Who sent those goons
to their lords? ♪
♪ Why, Prince Ali ♪
♪ Fellas, he's got ♪
♪ He's got
seventy-five golden camels ♪
♪ Now the ladies, what he got? ♪
♪ Purple peacocks,
he's got fifty-three ♪
♪ Uh-uh-uh, uh-uh-uh,
uh-uh-uh ♪
♪ When it comes to
exotic-type mammals ♪
♪ Everybody help me out! ♪
♪ He's got a zoo
I'm telling you ♪
♪ It's a world-class menagerie ♪
♪ Prince Ali! Handsome is he
There's no question this Ali's alluring ♪
♪ Ali Ababwa
Never ordinary, never boring ♪
♪ That physique! How can I speak?
Everything about that man ♪
♪ Weak at my knees
Just plain impresses ♪
♪ You yummy boy! ♪
♪ So, get on out in that square
He's a winner, he's a whiz, a wonder ♪
♪ Adjust your veil and prepare
He's about to pull my heart asunder ♪
♪ To gawk and grovel and stare
And I absolutely love ♪
♪ At Prince Ali, oops
The way he dresses ♪
♪ He's got ninety-five
white Persian monkeys ♪
♪ He got the monkeys,
a bunch of monkeys ♪
♪ And to view them
he charges no fee ♪
♪ He's generous, so generous ♪
♪ He's got 10,000
servants and flunkies ♪
♪ Proud to work for him! ♪
♪ They bow to his whim,
love serving him ♪
♪ They're just lousy
with loyalty to Ali! ♪
♪ Prince Ali! ♪
♪ Prince Aaaa- ♪
We waitin' for you!
♪ Aaaa ♪
We're not going 'til you go!
♪ Aa-aa ♪
♪ Aaaa ♪
You can do it!
There it is!
♪ Prince Ali! ♪
♪ Amorous he! ♪
♪ Ali Ababwa ♪
♪ Heard your princess was hot!
Where is she? ♪
♪ And that, good people, is why ♪
♪ He got all cute and dropped by ♪
♪ With sixty elephants, llamas galore
- For real? ♪
♪ With his bears and lions,
a brass band and more - What? ♪
♪ With his forty fakirs - Oh!
His cooks, his bakers - Oh! ♪
♪ His birds that warble on key
- Oh! ♪
♪ Make way ♪
♪ For Prince Ali ♪
Where are they?
Relax.
What is taking so long?
Here comes the man.
What you doing?
Put your arms down.
I'm... I'm presenting it.
It's a pleasure to
welcome you to Agrabah,
Prince Ali.
- How did you break that?
- I don't know. It fell off.
It's a pleasure to meet him.
Uh...
It's just as much... a pleasure
for me, Your Highness, Sir.
You look very serene.
That's a curtsy, not a bow.
Stand up.
I'm afraid I'm unfamiliar with...
Ababwa.
- Well, it's north.
- It's south.
Uh, we have a north
and a south.
What?
It's near, if you were to go...
it's... it's...
Around there, you can find it,
if you just look.
Don't help me.
The world is changing
quickly, Jafar.
It seems as if there is
a new country every day.
Don't touch me.
Well.
Yes!
You are very wise.
Um, tell him that we have
gifts, please.
Oh, right!
We have things! Gifts!
Did you organize this?
Bi-baba!
Yes, here we are! Gifts.
Coming right up.
We have spices. Golden camels.
And spoons, tiny spoons.
Spoons!
How do they make 'em that tiny?
We have jams!
- Jams?
- Jams.
Yes, jams!
Yam jams.
Fig jams.
Yam jams!
And date jams.
Seedless.
Delicious, e-exotic jams.
Move. Away. From the jams.
- What?
- We have jewels.
Jewels!
We have them.
And, uh, that!
Over there.
Hidden for...
suspense.
Wfoo.
Ta-da.
It's a... wheel?
It's a... very expensive.
And what do you hope to buy
with this... expensive?
You!
Wow.
No! No, no, no, no!
A moment with you.
A moment... that's not...
Pkkffw.
Are you suggesting I am for sale?
Of course.
Not! No, of course not!
No!
It's cold, and it's dark
in that lamp.
But I prefer it to this.
Please excuse me,
I... need to go and...
find some bread.
For the jams.
No, no, that's not
what I meant. I...
You did great.
That's not what I meant.
Just leave her alone.
You didn't do great.
You will... get a chance
to speak again.
We hope you can join us tonight,
Prince Ali,
when we celebrate our harvest.
Of course,
Your...
Serene Self.
We will join you.
Smooth.
In 10,000 years,
I've never been that embarrassed.
Don't worry. You are not
out of the game yet.
Just do whatever you
normally do at a party.
I've never been to a party.
What?
Oh, you gonna need to go
back to the room then.
You're not messin' up my night.
Prince Ali.
May I have a word?
Privately?
This doesn't concern your
servant.
Be over there,
minding my business.
I know who you are.
You do?
Yes.
You're a man of great
ambition, like myself.
I, uh, I don't believe we've
been properly introduced.
Jafar.
Vizier to the Sultan.
I could be a valuable ally
to help you get what you want.
I, uh, I will think on that.
I don't wanna keep
the Princess waiting.
Perhaps I'm not
making myself clear.
This offer will not be on
the table for long, you see.
Prince Ali...
Excuse me.
Prince Ali, your
presence is requested.
So I guess that's the guy.
Mm-hmm, that's the guy.
Okay, there she is.
This is your chance.
You know what?
There are a lot of people.
I don't think I can do this.
- You'll be fine.
- Okay.
This one's gonna be easy.
Ooh! Look at her handmaid.
She's gonna get some punch.
Feelin' a little thirsty myself.
No. No, no, no, no.
You can't leave me.
- They'll see right through me.
- No, they won't.
All you have to do
is walk over there.
And speak.
I also have to speak.
Okay, listen to me.
I live in a lamp.
But this is a party.
Do not mess this up for me.
Okay? I'd like to party.
Go get her!
Okay. Mm-hrm.
Princess Jasmine!
You! You're... still here.
Yas.
What you doing?
Hmm?
What are you doing?
I'm just making sure the water's...
a good temperature.
Why are you not over there?
How am I supposed to
compete with that?
Look at him. He's so princely.
You have got to be more confident
about what you have to offer.
What do I have to offer?
Knowledge of how to steal food?
How to jump between buildings?
Now, Prince Ali, he has jewels.
Stop, stop, stop.
I made you look like a prince
on the outside.
I didn't change anything
on the inside.
Prince Ali got you to the door.
But Aladdin has to open it.
Oh.
See, the sultan does like me.
Okay, well, maybe he'll
let you be his wife.
Look at that. Another prince
more interested in Baba.
I don't know. I think this
one might be different.
And he comes with an
incredibly attractive friend.
Please make it work.
And what about Prince Ali?
Oh, look at him,
he's trying so hard.
And that's the problem.
Showtime.
No, I'm waiting for
the right moment.
No, no. No waiting.
We're done waiting.
No. I'm in charge, okay?
I say when it's
the right moment.
Really? Really?
He's here. Say something.
Act natural.
Hi!
I'm sorry... for the...
The jams.
And the jewels,
and the-and the...
And the buying you.
That wasn't me.
It-It was me.
I don't, I-it was me. I don't
have a twin or anything.
But, uh, I... um...
- You're...
- Dance? I'd love to.
Yes.
Go. Go.
Something very
strange about him.
Keep a close eye on Prince Ali.
Walked out.
Maybe I went a tad far
with the backflip, but
that dance
may be the best thing
you ever do in your life.
I was pretty good.
But nothing seems
to impress her.
Yeah, it's crazy. Not
gems or jams or jewels.
If I can't impress her,
I wonder who can.
What's that supposed to mean?
I'm just sayin'
try being yourself?
But she has to marry a prince.
If I just had a few more
minutes with her, I know I could...
- You need to get me over there.
- Is that an official wish?
No. It's a favor... for a friend.
Ooh, yeah, see, genies
don't really have friends.
I thought you said you
never had a friend like me?
No. I said you...
never had a friend like me.
When you're a genie,
somebody always wants
somethin' from you.
I-It's awkward.
You're right. You're right.
Besides, it would've involved
distracting a
certain handmaiden...
Ooh! Ha! See what you're doin'.
You hooked me.
See you there?
Good evening.
How did you get past the guards?
Oh, uh, I snuck past.
All 48 of them?
Even the ones that eat fire?
Impressive.
That's why I'm, uh...
That's what people say about me.
Oh, that-that didn't come out
the right way.
No one says that.
I-I don't know why I said that.
They're beautiful.
She will hate them.
Tell Prince Ali, the way to
her heart is through her mind.
Actually, these are from me...
to you.
Could you excuse me
one moment?
Wait, just...
"That's what people
say about me."
Come on, Genie!
My favorites.
I accept. Please continue.
I was noticing how...
pleasant the evening is.
At the party, I noticed...
you noticing how...
pleasant I am.
Right. How's this going?
It's clumsy, but in a
charming sort of way.
Uh, a stroll.
Would you like to take
an evening stroll?
Just the two of us?
On purpose?
Yes. As people.
Just one more second.
Okay.
Why would I say "as people"?
The kid is contagious.
I've never done this before.
How does it work?
Do you like sheep cheese?
Come in.
Actually, I'm already in.
Don't move.
I just came back...
because you left so...
How did you get there?
Magic carpet?
Hmm.
Actually, I'm glad you are here.
You are?
I've been trying to find Ababwa,
but it doesn't seem to
be on any of my maps.
Care to show me?
I'd love to.
Oh, Rajah, let's not
eat the Prince today.
He needs his legs for dancing.
Did I go too far
with the backflip?
A little.
Ababwah?
Yes.
Genie, I need to find Ababwah.
The other brother, the short one.
Not the one who
gifted me a goat.
She has lots of maps.
Ababwah, of course.
Ababwah.
Yak napkins are not easy to find.
Have you lost your country?
My country? No. No.
There it is.
I don't think so.
I've been...
There it is!
How did I not see that?
Who needs maps anyway?
They're old and useless.
And have no practical value.
Maps are how I see the world.
I thought a princess
could go anywhere?
Not this princess.
Uh, well, uh, would you...?
Would you wanna...?
Sorry.
Rajah.
Thanks...
for that.
I-I was saying...
You should see these places.
I mean, there's a whole world
outside of books and maps.
Do you want to?
How? The door's guarded.
Who said anything about a door?
What are you doing?
Sometimes Princess...
Sometimes,
you just have to take a risk.
What just happened?
What?
Is this...?
A magic carpet.
Do you trust me?
What did you say?
Yes.
♪ I can show you the world ♪
♪ Shining, shimmering, splendid ♪
♪ Tell me, princess ♪
♪ Now when did you last
let your heart decide? ♪
♪ I can open your eyes ♪
♪ Take you wonder by wonder ♪
♪ Over, sideways and under ♪
♪ On a magic carpet ride ♪
♪ A whole new world ♪
♪ A new fantastic point of view ♪
♪ No one to tell us, "No" ♪
♪ Or where to go ♪
♪ Or say we're only dreaming ♪
♪ A whole new world ♪
♪ A dazzling place I never knew ♪
♪ But when I'm way up here ♪
♪ It's crystal clear ♪
♪ That now I'm in a whole
new world with you ♪
♪ Now I'm in a whole
♪ Unbelievable sights ♪
♪ Indescribable feeling ♪
♪ Soaring, tumbling, freewheeling ♪
♪ Through an endless diamond sky ♪
♪ A whole new world
Don't you dare close your eyes ♪
♪ A hundred thousand things to see
Hold your breath, it gets better ♪
♪ I'm like a shooting star ♪
♪ I've come so far ♪
♪ I can't go back to
where I used to be ♪
♪ A whole new world
Every turn, a surprise ♪
♪ With new horizons to pursue
Every moment, red-letter ♪
♪ I'll chase them anywhere ♪
♪ There's time to spare ♪
♪ Let me share this
whole new world with you ♪
♪ A whole new world
A whole new world ♪
♪ That's where we'll be
That's where we'll be ♪
♪ A thrilling chase
A wondrous place ♪
♪ For you and me ♪
Of all the places
you've shown me,
this is by far,
the most beautiful.
Sometimes you just have to see
it from a different perspective.
It's them, the people.
They make it beautiful.
And they deserve a
leader who knows that.
I don't know why I
think it could be me.
Because it should be you.
You think so?
Does it matter, what I think?
Oh, look at that adorable
monkey down there. Is that Abu?
No, no, it couldn't be Abu, he's...
So, how many names
do you have,
Prince Aladdin?
No, no, I...
So, who's Prince Ali?
I am... Prince Ali.
But how would you
know the city so well?
I came to Agrabah early.
Because to know a people,
you have to see them for yourself.
But you already know that.
When we first met, you were
disguised in your own city.
You saw us arrive
with dancers, an elephant,
and a magic carpet.
How could a street thief
have all that?
But how could I not
recognize you?
People don't see the real you
when you're royalty.
I'm sorry.
I'm embarrassed.
I mean, you've seen
more of Agrabah in days
than I have in an
entire lifetime.
We should...
probably head back.
Already?
Until tomorrow, Princess.
Good night.
Yes.
Woo-hoo!
Fascinating.
Ooh!
I like that face.
- Good date?
- The best.
But it was better than the best.
She figured out I was Aladdin.
You said that wouldn't happen.
Wow.
I mean, genie magic is
really just a facade.
At some point,
the real character's always
gonna shine through.
But that's a good thing, right?
Now, she knows.
- Well...
- Well, what?
He told me he was only pretending
to be a thief to see the city.
But he's actually a prince.
I convinced her that
I really was a prince.
And you believed him?
And she believed you?
I think so.
Eventually, you are going
to have to tell her the truth.
Eventually, I will tell her.
Anyway,
I sort of am a prince now.
Oh.
So you're gonna drink
from that cup.
You don't think maybe
you want to believe him
because you have to
marry a prince
but you can't marry a thief?
No.
I believe him.
I do.
When the time is right,
I will tell her.
Morning?
Morning.
Not again.
Please, please, I...
Gentlemen.
I-I think there's been
some sort of confusion.
I don't think
you know who I am.
Oh, no, no.
I know who you are.
Aladdin.
Aladdin?
I don't know who that is.
I-I'm Prince Ali...
Street rat.
Of-Of Ababwah.
A prince from a kingdom
that doesn't exist.
Who now possesses
a magic carpet
from the Cave of Wonders.
Seems to me,
the only way that's possible,
Where's your monkey?
Is if you found a certain treasure.
My treasure.
Where's the lamp?
This clearly, is some sort
of misunderstanding.
I'm Prince Ali.
If I throw you off
of that balcony,
and you are who
you say you are,
you will die a watery death.
If you survive,
it can only be
because of the lamp.
In which case,
I will have my answer.
For the last time...
Where is the lamp?
Listen to me.
I don't know who you think I am.
- Goodbye, Aladdin.
- No!
Hmm.
What in the...?
Oh! Hey, kid! Okay.
I can't get you out of this
unless you make a wish.
You have to make a wish!
Come on, wake up!
Okay, try and form the words.
"I wish."
Kid, come on, wake up!
Wake up.
You need to think.
Think, think.
Think.
Okay. Okay.
A little gray area here,
but it's worth a try.
I, Aladdin, being of
sound body and mind,
declare that my second wish
is to be saved from
certain doom.
I took the liberty to
backdate that a day.
I hope you don't mind.
Yes! Here we go!
Come on!
Come on, kid! Kid!
Kid, please. Come on.
Wake up.
Wake up, wake up. Kid!
Wake up, please.
Ew.
Probably coulda done that
the other direction though.
How you doin'?
Thanks, Genie.
Hey, no problem, uh,
I was in the neighborhood.
I thought you said no favors?
I wa-I wa...
I thought you said no friends?
Right, uh...
It actually cost you a wish.
Whatever it cost.
You saved my life.
Yeah, that's true.
I mean, strictly speaking though,
it was a team effort.
Thank you.
We have to stop Jafar.
That's not gonna be easy.
The Sultan trusts him completely.
He has everybody fooled.
Maybe not everyone.
I overheard Prince Ali
talking to his advisor
about returning with an
army to conquer Agrabah.
What?
Now it appears
he's fled in the night.
Jasmine.
You heard him say this, Jafar?
And you saw him leave?
Uh-oh.
Yes.
With my own ears
and my own eyes.
So, what's the problem now,
Princess?
This is the problem, Jafar.
If what you say is true,
why is Prince Ali still here?
Your Majesty.
Prince Ali.
This is a surprise.
Your Highness, your advisor's
not who he says he is.
Oh.
I'm not who I say I am.
Baba,
he tried to kill Prince Ali.
Jafar, can you explain this to me?
Yes.
My Sultan...
You know my loyalty
belongs to you.
Your loyalty.
Yes.
Prince Ali, you invited
yourself into our city.
And we welcomed you
as our guest.
But I believe your intentions are...
deceitful.
You are a grave
danger to Agrabah,
and you shall be
dealt with as such.
Baba, what are you saying?
Enough, Jasmine!
Jafar told me
of Prince Ali's ambition.
The staff.
He's here for my throne.
Hakim!
Baba?
What happened?
He had you under a spell.
He's not to be trusted.
Your Majesty.
He wants your throne.
Jafar, you were my
most trusted advisor!
Hakim!
Put him in the dungeon!
You should think
about how quickly
the sands of power shift
in the storm, Hakim.
I am loyal to my sultan.
As you should have been.
The law is the law.
Prince Ali,
I must apologize.
Well, Your Highness,
there's something I...
I'd like to explain.
Your honor and integrity
will never again be
questioned here in Agrabah.
- I...
- A more noble
and sincere young man
has never graced
the chambers of this palace.
- Well, uh...
- Wow.
I would be honored
- to call you my son.
- Oooh.
If that...
were something anyone wanted.
So you got the girl.
I mean, trust me, I had
my doubts after your whole
jam debacle.
But y-you pulled yourself
back together a little bit.
I did, didn't I?
I think I finally got the
hang of being a prince.
Oh, well, that-that's
not exactly what I meant.
But you were right.
People see what they wanna see.
Aladdin is gone.
I'm Prince Ali now.
Wow.
Got it all figured out now,
huh, kid?
And you know, I was thinking
about my last wish,
and I just...
I can't do this without you.
I know I told you
I'd use it to set you free,
but you heard the sultan.
I can't let everything that
we've worked for fall apart.
So...
You just never
tell her the truth?
You're gonna keep
living the lie?
It's not a lie.
People can change.
Heh, oh, they can change, all right.
And? That's a bad thing?
Everything's better now.
No one got hurt.
You'd rather me
be back on the streets
stealing to survive? I...
thought you'd be happy for me.
But all you cared about was that
I use my last wish
to set you free.
Wow. Kid,
I don't care
nothin' about that wish.
This is about you.
What's happening to you.
You'd rather lie
to somebody you love
than give all of this up.
You don't get it, Genie.
People like me
don't get anything
except by pretending.
I think, maybe,
you don't get it.
The more you gain
by pretending,
the less you're
actually gonna have.
10,000 years,
I have never once, ever...
called a master a friend.
I broke the rules for you.
I saved your life...
and for what?
You are breaking
my heart here, kid.
You're breaking my heart.
Genie, no. Hey, come on!
Master.
Who does he think he is?
He's supposed to serve me.
I'm the same as I always was
on the inside, right, Abu?
Hey!
Aah! Are you kidding?
Now, why would you rub
the thing under the...?
Archway.
Riffraff.
Street rat.
♪ Would they ♪
♪ Think that ♪
♪ If they look ♪
♪ Much closer? ♪
♪ Still, I can't play a prince here ♪
♪ No, siree ♪
♪ Gotta tell the truth ♪
♪ I can't pretend ♪
♪ Even if it means ♪
♪ This dream will end ♪
♪ Even if ♪
♪ She walks away ♪
♪ From me ♪
Jafar.
You should have left Agrabah
while you had the chance.
Why leave when the city
belongs to me now?
It's over, Jafar.
Over for you.
I've endured your spineless
incompetence for long enough.
Hakim.
Own throne.
Genie!
For my first wish,
I wish to be Sultan of Agrabah.
What?
As you wish, master.
No.
Hakim!
You obey the sultan.
So you obey me now.
You know the law, Hakim.
No.
My Sultan!
- My Sultan!
Hakim.
Marshal an army
to invade Sherabad.
- Sherabad?
- You cannot...
I think we've heard
enough from you, Princess.
It's time you start doing what
you should've done all along.
Stay silent.
Guards!
Remove her!
Control that cat if you
know what's good for you.
Rajah.
It's all right.
- Don't touch her!
- Baba.
Jasmine.
♪ Written in stone
Every rule, every word ♪
♪ Centuries old and unbending ♪
♪ Stay in your place
Better seen and not heard ♪
♪ Well, now that story is ending ♪
♪ 'Cause I ♪
♪ I cannot start to crumble ♪
♪ So come on and try ♪
♪ Try to shut me
and cut me down ♪
♪ I won't be silenced ♪
♪ You can't keep me quiet ♪
♪ Won't tremble when you try it ♪
♪ All I know is I won't go speechless ♪
♪ Speechless ♪
♪ Let the storm in ♪
♪ I cannot be broken ♪
♪ No, I won't live unspoken ♪
♪ 'Cause I won't go speechless ♪
♪ Try to lock me in this cage ♪
♪ I won't just lay me down and die ♪
♪ I will take these broken wings ♪
♪ And watch me burn across the sky ♪
♪ And it echoes saying ♪
♪ I won't be silenced ♪
♪ Though you wanna see me
tremble when you try it ♪
♪ All I know is I won't
go speechless ♪
♪ Speechless ♪
♪ 'Cause I'll breathe ♪
♪ When they try to suffocate me ♪
♪ Don't you underestimate me ♪
♪ Cause I know that I won't
go speechless ♪
♪ All I know is I won't
♪ Speechless! ♪
Hakim!
Take her away!
Tell them, Hakim.
You were just a boy
when your father came
to work the grounds.
But you have risen up
to become our
most trusted soldier.
As a man, I know you to be
both loyal and just.
But now, you have to choose.
Duty isn't always honor.
Our greatest challenge
isn't speaking up
against our enemies,
but defying those whose
approval we seek the most.
Jafar is not worthy
of your admiration
nor your sacrifice.
I wish nothing but glory
for the Kingdom of Agrabah.
No.
You seek glory for yourself.
And you would win it
off the backs of my people!
Hakim.
These men,
they will follow where you lead,
but it's up to you.
Will you stand silent
while Jafar destroys
our beloved kingdom?
Or will you do what is right...
And stand with the
people of Agrabah?
My Princess.
Forgive me.
My Sultan.
Hakim.
Guards! Arrest the Vizier.
Rub the lamp.
So this is how it will be.
Not even the title of sultan
would wake the herd
from their sleep.
I should have known.
If you won't bow
before a sultan,
you will cower
before a sorcerer.
Genie!
I wish to become the most
powerful sorcerer there is.
As you wish, master.
This could be fun.
Hakim.
I had such big plans for you.
But now...
you are no longer
of any use to me.
Perhaps your men would like
to follow you to the dungeon.
You too.
Prince Ali!
If it isn't our Prince Ali...
Ali!
Or should I say...
Aladdin.
He's been pretending
the entire time.
An impostor.
There is no Prince Ali.
There never was.
He's nothing but a lying thief.
I'm sorry.
You're insignificant.
An irritation I no longer
need to tolerate once I...
ensure your agonizing death by
banishing you to the
ends of the earth.
No!
No.
Abu!
I could simply kill you all.
But that would be inadequate
repayment for years of
humiliation and neglect.
"Remember your place, Jafar."
"You forget yourself, Jafar."
- Jafar.
- No.
What you need,
Baba,
is to suffer.
Like I have suffered.
Baba?
Watching me rule your
kingdom be enough?
Stop!
But watching my armies devour
your toothless allies...
Please, make it stop!
No, the most suitable punishment
would be to make you watch
- while I take what you love most.
- No!
- Baba!
- And marry your daughter.
No!
She will never marry you.
I will do as you wish!
Make it stop!
Make it stop.
Abu!
You okay?
Let's get outta here.
No.
Your Highness, Sultan.
In honesty and sincerity,
- do you accept Princess Jasmine...
- Yes.
Yes, I accept.
Princess.
Princess Jasmine, do you accept
the Sultan to be your husband?
Come on, woman!
Accept.
I...
Yes?
Do not!
- The lamp, the lamp!
- Ah! Stop her!
No, Jasmine!
No!
No! No!
The lamp! Iago!
- Are you okay?
- Yes!
Hold on!
The lamp!
Abu!
Carpet, get me up there!
Jump!
You are nothing
without your staff!
Nothing!
Carpet!
Jasmine.
Punish them. Punish them.
Genie should witness.
As the old man said,
"You should have left Agrabah
when you had the chance."
I told you before to think bigger.
You could have been the most
powerful man in the room.
But now, I hold the lamp.
I hold the power.
You can't find what you're
looking for in that lamp, Jafar.
I tried and failed,
and so will you.
You think so?
But I am Sultan!
I am the greatest sorcerer
the world has ever seen.
I will create an empire
that history cannot ignore.
I... can destroy cities.
I can destroy kingdoms!
And I can destroy you.
True.
But who made you a sultan?
Who made you a sorcerer?
There will always be some thing,
some man, some being
- more powerful than you.
- What are you doing?
Genie gave you your power,
and he can take it away.
- He serves me!
- For now.
But you'll never have
more power than the genie.
You said it yourself...
You're either the most
powerful in the room
or you're nothing.
You will always
be second.
Second.
Second!
Second?!
Only second?
He serves me!
I will make sure no one will
ever say these words again!
Genie!
For my final wish,
I wish to become
the most powerful
being in the universe!
More powerful than you!
A lotta gray area in that wish,
but, uh...
The most powerful being
in the universe!
Coming right up!
The most powerful in the universe!
At last!
Second to no one!
And I thought
I had power before!
First...
I'll lay waste to those
fools in Sherabad.
What have you done to me?
I haven't done
anything to you, Jafar.
What have you done to me?!
This was your wish, not mine.
A genie might have
phenomenal cosmic powers...
But an itty-bitty living space.
You see, a genie
without a master,
goes back in their lamp.
I will not forget you, boy!
Mark my words.
I will not forget what
you have done to me.
Goodbye, Jafar.
Parrot! You're coming with me!
No!
Baba!
- Baba.
- Come on.
A couple thousand years
in the Cave of Wonders
ought to cool you off.
Wait... wait.
How can I ever thank you?
Oh, no, no.
You don't need to thank me.
But I hope you
accept my apology.
I'm sorry...
to the both of you.
Especially you.
You deserve...
so much.
We all make mistakes.
Aladdin.
I hope you find
what you're looking for.
Ooh, that's a bit of a mess
there, Abu.
Let me take care
of that for you.
Cute.
Ah-ah-ah. No.
No long faces, all right?
I got an idea, all right?
It's your last wish.
Royalty was the
right idea, okay?
We should just
rip on that a little bit.
All right,
here's what I'm thinkin'.
Aladdin, warrior prince!
A noble heart in a land
where thieves run feral.
Jasmine!
You like it?
No? Okay, all right.
I hear you loud and clear.
But this is what you need.
The governing laws of
Agrabah by royal decree.
Okay, and... here it is!
"Must marry a prince."
Right. But, you say the words...
and this law just kinda like,
goes away.
You and the princess
are in it together forever.
You can just
make the law disappear?
Psshh. Please.
Like it never existed.
All right. Last wish.
Let's get it.
Okay.
Last wish.
Genie.
I'm ready. Hold on.
Here we go.
I wish...
Third and final wish.
To set you free.
What?
Whoa.
Oh!
Wait.
Am I...
Wait, wait, um...
Tell-Tell me to do somethin'.
Um... give me some jams.
Get it yourself?
Get your own jams!
Thank you.
No.
Thank you, Genie.
I owe you everything.
What are you gonna do now?
Um...
Actually, there is this...
handmaiden
that I would love
to travel the world with.
If she'll have me.
When do we leave?
Also, I want children.
Yes! Two of them.
Lian and Omar,
three years apart.
They will worship us both
and ask lots of questions.
And you will entertain them
with stories and songs.
- We'll have a boat.
- A large one
with multiple levels
and magnificent sails.
I was thinking more of a-
a smaller one.
- Perfect.
Sit with me, my child.
I'm sorry.
- Baba, why are you...?
- Please, let me finish.
I feared losing you.
Like I lost your mother.
All I saw was my little girl.
Not the woman you have become.
You have shown me
courage
and strength.
You...
are the future of Agrabah.
shall be the next sultan.
Thank you, Baba.
As sultan,
you may change the law.
He is a good man.
Where'd he go?
Stop, thief.
Your sultan commands it.
Sultan?
Does that mean I'm in trouble?
Only because you got caught.
♪ Can your friends do this? ♪
♪ You ain't never had
a friend like me ♪
Subs by enwansix