Subtitles by sub.Trader
subscene.com
Blake.
Blake!
Sorry, Sarge.
Pick a man, bring your kit.
Yes, Sarge.
- Don't dawdle.
- No, Sarge.
Did they feed us?
No, just mail.
Myrtle's having puppies.
You get anything?
No.
I'm bloody starving, aren't you?
I thought we might get
some decent grub out here.
It was the only reason
I decided against the priesthood.
- What you got there?
- Ham and bread.
Where did you find that?
I have my uses.
Here.
Tastes like old shoe.
Cheer up. This time next week
it'll be chicken dinner.
Not me. My leave got cancelled.
They say why?
No idea.
It's easier not to go back at all.
Something's up.
Did you hear anything?
No.
Has to be the push, right?
Ten-bob says we're going up.
I'm not taking that bet.
Why? 'Cos you know I'm right?
No. Because you haven't got ten-bob.
In your own time, gentlemen.
- Is there any news, Sarge?
- News of what?
The big push.
It was supposed to happen weeks ago.
They told us we'd be home by Christmas.
Yes, well, sorry to disrupt
your crowded schedule, Blake,
but the Brass Hats
didn't fancy it in the snow.
More's the pity, Sarge,
I could've done with some turkey.
Well, I'll make sure to relay
your displeasure to command.
So, what's on the cards then, Sergeant?
The Hun are up to something.
- Any idea what?
- No.
But it's bound to ruin
our weekend.
Now listen, Erinmore is inside,
so tidy yourselves up.
Never know -
might be mentions
in dispatches for this one,
if you don't bugger it up.
Must be something big
if the General's here.
Lance Corporals
Blake and Schofield, Sir.
- Which one of you is Blake?
- Sir.
You have a brother,
a Lieutenant in the 2nd Devons?
Yes, sir.
Joseph Blake, is he...?
Alive, as far as I know.
And with your help
I'd like to keep it that way.
Sanders tells me you're good
with maps, is that true?
Good enough, Sir.
So.
We are here.
The 2nd Devons are advancing here.
How long will it take you
to get there?
I don't understand, Sir.
Sir, that land is held
by the Germans.
Germans have gone.
Don't get your hopes up.
It appears to be a strategic withdrawal.
They seem to have created a new line,
nine miles back here, by the looks of it.
Colonel MacKenzie is in command
of the 2nd.
He sent word yesterday morning
he was going after the retreating Germans.
He is convinced
he has them on the run -
that if he can break their lines now,
he will turn the tide.
He is wrong.
Colonel MacKenzie has not seen
these aerials of the enemy's new line.
Come round here, Gentlemen.
Three miles deep, field fortifications,
defences, artillery,
the like of which we've
never seen before.
The 2nd are due to attack the line
shortly after dawn tomorrow.
They have no idea
what they are in for.
And we can't warn them -
as a parting gift,
the enemy cut
all our telegram lines.
Your orders are to get to the 2nd
at Croisilles Wood, one mile
south-east of the town of Ecoust.
Deliver this to Colonel MacKenzie.
It is a direct order to call off
tomorrow morning's attack.
If you don't,
it will be a massacre.
We would lose two battalions.
1600 men, your brother among them.
You think you can get there in time?
- Yes, Sir.
- Any questions?
- No, Sir.
- Good.
Over to you, Lieutenant.
Supplies, Gentlemen.
Map, torches, grenades,
and a couple of little treats.
Leave immediately, take this trench west,
up on Sauchiehall Street,
then north-west
on Paradise Alley at the front.
Continue along the front line
until you find the Yorks.
Give this note to Major Stevenson.
He's holding the line
at the shortest span
of No Man's Land.
You'll cross there.
It will be daylight, Sir.
They'll see us.
There's no need to be concerned.
You should meet no resistance.
Sir, is it just us?
"Down to Gehenna or up to the Throne,
He travels the fastest who travels alone."
- Wouldn't you say, Lieutenant?
- Yes, Sir. I would.
Good luck.
Blake - let's talk about this
for a minute.
Why?
Blake!
We just need to think about it.
There's nothing to think about.
He's my big brother.
We should at least wait
until it's dark.
Erinmore said to leave immediately.
Erinmore's never seen
No Man's Land.
We won't make it 10 yards.
If we just wait.
You heard him.
He said the Boche have gone.
Is that why he gave us grenades?
- Watch where you're going!
- Sorry.
All I'm saying is that we wait.
Yes, you would say that,
because he's not your brother, is it?
Look, the last time I was told
the Germans were gone, it didn't end well.
You don't know, Blake,
you weren't there.
Excuse me. Excuse me!
You're going up a down trench
you bloody idiots.
Orders of the General, Sir.
Alright, say the Boche have gone.
Nine miles will take us, what, six hours?
Eight at the very most.
So, we've got time
to wait until the sun sets...
It's enemy territory, we've got
no idea what we're walking into.
Blake, if we're not clever about this,
no one will get to your brother.
I will.
We're here.
This is the front line.
Now we need to find the Yorks.
- Watch who you're shoving.
- Get out of the way then.
Who the fuck do you think you are,
pushing wounded soldiers around?
Let go of me!
Arsehole knocked down our Sergeant,
the man's fucking wounded!
I'm sorry, alright, I'm sorry.
- We're on commission.
- Just let me through.
- Orders from the General.
Get out of the way.
Right. Just watch
where you're going.
It's bloody quiet.
Was it like this before Thiepval?
I don't remember.
You don't remember the Somme?
Not really.
Well, you did alright out of it.
At least wear your ribbon.
Don't have it anymore.
What? You lost your medal?
It's down, boys.
Stay low.
God's sake, careful there,
you're stepping on the dead.
That's our Sergeant.
Be better washing them out of this
dugout with a bloody hose.
Do you know where the Yorks are?
The next bend you'll be standing
on top of half of them.
Shot to hell two nights ago.
Yorks?
Yes, Corp.
Where's Major Stevenson?
Was killed a couple of nights ago,
Corporal.
Lieutenant Leslie has command.
Where can we find him?
Next dug-out.
Here.
Sir? Lieutenant Leslie, Sir?
What is it?
We have a message
from General Erinmore.
- Are you our relief?
- No, Sir.
Then, when the fucking hell
are they due?
We don't know, Sir.
But we've got orders to cross here.
- That is the German front line.
- We know, Sir.
If you'll just take the letter.
Settle a bet, what day is it?
Friday.
Friday? Well, well, well.
None of us was right.
This idiot thought it was Tuesday.
Sorry, Sir.
Are they out of their fucking minds?
One slow night, and the brass think
the Hun have just gone home.
Do you think they're wrong, Sir?
We lost an officer
and three men two nights ago.
They were shot to bits
patching up wire.
We dragged two of them back here.
Needn't have bothered.
Sir, the General is sure
the enemy have withdrawn.
There are aerials
of the new line...
Shut up. We've fought and died
over every inch of this fucking place,
now they suddenly give us miles?
It's a trap.
But, chin up.
There's a medal in it for sure.
Nothing like a scrap of ribbon
to cheer up a widow.
Alright.
Where's the nearest
way through, Sir?
Our wire's a mess.
But there is a path through, of sorts.
Rushworth! Let him look.
Straight ahead, to the left,
past the dead horses.
There's a gap directly behind them.
Useful, because if it's dark
you follow the stench.
When you get to the second wire,
look out for the bowing chap.
There's small break
just beside him.
The German line
is a 150 odd yards after that.
Watch out for the craters.
They're deeper than they look.
You fall in, there's no getting out.
This way.
Wake up, Kilgour.
Bloody waste of space.
Any cover, Sir?
Anywhere to jump off from?
No, the sap trench
was blown to hell weeks ago.
It's full of bodies anyway.
Your best bet is to pop over here.
If you do get shot,
try to make it back to the wire.
We won't come after you,
not until it's dark.
And, if by some fucking miracle
you do make it, send up a flare.
Don't have any, Sir.
Well, get him one, Kilgour!
Make yourself useful.
Yes, Sir.
"Through this holy unction
may the Lord pardon thee
all faults or whatever sins
thou hast committed."
I do hate losing these to the Hun.
So, when they start shooting at you,
could you be so kind as to
throw it back, there's a good chap.
Cheerio.
You sure?
Yes.
Age before beauty.
You alright?
Look for cover.
Sap trench.
Alright.
Stay still.
They're ours.
Keep going. We're half-way.
There's a gap in the wire.
Sco...
There! That's the front line.
Fuck me. They really have gone.
Your hand alright?
Put it through an effing German.
Patch it up.
You'll be wanking again
in no time.
Wrong hand.
They're not long gone.
No good.
Blocked.
This might be a way through.
Jesus...
Look at this. It's massive.
They built all this.
Here's our way through.
Sco.
How about this?
Bloody hell!
Even their rats
are bigger than ours.
What do you think
is in the bags?
You cannot be that hungry.
Look at him. Cocky little bastard.
You could eat this, though.
- What is it?
- Boche dog meat.
What's in the other boxes?
What's wrong?
Trip wire. Don't move.
Where is it?
Goes from here to the door.
Jesus!
No! No!
Sco?!
Sco!
Sco! Wake up! Wake up!
Sco! Sco!
Stand up! Stand up!
Come on! Stand up!
Up! Up! Up!
The whole thing's coming down.
Come on.
You keep hold of me!
We need to keep moving. Come on!
I can't see. I can't see!
Stop! Stop!
Stop. It's a mineshaft.
We will have to jump. Come on!
You're going to have to jump!
Just jump.
I can't... I can't see!
You need to trust me. Jump!
Don't let go of me!
Don't let go!
Light! There's light!
Stop. Stop.
Just let me stand.
Dirty bastards!
Careful, they may have left
other traps.
Jesus.
Dust. So much dust in my eyes.
Here. Have some of mine.
I wish I'd shot that rat now.
And I wish you'd picked
some other bloody idiot.
What?
Why in God's name
did you have to choose me?
I didn't know
what I was picking you for.
No, you didn't.
You never know.
That's your problem.
Alright then, go back.
Nothing's stopping you.
You can go all the way
bloody home if you want.
Don't. Just don't.
I didn't know
what I was picking you for.
I thought they were going to send us back
up the line, or for food, or something.
I thought it was going to be
something easy, alright?
I never thought it would be this.
So, do you want to go back?
Just fire the fucking flare.
Up yours, Lieutenant.
Do you know where we are?
Ecoust is directly south-east.
And if we keep that bearing,
we should make it.
Come on then.
Look at that.
They destroyed their own guns.
They destroyed
their own trenches too.
What do you mean?
I think they wanted us to go that way.
They wanted to bury us.
Bastard rats.
Hey, did you hear that story
about Wilko?
How he lost his ear?
I'm not in the mood.
Keep your eyes on the trees,
top of the ridge.
Bet he told you it was shrapnel.
What was it then?
Well, you know his girl's
a hairdresser, right?
And he was moaning about the lack of
bathing facilities when he wrote to her -
remember those rancid
Jakes at Arras?
Anyway, she sends him over
this 'hair oil'.
Smells sweet, like Golden Syrup.
Wilko loves the smell,
but he doesn't want to
cart it around in his pack, so
he slathers it all over his barnet,
goes to sleep,
and in the middle of the night
he wakes up,
and a rat is sitting on his shoulder
licking the oil off of his head.
Wilko panics, and he jumps up,
and when he does -
the rat bites clean through
his fucking ear and runs off with it!
Oh, he made a hell of a fuss,
yelling, screaming.
The best of it was he could put
so much bloody oil on himself
that he couldn't wash it off!
He was like a magnet.
Rats left us alone,
but they couldn't get enough of him.
Poor bastard.
Heading back home.
I wonder what they saw.
Watch the ridge lines.
Well, that's your medal
sorted then.
What do you mean?
"Lance Corporal Blake showed
unusual valour in rescuing
a comrade from certain death"
blah, blah, blah.
You reckon?
I do.
Well, that'd be nice.
Since you lost yours.
I didn't lose mine.
- What happened to it, then?
- Why do you care?
Why do you not?
I swapped it with a French captain.
You swapped it? For what?
Bottle of wine.
- What did you do that for?
- I was thirsty.
What a waste.
You should've taken it home
with you, you should've
given it to your family.
Men have died for that.
If I got a medal, I'd take it back home,
why didn't you just take it home...
Look it's just a bit of bloody tin!
It doesn't make you special,
it doesn't make any difference to anyone.
Yes, it does.
And it's not just a bit of tin.
It's got a ribbon on it.
I hated going home. I hated it.
When I knew I couldn't stay.
When I knew I had to leave,
and they might never see me.
Jesus.
They chopped them all down.
Cherries.
Lamberts.
They might be Dukes,
hard to tell when they aren't in fruit.
What's the difference?
People think there's one type,
but there's lots of them -
Cuthberts, Queen Annes, Montmorencys.
Sweet ones, sour ones...
Why on earth
would you know this?
Mum's got an orchard, back home.
Only a few trees.
This time of year it looks like
it's been snowing, blossom everywhere.
And then in May, we have to pick them.
Me and Joe.
Takes the whole day.
So, these ones all gonners?
Oh no, they'll grow again
when the stones rot.
You'll end up with more
trees than before.
- It looks abandoned.
- Let's hope so.
We have to make sure.
I'll take front, you take back.
Anything?
Nothing.
Did you find any food?
No. I don't like this place.
Map says we get over that ridge
and it's a straight shot to Ecoust.
Good.
Is that our friends again?
Looks like it. Dogfight.
Who's winning?
Us, I think. Two on one.
They got him.
We should put him out
of his misery.
No. Get him some water.
He needs water.
It's alright, you're alright.
Stay still. Stay still.
Stop! Stop!
No, no, no!
Bastard, bloody bastard.
Oh, God no. Oh, God no!
Jesus. Jesus, no.
We have to stop the bleeding.
Stop it. Stop it!
It's alright, it's going to be alright.
We're going to stand up.
Yes. Yes.
No! I can't. I can't.
- We have to get to an Aid Post.
- I can't.
- I'll carry you. It isn't very far.
- Just bring a doctor here.
We can't, we have to go together.
We're going to get up.
Stop, please! Stop!
Put me down! Put me down,
you bastard, please! Put me down!
- You have to try to keep moving.
- Let's just sit.
- Let me sit.
- No, we can't.
We have to find
the 2nd, remember?
Your brother.
We have to go now.
You can start on without me.
I'll catch up.
You can't stay here.
We have to move, alright?
We have to move. Come on.
Come on!
Come on. That's it.
Come on, come on.
Your brother.
We have to find your brother.
You'll recognise him.
He looks like me, he's a bit older.
What are they?
Are we being shelled?
They're embers.
The barn is on fire.
I've been hit.
What was it?
You were stabbed.
Am I dying?
Yes.
Yes. I think you are.
- This?
- Inside.
Will you write
to my mum for me?
I will.
Tell her I wasn't scared.
Anything else?
I love them.
I wish that...
I wish...
Talk to me.
Tell me you know the way.
I know the way.
I'm going to head south-east
until I hit Ecoust.
I'll pass through the town
and out to the east,
all the way to Croisilles Wood.
It'll be dark by then.
That won't bother me.
I'll find the 2nd,
I'll give them the message.
And then I'll find your brother.
Just like you, a little older.
You alright, mate?
It's alright, it's okay.
Come on, help him.
Jesus, what happened to him?
Was it the plane?
We saw the smoke.
Yeah.
Go fetch his things.
- Sir.
A friend?
What are you doing here?
I have an urgent message
for the 2nd Devons.
Orders to stop
tomorrow morning's attack.
- And where are they stationed?
- Just beyond Ecoust.
Come with me.
Come with me, Corporal.
That's an order.
We're passing through Ecoust.
We can take you some of the way.
Sir.
Oh, come on Sergeant.
Put more men at the base.
At the trunk!
It'll be heavier there.
Might be a tight squeeze.
You're not going to be able
to just lift it.
Pivot the front end to the left.
Jesus, they don't make
things easy, do they.
They could at least have retreated
with a bit of grace. Bastards.
Sir.
- You're not one of mine.
- No, Sir.
He has an urgent message
to deliver to the 2nd Devons, Sir.
- Can you get past it?
- No, Sir.
Oh, for God's sake.
Just move it!
There's room
in the casuals truck, sir.
- He has orders.
- Yes, yes, alright.
Come on now.
You can get through there sideways.
How did you get here, Sir?
Crossed No Man's Land
just outside Bapaume.
Took us the whole night.
Bumped into a couple of Hun stragglers on
the way who made a nuisance of themselves.
- You going up to the new line?
- Attempting to.
The Newfoundlands have pushed forwards
and requested reinforcements.
I'm sorry about your friend.
May I tell you something
that you probably already know?
It doesn't do to dwell on it.
No, Sir.
Hop on.
Make some space there.
Come on, in you get!
Alright. Here we go again boys.
Welcome aboard the night bus
to a fuck-knows-where.
Is that a dead dog?
- You got a fag?
- Yeah, there you go.
- Butler.
- Oy.
- Carry on with that story.
- Oh yeah, right.
So, when we get off the train,
Beaufoy comes up to us,
and he's having a right go:
"Lance Corporal! Whatever one does,
one never lets standards slip!"
Then, Scott comes out of the latrine,
he wipes his hand
on the back of Beaufoy's jacket!
Shit all down his back.
Was that meant to be Captain Beaufoy?
Oh, piss off you.
You can't do any better.
“Men! Your rifle stocks are an embarrassment
to the entire expeditionary force.”
You're both bloody awful.
You don't know, you barely
even speak the bloody language.
He's got a better grasp of it
than you, Cooke.
Go on then Jondalar,
give it a go, let's see it!
Let's hear it then Jonny!
"Rossi! Never in my 200 years
as a soldier have I seen
such a sorry excuse
for a latrine pit."
Shite. That is total shit.
Oy! You could've taken
my teeth out with that.
You could do with a new set.
You got somewhere you need to be?
Arsehole needs driving lessons.
- He should reverse.
- Yeah.
Try it in reverse. Reverse!
No. Stop. Stop!
Everyone needs to get out.
All out! Come on!
Alright, alright.
Keep your bloody hair on.
Right. One. Two. Three.
We need to get some wood,
put it under the wheels.
No! We haven't got the time!
We all need to push. Come on.
Come on!
Come oooon!
Please. I have to go now. Please.
- Alright, come on lads. Come on!
- Come on, boys.
One. Two. Three!
Come on boys! One last push! Yes!
Back in. Get back in. Go.
Are you alright?
Here, Driver, how about you try
to keep it on the bloody road for a change!
Oh, piss off.
So, where are you going?
I have to get to the 2nd Devons.
Just past Ecoust.
Why?
They're attacking at dawn.
I have orders to stop them.
How come?
They're walking into a trap.
How many?
1600.
Jesus.
Why did they send you
on your own?
They didn't. There were two of us.
So, now it's down to you.
Yes.
You'll never make it.
Yes. I will.
Thank you.
Look at it. Fucking look at it.
Three years fighting over this.
We should have just let
the bastards keep it.
I mean, who machine guns, cows?
- Huns with extra bullets.
- Bastards.
Clever. They know if they don't shoot
the cow, you will eat it.
Still, bastards.
Yeah, it's not even our
bloody country.
How long gone
d'you reckon they are?
Why? Worried we'll
catch up with them?
Yeah, right.
Be a bloody miracle at this rate.
They are probably
right around the next corner.
Piss off, no they're not.
Why don't they
just bloody well give up?
Don't they want to go home?
They hate their wives and mothers...
and Germany must be a shit hole.
They're retreating... they're miles back.
We've got them on the ropes at least.
No. We don't.
- Oh, bollocks. What's up now?
- Not another bloody tree.
- Bridge is down.
- Oh. That's a shame.
Looks like I'll be getting out here.
Good luck.
Keep some of that luck for yourself pal.
Think you'll be needing it.
- Good luck, mate.
- Good luck, guv.
- Good luck.
- Don't balls it up.
I hope you get there.
Thank you.
The next bridge is six miles.
We'll have to divert.
I can't, Sir.
I don't have the time.
Of course.
Best of luck.
Thank you, Sir.
Corporal.
If you do manage to get
to Colonel MacKenzie,
make sure there are witnesses.
They are direct orders, Sir.
I know.
But some men
just want the fight.
Thank you, Sir.
Driver! Move off!
Anglais. Not German.
Friend... I'm a friend.
This place, this town. Ecoust?
C'est Ecoust?
Others? No. Just me.
Only. Me.
I need to be somewhere.
I need to find a wood
to the South East.
Trees... Les arbres?
- Croiset?
- Croisilles?
Yes.
River?
River. It go there.
Trees. Croisilles.
Thank you.
A girl?
What is her name?
Who is her mother?
I have food. Here.
I have these.
You can have them - here,
take them all,
for you and the child. Here.
Milk?
Merci.
Bonjour.
Children, you?
It's alright.
"They went to sea
in a Sieve, they did,"
In a Sieve they went to sea:
In spite of all
their friends could say,
On a winter's morn,
on a stormy day,
"In a Sieve they went to sea!"
"Far and few, far and few,"
Are the lands
where the Jumblies live;
Their heads are green,
and their hands are blue,
"And they went to sea
in a Sieve."
Stay. Stay. Please.
I have to go.
- Please.
- I'm sorry.
Engländer!
Baumer?
Engländer! Engländer!
♪ I am a poor wayfaring stranger ♪
♪ I'm traveling through
this world of woe ♪
♪ Yet there's no sickness,
toil nor danger ♪
♪ In that bright land
to which I go ♪
♪ I'm going there
to see my Father ♪
no more to roam ♪
♪ I'm only going over Jordan ♪
♪ I'm only going over home ♪
♪ I know dark clouds
will gather around me ♪
♪ I know my way
is rough and steep ♪
♪ Yet golden fields
lie just before me ♪
♪ Where God's redeemed
shall ever sleep ♪
♪ I'm going home
to see my Mother ♪
♪ And all my loved ones
who've gone on ♪
♪ I'm only going over Jordan ♪
♪ I'm only going over home ♪
♪ I am just a poor wayfaring stranger ♪
♪ I'm traveling through
this world of woe ♪
♪ Yet there's no sickness,
toil nor danger ♪
♪ In that bright land
to which I go ♪
♪ I'm going there
to see my Father ♪
no more to roam ♪
♪ I'm only going over Jordan ♪
♪ I'm only going over home ♪
D Company! Move out!
You alright, pal?
Where are you from?
- He's probably got the wind up.
- Well, he's not one of ours.
He's bloody soaked.
Fuck it, let's just pick him up
and take him with us.
Have to find the Devons.
- What's he saying?
- What's that mate?
The Devons.
I have to find the Devons.
We're the Devons.
- You're the Devons?
- Yes, Corp.
Why haven't you gone over?
- We're the second wave.
- They don't send us all at once.
Yeah, we're D Company,
we spent the night digging in.
We go last.
Are you alright?
MacKenzie. Where's Colonel MacKenzie?
He's down at the line.
- Which way?
- This way.
We're headed up there now.
Oy! Steady on mate!
Where you going?
Move!
Let me by!
Let me through!
Where's your commanding officer?
He's in the holding pen.
B Company, stand to!
Now listen, and listen well!
On the first mark, A Company will advance!
B Company will then move to the front line!
Sir, I have a message
from General Erinmore!
Who the fuck are you?
The attack has been called off.
General Erinmore has called off the attack.
Balls, man. We're about to go over.
We've got them on the run.
You don't! Please.
Don't send your men over.
Get out of the way, Corporal!
These are direct orders from Army command!
Where is the Colonel MacKenzie?
Jesus Christ, man!
Go and see the Captain!
Now I want us up there quickly,
you understand? Do you understand!
Yes, Sir!
Sections 9 and 10 at the ready!
We will advance
on the first whistle blast!
You must not slow down!
If the man next to you falls, keep moving!
Your orders are to break the lines.
- Where is the Captain?
- He's over there.
Sir? Sir!
Captain, I have a message.
This attack is called off.
You have to stop,
you have to stop.
Where is Colonel MacKenzie?
Where is MacKenzie?!
Get back! Return to your sectors.
Get back! Back! Hold fast!
7 Platoon! One Minute!
Sir, I have orders
to stop this attack.
- What?
- Where is Colonel MacKenzie?
He's further up the line.
How far?
300 yards.
He's in a cut and cover.
You'll have to wait
until the first wave goes over.
No! No, I can't!
7 Platoon! 30 seconds!
You can't possibly make it
that way man, are you bloody insane?
What the hell are you doing,
Lance Corporal?
No! No!
- Colonel MacKenzie?
- He's in there.
B Company two minutes!
Let me through!
What the hell do you think
you're doing?
I have to see Colonel MacKenzie!
- What are you doing?!
- I have to stop this attack.
Colonel, we've seen flares,
the men on the left flank
have made it
to the German Line.
- Colonel!
- Hold him!
Colonel!
Listen to me, listen to me!
I have a letter!
I need to see Colonel MacKenzie!
There's no bloody way
you're getting in there, mate!
- Sergeant! Send the next wave!
- No!
Colonel MacKenzie!
This attack is not to go ahead!
You've been ordered to stop.
- You have to stop.
- Who the hell are you?
Lance Corporal Schofield, Sir. 8th.
I have orders from General Erinmore
to call off this attack.
You're too late, Lance Corporal.
Sir, these orders are from Army Command.
You have to read them.
Shall we hold back
the second wave, Sir?
No, Major. Hesitate now and we lose.
Victory is only 500 yards away.
- Sir! Please read the letter.
- I have heard it all before.
I'm not going to wait
until dusk, or for fog.
I'm not calling back my men,
only to send them out there again tomorrow.
Not when we've got the bastards on the run.
This is their last stand.
The German's planned this, Sir.
They've been planning it for months.
They want you to attack.
Read the letter.
- Major.
- Yes, Sir.
- Stand them down.
Call up the orderlies.
Tend the wounded.
- Hold the line in case they counter.
- Yes, Sir.
Stand down! Stand down!
I hoped today might be a good day.
Hope is a dangerous thing.
That's it for now, then next week,
Command will send a different message.
Attack at dawn.
There is only one way
this war ends.
Last man standing.
Have someone see to your wounds.
Now fuck off, Lance Corporal.
Well done, lad.
Thank you, Sir.
Do you know where
Lieutenant Blake is, Sir?
Blake?
There were two of us.
I was sent here with his brother.
Well, knowing Lieutenant Blake
he would've gone over with his men.
He was in the first wave.
How could I find him, Sir?
You can try the casualty clearing station,
behind the line.
Otherwise...
Thank you, Sir.
Sergeant, I have to find Lieutenant Blake.
Do you know where he is?
No.
- Sir, is Lieutenant Blake here?
- No idea.
Move along Corporal.
If you can walk,
move to the triage area.
Lieutenant Blake!
Blake?!
Has anyone seen Lieutenant Blake?
Now come on boys.
He's taken one in the leg.
He's lost a lot of blood.
- Lieutenant Blake?
- Yes.
Do you need medical assistance?
No, Sir. I'm from the 8th.
What the hell
are you doing here?
I was sent here
to deliver a message.
The 8th?
You must know my brother.
- I was sent here with him.
- Tom's here? Where is he?
It was very quick. I'm sorry.
What's your name?
Schofield, Sir.
I'm sorry, what?
It's Schofield, Sir.
William Schofield. Will.
Well, you need some food.
Get yourself to the mess tent.
If I may, I'd like to write
to your mother.
Tell her that Tom wasn't alone.
Of course.
He was...
He was a good man.
Always telling funny stories.
He saved my life.
Well, I am glad
you were with him.
Thank you, Will.
Subtitles by sub.Trader
subscene.com