Subtitles by sub.Trader
subscene.com
Corrected by gabbyu's Subs,
supertooth, and Riceroll
This is live coverage of the
1959 24 Hours of Le Mans.
We've reached the half-way
point and so far witnessed
Aston Martin #5
driven by Carroll Shelby
making great gains in the last hour.
If he keeps this pace up
he could have a chance at the...
He's coming in. He's coming in.
Let's go!
I know you're tired.
Come on! Let's make this fast!
Move! Move! Move!
She's running a little hot, but we're good.
Fire!
Get him the blanket.
Get it off me! Off!
You okay?
Fill the tank!
- Shelby, you just...
- Am I on fire?
- Am I on goddamn fire?
- No, you're not...
Fill the tank!
- Where am I, Eddie?
- Two laps up my friend.
We're good. Go get 'em.
Aston Martin #5 driven by Carroll Shelby
has maintained his lead
as we are nearing
the final minutes of the race.
Shelby.
The checkered flag is out.
The crowd are on their feet.
- Shelby.
- Takes the title.
-An American wins Le Mans!
-Shelby!
- Carroll Shelby.
- What?
This is something
you can't ignore anymore.
Oh, I take the pills. The pills work.
An elevated heart rate, say 130 BPM
sustained even for a short period,
you run a critical risk of cardiac arrest.
- I'll race shorter format then.
- That's not gonna work.
I could race NASCAR, Formula 1.
The valve is shot, Shelby.
This is as serious as it gets.
In my opinion you're lucky
to be sitting here today.
Well, I feel real lucky.
Luckiest guy on Earth.
There's a point at 7000 RPM
where everything fades.
The machine becomes
weightless, just disappears.
Hey!
And all that's left is a body
moving through space and time.
7000 RPM.
That's where you need it.
It asks you a question.
The only question that matters,
"Who are you?"
Now it's Von Trips in the Ferrari
coming into the corkscrew.
He's braking late,
He's set a new lap record!
- Yes I do.
- No, you don't!
A month ago this car was fun.
Now, it won't even start.
And when it does it's...
Boom, boom, boom!
When I pull out of the driveway,
the dog has a heart attack.
All I'm asking is for you
to make it like it was.
Yeah, you've cocked up the
inlet valves and the plugs.
Nothing wrong with the car.
It's the way it's being driven.
The way it's being driven?
Too much fuel and not enough spark.
That's what's making her misfire.
You wanna run that
by me in English?
All right, sir.
So...
That there, that is a sport car.
You have to drive her like a sport car.
If you drive her like a school teacher,
she'll clog up.
Try changing up at 5000 RPM, not two.
Drive like you mean it.
Hard, tight, she'll run clean.
Are you telling me
I don't know how to drive my own car?
No.
But if you ask me, this isn't your car.
Your car is more a Plymouth, a Studebaker.
You and me have a problem, buddy?
I don't have a problem.
I had an MG. Mine ran just fine.
Screw you you limey prick.
I want my money back!
Behave, I'd give it to ya.
But you haven't paid
for last months service yet.
This country,
the customer's always right.
- You ever hear that?
- Yeah.
Utter nonsense.
Now remember, I advanced the timing,
so, smidge twitchy in first!
Get her revs up. Good lad, revs up.
Tada.
Another satisfied customer?
Can I help you, Miss?
Wasn't that an MGA 1500?
You know your cars.
I like them.
I love the sound they make.
The way it goes right through you.
That vibration.
Mine's the
wood paneled Country Squire.
'Cross the street.
A real hotrod.
Oh, yeah?
- Is it fast?
- Very.
Wait a second,
what type of girl are ya?
Type of girl who likes the smell
of wet gasoline.
Burnt rubber.
Are you some kind of a deviant?
Only since I married you.
- Hey, Gary.
- What's going on?
- I don't know.
Shut it down, Mr. Beebe.
John!
All stop!
Hear that?
That's the sound
of the Ford Motor Company
out of business.
In 1899, my grandfather
Henry, by God, Ford
was walking home from Edison Illumination
after working a double shift.
He was ruminating.
That morning he had himself an idea
that changed the world.
65 years and 47 million
automobiles later,
what shall be his legacy?
Gettin' it in the tailpipe
from a Chevy Impala.
Here's what I want you to do,
walk home.
While you're walking,
I want you to ruminate.
Man comes to my office with an idea,
that man keeps his job.
Rest of you second best losers,
stay home.
You don't belong at Ford.
Shelby.
I see you. Up and at 'em, buddy.
- Hey.
- Go away.
Come on, you can do it.
Come on, baby.
8:30 AM, time to roll.
Let's go!
- Let's go! Let's go! Go! Go!
- Go away!
It's 8:30 AM, baby. Time to roll.
Come on.
- Hey, Phil.
- Hey, Bob.
Is Shelby here?
It's touch and go.
Shelby, you're up bright and early.
Well,
early bird gets the worm, Pops.
All right, who are you worried about?
Well, You got Red Faris and Bill Rushton.
They're all in 327's.
Corvettes. What about Bondurant?
Bondurant? Well, he's still driving...
Mr. Shelby, can I get an autograph?
number 614.
All right, just relax, all right?
We gonna eat
those 'Vettes for breakfast.
We're lighter, we're faster.
An' that don't work, we're nastier.
Hey Phil,
take it easy on us today, bud.
Alright.
Paragraph 15.4 Section 2B
of the SCCA standard
dictates all AF class cars must have
minimum trunk space of 20" by 12" by 6".
Your trunk doesn't close,
- ergo car fails standard.
- Wait, wait. What?
Ergo car is disqualified from
said Class AF.
No, no, no.
- Can I ask you a question?
- Alright.
When you were a little boy,
did you think, when I grow up
I wanna go to the fabled
Willow Springs Raceway
and I wanna enforce
Paragraph 15.4 Section 2B
of the SCCA regulations
on luggage capacity.
All right, that's it.
I'm ruling you and your team
disqualified from this race.
Ah well, If it isn't Lance Reventlow.
Shelby.
How you're doing Lance?
- Pops.
- Hey Lance.
Allow me to introduce
Dieter Voss.
Runs Brumos Porsche
out of Jacksonville Florida.
I know all about Mr. Voss,
you're having a hell of a
season with that Abarth, sir.
- Seeing results for your Cobra too.
- Thank you.
- Your guy Miles is impressive.
- You're following Miles?
Well, he was a USAC road
racing champ in '61.
He won the Pikes
Peak Hill Climb.
He was SCCA C-class champion,
3 years in a row
in this piece of shit
MG he built himself.
We heard he's difficult.
What, Ken? No, no.
Ken's a puppy dog.
Hey Lance,
tell the man you raced against Ken.
However, I've driven more
behind him than against him.
Brumos is looking for a driver
for our number two car at Sebring.
- Is that right?
- How is that even possble?
You think your guy Miles
can make the grade?
- Oh, well...
- Hey!
Jim, is he putting his
bloody carry-on in your trunk?
Gentlemen, excuse me a moment.
To be honest, Ken was born for Sebring.
Nothing in there about my trunk
and your lovely little portmanteau.
You're holding the '62 edition of the SCCA.
You can stick this bloody sticker
where the sun never shines.
Hey. Hey Bill,
what seems to be the problem?
The problem is
that Bill here is an arsehole.
- No, he doesn't mean that.
- Yes, he does.
He really does think
that Bill is an arsehole.
I'm just doing my job here.
Bill, in my experience, there is...
Listen to me.
Something like this, there's always
a middle ground, all right?
- Ken's out of line, all right?
- And I'm just doing my job.
I understand you are.
You know how he gets on a race day.
You know that, all right?
But you're not gonna DQ us
over a trunk.
Happy, Bill?
Yeah, ah, I am.
I'll talk to him.
You just go and have a great day.
Shit.
Bulldog.
Do you know who that was
I was just talking to?
- Bill.
- Before that.
No.
- It was Dieter Voss.
- Who's that?
He runs Porsche, Ken.
It's a little German car company,
maybe you heard of it.
Right?
He wanted you to drive at Sebring,
but he'd heard you were difficult.
I thought we felt
the same way about...
Germans.
Do you like losing, Ken?
- Excuse me?
- You heard me.
I don't lose.
Without sponsors,
you get no car, Ken.
Now last I checked,
the professionals all have a car.
You cannot win the SCCA without one.
If you're not winning you are losing.
Don't make me lump this
at your head.
Did you bring your son all the way
out here to watch you get disqualified
or just act like a jackass?
Well, that answers that.
Peter.
May I help you, gentlemen?
Ah, yes, is Ken Miles here?
No.
- We need to speak to Mr. Miles.
- I'm his wife.
Welcome to the 1963 Willow Springs 100
12 cars will be competing
in this 40 lap race.
Hey Ken,
what happened to your shield?
New design.
Well, it looks like we're about to begin.
The cars have completed the warm-up lap.
The green flag is out.
And they're approaching the starting line.
Here we go.
Bloody hell!
Learn to drive, you pillock!
So, Shelby, you miss it?
Hey, Sam.
Guy wins the 24 Hour of Le Mans.
Suddenly retires, starts selling cars.
It just don't make sense.
Well, unless the rumors are true,
of course.
What rumors would those be, Sam?
That Carroll Shelby quit driving
'cause he lost his nerve.
I'm gonna out brake ya
on the next turn, Bob.
Nice try, Bob
Nice move from Ken Miles.
22 laps remaining,
with Phil Hill and
Dan Gurney in the lead.
It's been an incredible day
here at Willow Springs.
And we've seen some exciting driving.
With just 1 lap remaining
in this 40 lap race.
We're coming to the final stretch.
Dan Gurney has been leading
the pack for the most of the...Woah!
Red Faris is off the track.
That leaves Dan Gurney for the lead,
followed by journeyman Ken Miles.
Now for you, Dan.
And they're coming
around the last turn.
Gurney is still in the lead
with Ken Miles hot on his heel.
Miles is looking for an opening.
Not yet.
Come on!
Can Gurney hold him off
in the final straight?
Not yet.
Gurney is blocking him out.
Now.
Nice move, Ken.
They're wheel to wheel.
Come on!
An incredible finish for Ken Miles.
Didn't see that one coming.
He's difficult but good.
That calls for a nice cup of tea.
- I've got the kettle on.
- Hop in.
Pops, frame this.
Hey.
We did it!
What's wrong?
The IRS came.
They've padlocked the garage.
All right, Petey.
Couple of years ago,
you said we'd a nest-egg.
Correct.
- A couple of years ago.
- Correct.
So, just to be clear,
we are buggered.
Absolutely.
As in totally?
As in not a bean
or a pot in which to piss.
Spares, stock, all gone.
Tools, my tools are locked up in there.
I'll figure something out.
In 1945, our soldiers came home.
What was the first thing
that they did?
They had sex.
17 years later, those babies,
they've grown.
They've got jobs,
they've got licenses.
But they do not wanna drive
the same dull 50's cars
their parents drove.
You see, kids today, they want glamor.
They want, eh, sex appeal.
They wanna go fast.
Gentlemen,
it's time for the Ford Motor Company
to go racing.
We're already in racing, Iacocca.
NASCAR? It's regional, sir.
If you go to the movies,
you open up a magazine, you don't see
good ol' boys in Winston-Salem.
You see
Sophia Loren,
Monica Vitti.
James Bond does not
drive a Ford, sir.
That's because he's a degenerate.
See?
God, I'd like to be a degenerate.
Just give me one second, please.
Is this part of it?
- Is this going anywhere, Iacocca?
- Sorry, sir.
- All right, Alright. That's enough.
- Sir, if you just bear with me...
Turn it off, lights!
Lee, in the last 3 years,
you and your marketing team
have presided over
the worst sale slump in US history.
Why exactly should
Mr. Ford listen to you?
Because we've been thinking wrong.
Ferrari.
Now they've won 4 out
of the last 5 Le Mans.
We need to think like Ferrari.
Ferrari makes fewer cars in a year
than we make in a day.
We spend more on toilet paper
than they do on their entire output.
You want us to think like them?
Enzo Ferrari will go down in history
as the greatest car
manufacturer of all time.
Why?
Is it because he built the most cars?
No.
It's because of what his cars mean.
Victory.
Ferrari wins at Le Mans.
People they...
They want some of that victory.
What if the Ford badge meant victory?
And meant it where it counts with the
first group of 17-year-olds in history,
- with money in their pockets.
- This would take years.
Decades to test and develop a race team
capable of taking on Ferrari.
Ferrari's bankrupt.
Enzo spent every lire he's got chasing
perfection, and you know something?
He got there.
But now he's broke.
You don't have to give up racing
to get a bloody day job, Ken.
I think I do.
I've had my fun, it's time
to put food on the table and grow up.
The garage didn't pay the pills.
Now it's locked up.
Racing doesn't pay them either
and I keep winning.
Yeah, because you're good.
But I can't play the game.
I'm not what they call 'a people person'.
You don't say.
And I'm 45 years old,
Do you really think I'm gonna change?
I'm never gonna get the good rides.
I started too late.
Because you fought
in the bloody war!
If you stop,
you'd be bloody insufferable.
It was quick going 'round the region.
It's over.
Let's look on the bright side.
Now I can get fat and old,
trim the roses and eat pork pies.
Scuzi, please.
No photos, prego.
Relax.
You gotta understand.
This is like the Mafia showing up
to buy the Statue of Liberty.
Kind of the opposite, actually.
If the Press gets wind of this,
the shit will hit the Fangio.
- Lee Iacocca, Ford Motor.
- Franco Gozzi, Ferrari.
Sonno queste...
Your journalist?
No, no, Mr. Iacocca.
It's our cameras, just for history.
Four liter Colombo engine.
One man assembles
the entire engine by himself.
Another man assembles the transmission.
Everything hand-built.
Bellissimo.
Racing department.
Lee, that's him.
This merger between our companies
will form two entities.
Ford-Ferarri, 90% owned by Ford
who controls all production.
Secondly, Ferarri-Ford, the race team.
90% owned by Ferrari.
In order to secure this
Ford will pay the sum...
10 million dollars.
Excuse me.
He will need some time to read this.
Please.
Yeah, of course.
All done, thank you.
Only one small question.
It concerns my race program.
If I wish to race Le Mans and you
do not wish for me to race Le Mans,
Do we or do we not go?
In that highly unlikely scenario,
if we just can't agree then, yes.
I mean, no.
You are correct.
You do not go.
My integrity as a constructor,
as a man, as an Italian
is deeply insulted by your proposal.
Go back to Michigan.
Back to your big ugly factory.
Back to your big ugly factory
making its ugly little cars.
Tell your pig-headed boss that all his...
smug executives are
worthless sons of whores.
Tell him he's not Henry Ford.
He is Henry Ford the second.
He played us.
Old man Enzo had no intention
of selling to us.
He used us to up his price.
Embarrass our company,
insult your leadership.
It was a bad idea from the start.
What exactly did he say?
He said Ford makes ugly little cars,
and we make 'em in an ugly factory.
He said our executives are
sons of whores.
About me.
He called you fat, sir.
Pig-headed.
Go on.
He said you're not Henry Ford.
You're Henry Ford the second.
I want the best engineers.
The best drivers.
I don't care what it costs.
We're gonna build a race car.
And we're gonna bury
that goddamn greasy wop
a hundred feet deep
under the finish line at Le Mans.
And I will be there to watch it.
Here they come.
Go, go, go!
- Asshole!
- You're really pathetic!
I'm so sorry, girls.
Charlie, quit throwing
crackers at the girls
all damn day, goddammit.
- Do I gotta deal with this?
- It's already taken care of.
Sorry about that.
- So, yeah. 289 cubic inch V8.
- Far out.
Extensive rework of AC Ace's front end
and a stronger rear diff
to handle the torque.
How'd she handle the quarter mile?
Well, I'm not saying
you should go drag racing.
But quarter mile is 13.6. Yeah.
- Is that good?
- That's real good.
He sold that same car
3 times this week.
- You take cash? Is cash okay?
- Cash is okay.
Yeah, mister, you just bought yourself
- one hell of a sport car.
- Alright.
I'll tell you what, I'm gonna...Phil.
I'm gonna pass you off to my colleague
here, he gonna take care of you.
Phil, Wyatt.
I'll steal him for one second.
You take the payment.
Whatever you do, do not let him take
that car, that's Jeff Blitzer's car.
And Frank Collins's,
and Steve McQueen's.
Shit, I forgot about McQueen.
Morning, can I help you?
Carroll Shelby.
Maybe.
Lee Iacocca, Ford Motor.
What's with the wrench?
That? Long story.
We are just goin'
from strength to strength here, Lee.
Terrific sales.
We're killing it on the track. Now..
Now I know I owe Ford
for that last batch of engines...
Mr. Shelby, I can assure you
I'm not here for money
that you might owe
Ford for spare parts.
You're not?
No, I'm not.
Okay.
I'm here on behalf of Mr. Ford,
Henry Ford II.
Suppose, hypothetically,
he wanted his company
to win the 24 Hours of Le Mans.
You're one of the only Americans
that's ever done it.
I'm wondering, what's it take?
Hypothetically?
Hypothetically.
Well, it'll take something money can't buy.
Money can buy speed.
It isn't about speed, Lee.
It's not just like those other
tracks where all you do is
turn to the left for 4 hours.
To win that race, you need a car
that's light enough to do
200 on the straightaways,
but strong enough to keep that up
for 3000 miles without a break.
Not just the best car y'all have ever made,
but better than anything that
Enzo Ferrari shows up with that year.
And that just gets
you to the green flag,
that's where your
problems really start.
- Is everything okay?
- Go away.
So, you're saying it's challenging.
Look, it's not even a track, Lee.
Le Mans' 8.5 miles of country road.
It's narrow, ungraded. It's rough.
There's no camber on the turns, no rails.
You gotta do that for 24 hours.
24 hours, Lee.
That means night.
Half of that race is in the dark,
you can't see shit.
Cars coming up on you out of nowhere.
Drivers stumblin' around the track,
pourin' blood.
Maybe one of 'em's your friend,
maybe he's on fire.
You're exhausted, you're hungry.
Can't remember your name,
what country you're in,
and all of a sudden you realize
you're doing 198 on the straight.
And if anything goes wrong.
You blow a gasket, 5 cent washer.
That's it, whole thing's over.
Ferrari wins again.
Just like it won last year.
The year before that,
and the year before that.
Yeah, it's challenging.
You don't think that
Ford Motor Company can build
the greatest race car
the world's ever seen?
You think that we are incapable
of winning an event like that?
Even if we had a brilliant partner?
Even if we wrote a blank check?
What I'm saying is
you can't buy a win, Lee,
but maybe you could buy the guy
who gets you a shot.
A new transmission.
Axles, shocks all around.
Ditch the body and the tires,
you have yourself a contender.
Anything on this beauty
that does work?
The mirrors are outstanding.
I saw that walking up.
So, what? You're just
passing or evening stroll?
Actually, bulldog,
I have a proposition for you.
You gonna build a car
to beat old man Ferrari?
With Ford. With a Ford?
Correct.
And how long did you tell them
that you needed?
Two, three hundred years?
90 days.
All right, so, let's just look
at this for a moment.
And for argument's sake,
let's just forget about
the whole 90 day thing.
Let's just pretend you got
all the money in the world
and all the time in the world.
- I like the sound of that.
- Alright, so.
You think that Ford
are gonna let you build
the car that you want
the way you want it?
The Ford Motor Company?
Those guys?
Have you ever been to Detroit? I mean,
they have floors and floors of lawyers,
and millions of marketing guys,
and they're all gonna wanna meet you,
all of them gonna wanna get their photo
taken with the great Carroll Shelby,
and they're gonna kiss your arse
and they're gonna go back
to their lovely offices,
and they're gonna work out
new ways to screw you.
Why? Because they can't help it.
Because they just wanna
please their boss,
who wants to please his boss,
who wants to please his boss.
And they hate themselves for it,
but deep down,
who they hate even
more, are guys like you,
because you're not like them,
because you don't think like them,
because you're different.
It's coming straight from the Deuce.
He's serious.
They're gonna put real money behind it.
I bet they are.
You know why? Because someone,
and I'm not saying who.
Someone has told them
that this is actually possible.
Look, this Sunday at Cloverfield,
they're launching the new Mustang.
They're gonna announce the race program.
Just come on by.
Come take a look.
Listen to my speech.
I'm making a speech.
Bring Peter, he'll love it.
Alright, Shel.
See you Sunday.
Woah.
Dad, look at that.
Ford Mustang. What do you think?
I think it's a secretary's car.
I like it.
Oh, excuse me, excuse me.
Would you not do that?
Sorry.
- Oh, is this your son?
- Yes, it is.
Would you ask him
to keep his hands off the paintwork?
No, no, Petey, you're okay.
Who are you?
Leo Beebe, Senior Executive Vice President,
Ford Motor Company.
I am responsible
for the launch of the Mustang.
Well, at least now we
know who's responsible.
- Don't get me wrong, Lenny.
- Leo.
It looks fantastic but
inside it's a lump of lard
dressed up to fool the public.
My advice is: lose the inline 6
and that idiotic 3 speed,
shorten the wheelbase.
Somehow lose half a ton.
- And lower the price.
- Dad.
But even then
I'll still choose the Chevy Chevelle.
That's a fucking terrible car.
How're we doing up there, Steve?
There's Cloverfield, Mr. Shelby.
Oh, yeah.
You mind if I take a shot
at the landing?
No no, I mean it. I flew B-29s
outta San Antonio in '44.
- You're kidding.
- I did.
Okay.
Carroll, what are you doing?
- Does he know how to fly?
- Carroll.
I had an instructor tell me
Look Don, I would say
it's probably a good time to buckle up.
Do everybody a favor
and stay on the ground.
That's a true story.
This is the car you never
expected from Detroit.
Alright, let's go.
Not staying, Ken?
Nah, it's a bloody pig
in a poke, isn't it?
Oh, here they come now.
- Wait, are they crashing?
- Oh, lord.
Who's the pilot?
My guess, Peter...
Someone we know.
Everything all right up there?
Oh, no!
- Hang on.
-Shit!
Shit!
Tell you what,
that's like riding a bike.
Talk about making an entrance.
Good grief.
- Shelby!
- Over here!
How're y'all doin'.
Can we get an autograph, sir?
Shelby, this is Roy Lunn.
Ol' Roy here is developing
the prototype over in England.
Oh hell, I know Roy.
Good to see you, Roy.
Welcome to the madhouse, Shelby.
Ford wheeled out the entire
executive committee for this one.
Hold that thought.
- Ah.
- Hello, Mr. Lindbergh.
You like that?
Hey, Peter, how're you doing?
- Mr. Shelby.
- Good to see you.
Are you building a car
that's gonna beat Ferrari?
Well, we're gonna go to Le Mans,
that's for sure.
And if we get across that finish
line first we gonna win.
Carroll, allow me to introduce Leo Beebe,
Senior Vice President Ford Motor.
Oh, sure, yeah.
- Please Mr. Beebe.
- Thank you for coming.
Say hello to Ken Miles
and his son Peter.
- We...
- Right.
We met.
Yeah.
- Didn't we?
- So, um...
I'll take Petey for some pop.
Good luck with these guys, Shel.
- Bye, Mr. Shelby.
- See you, Pete.
Don't worry, he's gonna stay.
So, you two get a chance
to talk on the plane?
Yeah, Carroll, why don't we just,
step this way for a second.
Look, it's pro forma,
it's window dressing.
But there's gotta be a sense of getting
the tape between you and you know.
- No, I don't.
- The group.
The group?
Senior creatives, Carroll.
Just to make sure everybody's comfortable.
I'm confused, Lee.
'Cause up until this moment
right now I was comfortable.
Why don't you take a look
out there, Carroll?
What do you see?
Do you know what I see?
I see a machine.
I see ten thousand moving parts
moving, hopefully, in harmony.
And it's my job to make it so.
It's my job to guide you through it.
I'm here to help you, Carroll.
But you gotta trust me.
- Excuse me, Lee.
- Carroll.
Do not step on that stage
if you don't trust me.
Please, welcome Mr. Carroll Shelby.
Gotta go.
- What'd he say?
- He gets the drill.
Thank you.
If my Daddy was here today,
he'd tell me to sit on down
and leave the yackin' to the college boys.
Like my cars, I'll make this fast.
When I was 10 years old,
Pops said to me, "Son,
it's a truly lucky man who knows
what he wants to do in this world."
'Cause that man will never work
a day in his life.
But there are a few, a precious few,
and hell I don't know
if they're lucky or not,
but there are a few people
who find something they have to do.
Something obsesses them.
Something if they can't do it,
it's gonna drive them
clean outta their mind.
I'm that guy.
And I know one other man
feels exactly the same.
His name...
His name is Mr. Henry Ford.
And together we're gonna build
the fastest automobile in the world.
And we're gonna make
history too, at Le Mans.
- Let's go.
- What?
My name is Carroll Shelby.
I build race cars.
No. Whatever it is, no.
No.
30 minutes.
Ah, I just...
I'm spent, I wanna have a bath.
You gonna wanna see this.
Trust me.
30 minutes. I'll have you back
for meatloaf and gravy.
- 30 minutes.
- Yeah.
Bloody hell.
Fresh off the plane from England.
Now,
She's still a little
on the rare side of cooked.
Come on.
Interesting.
Well?
- It's awful.
- It's worse than awful.
It doesn't track.
The 3rd gear is too high,
torque is not reaching the road.
Steering's loose because
the front end gets light.
At over 140 it thinks it's...
- Airplane.
- Yeah.
It wants to lift off and fly to Hawaii.
Anything else?
One second.
You were back late last night.
Yeah.
Were you working?
So you didn't go any place.
What?
I'm asking, did you go
any place last night?
Mollie.
It's a simple question.
And I answered, didn't I?
What was the answer?
Is something up, love?
What are you doing?
You're driving very fast.
Am I? Am I?
Yes, you are!
Bloody hell!
What are you? What is this?
You tell me 'cause I dunno.
What? Slow down!
Whoa, whoa, Mollie!
Please, Slow it down! Alright?
You're trying to kill us or something?
- I thought we love this shit.
- What?
Bloody hell!
- It's a bit of racing fun, no?
- No no no, it's not the same at all!
Well I think it's thrilling!
Alright.
Look, I saw you, all right?
I saw you leaving with Shelby,
and I saw you coming back.
Okay, shit, okay.
Slow down.
And then all day you got
that stupid look on your face.
Mollie, slow down!
You're too close in.
Mollie, put on the brakes right now!
Not until you tell
me what's going on!
Alright, I went to look at a car.
- With Shelby?
- With Shelby.
- A racing car?
- Sort of.
There's a corner coming,
you better hold on.
Mol, are you gonna lift your foot off
at all through this?
No. 'Cause I like a clean racing line.
Slow down!
Okay. Shel offered me a job.
Ford has a car
that they wanna put up
against Ferrari.
- You told me you were done!
- I didn't say yes!
- Slow down!
- You told me you quit!
- I don't understand.
- Get fat and old you said!
Fat and old!
- I don't understand.
- That's what you told me!
I don't understand.
Are you upset because I said I was done
or because I looked at a race car?
Just don't lie to me again!
Don't make it a secret,
what you want or what you feel
just because you think
it's gonna make me happy!
Mol, I don't even know what I feel.
If you do this
they better be paying you this time.
'Cause I can't work any more hours
and look after Peter.
The IRS have the garage,
I'm not losing my home.
It's 200 a day
plus expenses.
Are you shitting me?
But, I haven't decided.
200 dollars a day?
Are you nuts?
This is ridiculous.
Grabbing air. That's the problem.
Over 90, air's getting in, not getting out.
It's the nose.
I can feel it in the wheel.
Mr. Miles, if there's a problem
the computer will find it.
Charlie, get some scotch tape
and a ball of wool.
Alright.
Good, good good. So now let's just
get all of this junk out.
All right, Pops?
Yeah, yeah. I concur.
Come on guys.
What are they doing?
Making your car faster.
There, right there.
Airflow's getting stuck.
I see it. Yarn blows straight up.
- Yep.
- Front's lifting. Damn, he's right.
This car wants to go faster. I feel it.
Any lighter we're getting fragile.
We took 70 pounds out
of her in the last week.
She's outputting max horsepower
from this displacement.
- So put in a bigger engine.
- Where we gonna put it? On the roof?
Managed to make it 52 pounds lighter
than the NASCAR unit.
All new aluminum cylinder heads.
Vibration dampers, Water pump,
Smaller valves.
We call it 'The Beast'.
I can see why, but how's it gonna fit
without redesigning the engine bed?
Well, it certainly wasn't easy.
Good Morning, gentlemen, Mr. Shelby.
So, you already put that in a GT-40?
I'm afraid we have.
I'll be damned.
Well, it's heavy, of course.
Problems with the handling especially
the stopping. I can show you the data.
What problem?
- Understeers a little, but...
- Can I borrow that?
Just a second, thank you.
Ken, Ken!
Perhaps we ought to check
with HQ before you take...
- What'd he say?
- We should ask...
Alright.
Oh, yes!
Mr. Shelby. Welcome to Dearborn.
What are you doing
at a test track?
You're gonna get Castrol
all over that nice suit.
I want to hear your thoughts
on a few planning decisions.
You know, personnel for Le Mans.
Well, It's a hell of a line up,
Ken Miles, Phil Hill,
Chris Amon, Bruce McLaren.
Hill's a lock,  Amon, McLaren too.
We're less sure about Miles.
We like Richie Ginter,
Masten Gregory, Bob Bondurant?
You want the best driver for the car,
who understands the machine, that's Ken.
Oh, Yes!
More of that, please.
More of that, my girl.
I may not get the finer points of racing
Mr. Shelby, but I do know people.
Miles is...He's a beatnik.
He dresses like one.
Ford means reliability.
Ken Miles is not a Ford man.
Whoa!
Giddyup, giddyup!
What's the lap record here, Burt?
1.58.
1.50, dead.
A beatnik?
That man landed a busted
tank on the beach at D-Day
and drove it clean
across Europe to Berlin.
A beatnik?
You know, Lee here asked me a while back,
what's the one thing money can't buy.
I'll tell you what it is.
A pure racer behind
the wheel of your car.
That's Ken Miles.
Well, be that as it may,
we think he may be too pure.
Carroll, do not lose sight
of the big picture here.
Too pure?
What exactly does that mean?
Means he's all about himself.
ABC puts a microphone under his nose.
Perhaps there's a detail he dislikes.
Millions watching.
Do you trust him not to put out
the wrong message?
Well look, you could get a clean
cut all American poster boy.
And stick him behind the wheel.
Teach him what to say.
Shit, you get Doris Day to drive the car
if all you wanna do is lose.
So, you don't agree with us
on this issue?
I'm saying you're gotta trust me
on this one.
Carroll, with marketing concerns,
that's just not possible.
Put a Ford type driver
in a Ford car, Mr. Shelby.
That's the Ford way.
Yet another championship win for Ferrari...
Ferrari wins.
Wedges, we have wedges.
Good, good, good.
Perfect.
- 40?
- Yup.
Hey, boss.
You got a passport?
- What's that?
- Sign that, Get a passport.
Get it back to me by Friday.
Frosty.
Boys, I'm going to France.
Phil.
Ken, can I get a word?
Can I take this?
Do you know why Ford named it the GT-40?
Why they put that 40 on there?
- No.
- Regulations.
We gotta be 40 inches high
to make the ground clearance requirements.
No more, no less.
They measure it before every race.
Problem is that with that height
there's too much drag under the car.
So...
We have a solution, Wedges.
We put wedges in...
You're not coming next week.
You're not coming, Ken.
We're taking McLaren,
Chris Amon, Phil Hill
and Bob Bondurant.
This is Ford's call.
It is their opinion that
you are not a good image,
so you cannot drive their race car.
Putting aside the fact that you made
that car whatever the hell it is,
and you're the best man I got
behind the wheel.
I'm gonna re-route the oil line.
If there's spillage it could drip
onto the rear near side disc.
Ken.
Tell the boys to watch
their pace come sunrise.
The gearbox will overheat.
Ken, race is starting soon.
Want it on the radio?
Not unless you do.
There they are the Maserati
going into the esses,
but it's still the #2 car
driven by Chris Amon.
In third place is the #1 Ford
driven by Bruce McLaren.
A tremendously fast start for the Ford GT.
3:43.4 lap for car #2 Ford.
I think it's a little bit quick
for this stage of the game.
Racing too hot?
Another Ford has come in to the pit
it is being pushed into
the pit by the mechanic.
Head gasket.
The car's not a moon rocket.
Leading #20 Ferrari of Michael Fahr.
So, we have Fords running one,
two, three, how about that?
Too soon, surely too soon.
Here's the big story,
the lead Ford driven by
Rickie Getzer retires with
gearbox trouble and the new leader...
Gearbox.
I told them to be gentle with it.
Who's there?
What's that you're listening to?
Some race over in France.
Excited?
Not really paying much attention.
It's not exactly Champagne.
But it's got bubbles.
Thanks, Mollie.
Grace?
Yes, sir?
I will send him right in.
Thank you.
Mr. Shelby, Mr. Ford will see you now.
Alright.
This guy...
This way, Mr. Shelby.
Mr. Ford, gentlemen.
Shelby.
Give me one reason why
I don't fire everyone
associated with this
abomination, starting with you.
Well, sir.
I was thinking about that very question
as I sat out there in
your lovely waiting room.
As I was sitting there,
I watched that little red folder
right there go
through four pairs of hands
before it got to you.
Of course, that don't include
the 22 or so other Ford employees
who probably poked at it before it
made its way up to the 19th floor.
With all due respect, sir,
you can't win a race by committee.
You need one man in charge.
Now, the good news, as I see it,
is that even with all the extra weight
we still managed to put ol' Mr. Ferrari
exactly where we want him.
- Did we?
- Oh, yes.
Expand.
Well,
sure, we haven't...
We haven't worked out
how to corner yet.
Or stay cool,
or stay on the ground.
And a lot of stuff broke.
In fact, the only thing that didn't break
was the brakes.
Hell, right now, we don't even know
if our paint job will
last the whole 24 hours.
But our last lap, we clocked 218 mph
down the Mulsanne straight.
Now, in all his years of racing,
ol' Enzo ain't never seen
anything move that fast.
And now he knows without a doubt,
we're faster than he is.
Even with the wrong driver
and all the committees.
And that's what he's thinking about
while he's sitting in
Modena, Italy right now.
That man is scared to death
that this year you actually
might be smart enough to start trusting me.
So, yeah.
I'd say you got Ferrari
exactly where you want him.
You're welcome.
Come here.
You see that little building down there?
In World War II, three out of five
US bombers rolled off that line.
You think Roosevelt beat Hitler?
Think again.
This isn't the first time
Ford Motor's gone to war in Europe.
We know how to do more
than push paper.
And there is one man
running this company.
You report to him.
You understand me?
Yes, sir.
Go ahead, Carroll. Go to war.
Thank you, sir.
You were right.
It's the gearbox.
We ran too hot.
Three out of four of 'em broke.
Rod blew on other one.
We're goin' back, Ken.
They told me I had
a carte blanche this time.
I looked it up,
it's French for 'horse shit'.
I know they gonna squeeze
our nuts any way they can
as soon as they work out how.
Well, the ice cream's melting.
Alright. Hey, Ken.
You want me to apologize?
You want me to beg?
I don't know, let's try it out.
Let's see how that feels.
Ken, I'm sorry, sincerely.
Do you have any idea
the kind of shit
that I had to eat just to
get 4 wheels on that grid?
No, you don't, 'cause you don't deal
with any of that stuff.
Now, knock it off, Ken!
We got work to do,
and this car ain't gonna build itself.
Okay, alright.
Come here!
Bloody car salesman.
Shit!
Come on. Now you're
gonna get this.
Get off me!
Stubborn son of a bitch!
Come here!
Done.
Mollie, darling.
Yes, love?
Could you get me a fizzy pop, please?
Yes, love.
- Do you want one too, Shelby?
- No.
- Yes, please, Mollie.
- No, Mollie. No.
He can get his own. Just for me, please.
How long's that been?
It's gotta be
three or four years at least.
- Riverside.
- Yeah, the SCCA Divisional Championship.
You broke my finger.
What was that? That?
Nippy...
Nippy bloody thing?
You did on the arm that thing.
Yeah, I call that 'The Llama bite.'
You named it.
Where'd you learn that?
From the girl scouts?
You wanna go again?
Here you go.
- You're an angel.
- Thank you.
My pleasure.
Right. Well,
I'm about to go to the grocery store.
Anything you think you'll need?
Ice cream, Ice cream would be good.
And...bread.
- Right.
- No, I'm good. Thank you.
Thanks, Mol.
Still take those for you ticker?
Only because they're so delicious.
Up yours.
Ah, go to hell.
Giddyup, giddyup!
Sam.
One for you mate.
Dino, come here.
Well?
There's still a lag when I hit the gas.
Let's get rid of the vacuum secondaries.
Charlie, get a Holley carb
we're gonna rebuild the throttle assembly.
Three weeks to Daytona
and it still feels like a bag of squirrels.
Brake heat.
That's a whole different ball game.
All right, Petey.
Let's go for that ride.
What're you doing?
See that crack?
That's my marker for turn 8.
What, to slow down?
Ah, brush the brakes and downshift.
But you'll be going a 150 mph.
Yeah.
So how do you see it?
You go fast, but as the car speeds up
everything else slows down.
You don't do that.
You do this, right?
And then you see everything.
Do you set other markers?
Indeed I do. Lots of them.
Yeah, 'cause you can't just push
the car hard the whole way, right?
That's right.
You have to be kind to the car. You feel
the poor thing groaning underneath you.
If you're gonna push a piece
of machinery to the limit
and expect it to hold together,
you have to have some sense
of where that limit is.
Look out there.
Out there is the perfect lap.
No mistakes.
Every gear change, every corner.
Perfect.
You see it?
I think so.
Most people can't.
Most people don't even know
it's out there but it is.
It's there.
You want some ice cream?
- Yeah.
- Alright.
Come on then.
- You know what this marker is?
- What?
That one.
Pull my finger. You'll find out.
How much longer
before he comes in?
Well, we change drivers every 4 hours,
so about 10 minutes.
No, hang on,
You're saying Beebe is
a 100% in charge now?
Yes, and he wants Miles gone.
Look, it is personal with this guy.
Yes, he has the leverage
is to stick with you.
He and the Deuce are flying there tomorrow.
He's gonna tell you in person.
All he is hoping for
is that you lose your cool.
It's time to let this go.
You cannot destroy
the whole thing,
not for one goddamn guy.
- Sure I can.
- But why?
'Cause while we're here talking,
he's out there getting it done.
Oh, shit!
He's got brake fade.
Ease off!
- Get him out!
- Peter! Just go inside.
Just stay there!
- Ken!
- Get him out!
- Hurry!
- Ken!
- Come on.
The brakes.
Let's just rip out the damn
engine, alright.
We can't use it
if we can't stop.
The brakes would last longer
if you slowed down a bit.
Wouldn't that defeat the whole purpose
of the extra power?
Y'know, I thought the whole point was
to win the damned race.
Maybe we could design
a new assembly.
Instead of swapping out
the pads in the pits,
swap out the entire
braking system, rotors included.
Put in a fresh one.
Wait, wait. Pops.
We're allowed to do that?
I don't know. I don't read French.
Brakes are a part like any other, right?
- We are allowed to change parts.
- Yes.
Will we have time to do that?
I don't know yet, Charlie.
- I'm gonna take him home.
- Alright.
- Sort this shit out.
- I will.
Have you ever been on fire?
Well, no, no. It's never happened to me.
The suit's flameproof, see.
Keeps heat out.
Yeah.
But Lewis Evans burnt to death
in the Moroccan Grand Prix.
He had a flameproof suit on.
Yeah, but...
See, he got stuck.
He couldn't breathe.
So as long as you get out
of the car, you're okay.
Dad got out.
- He sure did.
- Peter.
- Bye.
- See ya.
- You all right?
- Yeah.
What's wrong with you?
Don't tell me brakes or me almost
kicking the bucket out there.
It's something to do
with the suits, isn't it?
It's under control.
What is it?
You know how we talked about
you do your thing, I do my thing.
This is my thing.
- Shel.
- Just trust me, Ken.
You got a plan?
Absolutely.
A good one?
It's high risk.
- How high risk?
- Extremely high risk.
Well, that's something.
- Glad we had this talk.
- Anytime.
Mr. Ford, this is a surprise.
Apologies for the
unannounced intrusion, Mr. Shelby.
A man pays 9 million dollars
for an automobile
he ought to at least be able to see it.
That sounds reasonable enough.
- Shelby, can I have a word?
- Sure.
In private?
- Ah, yeah, that would be preferable.
- Alright.
Hey Phil, you wanna take care of Mr. Ford
here? Mr. Ford, that's Phil Remington.
- Of course.
- Come to my office, Leo.
Pleasure, sir.
Let me give a little tour of your car.
We took out your 289 small block
and put in a 427.7 liter.
Firstly, I wanna just clear the air.
I hope that whatever disagreements
between us can just be chalked up to
natural red-bloodedness
in the heat of battle.
I appreciate that Leo. Truly, I do.
It falls on me, Shelby,
to inform you that
I have been appointed overall
Executive Director of the Racing program.
Now, I do hope that
this won't be a problem between us.
I assure you, Leo, it will not.
Hey, Carroll!
Carroll!
And what is the top speed
with the 427?
- Why don't we take it for a spin?
- What?
Go on, Mr. Ford.
Hope on in, go on.
- You want me to...
- To see what 9 million dollars feel like.
Open the door!
Hey, open the door!
Just hold me right there
and you take my hand.
Oh, God! I sat on my nuts.
I'm gonna build the next one
for comfort, don't you worry.
Open the door.
Sorry sir,
if you'd just give me a moment?
Open the door!
You ready?
The name in the middle
of that steering wheel
should tell you that I was born
ready, Shelby.
- Hit it.
- Attaboy.
Oh, that's got a little...
kick... doesn't it?
- Open the door!
- Here we go.
Good God, Mr. Beebe.
Are you okay, sir?
Oh my God!
Yeah, baby!
It's about right now they uninitiated
have a tendency to soil themselves.
Mr. Ford.
Are you okay?
Mr. Ford, You all right?
I had no idea.
I wish my daddy, he
were alive to see this.
To feel this.
This is not a machine just anybody
can get in and easily control.
Absolutely not. I had no idea.
Now you wanna win Le Mans.
You really wanna take 1st place,
Ken Miles is the man to do it.
Good timing.
He knows this car
because he helped me build it.
Shelby, you know I've already appointed
Leo Beebe Director of...
Which is exactly
why I'm talking to you.
You let Ken Miles race Daytona.
If he wins,
he gets to drive Le Mans.
And if he doesn't?
Ford Motor Company gets full ownership
of Shelby American.
Lock, stock and brand. Forever.
We're an hour of 6 at the Daytona 24.
And Fords are dominating the leaderboard.
Shelby American's Ken Miles
holds a narrow lead over
the Holman Moody Ford,
driven by Walt Hansgen.
I don't bloody think so, Walt.
This race is not just a test of our cars,
but also our teams.
As you know we have a second team
out there today.
- Holman Moody?
- That's right.
Walt's pushing it too fast.
He's pushing 7000 RPM!
Get the EZ sign out there.
Come on. Move! Do it now!
Every one of these GTs out there today
is under my direct supervision.
And, of course, the supervision
of Henry Ford II.
The drivers, the speed, the strategy
even the RPMs are determined by us.
Ken Miles is locked in a
pitched battle with Hansgen
as they pass the grandstand.
Hansgen is taking a run at
Miles into turn one.
Hansgen takes the lead...
Oh, blimey! Did you see that?
Still racing.
- Hey, we are still racing!
- Come on, guys! Let's go!
- Let's go! Move it!
- He's coming in!
Let's go! Let's go, guys!
Come on!
Let's go! Let's go! Move!
Hansgen is right up our arse.
If I can get outta the pit
ahead of him.
She's running hot but
I think she'll hold.
She's hot.
Hey, Walt. Good to see you.
After I get out of this pit, Shelby.
It's the last time you will.
Aw, don't worry,
we've got rear view mirrors.
What happened to that Mustang
he took out?
Don't know yet.
I can push her harder than 6, Shel.
I can feel it.
How come these guys's pit
so much faster than we do?
They got a goddamn
NASCAR crew, that's why.
- No shit?
- No shit.
Goddamn NASCAR crew.
Guys, they've already left!
Hello?
That's my Mollie, hello.
Hiya, love.
- What are you doing?
- Mom, mom.
- Just having a cuppa.
- Mom, ask him about the brakes!
Go to bed, it's 1 AM.
- Ask him.
- Go to bed! Now!
I take it he's not asleep.
I'm sure he smuggled in a radio.
He said to ask how are the brakes.
The brakes, yes.
No, no, tell him they're working, for now.
You know,
Shelby's been acting very strange.
- Ford's gonna...
- Ken.
push up another team with a GT.
Some sort of a yampy bloody corporate test
or something, I don't know but...
Take a rest whenever you get a chance.
Sorry, my love. What you were saying?
You've only got a few hours.
I can't hear you very well.
I'm sorry, I can't hear ya. Wish me luck.
- Good luck.
- I love you, darling.
After 23 hours here at Daytona,
Walt Hansgen,
driving a green and white Ford
has a commanding lead
over Ken Miles and Shelby American.
We're locked out, ain't nothing
Miles can do this late in the race.
Engine's hot,
we gotta keep it under 6 thou'.
Alright.
She could come apart.
One way to find out.
I thought we were keeping
him under 6000.
Shut up, Don.
We've only minutes of racing
left here at Daytona,
a pitched battle for the
lead is being raised
as the #98 Ford makes an
incredible late surge.
- What's happening?
- He's moving up.
Ken Miles' desperate bid for the win...
White flag, last lap!
Miles is pushing him, hard.
That's it.
Ken Miles drafts Walt Hansgen
coming in to the final turn.
Come on, come on!
What the hell?
Come on!
Alright.
Look at this now.
Damn it!
How about that?
Yes, Leo?
Mr. Ford, sir. We won.
We won. Ford won Daytona.
And which team was it, Leo?
Shelby American, Miles driving.
Son of a bitch.
Where the hell is he?
Hang on, wait a minute.
Someone lost a bulldog on the beach!
No, no. Come on, Come on.
Someone get this man a drink.
Oi!
In bed you!
What are you doing?
Dirty stop out.
I was drawing a map,
so I could follow you at Le Mans.
Look at that.
That is spot on.
You are a dab hand,
very accurate.
- Tell me about the track.
- No, I can't, Petey.
Please.
We start at the start line.
You actually start here, because you
have to run to your car at Le Mans.
True enough.
Once your old man
manages to hobble over and pull out.
- And not hit anyone.
- Yes, right.
Accelerate, very hard up to Dunlop bridge.
Road banking away from you.
Then down through the trees to the Esses.
Accelerate up to Terte Rouge,
critical first gear corner.
Fast entry, keep your speed up
for your exit onto Mulsanne.
Long straight-away,
hemmed in by poplars, Top gear.
210 mph, then down to third,
revs up, revs are your friend.
Get a maximum exit,
Let the car run free, Over the brow
then wham, the Mulsanne Corner,
Accelerate to Arnage.
Over the rise to the White House.
You get that right and
your first 3.5 minutes of the 24 hours.
But...
You can't make every lap perfect.
But I can try.
Alright, off to bed you.
I will wake you before
I leave for France.
I promise.
Okay, goodnight.
Where is that? Hotel Champier?
Where?
It's gonna rain again tomorrow.
There's always rain here.
Start will be dry, though.
We'll swap out your tires come rain.
Yeah.
Might be smart to sleep, bulldog.
You too.
I'm not driving.
That's a bloody shame, that.
Oh hell, I couldn't make this team.
I'm gonna walk the first corner.
Now I figured.
Counting on it.
Hey, Ken.
Chaz.
If this were a beauty pageant,
we just lost.
Looks fast, doesn't it?
Looks aren't everything.
Scarfiotti and Bandini
start for Ferrari.
You can take him.
4 minutes, Ken.
4 minutes, buddy.
- Live from Le Mans, France.
- Mom! Come on!
Alright, I'm coming.
The 24 Hours of Le Mans.
Drivers, please take your places.
- There he is.
- And here they are lined up, ready to go.
Bloody joking!
It's all right, son.
You looked great out there, sir.
What happened to Miles?
Bloody hell!
Poxy bastard!
After one lap, Bandini,
Ferrari is in first place.
Where's Miles?
- Where the hell is Ken?
- I don't know.
He's coming in.
Let's go! Faster! Come on!
Let's Go! Move it!
I think it's his door.
That's a rough start for the Ford team.
The bloody door won't close!
- Alright, alright.
- Maybe it's the heat.
Try that.
Shelby! What the hell is wrong?
- Something's hitting the frame.
- Oh, you're joking, aren't you?
Guys, get out of the way!
Get out of the way! Hold.
Go, go, go!
He's back out, go!
Tremendous gains for Ken Miles and Ford...
Come on dad, come on.
Ken Miles, Ford, has set a new lap record,
3 minutes and 34 seconds.
Shelby, he's pushing the car too hard.
That's not the plan.
Plan's changed.
Lap is 3.34, track is 8.36.
Someone tell me the mph!
3:31.9 that's a...
Another lap record.
Let's go, let's go, boys!
- Tea's ready, Ken.
- Thank you, Chaz.
- Happy Birthday, old chap.
- Cheers, mate. Great run.
You're 3 seconds
faster than Gurney.
If you hadn't blown the
start you'd be in the lead.
- Can you keep this up?
- Can the car?
There has been an incident on turn 6.
#18 and #26 have collided.
It appears, Ferrari, #20,
Ludovico Scarfiotti
has also left the track.
- All right, watch your head.
- Thank you.
Have a good dinner, sir.
Oi, McLaren's pitting.
Mr. Ford's probably going
somewhere nice for dinner.
What do you mean 'probably'?
Rain's coming.
Alright.
Coming in.
- Engine's running hot, Pops.
- Alright.
She's hot, mate. Crack on.
Tire.
- We're at 220. We're okay.
- Alright.
- Let's go.
- Swap that out.
Go! Go!
Hey, I need a stopwatch.
Lorenzo Bandini remains
in first place for Ferrari.
Easy, Dan. You're getting boxed in.
He's not batting
on a full wicket, that one.
Easy, Dan.
Oh bloody hell!
You arsehole!
Oh, piss off!
You wanker!
Face like a sprat arse, don't ya?
Porsche #58 with an unidentified Ford
are run off the track,
at Arnarge.
Nice stopwatch.
You want one? They're Italian.
Ken Miles in Ford #1,
and Bandini in Ferrari 21
are locked in a battle
against the elements
as they push their cars to the limit.
Past the White House corner.
Yes, sir? Yes, sir.
Okay, sir. Right away, sir.
Hey!
Give me that.
Dumbass.
Mr. Shelby.
Here we go.
Come on, girl. Come on.
Hold it together now.
Come on!
Leader at this moment is Ferrari #21,
being driven by Lorenzo Bandini.
His brakes are shot.
Alright, here we go.
It looks like Ken Miles is bringing
the #1 Ford into the pits very slowly.
Brakes! Nothing! Gone!
Alright. Let's go, let's go, let's go!
I had him, I almost had him!
Well, he's putting another
lap on us now.
Now, now! Faster!
They're doing it! The brakes!
Faster, faster!
Against the rules.
You can't just change things.
Oh, no, no, no.
You show me where it says in your book
that we cannot swap out the system
and then you can disqualify us.
- This is not legal.
- Calm down, calm down.
This is not legal.
You show me where it
says in that little rule book
where I can't swap out
my upright assembly.
A part is a part.
Be it a brake caliper or a rotor
or an upright assembly
and I can swap out
any damn thing I want to.
We read your damn rule book.
Bandini's pitting, He's pitting!
Oh, what a shame. I think he blew a line.
Well, he was trying to
keep up with you.
I don't speak Italian,
but he ain't happy.
Get me out of here, Pops.
Come on!
Almost set, Ken.
All yours, Ken.
Alright listen, you can still take
him, but you gotta pass him twice.
I get it, pass him twice.
Ford #1, driven by Ken Miles is back out.
Hot on the heels of Bandini in Ferrari 21.
Not bloody good enough Miles!
Come on!
He's off his pace.
He doesn't trust the car yet.
Come on, Ken.
I gave you new brakes, buddy.
Alright,
what did you come here for?
Let's do it.
That's it, come on!
He ain't done it yet.
He needs to take another lap on him.
- He needs to pit soon.
- He needs to catch Bandini first.
All right, you bastard.
Let's do this again.
Come on, girl.
That's my girl, that's my girl!
Oh my God, Oh my God!
Bloody hell!
He did it. We're in the lead.
Are we in the lead?
What about Bandini?
Where's Bandini?
He's done, finished. Ferrari's over.
McLaren's 4 minutes behind him in a GT.
So we're laying Ken first,
and 2 and 3. All Fords.
The Deuce is coming.
Ken's up in a half an hour.
Want me to wake him?
No, let him sleep.
- Unbelievable.
- Thank you.
- Good job.
- Not quite there yet, but...
There he is.
Brief me, Leo.
We're running one, two, three, Mr. Ford.
- Who's in the lead?
- Him. Miles.
I was thinking, Mr. Ford.
Wouldn't it be great
if all three Fords lined up
across the finish line at
the exact same time?
They'll lined up and came home together.
Ford, Ford, Ford.
I don't think we can actually do that, sir.
Why not?
Miles is laps ahead, Leo.
What would you have him do, slow down?
Yeah.
He thinks it'll be
a historic moment for Ford,
it'll make a great photograph.
Shelby, Miles needs to be
a team player here.
And so do you.
Are you gonna tell him or
you need me to?
Don't go near my driver. Go on.
- This is what Mr. Ford wants.
- Go on now.
- He expects loyalty.
- Go on.
Guys, let's go.
Come on, let's go.
What'd Beebe want?
It's off the scale, isn't it?
They want you to slow down.
Run that by me again.
You're outshining their car, Ken.
You're 4 minutes up on McLaren.
The Deuce wants the three Fords
across the finish line:
one, two, three, all together.
They're asking that you
be a team player.
And make that photograph
happen for 'em.
A photograph, that's good.
That is good!
Ken, even if you tie for first,
you'd still be first man ever to win
Sebring, Daytona, Le Mans
in the same year.
You'll have a triple crown.
Look, I didn't get...
I haven't been able to get you
to follow an order since day one.
Whatever you wanna do
is fine with me.
My choice?
Your choice.
Engine's running at boiling.
The brakes are shot.
How was that?
Taken care of.
The car is yours, Ken.
Ken, the car is yours.
Car is yours, Ken.
It's the Fords that are the cars
to beat, claiming the top 3 positions.
What the hell is he doing?
Don't answer that!
Get away from it!
- He's gonna break his own record.
- Shut up!
Wait for it.
Now.
Miles!
Bellissimo.
3:30.6.
That's another record.
That's a perfect lap.
And virtually guaranteeing 1st place
for Shelby American and
their exciting GT-40
Ken Miles and Shelby American's Ford #1
just beat his own lap record, 3:30.6.
Bring him in, right now!
He's outta control!
Bring him in before he wrecks that car
and we don't finish!
Bring him in, Shelby!
Or I will get you banned
from the SCCA and the FIA.
Ken Miles is behind the wheel, Leo.
That's his car to the finish.
H-a-p-p-y, I'm h-a-p-p-y,
I know I am, I'm sure I am...
Come on, lads. Where are ya?
What's he doing?
Mom, why is he slowing down?
The three Fords are going to
cross the line together.
Ken Miles slowed down.
He waited for them.
Dad? No.
- It's Alright.
- Dad.
It's Alright. He's bringing them in.
...lead by Ken Miles...
- He's bringing them all in together.
- He's certainly the leader of this group.
Good for you.
Good for you, Ken.
Look at that!
Well done, Leo.
You too, John.
Explain to me how he's finished first
if he's not won the race?
Because McLaren started from further,
so he came into and he won.
It's not a tie!
Because McLaren started further
back, they're saying.
He's traveled a little bit further.
So, he's won and not Ken.
That's bullshit!
Shel, hold on!
Where is the tie?
Where is the goddamn tie?
What?
You son of a bitch!
- You knew!
- I didn't, I swear.
Enough!
Nice race, mate. Congrats.
Shel!
They robbed you, Ken.
Here's the clarification, though the
drivers finished the race in a heat,
McLaren has been ruled the winner
as he started from farther back.
Some bullshit technicality.
I never should've asked you.
Selling cars, huh?
That's what they do.
Well,
you promised me the drive,
not the win.
It was a hell of a drive.
She's a hell of a machine.
She's fast.
Could be faster.
The 7 liter's sweet.
We still need a lighter chassis.
I was thinking bonded aluminum.
It's a ground up rebuild, but if it works
we can lose a couple of hundred pounds.
What the hell are we doing here?
Let me take a shower,
get a cup of tea.
Ham and cheese cob or something.
We gonna get the bastards next year.
Got a bit of fuel left in the tank.
What do you think of those honeycomb
panels. What you were looking for?
I don't know yet.
She looks pretty good.
There's a point at 7000 RPM
where everything fades.
The machine becomes
weightless, Just disappears.
And all that's left is a body
moving through space and time.
7000 RPM, that's where you need it.
You feel it coming.
It creeps up on you, close in your ear,
and asks you a question.
The only question that matters.
Get the van!
"Who are you?"
What do you think?
It's fantastic! That was really good.
Nice and smooth.
No vibration in the box.
It was really strong.
You drove her for less than an hour,
you can't tell shit after an hour.
Hey, Shel.
Hey, Shell. That guy, the one in the hat.
He's ready to close on those two 427's.
His and hers, full freight.
They flew in from Galveston.
I need you to come outside
for maybe a minute.
And do what?
Be Carroll Shelby.
Tell them a story.
Spin a few magic words.
What does that mean?
Magic words?
It means, come
outside, and say hello,
and make them feel good
about their purchase.
They're getting the damn cars.
That's what they get for their money, Phil.
Either they want them or they don't.
Am I some kind of a lounge act?!
- No.
- Am I here to talk people into things?!
It's been 6 months, Shel.
Six months.
Sometimes, they don't get
out of the car.
Peter!
Peter, come and take
the garbage out!
Mr. Shelby?
Hello, Pete.
I remember that wrench.
My Dad threw it at you.
I believe he did.
Why?
Oh.
I think I probably
said something to him.
Called him a few names.
That's right.
Do you wanna speak to my Mum?
Well, I did. I came to say hello,
check in on her and
then, I started thinking sometimes
that words just are not useful.
Tools are useful 'cause you
can make stuff with 'em,
and you can fix stuff with 'em.
Here.
Thanks.
Your Daddy was a...
He was your friend.
Yes, he was.
Yes, sir.
And he thought you was
just finer than frog fur.
Peter!
I think I've gotta go help my Mum.
What are you doing
here then? Go on.
Bye.
Subtitles by sub.Trader
subscene.com
Corrected by gabbyu's Subs,
supertooth, and Riceroll