Good night, Pat.
Good night.
What happened to the old bank?
It was beautiful.
People kept robbing it.
That's a small price to pay
for beauty.
Hit me.
Again.
Bust!
Give me credit,
Mr. Macon?
You know my rules, Tom.
Well, it looks like
you just about
cleaned everybody out,
fella.
You haven't lost a hand
since you got the deal.
What's the secret
of your success?
Prayer.
Let's just
you and me play.
Hit it.
Bust.
Yeah, you're a hell of
a card player, fella.
I know, 'cause I'm
a hell of a card player,
and I can't even spot
how you're cheating.
The money stays,
and you go.
Well, we seem to be
a little short
on brotherly love
around here.
If you're with him,
you better get out of here.
We're on our way.
I wasn't cheating.
Come on.
I wasn't cheating!
You can die.
You can both die.
You hear that?
If he invites us
to stay, then we'll go.
He's got to invite us
to stick around.
He'll draw on you.
You don't know
how fast he is.
I'm over the hill,
but it can happen to you.
That's just
what I want to hear.
Every day you get older.
That's a law.
What would you think about
maybe asking us
to stick around?
What?
You don't have to mean it
or anything.
Just ask us to stick around.
I promise...
I can't help you,
Sundance.
I didn't know you were
the Sundance Kid
when I said
you were cheating.
I draw on you,
you'll kill me.
There's that
possibility.
You'd be killing yourself.
Why don't you just invite us
to stick around?
You can do it...
and easy.
Come on.
Why don't you
stick around?
Thanks, but we
got to get going.
Hey, Kid.
Hey, Kid,
how good are you?
Like I been
telling you...
over the hill.
Boy, you know,
every time I see
Hole-In-The-Wall,
it's like seeing it
for the first time.
Every time, I ask myself
the same question...
how can I be so damn stupid
to keep coming back?
What's your idea
this time?
Bolivia.
What's Bolivia?
Bolivia... that's
a country, stupid.
Central or
South America.
One or the other.
Let's go to Mexico
instead.
All they got in Mexico
is sweat.
There's too much
of that here.
If we'd been in business
during the California gold rush,
where would we have gone?
California, right?
When I say Bolivia,
you just think California.
You wouldn't believe
what they're finding
in the ground down there.
They're just
falling into it.
Silver mines,
gold mines, tin mines.
Payrolls so heavy we'd strain
ourselves stealing them.
You just keep thinking,
Butch.
That's what you're good at.
Boy, I got vision,
and the rest of the world
wears bifocals.
Hi, News.
What you doing?
Aw, howdy, Butch.
Uh, nothing.
Nothing.
Howdy, Sundance.
You sure are. You're
doing something. What?
Just fixing to rob
the Union Pacific Flyer, Butch,
like what we had in mind.
You fellas got everything
I told you all wrong.
Sure, we might
hit the Flyer,
but even if we do,
it won't be this run.
It'll be the next one,
the return.
Sundance and me,
we been checking the banks.
No banks.
What?
The Flyer, Butch.
Fellas, bad as they are,
banks are better than trains.
They don't move.
They stay put.
You know
the money's in there.
When I left,
I gave orders.
New orders
been given.
I run things here,
Harvey.
Used to you did.
Me now.
This don't concern you.
You tell him
to stay out.
Well, he goes his own way,
like always.
What's the matter
with you guys?
When I came here,
you were nothing.
I formed you.
Who says?
Read them
a clipping, News.
Which one?
Any of them.
This one here's
from Salt Lake Herald.
"Butch Cassidy's
Hole-In-The-Wall Gang..."
That's me!
You want Harvey
to do your planning?
Want him to do your
thinking for you?
You want him
to run things?
Shut up now, News.
Not till I get
to the good part.
"Also known to have
participated in the holdup
are Flat Nose Curry
and News Carver."
I just love to read my name
in the paper, Butch.
So we just forget
about Logan taking over,
OK, Flat Nose?
You always said
that any one of us
could challenge you.
'Cause I figured
no one would do it.
Figured wrong, Butch.
You guys
can't want Logan!
At least
he's with us.
You been spending
a lot of time gone.
Well, that's because
everything's different now.
Guns or knives, Butch?
You got to plan more,
prepare more.
Guns or knives?
Neither.
Pick!
I don't want to shoot
with you, Harvey.
Anything you say, Butch.
Maybe there's a way
to make a profit in this.
Bet on Logan.
I would,
but who'd bet on you?
Sundance...
when we're done
and he's dead,
you're welcome to stay.
I don't mean to be
a sore loser,
but when it's done,
if I'm dead, kill him.
Love to.
No, no. Not yet.
Not until me and Harvey
get the rules
straightened out.
Rules in a knife fight?
No rules.
If there ain't any rules,
let's get started.
Someone count
1, 2, 3, go.
I was really rooting
for you, Butch.
Well, thank you,
Flat Nose.
That's what sustained me
in my time of trouble.
Hey, what's this
about the Flyer?
Harvey said we'd hit it
both this run
and the return.
Nobody's done that
to the Flyer before.
No matter how much
we got at first,
they'd figure
the return was safe
and load it up
with money.
Harvey thought of that?
Yes, sir, he did.
I'll tell you something,
fellas.
That's exactly what
we're going to do.
Stop it.
Where?
Up ahead there.
Bet that's old Butch
himself.
Hold it there.
Just thought I'd watch.
Bring the kids,
why don't you?
Stick your heads in.
You're just going to
get yourself blown up
you don't open
that door.
I can't do that.
I work for Mr. E.H. Harriman
of the Union Pacific
Railroad. He...
Shut up about
that E.H. Harriman stuff
and open up.
What's going on?
We got a patriot
in there.
That's young Woodcock.
He's awful dedicated.
Woodcock?
Yes, sir.
You know who we are?
You're the Hole-In-The-Wall
Gang, Mr. Cassidy.
I understand that,
but Mr. E.H. Harriman
himself give me this job.
I got to do my best.
Your best don't include
getting yourself killed.
Dynamite's ready.
Mr. E.H. Harriman himself
had the confidence...
Open the door,
or that's it.
You think
E.H. Harriman
would get himself
killed for you,
Woodcock?
I work
for Mr. E.H. Harriman
of the Union Pacific
Railroad,
and he entrusted me...
Hey, Woodcock.
Woodcock,
you all right?
Hey.
Hmm?
Whatever Harriman's
paying you ain't enough.
There ain't what I'd call
a fortune in there, Butch.
Well, just so
we come out ahead.
That's the main thing.
The Hole-In-The-Wall Gang
just robbed the Flyer
right outside of our town,
so that makes it
our responsibility
to get out there
and get after them.
You'll have to bring
your own horses.
How many of you
can bring your own guns?
How many of you will want me
to supply you with guns?
Well... come on now.
I think it's up to us
to do something, don't you?
What's the point?
They're probably
halfway
to Hole-In-The-Wall
already.
That's exactly
why we have got to hurry.
If we mount up
right now
and get out there
after them,
maybe we can head them off.
If we did that,
they'd kill us.
We don't want to let them
get away with this.
Boy, I just eat this up
with a spoon.
All right, youse two,
I want you at my party.
What party?
I'm losing
my piano player.
He's going off
to fight the war.
What war?
The war
with the Spanish.
Remember
the Maine.
Who can forget it?
I'm giving him a send-off.
so come on.
When I was a kid,
I always thought
I would grow up
to be a hero.
It's too late now.
Why'd you say something
like that?
You didn't have to say
something like that.
You want me
to go alone
and fight
the Hole-In-The-Wall Gang?
That's fine with me.
If you want your kids
to know you let me,
that's fine with me,
but I don't think
that's what you want.
Is it?
Why don't we enlist,
go fight the Spanish?
You and me in the war.
We got a lot of things
going for us...
experience, maturity,
leadership.
I'll bet
we end up officers.
I'd be Major Parker.
Parker?
Yeah.
That's my real name.
Robert Leroy Parker.
No fooling?
No.
Mine's Longbaugh.
No fooling.
Long what?
Harry Longbaugh.
So you'd be
Major Longbaugh.
What do you say?
You just keep thinking,
Butch.
That's what you're good at.
But you're not frightened.
No, sir.
You have got respect for me,
and I have got
respect for you.
That's why you
and you and you
are riding with me.
Am I right?
Well, what do you say?
I say this.
I say, ladies
and gentlemen,
boys and girls,
friends and enemies,
meet the future!
The future what?
The future mode
of transportation
for this weary
Western world.
Now, I'm not going to make
a lot of extravagant claims.
Sure, it'll change your
whole life for the better,
but that's all.
What the hell do you think
you're doing?
You got the crowd together,
so I thought I'd do
a little selling.
I'm trying to raise
a posse here.
A short presentation.
The horse is dead.
This item sells itself.
Are you going to listen
to him or come with me?
Butch, Fanny says to
come into her party
right now.
No oats, no mess,
no kicks, no bites,
no running away,
no stepping on your foot.
Well, I think
I'll get saddled up
and go looking
for a woman.
Good hunting.
Shouldn't take more
than a couple of days.
I'm not picky...
as long as she's smart,
pretty...
sweet...
gentle, and...
tender and refined...
lovely...
carefree.
Aah!
Keep going,
teacher lady.
It's OK Don't mind me.
Keep on going.
Let down your hair.
Shake your head.
Do you know
what I wish?
That once you'd get here
on time.
You are mine,
Etta Place.
Mine.
You hear me?
All mine.
Your soft white flesh
is mine.
Soft...
white...
bwhaa!
Meet the future.
Do you know
what you're doing?
Theoretically.
Aah!
You've come to get him
for the Flyer?
Would you believe
I'm broke already?
Why is there never
any money, Butch?
I swear, Etta,
I don't know.
I've been working
like a dog all my life,
and I can't get
a penny ahead.
Sundance says it's because
you're a soft touch
and always taking
expensive vacations,
buying drinks
for everyone,
and you're
a rotten gambler.
That might have
something to do with it.
Butch.
Hmm?
Do you ever wonder
if I'd met you first
we'd been the ones
to get involved?
We are involved, Etta.
Don't you know that?
You are riding
on my bicycle.
In some Arabian countries,
that's the same
as being married.
Hey.
What are you doing?
Stealing your woman.
Take her.
Well, you're
a romantic bastard.
I'll give you that.
OK, open up
in there.
I work for
Mr. E.H. Harriman...
Hey, Woodcock!
Butch?
You OK?
Uh, well, sort of.
Hey, that's wonderful.
Let's take a look at you.
Well, now, Butch,
you've got to have
more respect for me
than to think I'd fall
for a stunt like that.
You can't want to
get blown up again?
Uh, Butch, you know
if it were my money,
there's nobody I'd
rather have steal it
than you.
But I'm still
in the employ
of Mr. E.H. Harriman
of the Union Pacific
Railroad.
Start this train!
Get back inside,
lady.
I'm not afraid of you.
I'm not afraid
of anything.
I'm a grandmother
and a female,
and I've
got my rights.
We got no time
for this.
You can bull the others,
but not me.
I've fought whiskey,
and I've fought gambling...
We got no time
for this.
What are you doing?
Let go!
What are you
going to do to her?
Well,
leave her alone.
You're after
the money,
and the money's
in here.
Please! All I want
is for somebody to
start this train.
Somebody, please!
Open the door,
Woodcock,
or tell her
goodbye.
Our Father,
who art in heaven,
hallowed be Thy name,
Thy kingdom come,
Thy will be done,
on earth
as it is in heaven.
What am I going to tell
poor Mr. Harriman?
Woodcock, what'd
you have to go and do
something like that for?
Well, Butch, you blew
the last one so easy,
I just had to,
um, do something.
Give me that
and get some more,
a lot more!
Well, that
ought to do it.
Think you used enough
dynamite there, Butch?
Ha ha ha ha.
What the hell is that?
Whatever they're selling,
I don't want it.
Will you leave it?
Come on!
Hyah!
Hey, Butch!
What?
They're very good!
Split up!
How many of 'em
are following us?
All of 'em.
All of 'em?
What's the matter
with those guys?
Hyah!
I think we lost 'em.
Do you think we lost 'em?
No.
Neither do I. Hyah!
Take our horses out
back. Feed 'em good.
Where's Sweetface?
Just inside.
Trouble?
Listen,
you dirty old man,
I know you're
a lying thief
and so do you,
but who'd know it
to look at you?
Get yourself
out front fast.
You seen us
ride through
not five minutes
ago.
Do this right,
I'll get you
an old dog to kick.
Here, room 9.
Top of the stairs.
Hey, you realize
you're driving me crazy
staring out
the window like that?
I swear, Sweetface
can handle it, easy.
He wouldn't dare
louse me up.
He's that scared of me.
Hey, kid, how can I
give Agnes
the concentration
she deserves
with you staring out
the window like that?
Butch, you're
really something,
you know that?
Could you be
a little more specific
about that, Agnes?
Butch!
OK, Sweetface,
give them a nice smile.
Come on.
That's a nice touch.
I swear, if he told me
I rode out of town
10 minutes ago,
I'd believe him.
And there they go.
No, no.
Don't ask me
to stay.
You're the only
real man I ever met.
You know that, Butch?
It's not just 'cause
of all that money
you got to spend
on people. It's you.
The way you're always
looking to see
am I happy or not?
A lot of
the other girls,
they... they
might want you
for when you
got lots of money
to spend on people.
Me, I... I
don't care about...
clothes and
money and jewels...
and furs,
and
things like that.
Lots of the other
girls do,
but I never did.
I always said,
"Agnes..."
Don't move.
Stand up.
Put your hands up.
Higher.
Now turn around
and start...
Get our horses and
come on back here.
Hyah!
Get out of here!
Get out!
Go on!
Get out of here,
you fat-headed beast!
Come on!
You're the fat-headed beast.
Quit shouting!
Boy, somebody
sure trained 'em.
Which way?
Well,
it doesn't matter.
I don't know where
we've been,
and I've just
been there.
They can't follow us.
We're safe.
You really think so?
I will if you will.
How long you figure
we've been watching?
Oh, a while.
How long before you figure
they're not after us?
A while longer.
How come you're
so talkative?
Just naturally
blabby, I guess.
Ohh! I haven't done
so much riding
since I quit rustling.
That's a miserable
occupation.
Dusk to dawn,
no sleep, rotten food.
Hey.
I see it.
Torches you think?
Yeah, maybe.
Maybe lanterns.
They're
following our path.
Dead on it.
I couldn't do that.
Could you do that?
How can they do that?
Who are those guys?
You sure
this'll work?
It'll work.
That's what you said
about Sweetface.
This'll work.
Once they divide up,
we take them,
no trouble, right?
Maybe.
Boy, for a gunman,
you're one hell
of a pessimist.
They ought to get
to where we split up
any time.
They're
just about there.
How many of them do you
think will come our way?
Oh, I wish
we had rifles.
I mean,
they got rifles.
But we got surprise
on our side, right?
So far, they're
doing what we want.
You think we ought to
take them from up here?
Kid, look, you know this
work better than I do.
Is it best here,
or maybe down there,
closer to the trail?
Uh...
Damn it!
They're not
going for it.
Who are those guys?
I don't know.
We got to do something
and shake them.
Whatever
you come up with
is fine with me,
but whatever it is,
it better be now!
What are you
doing here?
Easy, Ray. Easy.
What the hell do you mean,
take it easy?
You promised you'd never
come into my territory.
And we haven't.
Just because
we were friendly
doesn't give you
the right to break in.
What if we was
seen together?
I'm too old
to find another job.
At least have the decency
to draw your guns.
Listen, Butch is trying
to tell you something.
All right.
What do you want?
A couple of things.
We want to enlist, Ray.
In the army.
Right away.
Go fight the Spanish.
Oh, you're crazy.
You are crazy.
You are,
both of you, crazy!
They'd throw you in jail
for a thousand years each.
Come on, Sundance.
Start trussing my feet.
Here. You seen these
before. Come on!
I'm not taking
the chance
that someone
saw you coming in.
We're serious about this.
You are known outlaws.
We'd quit.
That's the point.
Is that on tight?
That's all right.
There's some hankies
in the drawer
you can use
to gag me.
I swear,
this'd work, Ray.
You trust us.
The government trusts you.
Anything you tell them
they gotta believe, right?
You've never done
a dishonest thing ever,
and you're pushing 60.
We'd quit.
They'd drop the charges
against us,
we'd fight till
the war is over.
They don't even have
to make us officers.
That's some proposition.
They forget
all about the years
of thieving and robbing.
They take you
into the army,
which is what you want
in the first place.
There's something
out there
that scares you, huh?
But it's too late.
You should've let
yourself get killed
while you had
the chance.
You may be the biggest
thing to hit this area,
but you're still
two-bit outlaws.
I never met a soul more
affable than you, Butch,
or faster than the Kid.
But you're still
two-bit outlaws
on the dodge.
It's over!
Don't you get that?
Your times is over,
and you're gonna
die bloody,
and all you can do
is choose where.
I'm sorry,
I'm getting mean
in my old age.
Come on. Shut me up,
Sundance.
Ah, you're wasting
your time.
They can't track us
over rock.
Tell them that.
They're beginning
to get on my nerves.
Who are those guys?
You remember the time
you, me, and Etta
went to Denver
for a vacation?
I'm glad you
brought that up, Kid.
That's an important topic,
considering our situation.
The night we went
gambling, remember?
We had dinner
at the hotel.
Etta had roast beef,
and I had chicken.
If I can remember
what you had,
I'll die happy.
Look out there.
What?
I got to talking to
some gambler that night.
He told us
about an Indian...
full-blooded Indian,
except he used
an English name,
Sir... somebody.
Lord Baltimore?
That's right, and he
could track anybody
over anything
day or night.
So?
The guy on the ground,
I think it's him.
No. Baltimore works
out of Oklahoma.
He's strictly
an Oklahoma man.
I don't know
where we are,
but it isn't Oklahoma.
Ah, it couldn't be him.
It couldn't be him.
I guess.
Whoever it is,
it sure the hell
is somebody.
Damn it!
Don't they get tired?
Don't they get hungry?
They've gotta be.
Why don't they
slow up?
They could even
go faster.
At least that'd
be a change.
They don't even
break formation.
Do something!
Kid.
What?
Who's the best
lawman?
Best? How?
You mean toughest
or easiest to bribe?
Toughest.
Joe LeFors.
Gotta be.
LeFors never leaves
Wyoming. Never.
You know that.
He always wears
a white skimmer.
That's how you tell
it's Joe LeFors,
'cause he wears
a white straw hat.
Look at that guy
out front.
Jesus, who are those guys?
Hyah!
Come on now.
Here you go, Kid.
Go on! Get out of here!
Go on!
What if they don't
follow the horse?
You're the brains,
Butch.
You'll think
of something.
Damn it!
The way I figure it,
we can either fight
or give.
If we give,
we go to jail.
I've been there already.
If we fight,
they can stay
where they are
and starve us out...
or go for position,
shoot us.
Might even get
a rock slide started.
What else can they do?
They could surrender to us,
but I wouldn't
count on that.
They're going for
position, all right.
Better get ready.
Kid, the next time
I say
let's go someplace
like Bolivia,
like Bolivia.
Next time.
Ready?
No. We'll jump.
Like hell we will.
No. It'll be O.K.
if the water's
deep enough
and we don't get
squished to death.
They'll never follow us.
How do you know?
Would you jump that
if you didn't have to?
I have to,
and I'm not gonna.
We got to.
Otherwise we're dead.
Come on.
Just one clear shot...
that's all I want.
I want to fight them!
They'll kill us.
Maybe.
You want to die?
Do you?
All right,
I'll jump first.
No.
Then you jump first.
No, I said.
What's the matter?
I can't swim!
Why, you crazy?
The fall will
probably kill you.
Oh-oh...
ohhh...
shiiiit!
Hang on to me.
You're drowning me!
I can't help it.
I can't swim.
You're choking me!
I can't swim!
I'm telling you,
if I drown,
I swear to God
I'll kill you.
Never said I was
a great swimmer.
Oh! You're choking me!
Oh! I'm choking!
Let go of me.
I'm choking!
Let go of my throat.
The papers said
they had you.
Was it LeFors?
Did they say?
Joe LeFors?
I think so.
And their tracker?
Tracker?
Was it Lord Baltimore?
I think so.
The paper's inside.
You got enough
to feed us?
Don't you know I do?
They said you were dead.
Don't make a big thing
out of it.
No. Make a big thing
Hey.
It was Baltimore
and LeFors.
You know who else?
Who?
Jeff Carr,
George Hiatt...
Hiatt?
T.T. Kelliher.
We lucked out getting away.
You know that?
Why would these guys
join up
and take after us, though?
Forget it.
Bunch like that
won't stay together
long.
They will...
if Mr. Harriman
has his way.
Who?
Mr. E.H. Harriman
of the Union Pacific
Railroad.
He resents the way you've
been picking on him,
so he's outfitted
a special train
and hired
special employees.
You've been avoiding them
for two days.
It's really
sort of flattering
if you want to think
about it that way.
A setup like that
costs more
than we ever took.
Apparently
he can afford it.
That crazy Harriman.
That's bad business.
How long
do you think
I'd stay
in operation
if every job
cost me money?
If he'd just pay me
what he's spending
to make me
stop robbing him,
I'd stop
robbing him.
You probably inherited
every penny you got!
Inherited guys,
what the hell
do they know?
You say they were
hired permanent?
No. Just till
they kill you.
That means they're still
after us, Butch,
and it's going to be
the same thing
all over again.
They'll show up here...
sooner or later.
Hey, Etta.
I'll get you
some more.
Butch and me have been
talking it all over.
Wherever the hell
Bolivia is,
that's where we're off to.
We'll go down there
and play it safe,
maybe keep our hand in
a little bit.
Butch speaks some Spanish.
I can wrestle
with a menu O.K.
And you speak it good.
And it'd be good cover
going with a woman.
No one expects it.
Then we could
travel safer.
What I'm saying is,
if you want to go,
I won't stop you,
but the minute
you start to whine
or make a nuisance,
I don't care
where we are,
I'm dumping you flat.
Don't sugarcoat it
like that, Kid.
Tell her straight.
I'm 26, and I'm single
and a schoolteacher,
and that's the
bottom of the pit.
And the only excitement
I've known
is here with me now.
So I'll go with you,
and I won't whine,
and I'll sew
your socks,
and I'll stitch you
when you're wounded,
and I'll do anything
you ask of me
except one thing.
I won't watch you die.
I'll miss that scene,
if you don't mind.
The future's all yours,
you lousy bicycles.
Well, you know,
it could be worse.
You get a lot more
for your money in Bolivia.
I checked on it.
What could they have here
that you could possibly
want to buy?
Jeez, all Bolivia
can't look like this.
How do you know?
This might be
the garden spot
of the whole country.
People may travel
hundreds of miles
just to get to this spot
where we're standing now.
This might be
the Atlantic City, New Jersey,
of all Bolivia
for all you know.
I know more
about Bolivia
than you know about
Atlantic City, New Jersey,
I can tell you that.
Aha!
You do, huh?
I was born there.
I was born
in New Jersey...
brought up there, so...
I didn't know that.
The total tonnage
of what you don't know
is enough to shatter...
We're not
accomplishing
as much as we might.
Listen, your job
is to back me up,
because you'd starve
without me.
And you,
your job is to shut up.
He'll feel a lot better
after he's robbed
a couple of banks.
Ha ha ha ha!
Bolivia.
Hell,
it's just a bank
like any other bank.
You got to
move in slowly,
check out
everything.
The thing
to remember...
Don't tell me
how to rob a bank.
I know how
to rob a bank.
A few dark clouds
appear on your horizon,
and you just go all
to pieces, don't you?
Buenos das, seores.
Les puedo servir
en algo?
Ordenen para atenderlos
por favor inmediatamente.
Quieren hacer
algn depsito?
Quieren abrir
una cuenta?
Bien, el cajero los
atienda inmediatamente.
Los atendemos por todo.
Seor?
Adis.
This is a robbery.
Esto es un robo.
This is supposed to be
a unison recitation.
Why do I have to
do any of this?
He's the one
who claimed he knew
the language.
Your line of work requires
a specialized vocabulary.
I got nervous. I forgot
the words. Shoot me.
You've had
worse ideas lately.
Raise
your hands.
Uh... las manos arriba.
Raise them.
Arriba.
All of you back
against the wall.
Todos ustedes, um...
arrmense a la pared.
Give me the money.
This is not
going to work,
and we're going to be
up all night
until you get this.
Now give me the money.
It's on the tip
of my tongue, Etta.
I swear it.
Butch, are you still
thinking in there?
What the hell else
is there to do?
Try this one.
Where is the safe?
Open it.
Dnde es...
Uh, that's a hard one.
Dnde est la caja?
brala!
That's very good, Butch.
You're a good teacher,
Etta.
Esto es un robo!
Manos a...
Manos, um...
Manos arriba!
They got them up!
Skip down!
- Arriba!
- Skip on down!
Todos ustedes arrsmense
a la pared.
They're against
the wall already!
Dnde es...
Oh, you're so damn smart,
you read it.
A goddamn crib sheet.
You almost blew it.
You sure didn't help much.
You can't do anything
without a crib sheet.
For God's sake,
don't drop the money!
I won't drop the money!
Voy a traer
el comisario.
S, vamos.
Ay, nombre.
Evarista.
Evarista qu?
Seor comandante,
dos hombres acometen
y asaltan el banco.
Dos yanquis
y una muchacha
se fueron por la caada.
Se llevaron mi pistola
y todo el dinero.
Vmanos!
A caballos!
Isn't that
a pretty sight?
Well, we're back in business,
boys and girls,
just like the old days.
Let's stay here
and get him
and be done with it.
But what if
we lose?
We saw him
with two guys.
What if he's got 20?
You don't know for sure
it's LeFors.
I'm a hell of a guesser.
He can't arrest you.
It's a foreign country.
He can't take you back.
He's not going to
take anybody back.
He's going to
wait for us
to pull
another job
and then
hunt us down.
Let's finish it now,
Butch,
one way
or the other.
He's got to wait for us
to pull another job.
Well, what if there isn't
another job?
He can't arrest us,
and he can't take us
out of here.
We'll drive him crazy.
We'll outlast
the bastard.
We'll go straight.
So you want jobs.
You're from the U.S. of A.,
and you are seeking
after employment.
Well, you couldn't
have picked
a more
out of the way place
in all of Bolivia,
I'll tell you that.
Gracias, Jess.
Ordinarily
you've got to wait
to work for
Percy Garrison,
but this ain't
ordinarily.
Bingo.
You mean there are jobs.
Yes, there are jobs.
There are lots
of jobs.
Don't you want to
know why?
Yeah, why?
Damn it.
Because I cannot
promise to pay you.
Don't you want to
know why?
OK, why?
On account of
the payroll thieves,
fellow citizens.
You see,
every mine around
gets its payroll
from La Paz.
And every
mine around
gets its payroll
held up.
Some say it's the
Bolivian Bandits,
and some say
that it's the
bandidos yanquis.
Could I see that?
Mm-hmm.
Fairly nice-looking
piece.
Can you hit
anything?
Sometimes.
Hit that.
No, no, son.
No, son.
I just want to know,
can you shoot
your piece?
Shoot.
Damn it.
Can I move?
Move?
What the hell
you mean, move?
I'm better
when I move.
Yeah.
Well, considering
that I'm desperate
and you're just what
I'm looking for,
on top of which
you stem
from the U.S. of A.,
we start
tomorrow morning.
You mean we got jobs.
Payroll guard.
Damn.
Vmanos
a trabajar!
Hey, Chucho!
Chucho!
I think they're in
the trees up ahead.
In the bushes
on the left.
They're in the trees
up ahead.
You take the trees,
I'll take
the bushes.
Will you two beginners
cut it out?
Well, we're just trying
to spot an ambush.
Morons.
I've got morons
on my team.
Nobody is going to
rob us
going down the mountain.
We have got no money
When we have got
the money
on the way back,
then you can sweat.
Bingo.
Move it out!
Move it!
We hit this place
in June, didn't we?
Jones!
Give me a hand
over here.
Who am I,
Smith or Jones?
Live.
About
a half hour more,
and we can start
to worry...
as soon as we get
to that pass
up there.
We'll be all right
till then.
They might
try something here.
No. Better cover
up there.
You got to relax,
you fellas.
You got to get used
to Bolivian ways.
You got to go easy.
Damn it!
Like I do.
Of course, you probably
think I'm crazy,
but I'm not.
Bingo.
I'm colorful.
That's what happens
when you live 10 years
alone in Bolivia.
You get colorful.
Where are they?
I can't see them.
Let's get
out of here.
Tell them to leave
the money and go.
Dijen el dinoro...
Dinero...
and, uh...
y vyanese.
Que dejemos el dinero
y nos vayamos?
Tell them
we were hired
to take it back.
It's our job.
Tell them the money
isn't ours.
El dinero...
no es nuestro.
No, ya no es de ustedes.
Ahora es de nosotros.
Claro.
We'll try
telling them again.
It's our job.
The money isn't ours.
El dinero
no es nuestro.
Lo necesitamos.
Tambin nosotros
necesitamos.
What do you think?
Not so good.
Can you take the two
on the right?
Kid, there's something
I think I ought to tell you.
I never shot
anybody before.
One hell of a time
to tell me.
Try for the two
on the right
dead center.
That way, if you
miss a little,
you'll still
hit something.
Go.
Please.
Qu?
Por favor.
Por favor?
Aah!
Well,
we've gone straight.
What'll we try now?
There are other ways of
going straight, you know.
There are other ways
of going straight.
There's farming.
We could buy a place.
I don't know
how to farm.
What about a ranch,
then?
I don't know.
The last time
we tried ranching
was during
our rustling days.
Even then,
we weren't much good
at it.
It's hard.
Hours are brutal.
No, you got to be
a kid
to start a ranch.
Hey.
Hmm?
I might go back
ahead of you.
You mean home?
I was thinking of it.
Whatever you want, Etta.
Maybe I'll go.
Hey.
Hmm?
Etta's thinking of, uh,
maybe going home
ahead of us.
Whatever she wants.
I'll go, then.
Manos arriba!
How much you got?
It's hardly worth it.
Alpoca mine.
I tell you, no more
jungle work for me.
You're getting
to be an old maid.
Keep your old maid
remarks to yourself.
I'll work in the city,
in the mountains,
but from now on
jungle work is out.
Bandidos yanquis?
Mm-hmm.
Tell them to be quiet.
What's the word?
Quietas.
I tell you,
the jungle's a better
cover for payrolls.
Kid, I got a right
to my opinion,
and in my opinion,
there are snakes
in the jungle.
I don't work
around snakes.
What is this place?
I don't know.
San Vincente,
I think.
Comer?
Si, Seor.
Pasen.
Juan, ven.
Llvate los caballos.
I don't enjoy jungles.
I don't enjoy swamps.
I don't like snakes.
I don't much care
for night work.
Bitch, bitch, bitch.
Capitn! Capitn!
Capitn,
all en la plaza,
hay una mula
de las minas de Alpoca.
Las minas de Alpoca?
S, s. All estn.
Dos hombres la acaban
de traer.
Estn comiendo en el
restaurante de mi pap.
El guisado
est delicioso.
Para chuparse
los dedos.
Si quieren mas, es
la especialidad de la casa,
si quieren mas,
no tengan pena
y dganmelo.
Yo estoy aqu
para servirles.
Agradezco la visita de tan
distinguidos caballeros.
Muchas gracias.
Para servirles.
S.
The specialty
of the house,
and it's
still moving.
Well, that settles it.
This place gets no more
of my business.
Hey.
What?
What do you think?
I bet it's just one guy.
Don't you get sick of
being right all the time?
Reloading.
That's all I got.
We're going to run out
unless we can get to that
mule and get some more.
I'll go.
This is no time for bravery.
I'll let you.
Loaded.
Hell!
I'm the one
that has to go.
Why you?
'Cause I could never
give you cover.
You can cover me.
You can see I'm right,
can't you?
You go.
Yeah, why am I always
so damn smart?
Here.
Go.
O.K.
Ah!
Is... Is that what you call
giving cover?
Is that what
you call running?
If I knew you were
going to stroll...
You never could shoot,
not from
the very beginning.
And you are all mouth.
Jefe, llega el ejrcito.
Mi capitn.
Dnde estn?
All en la plaza.
Cuntos hombres son?
Dos hombres.
Dos hombres?
Mi capitn,
por favor...
Dos?
Bandidos yanquis.
Bandidos yanquis, eh?
S, mi capitn.
Hmm.
Sargento Rico,
desmonten 20 hombres
y vayan con el teniente.
I've got a great idea
where we should go next.
I don't want
to hear it.
You'll change your mind.
Shut up!
OK, O.K.
Your ideas
got us here.
Forget it!
I never want to hear
another of your ideas.
All right.
O.K.
Australia.
I figured secretly
you wanted to know,
so I told you.
Australia.
That's your great idea?
Oh, boy,
it's the latest in...
in a long line.
Australia's
no better than here.
Aw, that's all you know.
Name me one thing.
They speak English
in Australia.
They do?
That's right, smart guy.
So we wouldn't be
foreigners.
They got horses in Australia.
They got thousands of miles
we could hide out in.
And a good climate,
nice beaches.
You could learn to swim.
No!
Swimming
isn't important.
What about the banks?
They're easy.
Easy, ripe,
and luscious.
The banks
or the women?
Well, once you've got one,
you've got the other.
It's a long way,
isn't it?
Aw! Everything's
got to be perfect with you.
I don't want
to get there
and find out
it stinks.
At least
think about it.
All right.
I'll think about it.
Hey.
When we get outside...
and we get to the horses,
just remember one thing.
Hey, wait a minute.
What?
You didn't see LeFors
out there, did you?
LeFors?
No.
Oh, good.
For a moment there,
I thought we were
in trouble.
Fuego!