♪ GOLD ♪
♪ GOT A DREAM, BOY ♪
♪ GOT A SONG ♪
♪ PAINT YOUR WAGON ♪
♪ AND COME ALONG ♪
♪ WHERE AM I
GOIN'? I DON'T KNOW ♪
♪ WHERE AM I HEADIN'?
I AIN'T CERTAIN ♪
♪ ALL I KNOW IS I AM ON MY WAY ♪
♪ WHEN WILL I BE
THERE? I DON'T KNOW ♪
♪ WHEN WILL I GET
THERE? I AIN'T CERTAIN ♪
♪ ALL I KNOW IS I AM ON MY WAY ♪
[COCKNEY ACCENT]
♪ GOT A DREAM, BOY ♪
♪ GOT A SONG ♪
♪ PAINT YOUR WAGON ♪
♪ ET ALLONS-Y ♪
♪ OU NOUS ALLONS?
JE NE SAIS PAS ♪
[SINGING IN SWEDISH]
[SINGING IN GERMAN]
[SINGING IN CHINESE]
[SINGING IN RUSSIAN]
♪ GOT A DREAM, BOY ♪
♪ GOT A SONG ♪
♪ PAINT YOUR WAGON ♪
♪ AND COME ALONG ♪
♪ WHERE AM I
GOIN'? I DON'T KNOW ♪
♪ WHEN WILL I BE
THERE? I AIN'T CERTAIN ♪
♪ WHAT WILL I GET? I
AIN'T EQUIPPED TO SAY ♪
♪ BUT WHO GIVES A DAMN? ♪
♪ WHO GIVES A DAMN? ♪
♪ WE'RE ON OUR WAY ♪
♪ WHERE AM I
GOIN'? I DON'T KNOW ♪
♪ WHERE AM I HEADIN'?
I AIN'T CERTAIN ♪
♪ ALL I KNOW IS I AM ON MY WAY ♪
♪ WHEN WILL I BE
THERE? I DON'T KNOW ♪
♪ WHEN WILL I GET
THERE? I AIN'T CERTAIN ♪
♪ ALL I KNOW IS I AM ON MY WAY ♪
♪ WHERE AM I
GOIN'? I DON'T KNOW ♪
♪ WHERE AM I HEADIN'?
I AIN'T CERTAIN ♪
♪ ALL I KNOW IS I AM ON MY WAY ♪
♪ WHEN WILL I BE
THERE? I DON'T KNOW ♪
♪ WHEN WILL I GET
THERE? I AIN'T CERTAIN ♪
♪ ALL I KNOW IS I AM ON MY WAY ♪
♪ GOT A DREAM, BOY ♪
♪ GOT A SONG ♪
♪ AND COME ALONG ♪
♪ WHERE AM I
GOIN'? I DON'T KNOW ♪
♪ WHEN WILL I BE
THERE? I AIN'T CERTAIN ♪
♪ WHAT WILL I GET? I
AIN'T EQUIPPED TO SAY ♪
♪ BUT WHO GIVES A DAMN? ♪
♪ WHO GIVES A DAMN? ♪
♪ WE'RE... ♪♪
FARMERS.
LET'S GO.
WHOA! HOLD IT.
THERE IT IS!
GET OVER HERE.
NOW STOP IT!
HELLO!
IS...
THEY...
DEAD?
THEY'D...
BETTER BE...
'CAUSE I'M GONNA BURY 'EM!
LET'S GO.
[CHICKEN CLUCKS]
[CHICKEN SQUAWKS]
AAH... AAH...
AAH...
MY BROTHER.
HE'S DEAD.
SHOULDER AND LEG IS
PRETTY BADLY BROKEN.
YOU A DOCTOR?
HORSE DOCTOR,
BUT BONES IS BONES.
ALSO A BLACKSMITH.
BRING BROTHER.
LITTLE MORE IN THE CENTER.
OH, GOD...
WE PASS ON TO YOU
THE BODY AND SOUL
OF THIS NAMELESS PECKERHEAD.
WELL, AT LEAST HE WENT QUICK,
AND HE AIN'T GOING
TO HAVE TO SUFFER
THROUGH THE SCURVY,
THE DYSENTERY,
THE SPOTTED FEVER, THE
CHOLERA, OR THE AGUE,
NOT TO MENTION
THEM OTHER MALADIES
CONTRACTED IN A
CONSORT WITH LOW WOMEN,
OR WASTE YEARS
DIGGING IN THE DIRT
AND FINDING DIRT
LIKE I'VE BEEN DOING.
TALK ABOUT HIM!
YOU WANT TO BE NEXT?
AND SEEING HOW HE
SURVIVED ALL THAT,
HE COULD HAVE
BEEN HIT BY TIMBER,
FALL DOWN A SHAFT, STARVED,
GET MURDERED,
OR COMMITTED SUICIDE
ON CHRISTMAS EVE.
WHAT I'M SAYING, GOD, IS,
YOU DON'T HAVE NO
PITY FOR YOUR CHILDREN
WHEN THEY LIVING,
SO THAT'S WHY WE'RE ASKING YOU
TO BE A LITTLE KINDER
TO 'EM WHEN THEY DEAD.
SO, WITH ALL DUE
REVERENCE, LORD,
WE PASS ON TO YOU
THIS CORNCRACKER'S BODY AND SOUL
TO TAKE HIM AND TO KEEP HIM...
I STAKE THIS CLAIM
FOR ME AND MY NEW
PARDNER OVER THERE,
WHATEVER THE HELL HIS NAME IS...
FOREVER AND EVER.
AMEN.
PULL HIM UP.
♪ GOT A DREAM, BOY ♪
♪ GOT A SONG ♪
♪ PAINT YOUR WAGON ♪
♪ AND COME ALONG ♪
♪ WHERE AM I
GOIN'? I DON'T KNOW ♪
♪ WHERE AM I HEADIN'?
I AIN'T CERTAIN ♪
♪ ALL I KNOW IS I AM ON MY WAY ♪
♪ WHEN WILL I BE
THERE? I DON'T KNOW ♪
♪ WHEN WILL I GET
THERE? I AIN'T CERTAIN ♪
♪ ALL I KNOW IS I AM ON MY WAY ♪
♪ GOT A DREAM, BOY ♪
♪ GOT A SONG ♪
♪ PAINT YOUR WAGON ♪
♪ AND COME ALONG ♪
♪ WHERE AM I
GOIN'? I DON'T KNOW ♪
♪ WHEN WILL I BE
THERE? I AIN'T CERTAIN ♪
♪ WHAT WILL I GET? I
AIN'T EQUIPPED TO SAY-AY ♪
♪ BUT WHO GIVES A DAMN? ♪
♪ WHO GIVES A DAMN? ♪
♪ WE'RE ON OUR WAY ♪♪
♪ I STILL SEE ELISA ♪
♪ SHE KEEPS ON RETURNING ♪
♪ AS BREATHLESS ♪
♪ AND YOUNG ♪
♪ AS EVER ♪
♪ I STILL HEAR ELISA ♪
♪ AND STILL FEEL A YEARNING ♪
♪ TO HOLD HER AGAINST ME AGAIN ♪
♪ HER HEART WAS
MADE OF HOLIDAYS ♪
♪ HER SMILE WAS MADE OF DAWN ♪
♪ HER LAUGHTER
WAS AN APRIL SONG ♪
♪ THAT ECHOES ON AND ON ♪
♪ SINCE I SAW ELISA ♪
♪ THE SHADOWS ARE FALLING ♪
♪ AND WINTER IS CALLING ABOVE ♪
♪ BUT I STILL SEE ELISA ♪
♪ WHENEVER I DREAM ♪
♪ OF LOVE ♪
ELISA... THAT THE
NAME OF YOUR GIRL?
YEAH.
OH, I FOUND THIS.
I THOUGHT IT MIGHT MAKE
A GOOD CRUTCH FOR YOU
NOW THAT YOU SEEM TO BE
GETTING AROUND PRETTY GOOD.
THANKS.
YOU KNOW,
IT JUST DON'T SEEM
RIGHT, MR. RUMSON...
YOU DOING ALL THE WORK
AND ME GETTING HALF.
I MEAN, IT'S YOUR MULE,
YOUR TOOLS AND ALL.
WELL, IT WAS YOUR BROTHER.
WELL...
WHERE I COME FROM, MR. RUMSON,
WE'RE CAUTIOUS OF STRANGERS
WHO TALK IN AN EASY MANNER.
OH, YOU GOT ME DOWN
FOR SOME KIND OF LOW SCUFF
FROM NEW ORLEANS, HMM?
SELL YOU PATENT
MEDICINE WITH ONE HAND,
PINCH YOUR PURSE WITH THE OTHER?
MATTER OF FACT, THAT'S
KIND OF WHAT I WAS THINKING.
AS A MATTER OF FACT,
PARDNER, YOU'RE RIGHT,
BUT I AIN'T YET SUNK
TO HORSE STEALING.
OH, I'VE SALTED CLAIMS, YEAH.
I'VE SOLD WHISKEY TO INJUNS.
ONCE, A MAN IN WALLA
WALLA COME AT ME WITH A GUN,
AND I KILLED HIM.
I CAN'T THINK OF ONE COMMANDMENT
I AIN'T SHATTERED REGULAR.
I NEVER DID FANCY MY
MOTHER AND FATHER,
LET ALONE RESPECT
THEM OR HONOR THEM,
AND I HAVE COVETED
MY NEIGHBOR'S WIFE...
WHENEVER I HAD A NEIGHBOR
AND WHENEVER HE HAD A WIFE.
MM-MMM.
AND I GAMBLE, AND
I CHEAT AT CARDS,
BUT THERE IS ONE
THING I DO NOT DO.
I AIN'T NEVER GULLED A PARDNER.
THE ONE SACRED THING,
EVEN TO LOW SCUFF LIKE ME,
IS A MAN'S PARDNER.
2 PENNYWEIGHT SHORT OF 4 OUNCES.
NOW YOU PASS ME YOUR POUCH.
I'LL POUR YOUR SHARE.
AND, PARDNER,
I'LL SWAP POUCHES WITH
YOU ANYTIME YOU SAY.
WELL...
I MEANT NO OFFENSE, MR. RUMSON,
AND I APPRECIATE YOU
SAVING MY LIFE AND ALL.
YOU JUST WANT TO KNOW WHAT'S
EXPECTED OF YOU IN RETURN.
THAT'S RIGHT.
I LIKE TO KNOW WHAT
CROPS I'M PLANTING.
WELL, WHEN I GET DEAD DRUNK,
FALL IN A MUDDY STREET,
I EXPECT YOU TO COME GET ME,
'CAUSE I DON'T WANT
TO DIE MUDDY DRUNK.
IF I OWE A MAN $100,
STAND GOOD FOR ME,
AND IF I GET MELANCHOLY,
WHICH CAN HAPPEN,
I EXPECT YOU TO BE MY
COMPANION AND SOLACE ME.
WHAT HAPPENS WHEN
YOU GET IN A FIGHT?
WELL, IF 4 OF ANYTHING
COME AT ME AT ONE TIME,
YOU MIGHT LEND A FIST.
UP UNTIL THAT,
I CAN PRETTY WELL
TAKE CARE OF MYSELF.
YOU SEE, I DON'T FIGHT FAIR.
WELL, I DON'T FIGHT AT ALL
UNLESS I ABSOLUTELY HAVE TO.
I GOT KIND OF A TEMPER,
AND ONCE I START,
I JUST CAN'T QUIT.
WELL, GOOD.
JUST REMEMBER
THAT I'M ON YOUR SIDE.
WELL...
I HEAR A SHOPKEEPER'S
PULLED INTO TOWN
WITH A WAGON FULL OF WHISKEY.
WHAT DO YOU SAY I
HOIST YOU UP THAT MULE
AND WE GO GET BOILED?
OH, I AIN'T A BOOZING
MAN EITHER, MR. RUMSON.
WELL, I AM.
[MAN] TOWN MEETING TONIGHT!
THERE'S GOING TO BE A
TOWN MEETING TONIGHT!
TOWN MEETING TONIGHT, BEN.
BLAAH!
BEN! BEN RUMSON!
MOONEY! THIS IS MY PARDNER.
I THOUGHT YOU WERE ON
YOUR WAY BACK TO IRELAND.
WELL, I AM. I'M JUST
PASSING THROUGH HERE.
IT'S RIGHT ON THE WAY, YOU KNOW.
MOONEY.
HOW'S IT GOING, WILLIE?
I AIN'T WON A HAND
IN 3 WEEKS, BEN.
THIS IS MY PARDNER.
HE CALLS HIMSELF
ROTTEN LUCK WILLIE,
BUT THAT'S JUST TO
GET THE SUCKERS.
YOU COULDN'T BEAT
HIM WITH 5 ACES,
SO DON'T PLAY WITH HIM.
OH, I DON'T GAMBLE.
UH-HUH. NEITHER DOES HE.
[SNORING]
MY NAME'S BEN RUMSON.
THIS HERE'S MY PARDNER,
AND I'M BUYING WHISKEY
FOR ANY MAN THAT CAN STAND UP.
AHA!
HEY, I WAS SITTING THERE.
NOW YOU'RE STANDING THERE.
GIVE HIM A WHISKEY.
BEN RUMSON,
YOU HAVE AN OUTSTANDING ACCOUNT
IN THE AMOUNT OF
$68 FROM YUBA CITY,
AND WHICH YOU
SKIPPED TOWN ON ME.
SKIPPED TOWN ON YOU?
I WAS RUN OUT. DON'T
YOU REMEMBER, GUS?
I WANT TO BE PAID NOW
BEFORE THEY RUN
YOU OUT OF THIS TOWN.
PUT THAT DAMN GUN DOWN
AND STAND THESE
BOYS THE WHISKEY I SAID.
DRY YOUR HANDS
BEFORE YOU WEIGH IT.
CHIEF, ME AND MY PARDNER
NEED SOME SUPPLIES.
A POUND OF SUGAR,
A HALF A CASE OF WHISKEY,
AND A CASE OF PNEUMONIA
FOR SCHERMERHORN THERE.
A POUND OF SUGAR
AND A 2-POUND SACK
OF FLOUR, PLEASE.
EVENING.
HORACE TABOR,
WORCESTER, MASSACHUSETTS.
WHEN DID YOU GET IN?
ARRIVED THIS MORNING.
HIT A VEIN THIS AFTERNOON,
AND I AIM TO BE BACK
IN WORCESTER BY CHRISTMAS.
IT SAYS HERE
CALIFORNIA'S GOING TO
BE ADMITTED TO THE UNION.
JUST WHAT IT NEEDS...
LAW AND ORDER.
THAT'S GOOD NEWS.
WELL, IT AIN'T TO ME.
IT'S MY POLICY TO BUST
OUT OF ANY TERRITORY
THE DAY IT BECOME A STATE AND
HEAD FOR ANOTHER WILDERNESS.
I DON'T AGREE, SIR.
WELL, I DON'T WANT
TO HEAR ABOUT IT.
ALL I KNOW IS, YOU LOOK
AROUND AT THE HUMAN RACE,
YOU GOT TO WONDER WHAT THE
HELL GOD WAS THINKING ABOUT.
OH! OH!
OH, OH, OH!
♪ GOD MADE THE MOUNTAINS ♪
♪ GOD MADE THE SKY ♪
♪ GOD MADE THE PEOPLE ♪
♪ GOD KNOWS WHY ♪
♪ HE FIXED UP THE PLANET ♪
♪ AS BEST AS HE COULD ♪
♪ THEN IN COME THE PEOPLE ♪
♪ AND GUM IT UP GOOD ♪
♪ THE FIRST THING YA KNOW ♪
♪ THEY CIVILIZE THE FOOTHILLS ♪
♪ AND EVERYWHERE HE PUT HILLS ♪
♪ THE MOUNTAINS
AND VALLEYS BELOW ♪
♪ THEY COME ALONG AND TAKE 'EM ♪
♪ AND CIVILIZE AND MAKE 'EM ♪
♪ A PLACE WHERE NO
CIVILIZED PERSON WOULD GO ♪
♪ THE FIRST THING YA KNOW ♪
♪ THE FIRST THING YOU KNOW ♪
♪ THEY CIVILIZE WHAT'S PRETTY ♪
♪ BY PUTTIN' UP A CITY ♪
♪ WHERE NOTHIN' THAT'S
PRETTY CAN GROW ♪
♪ THEY MUDDY UP THE WINTER ♪
♪ AND CIVILIZE IT INTER A
PLACE TOO UNCIVILIZED ♪
♪ EVEN FOR SNOW ♪
♪ THE FIRST THING YA KNOW ♪
♪ THEY CIVILIZE LEFT ♪
♪ THEY CIVILIZE RIGHT ♪
♪ TILL NOTHIN' IS LEFT ♪
♪ TILL NOTHIN' IS RIGHT ♪
♪ THEY CIVILIZE FREEDOM
TILL NO ONE IS FREE ♪
♪ NO ONE EXCEPT ♪
♪ BY COINCIDENCE, ME ♪
♪ THE FIRST THING YA KNOW ♪
♪ THE BOOZER'S IN PRISON ♪
♪ AND THE CRIMINAL, HE ISN'T ♪
♪ AND ONLY THE
RASCALS HAVE DOUGH ♪
♪ WHEN I SEE A PARSON ♪
♪ I GOTTA PUT MY
ARSE IN THE WAGON ♪
♪ THAT FOLLOWS
THE TAIL OF A CROW ♪
♪ THE FIRST THING YA KNOW ♪
♪ I PICK UP AND BLOW ♪
♪ THE FIRST THING
YOU KNOW-OH-OH-OH ♪♪
BEN!
BEN RUMSON!
YOU BLOODY OLD RUMPOT!
MAD JACK DUNCAN!
WELL, THIS IS MY PARDNER.
I HEARD YOU WAS IN TOWN.
WAIT TILL I TELL
YOU WHAT HAPPENED
TO HARRY AND ERNEST AND ME.
WE NEVER WENT HOME.
WE'RE HAVING A DANCE. JUMP IN!
HEY, CLIMB ON, PARDNER.
WE'RE GOING TO A DANCE!
♪ OUT THE WINDER GO THE BEANS ♪
♪ I HAD A LUCKY DAY ♪
♪ MARY ♪
♪ MY MARY ♪
♪ MY SWEET CANARY ♪
♪ WE'RE GOIN' OUT THIS EVENIN' ♪
♪ MARY ♪
♪ MY MARY ♪
♪ I'M GONNA TAKE
YOU OUT TONIGHT ♪
♪ SO HAND ME DOWN
THAT CAN O' BEANS ♪
♪ HAND ME DOWN
♪ I'M THROWIN' IT AWAY ♪
♪ OUT THE WINDER GO THE BEANS ♪
♪ GOOD TIMES ARE HERE TO STAY ♪
THIS TOWN MEETING
WILL NOW COME TO ORDER!
♪ HAND ME DOWN
THAT CAN O' BEANS ♪
♪ I'M THROWIN' IT AWAY ♪
♪ OUT THE WINDER GO THE BEANS ♪
♪ I HAD A LUCKY DAY ♪
♪ MARY ♪
♪ MA-MA-MA-MARY ♪
♪ MY CUTE CANARY ♪
♪ WE'RE GOIN' OUT THIS EVENIN' ♪
♪ MARY ♪
♪ MA-MA-MA-MARY ♪
♪ I'M GONNA TAKE
YOU OUT TONIGHT ♪
♪ SO HAND ME DOWN
THAT CAN O' BEANS ♪
ORDER!
♪ HAND ME DOWN
THAT CAN O' BEANS ♪
♪ I'M THROWIN' IT AWAY ♪
♪ OUT THE WINDER GO THE BEANS ♪
♪ GO THE BEANS, GO THE BEANS ♪
♪ GOOD TIMES ARE HERE TO STAY ♪
♪ YEAH! ♪
♪ HAND ME DOWN
THAT CAN O' BEANS ♪
♪ I'M THROWIN' IT AWAY ♪
♪ OUT THE WINDER GO THE BEANS ♪
♪ I HAD A LUCKY DAY ♪
♪ MARY ♪
♪ MA-MA-MA-MARY ♪
♪ MY SWEET CANARY ♪
♪ WE'RE GOIN' OUT THIS EVENIN' ♪
♪ MARY ♪
♪ MA-MA-MA-MARY ♪
♪ I'M GONNA TAKE
YOU OUT TONIGHT ♪
♪ SO HAND ME DOWN
THAT CAN O' BEANS ♪
♪ HAND ME DOWN
♪ I'M THROWIN' IT AWAY ♪
♪ OUT THE WINDER GO THE BEANS ♪
♪ GO THE BEANS, GO THE BEANS ♪
♪ GOOD TIMES ARE HERE TO STAY ♪♪
[THUNDER]
ANYBODY SEEN BEN RUMSON?
HE, UH, LEFT HERE
ABOUT 20 MINUTES AGO.
THANKS.
ARE YOU HIS PARDNER?
YEAH.
HE, UH, OWES ME $80.
HE SAID YOU WOULD STAND GOOD.
[WEAKLY] HEY, PARDNER.
CAN YOU HELP ME
GET UP ON THAT MULE?
YOU ALL RIGHT?
I GET MELANCHOLY
EVERY NOW AND THEN.
IT'S A DISEASE COMMON
TO MOUNTAIN MEN
WHO LIVE ALONE A LOT,
BUT IF YOU STAY WITH
ME AT SUCH... SUCH TIMES,
I'LL... I'LL BE OK.
ALL RIGHT.
DID EZRA ATWELL COME TO YOU
FOR THAT $80?
YEAH.
I STOOD GOOD FOR YOU.
I GUESS THIS IS
WHAT YOU MEANT, UH,
WHEN YOU SAID YOU EXPECTED ME
TO COME GET YOU MUDDY
DRUNK IN THE STREET.
AND NOW YOU'RE GOING
TO BE MY COMPANION
IN MY MOMENT OF DESPAIR.
WELL,
YOU'RE MY PARDNER, AIN'T YOU?
HEY.
I LIKE YOU, PARDNER.
I LIKE YOU, BEN.
WELL, MY MOTHER
AND FATHER'S DEAD,
AND MY TWO BROTHERS AND MYSELF,
WE WORKED THE...
WE WORKED THE FARM.
THEN LAST YEAR,
MY OLDER BROTHER,
HE TOOK HIMSELF A WIFE.
ME AND MY KID BROTHER,
WE DECIDED TO LEAVE MICHIGAN
AND COME OUT HERE,
MAYBE DIG SOME GOLD,
GET ENOUGH MONEY
TO BUY SOME LAND.
I DON'T HAVE TOO MUCH
APPETITE FOR FARMING.
WELL, WHAT ABOUT YOUR GIRL?
GIRL?
YEAH. ELISA.
IS SHE GONNA COME
OUT AND JOIN YOU,
OR DID SHE MARRY YOUR BROTHER?
WELL, TO TELL YOU THE TRUTH,
THERE IS NO ELISA.
I JUST...
READ THAT NAME
SOMEWHERE AND MADE IT UP.
WELL, THEM'S THE BEST KIND,
BUT WHAT I NEED NOW
IS THE WORST KIND.
IT'S A LIVING HELL UP HERE,
WHAT WITH THE BLOODY RAIN
AND THE BLOODY LONELINESS
AND THAT BLOODY, BLOODY WIND.
♪ MARIA ♪
♪ THEY CALL THE WIND ♪
♪ AWAY OUT HERE
THEY GOT A NAME ♪
♪ FOR RAIN AND WIND AND FIRE ♪
♪ THE RAIN IS TESS ♪
♪ THE FIRE'S JOE ♪
♪ AND THEY CALL THE WIND MARIA ♪
♪ MARIA BLOWS THE STARS AROUND ♪
♪ AND SENDS THE
CLOUDS A-FLYIN' ♪
♪ MARIA MAKES THE
MOUNTAINS SOUND ♪
♪ LIKE FOLKS WERE
UP THERE DYIN' ♪
♪ MARIA ♪
♪ THEY CALL THE WIND MARIA ♪
♪ BEFORE I KNEW MARIA'S NAME ♪
♪ AND HEARD HER
WAIL AND WHININ' ♪
♪ I HAD A GIRL, AND SHE HAD ME ♪
♪ AND THE SUN WAS
ALWAYS SHININ' ♪
♪ BUT THEN ONE
DAY I LEFT MY GIRL ♪
♪ I LEFT HER FAR BEHIND ME ♪
♪ AND NOW I'M LOST ♪
♪ SO GOL DURN LOST ♪
♪ NOT EVEN GOD CAN FIND ME ♪
♪ MARIA ♪
♪ THEY CALL THE WIND MARIA ♪
♪ OUT HERE THEY
GOT A NAME FOR RAIN ♪
♪ FOR WIND AND FIRE ONLY ♪
♪ BUT WHEN YOU'RE
LOST AND ALL ALONE ♪
♪ THERE AIN'T NO
WORD BUT LONELY ♪
♪ AND I'M A LOST
AND LONELY MAN ♪
♪ WITHOUT A STAR TO GUIDE ME ♪
♪ MARIA, BLOW MY LOVE TO ME ♪
♪ I NEED MY GIRL BESIDE ME ♪
♪ MARIA ♪
♪ THEY CALL THE WIND MARIA ♪
♪ BLOW MY LOVE ♪
♪ TO ♪
♪ ME ♪♪
WOMEN! LOOK AT THE WOMEN!
LOOK! TWO WOMEN!
THERE'S TWO WOMEN!
LOOK AT THE TWO WOMEN!
THERE'S FIVE WOMEN!
I WANT TO GET ONE OF THEM GALS!
[CHEERING]
THERE'S EIGHT WOMEN DOWN THERE!
THERE'S 15 WOMEN!
20 WOMEN!
40 WOMEN COMIN'!
HEY, THERE'S 64 WOMEN
COMING INTO TOWN!
YAHOO!
HEY, MEN, THERE'S 80 WOMEN
COMING DOWN THE RIVER!
[CHEERING]
LADY, I, UH...
GOT $50 HERE IN GOLD DUST.
YOU CAN HAVE IT ALL
IF YOU, UH...
LET ME HOLD THE BABY.
VERY WELL.
NO, I DON'T WANT
ANY MONEY FOR IT.
YOU'LL HURT HIS
FEELINGS, SARAH. TAKE IT.
[BABY COOS]
LOOK AT THEM EYES,
GLOWING LIKE HE
JUST HIT PAY DIRT.
HE'S A GIRL, YOU BUMMER!
WOULD ANYONE ELSE
CARE TO HOLD THE BABY?
NOT NOW, JACOB.
JUST WHERE ARE YOU PEOPLE FROM?
ILLINOIS, ORIGINALLY.
I'M JACOB WOODLING.
THIS IS MY WIFE SARAH.
AND WHO MIGHT THIS
FINE YOUNG LADY BE?
HER NAME IS ELIZABETH WOODLING.
YOUR SISTER?
NO. MY WIFE.
YOUR WIFE? I THOUGHT
THAT ONE WAS YOUR WIFE.
THEY BOTH ARE.
HOLY MOSES!
THEY'RE MORMONS!
DU LIEBER HIMMEL!
NICE WORK, OLD MAN!
HA HA HA!
CAN WE GET SOMETHING
TO EAT OVER THERE?
WITH $50 YOU CAN, SIR.
UH, FOLLOW ME.
WHAT THE HELL IS A MORMONS?
ICH VERSTEHE NICHT.
AAH!
NOW, I DON'T BLOODY GIVE
A DAMN HOW A MAN PRAYS.
THERE'S ENOUGH ROOM
IN HELL FOR ALL OF US,
BUT IT JUST AIN'T
EQUITABLE, MAN,
FOR YOU TO BE HAVING
TWO OF SOMETHING
ALL OF US GOT NONE OF.
YEAH! YEAH!
TELL YOU WHAT I'LL DO.
YOUR MULE'S LAME,
AND I GOT A BEAUTY
THAT COST ME $140.
I'LL SWAP YOU STRAIGHT...
MY MULE FOR ONE OF YOUR WIVES.
NOW...
WHICH ONE'S BABY'S MOTHER?
GOD KNOWS I WOULDN'T WANT
TO SEPARATE MOTHER AND CHILD.
I AM.
GOOD. I FANCY THE
OTHER ONE, I DID.
[TABOR] THIS IS IMMORAL.
I HOPE SO!
THE WOMAN'S MARRIED.
NO, SHE'S NOT!
WE DON'T RECOGNIZE
PLURAL MARRIAGE
IN CALIFORNIA.
THEN I BID $250 IN GOLD FOR HER.
260!
265!
WAIT! YOU CAN'T BUY
A WOMAN FOR MONEY.
TRY AND GET ONE WITHOUT IT.
HA HA HA!
ALL RIGHT, WHAT
ABOUT IT, MORMONS?
JACOB, WE NEED
EVERY PENNY, JACOB,
AND I CAN'T BEAR ANOTHER DAY
OF THOSE MARTYRED LOOKS.
THERE. THERE IT IS AGAIN.
THIS AIN'T A MARTYRED
LOOK, SARAH.
THIS LOOK IS PURE...
HATRED.
QUIET!
BRIGHAM YOUNG HAS 27 WIVES,
AND HE HASN'T HAD HALF
THE TROUBLE WITH THEM
I'VE HAD WITH THE TWO OF YOU.
THEN SIMPLIFY YOUR LIFE, JACOB.
SELL ME.
BUT, ELIZABETH,
YOU DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU'LL GET.
I KNOW WHAT I'VE HAD.
- HA HA HA!
Sarah: GO AHEAD.
GENTLEMEN...
OUT HERE...
I AIN'T A MORMON.
NOW, ELIZABETH IS A
HEADSTRONG WOMAN,
ESPECIALLY SINCE HER OWN
BABY DIED TWO WEEKS AGO,
BUT SHE'S GIVEN HER
CONSENT TO BE SOLD.
THEREFORE, IF ANY OF
YOU WANT TO BID FOR HER,
SO BE IT.
BUT...
LET'S GO OUTSIDE...
WHERE THERE'S ROOM
FOR MORE PEOPLE.
OOH!
BUT THESE RELIGIOUS
DOGS ARE BLOODY GREEDY!
AH, COME ON! COME ON!
ELIZABETH, YOU WAIT
HERE AND FEED THE BABY.
I DON'T DEEM IT PROPER THAT
YOU BE STANDING ON A BLOCK.
IF ANYONE WANTS TO INSPECT YOU,
I'LL SEND THEM IN.
ORDER!
I INTEND TO CONDUCT THIS AUCTION
IN AN ORDERLY MANNER!
AND NO BIDS IN SPANISH.
THE LAST BID WAS $265
AND TWO BLANKETS.
$265, TWO BLANKETS,
AND A JACKASS!
A 2-POUND SACK OF COFFEE,
A 2-POUND SACK OF BROWN SUGAR...
HEY, HOLBROOK,
EVEN IF SHE IS BOUGHT,
HOW WILL SHE MARRY
WHO BOUGHT HER?
SHE'LL BE MARRIED
ACCORDING TO THE PREVAILING
LAW OF THIS COMMUNITY,
WHICH IS MINING LAW,
AND SHE'LL BE TREATED
LIKE ANY OTHER LEGAL CLAIM!
[CHEERING]
ORDER! ORDER! ORDER!
[SHOUTING BIDS]
THE MAN BIDS $275,
FOUR BLANKETS,
ONE PICKAX,
AND A BEDPAN.
HEY, MOONEY...
MOONEY, THERE'S A
WOMAN IN THE SALOON
WITH A BABY PRESSED
AGAINST HER BREAST.
THAT'S RIGHT, BEN.
WAIT. IT AIN'T EVERY DAY
THAT WE GOT A WOMAN IN ATWELL'S
PRESSING HER
BREAST WITH HER BABY.
THAT'S RIGHT, BEN.
[SHOUTING BIDS]
CLENDENNON...
SHH!
THERE'S A WOMAN IN ATWELL'S
PRESSING HER
BREAST IN THE SALOON.
I KNOW, BEN, AND
WE'RE BIDDING FOR HER.
AND SAM FLETCHER BIDS $300,
FOUR BLANKETS...
BEN, WHERE YOU GOING?
HEY, PARDNER, THERE'S
A BREAST IN ATWELL'S
PRESSING A WOMAN AGAINST HER.
YOU WANT TO BET?
YOU BETTER STAY HERE, BEN.
HUH?
LOOK! THERE'S ANOTHER ONE!
WELL, HE'S A MORMON.
HE HAS TWO WIVES.
I'LL KILL HIM.
BEN, THEY'RE BIDDING
ON HER RIGHT NOW.
WHATEVER THE BID IS...
WHATEVER THE
BID IS, I DOUBLE IT!
OHH!
$400 WAS BID LAST.
MR. BEN RUMSON
GALLANTLY DOUBLES THAT BID
TO $800!
800 ONCE...
WAIT A MINUTE! I'M HIS PARDNER,
AND HE WITHDRAWS THE BID.
YOU HAVE POWER OF ATTORNEY?
POWER OF WHAT?
WRITTEN PERMISSION,
SIGNED AND WITNESSED.
IF HE COULD DO THAT,
HE'D TALK FOR HIMSELF.
800 TWICE!
WAKE UP, BEN. COME ON.
SOLD TO MR. BEN RUMSON
FOR $800!
HE ONLY LOOKS THAT WAY
WHEN HE'S DRUNK, MA'AM.
YOU AIN'T EXACTLY
SEEIN' HIM AT HIS BEST,
BUT ONCE I GET HIM
WASHED DOWN AND CLIPPED,
I THINK YOU'LL BE
AGREEABLY SURPRISED.
♪ GET THE SOAP AND WATER ♪
♪ WHOOP-TI-AY ♪
♪ GOT A SWEET PERFUMER ♪
♪ TO TRY HIS HUMOR ♪
♪ IT'S BEN'S WEDDIN' DAY ♪
♪ WASH HIM DOWN AND CLIP HIM ♪
♪ WHOOP-TI-AY ♪
♪ HE'S GOT A BLUE-EYED WONDER ♪
♪ TO PUT HIM UNDER ♪
♪ IT'S HIS WEDDIN'... YEAH ♪
♪ BEN'S WEDDIN'... YAY ♪
♪ BEN'S WEDDIN' DAY ♪♪
♪ WHERE AM I GOIN'? ♪
♪ I DON'T KNOW ♪
♪ WHERE AM I HEADIN'? ♪
♪ I AIN'T CERTAIN ♪
♪ ALL I KNOW IS I AM ON MY WAY ♪
♪ AMEN ♪
DEARLY BELOVED,
WE HAVE GATHERED TOGETHER
TO GRANT THIS MAN BEN RUMSON
EXCLUSIVE TITLE TO THIS WOMAN
MRS. ELIZABETH WOODLING
AND TO ALL HER
MINERAL RESOURCES.
I HAVE DRAWN UP
THIS RECORD OF CLAIM,
WHICH HERE AND HENCEFORTH
WILL BE RECOGNIZED
AS A CERTIFICATE OF MARRIAGE.
SO I ASK YOU, BEN,
DO YOU RECOGNIZE THIS CLAIM
AS A CONTRACT OF MARRIAGE,
AND DO YOU TAKE THIS WOMAN
TO LOVE, HONOR, AND CHERISH?
OH, HE DOES.
ELIZABETH WOODLING,
DO YOU TAKE THIS MAN BEN RUMSON
TO LOVE, HONOR, AND OBEY HIM
UNTIL DEATH DO YOU PART?
SHE DOES.
I NOW PRONOUNCE
YOU CLAIMED AND FILED
AS MR. AND MRS. BEN RUMSON.
YAY! YAY! YAY!
♪ MR. RUMSON WENT TO TOWN ♪
♪ RIDIN' ON A PONY ♪
♪ BOUGHT A WIFE AND
BROUGHT HER HOME ♪
♪ AND CALLED IT MATRIMONY ♪
♪ MR. RUMSON BOUGHT A BRIDE ♪
♪ OUT IN CALIFORNY ♪
♪ HE'D HAVE SAVED
A LOT OF MONEY ♪
♪ STAYIN' DRUNK AND HORNY ♪♪
♪ OH, SUSANNAH ♪
♪ HE'S HAPPY AS CAN BE ♪
♪ FOR HE'S GOT HIM
SOMETHIN' BETTER ♪
♪ THAN A BANJO ON HIS KNEE ♪♪
♪ RUMSON, HE GOT MARRIED TODAY ♪
♪ MARRIED TODAY ♪
♪ WHAT'LL HE DO TOMORROW? ♪
HEY, BEN!
I'LL BE GLAD TO HELP
YOU WORK YOUR CLAIM!
I'LL BED DOWN BY THE FIRE
IF YOU NEED ME.
YOU'LL NOT REGRET TAKING ME IN.
I'LL MAKE YOU A GOOD WIFE.
YOU SURE AS HELL WILL.
I DON'T FAULT YOU
FOR TAKING ME FOR AN EASY WOMAN.
I WAS BOUGHT AND PAID FOR.
BUT YOU BOUGHT ME FOR A WIFE,
NOT A WHORE.
IF YOU COME AGAIN AT
ME LIKE A SLAVERING DOG,
I'LL SHOOT YOU AS YOU COME.
WATCH WHERE YOU
POINT THAT THING.
YOU'D LIKE TO BLOW MY
MANHOOD HALFWAY TO THE MOON.
I MEAN TO MAKE YOU A GOOD WIFE
AND HONOR THIS
CONTRACT OF MARRIAGE,
BUT ONLY IF YOU WILL
HONOR IT AS WELL.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU MEAN BY HONOR IT.
I KNOW YOUR SORT
OF MAN, MR. RUMSON.
MY FATHER WAS THE SAME SORT,
BORN UNDER A WANDERING STAR.
I AIN'T FOOL ENOUGH
TO BOND YOU WITH ALL THE
TYRANNIES OF MARRIAGE.
ALL I WANT IS YOUR
NAME, MR. RUMSON,
AND THE LEAST MEASURE OF RESPECT
DUE TO A MAN'S WIFE.
BUT...
MOST OF ALL...
I WANT YOU TO BUILD ME A CABIN.
A CABIN...
THAT'LL STAND UP IN WINTER
WITH A FIREPLACE OF STONE
AND A DOOR I CAN
BOLT IF I HAVE TO.
AND IF YOU DO THAT,
I WILL SAY YOU HAVE
HONORED THE CONTRACT.
BUT IF YOU REGRET HAVING
BOUGHT ME, MR. RUMSON,
SAY SO NOW,
AND IF I HAVE TO WORK
THE REST OF MY LIFE,
I'LL SEE YOU GET YOUR $800 BACK.
I ADMIRE YOUR PIONEER SPIRIT
AND YOUR STRAIGHTFORWARD
MANNER, MA'AM.
IS THAT WHAT YOU'VE
BEEN ADMIRING?
I'VE BEEN ADMIRING YOU, MA'AM.
ALL RIGHT, I'LL
BUILD YOU A CABIN,
AND I'LL GIVE YOU
MY NAME PROUDLY.
YOU'RE MRS. BEN RUMSON,
AND I'LL KILL ANY MAN
THAT SAYS YOU AIN'T.
I'LL STICK TO IT TILL I MOVE ON,
WHICH IS WHEN THE
GOLD PINCHES OUT
OR THE FIRST SNOW OF WINTER.
YOU...
YOU AIN'T GOING TO
CLAIM DURESS LATER
JUST 'CAUSE I HELD A GUN ON YOU?
NO, MA'AM,
I AIN'T GOING TO CLAIM DURESS.
I SEEM TO LACK
ALL SENSE OF SHAME
WITH YOU, MR. RUMSON.
[CHEERING]
HEY, BEN!
THESE MEN CAME ALL THE
WAY FROM FIDDLER'S CAMP
JUST TO SEE YOUR WIFE.
HIYA, BEN!
WELL...
LOOKS LIKE I MARRIED
MYSELF A TOURIST ATTRACTION.
SOME OF THESE
BOYS HIKED 15 MILES.
BEN, HOW'S MARRIED LIFE?
PARDNER, IT WAS SO GOOD
THAT I FORGOT
THAT I WAS MARRIED.
[CROWD OOOHS]
WOW.
I'D HIKE 15 MILES TO
LOOK AT THAT MYSELF.
HMM. WELL,
I CAN SEE IT AIN'T
GOING TO BE EASY
MARRIED TO THE ONLY
WOMAN IN THESE MOUNTAINS.
[CHEERING]
ALL RIGHT, BOYS!
THE LADY WANTS
A CABIN TO LIVE IN.
A PROPER CABIN MADE OUT OF WOOD
THAT'LL HOLD UP IN THE WINTER!
SO JUST DON'T SIT THERE GAPING.
GET TO WORK!
♪ SEND BACK THE WORLD ♪
♪ THERE'S TOO
MUCH NIGHT FOR ME ♪
♪ THE SKY IS MUCH TOO
HIGH TO SHELTER ME ♪
♪ WHEN DARKNESS FALLS ♪
♪ FOUR CABIN WALLS ♪
♪ WOULD BE JUST RIGHT FOR ME ♪
♪ I NEED A THRESHOLD
I CAN CROSS ♪
♪ WHERE I CAN SIT AND
GATHER MOSS FOREVERMORE ♪
♪ A MILLION MILES AWAY ♪
♪ BEHIND THE DOOR ♪
♪ ROLL UP THE PLAINS ♪
♪ THERE'S TOO MUCH VIEW FOR ME ♪
♪ THERE'S SO MUCH SPACE ♪
♪ BETWEEN THE WAITING
HEART AND WHISPERED WORD ♪
♪ IT'S NEVER HEARD ♪
♪ ONE ROOM WILL DO FOR ME ♪
♪ WHERE EVERY EVENING I
CAN STARE AT SOMEONE ♪
♪ SMILING FROM HIS
CHAIR ACROSS THE FLOOR ♪
♪ A MILLION MILES AWAY ♪
♪ BEHIND THE DOOR ♪
♪ WHERE EVERY EVENING I
CAN STARE AT SOMEONE ♪
♪ SMILING FROM HIS
CHAIR ACROSS THE FLOOR ♪
♪ A MILLION MILES AWAY ♪
♪ BEHIND THE DOOR ♪
♪ NO FEARS ♪
♪ NO FOOLS ♪
♪ NO LIES ♪
♪ NO RULES ♪
♪ JUST DOING WITH MY
LIFE WHAT LIFE IS FOR ♪
♪ A MILLION MILES AWAY ♪
♪ BEHIND ♪
♪ THE DOOR ♪♪
ELIZABETH.
ELIZABETH?
[WHISPERING]
Where have you been?
I was down at the rapids
taking a bath.
You mean you was taking a bath?
I mean I was taking a bath.
What do you think I mean?
You was down at
the rapids just now,
bare beam...
and buck naked?
I'm not like to take a bath
with my clothes on, Mr. Rumson.
Are you trying to tell me
you was taking a bath?
That's right.
I was taking a bath.
In the middle of the night?
Mr. Rumson,
in a community of 400 men,
would you rather
I took my bath...
Bare beam and buck naked...
In the middle of the day?
WHAT'S THE MATTER WITH YOU?
WHAT'S THE MATTER WITH ME?
I AIN'T RUNNING AROUND
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT
IN MY DRAWERS.
HEY! HEY, BOYS!
LISTEN TO THIS.
"THE PROPRIETORS
"OF THE HARES AND
HOUNDS CLUB IN SONORA
"WISH TO ANNOUNCE
"THAT SIX LADIES ARE
EXPECTED TO ARRIVE
"BY STAGE FROM SAN FRANCISCO
ON THE 15th OF AUGUST."
[CHEERING]
HOW ABOUT THAT, HUH?
THAT'S A HUNDRED MILES AWAY.
WHAT GOOD IS THAT
GOING TO DO US?
AIN'T NO ONE TRYING
TO STEAL YOUR WIFE.
I'LL ADMIT THERE'S A FEW
WHO WOULDN'T MIND TRYING.
HORACE TABOR, FOR INSTANCE.
HE LIKES TO GIVE HER A
LOOK EVERY NOW AND THEN.
HORACE TABOR?
COME ON, BEN.
HE JUST LOOKS
AT HER, THAT'S ALL.
SHE DOESN'T ENCOURAGE
HIM OR ANYBODY ELSE.
YOU'RE BEGINNING TO CUT
A COMICAL FIGURE
AND EVERYBODY'S LAUGHING AT YOU.
I WOULD'VE NEVER
THOUGHT OF HORACE TABOR.
[DOOR OPENS]
WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU
LOOKING AT, HORACE TABOR?
I'M LOOKING FOR
MY STIRRING STICK.
YOU MAKE ANY MORE
ADVANCES TOWARDS MY WIFE,
AND I'M GOING TO SHOOT YOU DOWN
LIKE THE RATTLE-BONED
MOTHER-LOVIN' DOG YOU ARE!
THAT GOES FOR THE REST
OF YOU HORNY GORILLAS!
YOU WANT SOMETHING TO DO?
GET ON YOUR MULE
AND PUT UP YOUR MONEY
FOR THEM SIX FRENCH
TARTS COMING INTO SONORA!
BUT KEEP YOUR LUSTING,
LECHERING MINDS OFF OF MY WIFE!
I'D ADVISE YOU, RUMSON,
NOT TO REFER TO ME
AS A RATTLE-BONED DOG AGAIN.
IS THAT CLEAR?
I'LL STICK MY FIST IN ONE
EAR AND OUT THE OTHER!
GRAB TABOR! STOP HIM!
MR. RUMSON!
RUMSON, I...
NOBODY HAS BEHAVED
UNSEEMLY TO ME.
I HAVE BEEN TREATED
WITH NOTHING BUT KINDNESS
IN THIS CAMP,
AND YOU OWE EVERY
ONE OF THESE MEN,
AND ESPECIALLY MR. TABOR,
AN APOLOGY.
BY GOD, YOU'RE RIGHT!
I DON'T KNOW WHAT'S
COME OVER ME.
I'VE BEEN BEHAVING
LIKE A DAMN FOOL,
AND I WISH TO BEG YOUR
COMMUNAL PARDONS,
AND ESPECIALLY YOURS,
HORACE TABOR.
WELL, I SUPPOSE IF I WAS MARRIED
TO THE ONLY WOMAN
IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD,
I MIGHT BE JUST AS DEMENTED.
AND, MRS. RUMSON.
UH, MRS. RUMSON,
MAY I EXTEND MY COMPLIMENTS?
YOU ARE AS WISE AS YOU ARE FAIR.
[GASP]
GET YOUR HANDS OFF ME!
THAT LUNATIC TRIED TO KILL ME!
I DEMAND A TOWN MEETING
TO CONSIDER A PROPER
COURSE OF ACTION.
YEAH. YEAH.
IF THAT KNIFE HAD
COME 1 INCH LOWER,
I WOULD NOT BE HERE TODAY.
THAT'S RIGHT. YEAH.
MY FELLOW CITIZENS,
AS LONG AS THAT MADMAN
PROWLS AMONG US,
NO ONE IS SAFE.
YEAH. YEAH.
THEREFORE...
WE MUST FIND A
SOLUTION BY TONIGHT.
LET US NOT WAIT UNTIL
THE CONDITION WORSENS
OR HIS AIM IMPROVES!
YEAH! YEAH!
Holbrook: ORDER!
MR. CHAIRMAN!
THE CHAIR RECOGNIZES
EZRA ATWELL.
I WOULD LIKE TO ASK
BEN RUMSON DIRECTLY
IF HE DOESN'T THINK
THAT WITH A LITTLE SOBER EFFORT
HE COULD CONTROL
THESE FITS OF JEALOUSY?
NOT A CHANCE, AND IT'S
GETTING WORSE EVERY DAY.
SORRY, CAN'T HELP YOU.
THE CHAIR RECOGNIZES
BEN'S PARDNER.
AH, THANK YOU, MR. HOLBROOK.
I'VE BEEN GIVING IT SOME
CONSIDERABLE THOUGHT.
EVER SINCE BEN RUMSON,
MY PARDNER HERE, POOR BASTARD...
OH, EXCUSE ME, MA'AM...
WELL, EVER SINCE
HE BECAME A LUNATIC.
WHAT'S PUTTING THE
STRAIN ON BEN'S MIND
IS, UH, WELL, HAVING
THE ONLY WOMAN
FOR 90 MILES AROUND HERE.
NOW, MY PROPOSAL IS
THAT WE GET SOME MORE
WOMEN FOR THIS TOWN.
HOW YOU GOING TO GET WOMEN
TO COME UP HERE?
Holbrook: ORDER! ORDER!
I KNOW WHERE WE
CAN GET SOME WOMEN.
THERE'S SIX FRENCH
BAWDS ARRIVING IN SONORA
A WEEK AFTER SATURDAY.
BEN, YOU'RE RIGHT.
WHY DON'T WE GET THEM
TO COME UP HERE INSTEAD?
Rotten Luck Willie: HOW YOU GONNA GET
SIX FRENCH BAWDS TO COME UP HERE?
IF I WAS A FRENCH
BAWD, I'D GO TO SONORA.
IF YOU WAS A FRENCH BAWD, WE
WOULDN'T BE HAVING THIS TROUBLE.
ALL RIGHT, HOW ARE WE GONNA
GET 'EM TO COME UP HERE?
IT'S SIMPLE.
THEY GOTTA TAKE THE MORNING
STAGE FROM SACRAMENTO.
THEY GOTTA STOP AT STARBOTTLE'S
PASS TO CHANGE HORSES.
SO FIVE OR SIX OF
US GO DOWN THERE,
HIJACK THAT STAGE,
AND REROUTE THEM TARTS
BACK UP HERE INSTEAD.
NOW, WHAT'S SO HARD ABOUT THAT?
IT ALL SOUNDS JUST FINE TO ME.
WHEN DO WE GO?
ORDER! ORDER!
IS IT YOUR PROPOSAL, MR. RUMSON,
THAT WE KNOCK OUT
THE STAGE DRIVER,
STEAL A COACH,
AND KIDNAP SIX WOMEN?
SOUNDS BETTER
EVERY TIME I HEAR IT.
YOU FAIL TO SEE WHAT'S WRONG
WITH THIS PROPOSAL?
WHAT'S WRONG WITH IT?
WELL, IF YOU DON'T CONSIDER
ASSAULT AND BATTERY,
GRAND LARCENY, AND
KIDNAPPING WRONG,
WHAT THE HELL DO
YOU CONSIDER WRONG?
OH, YOU MANIAC!
SIT DOWN!
YOU INSANE MAN!
SCHERMERHORN,
YOU'RE OUT OF ORDER.
WHAT?
I YIELD THE FLOOR.
PROCEED, SCHERMERHORN.
WHAT?
SPEAK!
YOU MANIAC!
YOU INSANE MAN!
WHAT DO YOU THINK
THEM PEOPLE IN
SONORA GOING TO DO
WHEN WE HIJACK THEIR FRAULEINS?
THEY GRAB THEIR GUNS
AND COME UP HERE
TO GET THEM BACK!
[BANGING GAVEL]
GENTLEMEN!
MR. ATWELL HAS THE FLOOR.
GENTLEMEN, IT IS 50 MILES
FROM HERE TO STARBOTTLE'S
WITHOUT A ROAD OR A TRAIL.
NOT EVEN A MULE CAN DO
IT. HOW DO YOU EXPECT...
OH, YOU LUNATICS!
BESIDES A CIVIL WAR WITH SONORA,
YOU WANT TO PUT US
IN THE WHITE SLAVE BUSINESS!
SCHERMERHORN,
YOU'RE OUT OF ORDER!
AGAIN?
YOU HAVEN'T BEEN RECOGNIZED!
I'M SCHERMERHORN.
Pardner: MR. HOLBROOK.
AW, SIT DOWN!
BEN, THESE BOYS ARE RIGHT.
MR. HOLBROOK, I
WITHDRAW THE PROPOSAL.
[MUTTERING]
HAVE YOU GONE OUT OF YOUR SKULL?
YOU CAN'T EXPECT THESE MEN
TO BUILD A TWO-STORY BUILDING
JUST TO GET WOMEN UP HERE.
WHO SAID TWO STORIES?
SOMEBODY'S GOT TO
RUN THE FARO TABLES
ON THE GROUND FLOOR, DON'T THEY?
ROTTEN LUCK WILLIE WILL DO THAT.
YOU CAN'T EXPECT
ROTTEN LUCK WILLIE
TO BUILD A FANCY BUILDING
WITH CHANDELIERS
AND ART OVER THE BAR
AND GAMBLING AND SIX
BEAUTIFUL TARTS UPSTAIRS.
CRIMINY, BEN.
WE'D HAVE EVERY
BUMMER FOR MILES AROUND
COMING AROUND HERE
TO SPEND HIS MONEY
ON WOMEN AND WHISKEY
AT ATWELL'S AND SCHERMERHORN'S.
YOU THINK THAT'S BAD?
WHY, IT'S TERRIBLE!
JUST TERRIBLE!
YOU'D TURN THIS CAMP
INTO A BOOM TOWN,
AND WE DON'T WANT TO DO THAT.
SOON THERE'D BE ANOTHER SALOON.
AND ANOTHER BAWDY HOUSE.
AND ANOTHER GAMBLING HALL.
AND ANOTHER HOTEL.
AND ANOTHER BAWDY HOUSE.
WHY, PROPERTY WOULD
SHOOT STRAIGHT UP.
THEY'D BE MAKING
MORE MONEY SELLING
THEIR OLD CLAIMS THAN FROM GOLD.
THEY DIDN'T COME
HERE TO FORGE A NATION
OUT OF THE WILDERNESS.
WHADDAYA THINK THEY ARE?
THAT'S TIGHT! THAT'S FOR
MEN WITH A BIG DREAM,
WITH VISIONS OF
AMERICA'S GREATNESS.
WELL, I'M WARNING YOU,
IF YOU WANT TO TURN THIS
INTO A DREARY BOOM
TOWN METROPOLIS
FILLED WITH NOTHING
BUT MILLIONAIRES,
ALL YOU GOT TO DO
IS PUT UP ONE LITTLE, TINY...
TWO-STORY CATHOUSE.
LET'S PUT IT TO A VOTE.
ANY MAN OPPOSED IS A
TRAITOR TO HIS COUNTRY.
ALL THOSE IN FAVOR
OF BRINGING PROSTITUTION
TO THIS CAMP, SAY AYE.
AYE! AYE!
PASSED!
PARDNER, THERE'S
A SHIFTY SIDE TO YOU
THAT I'M JUST BEGINNING
TO APPRECIATE.
WHY CAN'T I GO ALONG WITH YOU?
WHO'S GOING TO TAKE
CARE OF ELIZABETH?
IT'LL TAKE THREE DAYS AND NIGHTS
TO GET THEM TARTS BACK HERE.
YOU DON'T EXPECT ME TO LEAVE
A FEAST LIKE ELIZABETH ALONE
IN THIS FAMINE?
WHO CAN I TRUST IF IT AIN'T YOU?
YOU DIDN'T SAY BEING PARDNERS
MEANT WIFE-GUARDING.
WELL, IT JUST COME UP.
[CHEERING]
HOWDY.
CAPTAIN BARNSFEATHER,
FORT SUMTER.
WHEN DOES THE SONORA
STAGE COME THROUGH?
ABOUT 4:00 TOMORROW AFTERNOON.
WHY?
UH, SUPPLIES FOR THE TROOPS.
UNMOUNT!
[ELIZABETH HUMMING]
COME IN, PARDNER.
[HUMMING]
YOU SURE I'M NOT INTRUDING?
COME IN.
[HUMMING]
YOU THINK BEN WILL
REALLY GET BACK
IN THREE DAYS?
WHY?
I'D LIKE TO KNOW.
WHO YOU EXPECTING FOR DINNER?
YOU!
SIT DOWN.
OH.
THANKS.
[HUMMING]
I DIDN'T KNOW YOU
WAS EXPECTING ME.
♪ I TALK TO THE TREES ♪
♪ BUT THEY DON'T LISTEN TO ME ♪
♪ I TALK TO THE STARS ♪
♪ BUT THEY NEVER HEAR ME ♪
♪ THE BREEZE HASN'T TIME ♪
♪ TO STOP AND HEAR WHAT I SAY ♪
♪ I TALK TO THEM ALL ♪
♪ IN VAIN ♪
♪ BUT SUDDENLY MY WORDS ♪
♪ REACH SOMEONE ELSE'S EAR ♪
♪ TOUCH SOMEONE ELSE'S
HEARTSTRINGS, TOO ♪
♪ I TELL YOU MY DREAMS ♪
♪ AND WHILE YOU'RE
LISTENING TO ME ♪
♪ I SUDDENLY SEE THEM ♪
♪ COME TRUE ♪
♪ I CAN SEE US ON
AN APRIL NIGHT ♪
♪ LOOKING OUT
ACROSS A ROLLIN' FARM ♪
♪ HAVING SUPPER
IN THE CANDLELIGHT ♪
♪ WALKIN' LATER ARM IN ARM ♪
♪ THEN I'LL TELL YOU
HOW I PASSED THE DAY ♪
♪ THINKING MAINLY HOW
THE NIGHT WOULD BE ♪
♪ THEN I'LL TRY TO FIND
THE WORDS TO SAY ♪
♪ ALL THE THINGS
YOU MEAN TO ME ♪
♪ I TELL YOU MY DREAMS ♪
♪ AND WHILE YOU'RE
LISTENING TO ME ♪
♪ I SUDDENLY SEE THEM ♪
♪ COME TRUE ♪♪
THEY'RE COMING
OUT OF STARBOTTLE'S!
FALL TOGETHER!
HEY, PUT ME DOWN,
YOU BLOOMIN' IDIOT!
DOWN, DOWN, DOWN, DOWN!
OW!
THAT'S IT! GET IN LINE!
COME ON! COME ON, MOVE!
YAH!
WHOA!
CAPTAIN BARNSFEATHER,
FORT SUMTER.
AT YOUR SERVICE, LADIES.
HERE TO PROTECT
YOU ALONG THE WAY.
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO
TAKE THIS HERE DETOUR.
WHAT DETOUR?
I CAN'T DRIVE THESE LADIES
THROUGH OPEN COUNTRY.
YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE TO.
THE ROAD UP AHEAD
AIN'T SAFE. INJUNS.
AIN'T NO TROUBLE WITH
INJUNS AROUND HERE.
GET DOWN.
GET BACK IN THE
COACH, WILL YOU, LADIES?
PLEASE SIT DOWN, LADIES!
COME ON!
THERE'S A COACH COMIN' IN!
COMIN' IN! COMIN' IN!
♪ THERE'S A COACH COMIN' IN ♪
♪ IF YOU LISTEN,
YOU CAN HEAR IT ♪
♪ A-CLIP-CLOPPIN'
OVER THE HILL ♪
♪ AND THE SOUND THAT YOU HEAR ♪
♪ IS AS GOOD TO YOUR EAR ♪
♪ AS THE CALL OF A
WILD WHIPPOORWILL ♪
♪ THERE'S A COACH COMIN' IN ♪
♪ YOU CAN FEEL IT GETTIN' NEAR ♪
♪ ALL AT ONCE, AND
IT BURSTS INTO VIEW ♪
♪ AND IT LOOKS TO YOUR EYE ♪
♪ LIKE IT FELL FROM THE SKY ♪
♪ LIKE A COACH FULL
OF DREAMS COME TRUE ♪
♪ FOR IT'S BRINGIN' ME
EYES THAT ARE MOONLIGHT ♪
♪ AND IT'S CARRYIN'
LIPS THAT ARE WINE ♪
♪ AND IT'S COMIN' WITH
ARMS THAT ARE PILLOWS ♪
♪ AND THIS EVENING
IT ALL WILL BE MINE ♪
♪ THERE'S A COACH COMIN' IN ♪
♪ AND YOU'RE
SMELLIN' LIKE A STEER ♪
♪ GET THE SOAP OUT,
IT AIN'T FAR AWAY ♪
♪ CUT THE SOCKS FROM YOUR FEET ♪
♪ RAKE YOUR HAIR
TILL IT'S NEAT ♪
♪ THERE'S A COACH COMIN' IN ♪
♪ THERE'S A COACH
COMIN' IN TODAY ♪
♪ THERE'S A COACH COMIN' IN ♪
♪ HURRY, HURRY, DO YOU HEAR? ♪
♪ WITH A CARGO O'
JOY FROM PAREE ♪
♪ DROP THE TABLES AND CHAIRS ♪
♪ GET THEM BEDS UP THE STAIRS ♪
♪ AND BE SURE EVERY
LOCK HAS A KEY ♪
[SHRIEKING AND SHOUTING]
♪ FOR IT'S COMING MIT GIRLS ♪
♪ WHO BUY PERFUME ♪
♪ WHO WEAR POWDER
AND ROUGE FROM PAREE ♪
♪ WHO WILL HAVE TO GO
SOMEWHERE TO GET THEM ♪
♪ AND THE SOMEWHERE
TO GO WILL BE ME ♪
♪ THERE'S A COACH COMIN' IN ♪
♪ AND IT'S FLYIN' LIKE A DEER ♪
♪ THANK THE LORD THERE'S
RELIEF ON THE WAY ♪
♪ THANK WITH ALL
OF YOUR HEARTS ♪
♪ FOR THEM HALF-DOZEN TARTS ♪
♪ THERE'S A COACH COMIN' IN ♪
♪ TODAY ♪
♪ IF YOU LISTEN
YOU CAN HEAR IT ♪
♪ A-CLIP-CLOPPIN'
OVER THE HILL ♪
♪ AND THE SOUND THAT YOU HEAR ♪
♪ IS AS GOOD TO YOUR EAR ♪
♪ AS THE CALL OF A
WILD WHIPPOORWILL ♪
[WOMEN SHRIEKING AND SHOUTING]
♪ FOR IT'S BRINGIN' ME EYES ♪
♪ THAT ARE MOONLIGHT ♪
♪ AND IT'S CARRYIN'
LIPS THAT ARE WINE ♪
♪ AND IT'S COMIN' WITH
ARMS THAT ARE PILLOWS ♪
♪ AND THIS EVENING
IT ALL WILL BE MINE ♪
[WHOOPING AND HOLLERING]
♪
♪ ♪
♪ THERE'S A COACH COMIN' IN ♪
♪ YOU CAN FEEL IT GETTIN' NEAR ♪
♪ ALL AT ONCE, AND
IT BURSTS INTO VIEW ♪
♪ AND IT LOOKS TO YOUR EYE ♪
♪ LIKE IT FELL FROM THE SKY ♪
♪ LIKE A COACH FULL
OF DREAMS COME TRUE ♪
♪ FOR IT'S BRINGIN' ME
EYES THAT ARE MOONLIGHT ♪
♪ AND IT'S CARRYIN'
LIPS THAT ARE WINE ♪
♪ AND IT'S COMIN' WITH
ARMS THAT ARE PILLOWS ♪
♪ AND THIS EVENING
IT ALL WILL BE MINE ♪
♪ THERE'S A COACH COMIN' IN ♪
♪ NOW IT'S RIDING IN THE CLEAR ♪
♪ AND THE SOUND OF
IT GROWS TO A DIN ♪
♪ NO, THERE AIN'T FAR TO GO ♪
♪ NOW THEY'RE HOLLERIN' WHOA ♪
WHOA!
♪ THERE'S A COACH COMIN' IN ♪
♪ THERE'S A COACH COMIN' ♪
♪ AND IT'S HERE ♪♪
[CHEERING]
[PLAYING LA MARSEILLAISE]
BEN!
PARDNER, I WANT TO TALK TO YOU!
UHH!
DECEIVING, NO-GOOD, THIEVING...
THE ONLY REASON
I AIN'T BLOWING YOUR BRAINS OUT
IS THE RELIEF IT'S
GOING TO GIVE ME
WHEN I TEAR YOU APART
WITH MY BARE HANDS.
WHAT'S THE MATTER WITH YOU?
WHAT WAS THE TWO OF YOU
DOING ON THE SAME HORSE?
RIDING. WHAT ELSE IS THERE?
THAT'S THE LAST
PLACE I'D PICK...
WHERE WAS HER HORSE?
THAT WAS HER HORSE.
AND WHERE... HA HA...
WAS YOUR HORSE?
YOU HAD MY HORSE.
UH.
IF THAT'S TRUE,
WHY AIN'T YOU FIGHTING BACK?
YOU AIN'T BEEN YOURSELF LATELY.
THAT'S A WIDELY KNOWN FACT,
AND YOU KNOW IT YOURSELF.
GET UP, PARDNER.
HOW'S YOUR JAW?
FEELS LIKE IT'S COMING OFF.
YOU OUGHT TO TRUST ME, BEN.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
YOU AIN'T THE KIND OF MAN
THAT'D GO LUSTING AFTER
ANOTHER MAN'S WIFE,
ESPECIALLY WITH THEM SIX BAWDS
ARRIVING IN TOWN.
THAT'S RIGHT, BEN.
I WOULDN'T DO THAT.
THE ONLY KIND OF FEELINGS
YOU'D EVER HAVE
WOULD BE DEEP ONES,
AND IF YOU HAD
'EM FOR ELIZABETH,
YOU'D COME AND TELL ME
BEFORE YOU WOULD HER.
THAT'S RIGHT, BEN.
THAT'S WHAT I'D DO.
YOU'RE A GOOD MAN, PARDNER.
THAT'S WHAT I WAS
COMING TO DO, BEN...
TELL YOU THAT I GOT
SOME DEEP FEELINGS
FOR ELIZABETH.
BEN, YOU HIT ME ONE MORE TIME,
I'LL BUST YOUR SKULL OPEN.
I'M TELLING YOU,
NOTHING'S HAPPENED,
AND NOTHING'S GOING TO HAPPEN,
'CAUSE I'M LEAVING.
YOU'RE BREAKING
UP THE PARTNERSHIP?
WELL, IF I HANG AROUND
HERE LONG ENOUGH
WATCHING YOU AND HER TOGETHER,
I'LL BECOME AS BIG A
LUNATIC AS YOU ARE.
ALL RIGHT.
I'LL GO GET YOUR
SHARE OF THE GOLD DUST.
YOU CAN HAVE THE MULE
AND THAT NEW GOLD PAN.
YOU CAN EVEN HAVE THE ROCKER,
IF YOU WANT TO.
WHAT'S THE MATTER, BEN?
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
WHERE ARE YOU TAKING THE ROCKER?
I'M GIVING IT TO PARDNER.
HE'S GOING AWAY.
GOING AWAY?
HE... HE NEVER MENTIONED
GOING AWAY TO ME.
OF COURSE HE DIDN'T.
YOU DON'T KNOW THAT MAN
LIKE I DO, ELIZABETH.
WHAT ARE YOU SAYING, BEN?
HE LOVES YOU.
THAT'S WHY HE'S GOING.
I DON'T WANT PARDNER TO GO, BEN.
I LOVE HIM.
UNPACK, PARDNER.
YOU AIN'T GOING NOWHERE.
THAT WOMAN LOVES YOU.
AND THAT PUTS A NEW WHEEL
ON THE WAGON, DON'T IT?
NOW, YOU GET THIS STRAIGHT, BEN.
I'M NOT GOING TO
TAKE AWAY YOUR WIFE,
AND THAT'S FINAL.
BUT YOU LOVE HER.
SO DO YOU.
THERE'S ONLY ONE WAY
FOR ANYBODY TO BE HAPPY,
AND THAT'S FOR ONE OF US
TO MOVE AWAY AND FORGET IT.
AND I'M GOING.
NOW, GET OUT OF MY WAY.
PARDNER, THERE COMES A TIME
IN THE LIFE OF EVERY PARTNERSHIP
WHEN THE PARTY OF THE FIRST PART
HAS NO RECOURSE EXCEPT
TO KNOCK SOME SENSE
INTO THE PARTY OF
THE SECOND PART.
YOU'RE STAYING!
OOH!
[BONG]
WHAT HAPPENED?
HE'S STAYING.
IS HE HURT?
NO, MA'AM. JUST TIRED.
HE'LL BE GOOD AS NEW
IN A COUPLE OF WEEKS.
WHERE YOU GOING, BEN?
YOU LOVE PARDNER?
YOU TAKE HIM.
AND YOU TAKE GOOD CARE OF HIM.
THAT'S THE DECENTEST MAN
I EVER RUN ACROSS.
AND THE STRONGEST.
NOW...
I KNOW YOU WOMEN
LIKE THINGS LEGAL,
SO HERE'S WHAT.
IT TAKES TWO WEEKS
FOR YOU TO BE AN
ABANDONED CLAIM.
AFTER THAT, YOU TAKE THE NAME
OF YOUR NEW OWNER
AND FILE IT DOWN
AT THE MINING OFFICE.
THEN EVERYTHING WILL BE LEGAL.
BEN!
I DON'T WANT YOU TO GO.
I LOVE YOU.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING
ABOUT, ELIZABETH?
YOU'RE MY HUSBAND.
I DON'T WANT YOU TO GO AWAY.
WHAT WAS THAT?
DON'T LET HIM GO, PARDNER.
YOU SAID SHE WAS
IN LOVE WITH ME.
DIDN'T YOU JUST SAY
THAT YOU LOVED HIM?
YES, I DID, AND I DO.
YOU JUST SAID YOU
WERE IN LOVE WITH BEN.
YES, I DID, AND I AM.
BEN, DO YOU, UH...
DO YOU GET THE FEELING
YOU NEED A DRINK?
HOW DID YOU KNOW?
'CAUSE I DO, TOO.
BUT, PARDNER, YOU DON'T DRINK.
NO, BUT I'M CHANGING.
HMM, AND IT TAKES
A WOMAN TO DO IT.
BLESS THEIR HEARTS.
[COUGHS]
NOW, ELIZABETH,
LET'S TRY AND BE
REASONABLE ABOUT THIS.
FOR GOD'S SAKE,
MAKE UP YOUR MIND!
I CAN'T.
I LOVE BOTH OF YOU.
BUT THAT AIN'T GOING
TO WORK, ELIZABETH.
YOU CAN'T HAVE BOTH OF US.
WHY NOT?
'CAUSE, UH...
A WOMAN CAN'T HAVE TWO HUSBANDS.
WELL, I WAS MARRIED TO A MAN
WHO HAD TWO WIVES.
WHY CAN'T A WOMAN
HAVE TWO HUSBANDS?
BECAUSE YOU CAN'T.
WELL, WHY?
YOU EXPLAIN IT TO
HER, WILL YOU, BEN?
I'D LIKE TO OBLIGE, PARDNER,
BUT I'LL BE DAMNED IF I
CAN THINK OF A REASON.
OUT HERE WE MAKE UP OUR
OWN RULES AS WE GO ALONG.
A MAN RIDES INTO
TOWN WITH TWO WIVES,
WANTS TO SELL ONE AT AUCTION,
NOBODY THINKS TWICE.
IF A TOWN NEEDS
FEMALE COMPANIONSHIP,
HIJACKING THEM SEEMS
THE NATURAL THING TO DO,
AND IF TWO PARDNERS WANT
TO SHARE THE SAME WIFE,
WHY NOT?
THIS AIN'T MICHIGAN.
IT'S GOLD COUNTRY.
WHY, HELL, IT'S THE
GOLDEN COUNTRY,
UNTOUCHED AND
UNCONTAMINATED BY HUMAN HANDS!
IT'S WHERE PEOPLE CAN SOMEDAY
LOOK CIVILIZATION
STRAIGHT IN THE EYE AND SPIT!
YOU DON'T HAVE
TO PLEASE ANYBODY,
DON'T HAVE TO LOVE THY NEIGHBOR.
LEAVE THE BASTARD ALONE.
IT'S WILD, HUMAN, AND FREE,
AND ALL OVER THIS NATION,
THEY PREACH AGAINST
IT EVERY SUNDAY,
BUT I DON'T THINK
GOD'S LISTENING.
YOU KNOW WHY?
BECAUSE HE'S HERE...
IN GLORIOUS CALIFORNIA!
YOU TRYING TO TELL ME,
BEN, THAT YOU'RE WILLING?
I AM.
I THINK IT'S A HUMANE,
PRACTICAL, BEAUTIFUL SOLUTION.
IT DOES MAKE A LOT OF SENSE.
IT DON'T.
IT DON'T IN MICHIGAN.
IT DOES IN CALIFORNIA.
WELL, WHAT'S
EVERYBODY GONNA SAY?
WHAT EVERYBODY ARE
YOU TALKING ABOUT?
YOU MEAN EVERYBODY IN TOWN
PLAYING CHAMBER MUSIC
WITH THEM FRENCH HORNS?
THEY'D BE DAMN GLAD TO HAVE
TWO LESS IN LINE, AND YOU KNOW IT.
BEN, YOU'RE RIGHT.
OF COURSE I'M RIGHT.
YOU'VE BEEN CARRYING ON
LIKE SOMEBODY WAS ASKING YOU
TO DO SOMETHING
DOWNRIGHT IMMORAL,
LIKE STEALING GOLD!
IT AIN'T AS BAD AS ALL THAT.
WHAT'S BAD ABOUT IT?
SHOW ME ON THAT LIST
OF TEN COMMANDMENTS
WHERE IT SAYS A WOMAN
CAN'T HAVE TWO HUSBANDS.
THERE AIN'T NO
COMMANDMENT LIKE THAT.
HOT DAMN.
I THINK IT'S GREAT.
IT'S HISTORY-MAKING.
CAN'T HOLD IT.
ELIZABETH...
YES, BEN?
WE WILL BE THREE...
FOR DINNER.
[PAINT YOUR WAGON MEDLEY PLAYS]
SHAMELESS HARLOTS!
YOU THINK THE LORD
WAS SOME OLD BOY
GOING AROUND IN A
RAGGEDY OLD SHEET
2,000 YEARS AGO?
YOU'RE WRONG. HE'S HERE NOW,
AND HE SEES YOU!
YE GODLESS JASPERS!
WHO ARE YOU?
FREEMASONS?
ROSICRUCIANS?
HEATHEN EMISSARIES
FROM THE DENS OF BABYLON?
BOOZERS.
GLUTTONS.
GAMBLERS.
HARLOTS.
FORNICATORS!
WHAT'S A FORNICATOR?
I DON'T KNOW. I AIN'T
A RELIGIOUS MAN.
THE STENCH OF THE CITY
IS IN THE LORD'S NOSTRILS,
AND IT'S MAKING HIM SICK.
THE LORD AIN'T GOING
TO TAKE IT MUCH LONGER!
COME ON UP, PARSON,
AND GET SOME OLD-TIME RELIGION.
HA HA HA! HA HA HA!
GOOD MORNING, MRS. RUMSON.
HOW ARE YOUR HUSBANDS?
THEY'RE FINE. THANK
YOU, MR. ATWELL.
HUSBANDS?
DID I HEAR HUSBANDS?
YOU ANIMALS!
YOU PAGANS!
O GOD, LORD OF HOSTS,
CLOSE THINE EYES,
THEN HOLD THY NOSE.
I AM PASSING THROUGH
THE GARBAGE OF HUMANITY!
HA HA HA! HA HA HA!
COME ON, DEARIE.
SCUM, KEEP YOUR FILTHY CLAWS
OFF MY WIFE PRINCESS
HUMMINGBIRD!
HA HA HA! HA HA HA!
YOU HEATHEN SWINE!
DO YOU KNOW WHAT GOD
DONE TO SODOM AND GOMORRAH
WHEN HE COULDN'T
FIND 50 RIGHTEOUS MEN
IN THEM STINKING CITIES?
NO! NO!
I'LL SHOW GOD A PLACE
WHERE THERE AIN'T 40.
YEAH! YEAH!
30!
TWO!
YEAH! YEAH!
OR ONE!
YEAH! YEAH! YEAH!
AND HERE IT IS.
HOORAY! HOORAY! HOORAY!
♪ YOU WANT TO SEE SIN
OF THE WICKEDEST KIND? ♪
♪ HERE IT IS ♪
♪ YOU WANT TO SEE
VIRTUE LEFT BEHIND? ♪
♪ HERE IT IS ♪
♪ SODOM WAS VICE
AND VICE-A VERSA ♪
♪ YOU WANT TO SEE WHERE
THE VICE IS WORSER? ♪
♪ HERE IT IS ♪
♪ I MEAN, HERE IT IS ♪
♪ YOU WANT TO LIVE LIFE
IN THE ROTTENEST WAY? ♪
♪ HERE IT IS ♪
♪ WOMEN AND WHISKEY
NIGHT AND DAY ♪
♪ HERE IT IS ♪
♪ YOU WANT TO EMBRACE
THE GOLDEN CALF ♪
♪ ANKLE AND THIGH
AND UPPER HALF? ♪
♪ HERE IT IS ♪
♪ I MEAN, HERE IT IS ♪
♪ NO NAME CITY ♪
♪ THE LORD DON'T LIKE IT HERE ♪
♪ YOUR RECKONIN' DAY IS NEAR ♪
♪ NO NAME CITY ♪
♪ HERE'S WHAT HE'S GONNA DO ♪
♪ GOBBLE UP THIS TOWN ♪
♪ AND SWALLOW IT DOWN ♪
♪ AND GOODBYE TO YOU ♪
♪ WILL YOU GO TO HEAVEN? ♪
♪ WILL YOU GO TO HELL? ♪
♪ GO TO HELL ♪
♪ EITHER REPENT
OR FARE THEE WELL ♪
♪ FARE THEE WELL ♪
♪ GOD'LL TAKE CARE
O' NO NAME CITY ♪
♪ COMES THE END, AND
IT WON'T BE PRETTY ♪
♪ HERE IT IS ♪
♪ I MEAN, HERE IT IS ♪
♪ A... ♪
♪ MEN ♪ ♪ MEN ♪ ♪ MEN ♪
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
EVENING, PARDNER.
EVENING, ELIZABETH.
EVENING, BEN.
I HEAR...
GEORGE LONERGAN
PULLED OUT TODAY.
Elizabeth: HE'S SMART.
HE'S BROKE.
BEN THINKS PLACER MINING
IS ALL BUT FINISHED
IN THESE PARTS.
WHAT ARE WE GOING TO DO?
I HEAR TALK OF A
STRIKE UP TO RED DOG.
I'M NOT LEAVING MY HOME, BEN.
I WASN'T SUGGESTING IT.
I'LL LIVE ON GRASS AND MUD WATER
BEFORE I'D DO THAT.
BEN ISN'T ASKING YOU
TO LEAVE YOUR HOME.
DAMN IT! WHY WON'T
YOU LEAVE, ELIZABETH?
YOU LIKE THIS TOWN AS
MUCH AS I LIKE SCHERMERHORN!
I HATE WHAT THIS
TOWN HAS BECOME,
BUT IT'S ONE PLACE
WHERE THE THREE OF
US CAN LIVE TOGETHER,
AND THERE'S NOTHING I HATE
AS MUCH AS I LOVE THE
TWO OF YOU AND THIS CABIN.
IF YOU WANT TO GO UP TO RED DOG,
YOU GO AHEAD AND GO,
BUT I'M STAYING HERE.
YOU COME BACK
WHENEVER YOU WANT TO.
THE ONLY THING
THAT'S KEEPING YOU
FROM BEING THE PERFECT
WOMAN IS YOUR STUBBORNNESS.
SOMEBODY OUGHT TO HIT YOU
WITH A SHOVEL TILL YOU GET OVER IT!
SOMEBODY'S GOT TO
SUPPORT THIS FAMILY!
YOU CAN'T GO THROUGH
A WINTER ALONE HERE.
I'M NOT GOING TO
LEAVE HER HERE ALONE.
YOU MEAN YOU'D LET THIS
MAN WHO TOOK CARE OF YOU
AND NURSED YOU BACK TO HEALTH
LIGHT OUT ALONE WHILE YOU
SLEEP THROUGH THE WINTER
LIKE A FAT GROUNDHOG?
IF HE GOES, YOU GO.
AND I AIN'T GOING.
WELL, I'LL GO, THEN.
IF HE GOES, YOU GO WITH HIM.
DAMN IT! DIDN'T I JUST
GET THROUGH TELLING YOU
YOU CAN'T GO THROUGH
A WINTER ALONE HERE?
YOU EVER SEE SUCH
A STUBBORN WOMAN?
NO, I NEVER DID.
BUT IF YOU EVER HIT HER,
YOU'LL HAVE TO DEAL
WITH ME STRAIGHTAWAY.
I SURE AM ONE TIRED MAN TONIGHT.
MUST BE FROM LIFTING
THOSE CARDS ALL NIGHT.
I ONLY PLAYED A FEW
HANDS LAST NIGHT, ELIZABETH.
I HAD A LUCKY STREAK,
TOO. I BROKE EVEN.
You'll tell
Three-fingered Sweeney
I'll pay him back next week?
YOU WAS PLAYING
POKER LAST NIGHT?
YEAH, I WAS, AND YOU
WAS TIRED. REMEMBER?
OH. WELL, I THINK I'LL GO DOWN
AND HAVE A LAST DRINK
WITH THEM THREE LIMEYS.
THEY'RE, UH, PULLING
OUT TOMORROW.
HOW MUCH DOES HE OWE SWEENEY?
OH, NOW, WAIT A MINUTE.
I'M NOT GOING TO
TAKE YOUR MONEY.
WHY NOT?
'CAUSE A MAN DON'T DO THAT
IN MICHIGAN OR IN CALIFORNIA.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT WITH ME,
BUT IF YOU WANT TO
KEEP YOUR MANHOOD,
QUIT TRYING TO BEAT THREE ACES
WITH A PAIR OF 4s.
SEE YOU AT BREAKFAST.
[CANCAN MUSIC PLAYS]
SORRY, BOYS, PARDNER
AIN'T PLAYING TONIGHT.
WILLIE?
WHAT?
HAVE YOU SEEN MAD JACK?
HE'S OVER THERE.
HEY, I WANT TO CONVERT
THIS DUST INTO DOLLARS.
LOOK OUT, MAD JACK!
THAT MAN'S LOSING GOLD DUST
EVERY TIME YOU BUMP HIS ELBOW.
THERE'S MORE GOLD DUST
SPILLED HERE IN ONE NIGHT
THAN WE'VE DUG UP IN A MONTH.
MUST BE A PIRATE'S FORTUNE
UNDER THEM FLOORBOARDS.
WHERE ARE YOU HEADING?
WHERE I CAN FIND SOME GOLD,
MAYBE FLESHPOT HILL,
MAYBE BRASS MONKEY RAVINE.
I DON'T KNOW.
SAVE YOUR SOULS.
HELP BUILD A HOUSE FOR THE LORD.
HE CAN HAVE MY
SHACK. I'M MOVING OUT.
HA HA HA! HA HA HA!
YOU HEATHEN SCUM.
AND THE LORD SAYETH,
"MONEY IS THE ROOT OF ALL EVIL."
THE LORD SAYETH THAT
'CAUSE HE AIN'T RICH.
HE KNOWETH ALL ABOUT YOU,
LIVING LIKE ANIMALS
IN THAT CABIN.
YOU'RE GOING TO HELL!
I HOPE SO.
IF IT AIN'T TOO FAR DOWN,
I'LL TUNNEL UP AND
GET SOME GOLD DUST
THAT'S BEEN FALLING
THROUGH THESE FLOOR...
HOW DO YOU FIGURE
WE CAN DIG A TUNNEL
WITHOUT BEING SEEN?
WE'LL DIG DOWN FROM
THE FLOOR IN OUR CABIN,
UNDER THE STREET, AND
RIGHT UP UNDER HERE.
A TUNNEL?
YOU IDIOT!
[SNORING]
WHY, YOU...
DIG NOW. HIT HIM LATER, LUNATIC.
HERE.
WHAT THE HELL'S HAPPENING?
WE'RE GOING TO TUNNEL
IN UNDER WILLIE'S PLACE.
AFTER THAT GOLD DUST
UNDER WILLIE'S FLOOR, EH?
HOW IN HELL DID YOU KNOW THAT?
I'VE BEEN THINKING
ABOUT THAT FOR WEEKS.
WHY DIDN'T YOU SPEAK UP, EH?
YOU DIRTY, LAZY, NO-GOOD
DRUNKEN... OH, HEY!
LAZY, AM I?
DAMN YOU.
SHUT UP.
DUNCAN... OW!
DIG NOW. HIT HIM LATER.
RIGHT.
YOU CAN HIT ME LATER.
I'LL REMIND YOU.
DON'T FORGET.
PARDNER'S IN ON THIS.
THEN WHERE IS HE?
HE'S HOME TONIGHT.
DOING WHAT?
DAMN YOU!
KEEP A CIVIL TONGUE
IN YOUR MOUTH,
OR I'LL...
YOU CAN HIT HIM LATER.
YOU CAN HIT ME LATER.
AND I'LL REMIND YOU.
DIG.
OH!
HEY, WILLIE, YOU
SEEN BEN RUMSON?
UH-UH.
SORRY.
CLOSE THE BLOODY DOOR.
OH, YOU'RE DIGGING A HOLE.
HEY, YOU DON'T
MISS A TRICK, DO YOU?
BEN?
PARDNER, WE GOT
BIG NEWS FOR YOU.
YOU'RE DOING WHAT?
WE AIN'T STOPPING AT WILLIE'S.
THERE'S 16 GAMBLING HALLS,
7 HOTELS, AND 21 SALOONS,
AND ASSORTED PLAYGROUNDS.
WE CAN BUILD TUNNELS
UNDER ALL OF THEM,
HONEYCOMB MAIN STREET,
ONE END TO THE OTHER.
WHAT WILL WE DO
WITH ALL THAT EARTH?
GIVE IT TO THE MEEK.
HAVE YOU GONE CRAZY?
OH, HE'S NOT CRAZY.
THERE'S A LOT OF GOLD DUST
GOING THROUGH THOSE FLOORS.
I THINK MAYBE THERE'S
MORE THAN A LOT.
ENOUGH FOR THE WINTER.
HURRY UP AND EAT
THIS, BOTH OF YOU.
COFFEE WILL BE
READY IN A MINUTE.
I DON'T WANT YOU
TO BE LATE TO WORK.
♪ THE EARTH IS PURE MUCK ♪
♪ MUCK'S A GOOD THING ♪
♪ AND OOZIN' WITH MUD ♪
♪ MUD IS JUST FINE ♪
♪ IT'S DROWNIN' IN BOG ♪
♪ BOG IS GOOD LUCK ♪
♪ AND CRAWLIN' WITH CRUD ♪
♪ CRUD'S A GOOD SIGN ♪
♪ THE POOR, THEY GOT HOPE ♪
♪ THE RICH CAN BUY SOAP ♪
♪ WHAT RAINBOWS
AIN'T GOT A POT OF ♪
♪ AND I AIN'T GOT A SPOT OF ♪
♪ A FEW FEET DOWN
THERE'S A LOT OF ♪
♪ JUST WAITIN' TO BUY ♪
♪ TOBACCO AND RYE ♪
♪ FROM NOW TILL I DIE ♪
♪ THE BEST THINGS
IN LIFE ARE DIRTY ♪
♪ AND NOTHING IN LIFE IS ♪
♪ BETTER TO HOLD
THAN DIRTY GOLD ♪
♪ THE BEST THINGS IN LIFE ARE ♪
♪ FILTHY, DIRTY HUNKS
OF GOLD, GOLD, GOLD ♪
♪ THERE'S MORE THAN JUST GOLD ♪
♪ GOLD IS ENOUGH ♪
♪ THAT'S BURIED BELOW ♪
♪ BEAUTIFUL GOLD ♪
♪ THERE'S SEED IN THE GROUND ♪
♪ LOVABLE GOLD ♪
♪ JUST WAITIN' TO GROW ♪
♪ SPENDABLE GOLD ♪
♪ A MAN HAS HIS CREED ♪
♪ AND MINE IS ALL GREED ♪
♪ WHAT BANKS HAVE
BULGIN' ACCOUNTS OF ♪
♪ AND I AIN'T GOT AN OUNCE OF ♪
♪ BELOW THERE'S
ENDLESS AMOUNTS OF ♪
♪ JUST DIRTY OLD TRASH ♪
♪ THAT TURNS IN A FLASH ♪
♪ TO DIRTY OLD CASH ♪
[CRASH]
♪ THE BEST THINGS
IN LIFE ARE DIRTY ♪
♪ THE WORST THING IN LIFE IS ♪
♪ WAKIN' UP CLEAN
WITHOUT A BEAN ♪
♪ THE BEST THINGS IN LIFE ARE ♪
♪ FILTHY DIRTY HUNKS
OF GOLD, GOLD, GOLD ♪
♪ THE BEST THINGS
IN LIFE ARE DIRTY ♪
♪ THE WORST THING IN LIFE IS ♪
♪ BEING CONTENT WITHOUT A CENT ♪
♪ THE BEST THINGS IN LIFE ARE ♪
♪ FILTHY DIRTY HUNKS OF
GOLD, GOLD, GOLD, GOLD ♪
♪ STINKIN' ROTTEN
CHUNKS OF BLIMEY, SLIMY ♪
♪ LOUSY, LOVELY... ♪
All: ♪ GOLD ♪♪
HEY, YOU BUMMERS, OVER HERE!
I FOUND HIM IN THE MOUNTAINS.
HE'S HALF-FROZEN.
GET HIM TO A FIRE.
HE SAYS THERE'S A WAGON
TRAIN MAROONED UP THERE.
GET UP A RESCUE PARTY.
LET'S GET OUT OF THESE MOUNTAINS
BEFORE ANOTHER STORM COMES UP.
PACK UP!
YOU'VE ARRIVED AT THE HEIGHT
OF THE SEASON, MR. FENTY,
BUT WE'LL FIND HOTEL SPACE
FOR THE WHOLE BLOODY LOT OF YOU.
IF YOU CAN SHAKE YOUR
FAMILY AND DON'T DIE,
YOU'LL HAVE ONE HELL OF A TIME.
WE SHOULDN'T TAKE
RESPECTABLE PEOPLE
TO NO NAME CITY.
WE'LL TAKE IN A
FEW AT OUR PLACE.
MAYBE YOU CAN TAKE THE REST.
IS THERE ROOM IN YOUR CABIN
TO PUT A COUPLE OF INVALIDS?
BEN'S BRINGING IN HER HUSBAND.
OH, MRS. FENTY,
THIS IS MRS. RUMSON.
I'M MRS. FENTY'S SON HORTON.
THIS IS MY SISTER LAURA SUE.
HERE ARE SOME BLANKETS.
YOU KEEP WARM BY THE FIRE.
I'LL TAKE CARE OF THE CHILDREN.
YOUR HUSBAND IS A
GOOD MAN, MRS. RUMSON.
YES, THEY ARE.
I SAID THAT HUSBAND
OF YOURS IS A GOOD MAN.
YES, UH, THANK YOU, MRS. FENTY.
DON'T YOU WORRY.
THOSE CHILDREN WENT
STRAIGHT TO SLEEP.
I'LL SEE TO MR. FENTY NOW.
THANK YOU, MR. RUMSON.
OH, MY NAME'S NOT RUMSON, MA'AM.
THAT'S MY WIFE'S NAME.
NOW, I'LL BET THAT
SEEMS A LITTLE CONFUSING,
DON'T IT?
A LITTLE, YES.
HOW IS IT YOU AND YOUR HUSBAND
DON'T HAVE THE SAME NAME?
OH, WELL, THAT'S
EASY TO EXPLAIN.
IT IS?
IN THE CHINESE SECTION OF TOWN
WAS A JOINT CALLED
THE PAGODA HELL SALOON,
AND UPSTAIRS THERE LIVED
A REAL MANDARIN PRINCESS
WHO USED TO INVITE
ME OVER OCCASIONALLY
FOR A LITTLE EGG ROLL.
BEN.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
I'M ENTERING YOUR HOUSE
TO PRAY FOR THE
UNFORTUNATE VICTIMS.
NOT TONIGHT, PARSON.
THESE FOLKS HAVE
SUFFERED ENOUGH.
WHY DON'T YOU DO THAT OUTSIDE
WHERE GOD CAN HEAR YOU BETTER?
'CAUSE I'LL BE TALKING IN HERE.
YOU CAN'T TALK TO
THE PARSON THAT WAY
IN FRONT OF THESE PEOPLE.
THIS IS A NICE,
CHURCH-GOING FAMILY.
NOW GO SEE WHERE PARDNER IS
WITH THE SUPPLIES.
YES, MA'AM.
WILL YOU TELL ME
THE REST OF THE
STORY AFTER DINNER?
SURE. ABOUT 10
YEARS AFTER DINNER.
[COUGHING]
I'LL TAKE CARE OF
YOUR LITTLE SISTER.
YOU KEEP WARM.
MRS. RUMSON, IF THE OTHER
GENTLEMAN IS YOUR HUSBAND,
WHO'S MR. RUMSON?
HE'S MY HUSBAND'S PARDNER.
WELL, HOW IS IT
YOU HAVE HIS NAME?
JUST A COINCIDENCE.
OH.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
ELIZABETH AIN'T SICK.
NOW, YOU LISTEN TO ME.
SHE'S PICKED UP A BAD CASE
OF THE RESPECTABILITIES.
IN A FEW DAYS,
THAT POOR WOMAN'S
GOING TO BE BURNING UP
IN A FEVER OF VIRTUE.
AND THEN LOOK OUT.
WHY?
PARDNER, IT'S BEEN MY EXPERIENCE
THAT THERE AIN'T NOTHING MORE
RUTHLESS AND TREACHEROUS
THAN A GENUINE GOOD WOMAN.
BEN, YOU HAVE TO PUT UP
AT ATWELL'S HOTEL TONIGHT.
I WHAT?
I CAN'T TELL THEM I'M
LIVING WITH TWO MEN.
ELIZABETH, YOU AIN'T
MAKING ANY SENSE.
IF YOU WANT TO BE RESPECTABLE,
HOW COME MR. RUMSON
HAS TO MOVE OUT
WHILE MRS. RUMSON
STAYS WITH ANOTHER MAN?
IF ANYBODY LEAVES, IT
REALLY OUGHT TO BE ME.
YOU CAN'T.
I ALREADY TOLD THEM
PARDNER'S MY HUSBAND.
TELL THEM YOU'VE MADE A MISTAKE.
IT'S ONLY FOR ONE OR TWO NIGHTS.
WHAT GIVES YOU THAT IDEA?
WHY, IT'LL BE 6 WEEKS
BEFORE THEY CAN MOVE.
ONLY A FARMER'S DUMB
ENOUGH TO GET FROZE
AND TOUGH ENOUGH TO SURVIVE IT.
DAMN FARMERS!
ALL RIGHT, I'LL SLEEP OUT.
WHERE YOU GOING?
TO GET MY THINGS.
I GOT THEM RIGHT HERE.
MM-HMM.
SEE YOU IN THE TUNNELS, BEN.
YOU MOVING OUT, BEN?
NO.
ME, NEITHER.
I GUESS THERE'S TWO
KINDS IN THE WORLD, BEN...
PEOPLE WHO MOVE,
PEOPLE WHO STAY.
AIN'T THAT TRUE?
NO, THAT AIN'T TRUE.
WELL, WHAT'S TRUE?
OH, THERE'S TWO
KINDS OF PEOPLE...
THEM GOING SOMEWHERE
AND THEM GOING NOWHERE,
AND THAT'S WHAT'S TRUE.
I DON'T AGREE, BEN.
THAT'S 'CAUSE YOU DON'T KNOW
WHAT THE HELL I'M TALKING ABOUT.
I'M AN EX-CITIZEN OF NOWHERE,
AND SOMETIMES I
GET MIGHTY HOMESICK.
♪ I WAS BORN ♪
♪ UNDER A WAND'RIN' STAR ♪
♪ WHEELS ARE MADE FOR ROLLIN' ♪
♪ MULES ARE MADE TO PACK ♪
♪ I'VE NEVER SEEN A SIGHT ♪
♪ THAT DIDN'T LOOK
BETTER LOOKIN' BACK ♪
♪ I WAS BORN ♪
♪ UNDER A WAND'RIN' STAR ♪
♪ MUD CAN MAKE YOU A PRISONER ♪
♪ AND THE PLAINS
CAN BAKE YOU DRY ♪
♪ SNOW CAN BURN YOUR EYES ♪
♪ BUT ONLY PEOPLE MAKE YOU CRY ♪
♪ HOME IS MADE FOR COMIN' FROM ♪
♪ FOR DREAMS OF GOIN' TO ♪
♪ WHICH, WITH ANY LUCK,
WILL NEVER COME TRUE ♪
♪ I WAS BORN ♪
♪ UNDER A WAND'RIN' STAR ♪
♪ DO I KNOW WHERE HELL IS? ♪
♪ HELL IS IN HELLO ♪
♪ HEAVEN IS GOODBYE FOREVER ♪
♪ IT'S TIME FOR ME TO GO ♪
♪ I WAS BORN ♪
♪ UNDER A WAND'RIN' STAR ♪
♪ A WAND'RIN' ♪
♪ WAND'RIN' STAR ♪
♪ MUD CAN MAKE YOU PRISONER ♪
♪ AND THE PLAINS
CAN BAKE YOU DRY ♪
♪ SNOW CAN BURN YOUR EYES ♪
♪ BUT ONLY PEOPLE MAKE YOU CRY ♪
♪ HOME IS MADE FOR COMIN' FROM ♪
♪ FOR DREAMS OF GOIN' TO ♪
♪ WHICH, WITH ANY LUCK,
WILL NEVER COME TRUE ♪
♪ I WAS BORN ♪
♪ UNDER A WAND'RIN' STAR ♪
♪ WHEN I GET TO HEAVEN ♪
♪ TIE ME TO A TREE ♪
♪ OR I'LL BEGIN TO ROAM ♪
♪ AND SOON YOU
KNOW WHERE I WILL BE ♪
♪ I WAS BORN ♪
♪ UNDER A WAND'RIN' STAR ♪
♪ A WAND'RIN' ♪
♪ WAND'RIN' STAR ♪♪
WELL, WILLIE, COULD
YOU ACCOMMODATE ME
FOR A COUPLE OF DAYS?
SURE. TAKE YOUR PICK.
NO. I MEAN A ROOM
I CAN SLEEP IN.
WE DON'T RENT EMPTY BEDS.
JUST TILL THEM SICK
FARMERS LEAVE MY HOUSE.
WAIT. CLOTILDE'S
GONE OFF FOR A WHILE.
YOU CAN USE HER ROOM.
WHAT HAPPENED TO CLOTILDE?
SOME BUMMER SAYS IF
SHE DON'T MARRY HIM,
HE'S GOING TO KILL HER.
SHE TOOK OFF FOR A WHILE
TO LET HIM SIMMER DOWN.
SHE SAID SHE'D MARRY HIM.
HE WANTS HER TO QUIT WORKING.
WELL, THAT'S A
NARROW-MINDED ATTITUDE.
[SNIFFING]
WHEW.
YEAH. SHE'S A FANCY
SMELLER, ALL RIGHT.
DAMN FARMERS.
[SNORING]
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
Man: SUGAR, GUESS WHO THIS IS.
SUGAR, GUESS WHO THIS IS.
[SNIFFING]
HEY, BY GOOM,
I MUST HAVE BEEN
DOWN HERE TOO LONG.
YOU'RE BEGINNING TO
SMELL LIKE A WOMAN.
GOOD MORNING. GOOD MORNING.
GOOD MORNING, MR. RUMSON.
YOU'RE AN HOUR LATE.
WHO THE HELL'S THE STRANGER?
HE WON'T TELL ANYBODY.
HE'S PRACTICALLY
ONE OF THE FAMILY.
JUST WANTED TO SEE WHAT
A GOLD MINE LOOKED LIKE.
YOU OPEN YOUR MOUTH
ABOUT THIS TUNNEL,
I'LL PUT A STICK
OF DYNAMITE IN IT.
YOU TELL NO ONE, DO YOU HEAR?
I SWEAR BEFORE GOD.
I SAID NO ONE.
START AT END OF NUMBER FOUR.
WORK AN EXTRA HOUR
TO MAKE UP FOR BEING LATE.
HOW'S ELIZABETH?
OH, SHE'S FINE.
IN FACT, WE'D LIKE
TO HAVE YOU FOR DINNER TONIGHT.
IS THAT RIGHT?
YEAH. AROUND 6:30.
IS THAT ALL RIGHT?
WELL, THAT'S MIGHTY NEIGHBORLY,
BUT I GOT TO PLAY THE ORGAN
FOR THE PARSON TONIGHT.
WELL, POSSIBLY SOME OTHER TIME.
WELL, IF YOU'RE JUST
ONE OF THE FAMILY,
DIG!
MR. RUMSON, I SWORE I
WOULDN'T TELL ANYONE.
I HOPE THAT MEANS EXCEPT
MY MOTHER AND FATHER.
THAT MEANS ESPECIALLY
YOUR MOTHER AND FATHER.
BUT I'VE NEVER KEPT
ANYTHING FROM THEM.
IT'S ABOUT TIME YOU STARTED,
'CAUSE WHEN YOU DO,
A WHOLE NEW WORLD OPENS UP.
YOU GOT THAT KIND OF COLD,
EMPTY FEELING INSIDE OF YOU?
DO ALL GOLD MINERS GET THAT?
IT'S VERY COMMON.
WHAT DO THEY DO FOR IT?
I'LL SHOW YOU.
ARE WE GOING IN A SALOON?
WELL, THAT'S WHERE
THE MEDICINE CLOSET IS.
IT'S PART OF THAT
WHOLE NEW WORLD
I WAS TELLING YOU ABOUT.
AFTER YOU, COLUMBUS.
♪ GENTLE MUSIC FILLS THE SKY ♪
♪ AT NO NAME CITY ♪
♪ AND THE DAYS,
THEY WHISPER BY ♪
♪ AT NO NAME CITY ♪
COME ON.
♪ SURE, THERE'S NOT
A SPOT AS RARE IN ♪
♪ ALL HEAVEN OR IN ERIN ♪
♪ LET ME LIVE UNTIL I DIE ♪
♪ IN NO NAME TOWN ♪
[HICCUP]
AHH.
THAT'S GOOD.
MY FIRST DRINK.
AHH.
YOU, UH... FEELING ALL RIGHT?
OH, YES, SIR. THANK YOU.
THAT, UH, COLD, HOLLOW FEELING
IS ALMOST GONE.
BARTENDER, CIGARS.
THANK YOU.
I'LL BET THAT'S THE
STRONGEST CIGAR
YOU EVER SMOKED.
IT'S THE FIRST CIGAR
I EVER SMOKED.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
[GAG]
[COUGHING]
YOU ALL RIGHT, MR. RUMSON?
[GASPING] YEAH, FINE.
WHY DO YOU THINK
MY FATHER IS SO DEAD
SET AGAINST SALOONS?
'CAUSE FARMERS
AIN'T GOT THE TIME
TO ENJOY THE
GOOD THINGS IN LIFE.
FARMER'S GOT A BUSY DAY...
GOT TO PULL THEM TURNIPS,
TALK ABOUT THE WEATHER.
THAT'S ABOUT AS MUCH
AS HE CAN HANDLE.
[WOMEN SHOUTING]
QUIET!
WHO ARE THEY, MR. RUMSON?
OH, THEY'RE ON THE MENU.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND, SIR.
NOW, HORTON... NOW,
YOU AIN'T GOING TO TELL ME
THAT YOU AIN'T NEVER
HAD A WOMAN, NEITHER?
NO, SIR, I HAVEN'T.
THAT'S ABSO...
WHY, THAT'S TERRIBLE!
DO YOU KNOW THAT
YOU COULD GO BLIND?
WE GOT TO DO SOMETHING
ABOUT THAT RIGHT AWAY.
I WOULDN'T KNOW WHAT TO DO.
DON'T WORRY. WITH YOUR TALENT,
YOU'LL CATCH ON IN NO TIME.
UH, WILLIE, AHEM...
IF YOU WAS TO GO
TRAPPING FOR THE FIRST TIME,
WHO WOULD YOU TAKE
ALONG AS A GUIDE?
THAT WOULD BE GRACIE.
SHE LOVES ADVENTURE.
OH, GRACE, UH...
I GIVE YOU THE BOY.
GIVE ME BACK THE MAN.
THAT WAS THE BEST, MR. RUMSON.
YOU THINK SO, HUH?
WITHOUT ANY DOUBT. NOW, I LIKE
SMOKING AND DRINKING VERY MUCH,
BUT THEY CAN'T
TOUCH THE LAST ONE.
THAT'S GOT EVERYTHING.
MOST PEOPLE WOULD
GO ALONG WITH THAT.
WELL, GOOD NIGHT.
MRS. RUMSON WILL BE SORRY
YOU'RE NOT COMING FOR DINNER.
LAST THING SHE SAID
WAS TO BRING YOU.
OH?
WELL, IN THAT
CASE, MAYBE I WILL.
GOOD.
I'LL WALK YOU HOME AFTER.
NOW, REMEMBER,
YOU WASN'T IN NO TUNNELS,
AND YOU WASN'T IN NO SALOON.
I REMEMBER.
AND THE FOOD THAT...
SHUT THE DOOR, WILL YOU, BEN?
FOR THIS WE THANK THEE, LORD.
AMEN.
AMEN. AMEN. AMEN.
WILL YOU WIPE YOUR FEET OFF?
EVENING, BEN. COME SIT DOWN.
EVENING, ELIZABETH.
WELL, PARDNER,
YOU HANDLED GRACE PRETTY GOOD.
NOT AS GOOD AS HORTON
DID THIS AFTERNOON,
BUT PRETTY GOOD.
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN, HORTON?
UH, GOLD MINING, PA.
YOUR SON'S THE MOST NATURAL-BORN
GOLD MINER THAT I EVER MET.
I BROUGHT HIM UP NOT TO
BE AFRAID TO TRY ANYTHING.
WELL, THAT BOY TRIES EVERYTHING.
DID YOU KNOW THAT THE FENTYS
HAD AN APPLE FARM
BACK IN PENNSYLVANIA?
APPLEJACK, HUH?
NO, SIR, WE DID NOT
MAKE APPLEJACK.
THEN WHY GROW APPLES?
YOU THINK EVERYTHING
THAT COMES OUT OF THE EARTH
SHOULD BE USED TO MAKE LIQUOR?
WHENEVER POSSIBLE, YES.
Mrs. Fenty: YOU
SHOULD READ THE BIBLE.
I HAVE READ THE BIBLE.
DIDN'T THAT DISCOURAGE
YOU ABOUT DRINKING?
NO, BUT IT SURE KILLED
MY APPETITE FOR READING.
WE'VE BEEN TELLING THE FENTYS
WHAT GOOD LAND'S
ALL AROUND THIS VALLEY.
Mr. Fenty: YES. WE'RE THINKING
OF SETTLING DOWN HERE.
OH, GREAT!
THAT NEWS IS SO GOD DAMN GREAT,
I NEED A DRINK.
DON'T LISTEN TO HIM.
HE'S ALWAYS JOKING.
ELIZABETH, THE WHISKEY'S GONE.
I KNOW.
I POURED IT ALL OUT.
YOU WHAT?
OUT OF COURTESY
TO OUR GUESTS, BEN.
IF YOU WANT A DRINK,
GET YOUR CARCASS
OUT OF THIS HOUSE.
YOU CAN'T ORDER A MAN
OUT OF HIS OWN HOUSE.
HIS HOUSE?
THAT'S RIGHT. IT'S HIS HOUSE.
MRS. RUMSON IS MARRIED TO HIM?
SHE'S MARRIED TO THE BOTH OF US.
AT THE SAME TIME?
WELL, WE'RE PARDNERS.
I HAVE NEVER HEARD...
SHUT UP AND SIT DOWN!
DON'T ORDER THE GUESTS AROUND.
WHY NOT? IT'S HIS FAULT.
WITHOUT HIS GOD
DAMN RESPECTABILITY,
WE'D STILL BE A
HAPPILY MARRIED...
TRIPLE.
THERE'S NOT ONE
DRINK OF WHISKEY?
TAKE MINE.
BOY, YOU SAVED MY LIFE.
HORTON, HOW DID THAT BOTTLE
GET INTO YOUR POCKET?
HOW LONG HAVE YOU BEEN
DRINKING HARD LIQUOR?
WELL, SINCE THIS AFTERNOON.
YOU DON'T APPROVE,
BUT, BELIEVE ME,
UNTIL YOU'VE HAD A
GOOD CIGAR AND WHISKEY,
YOU'RE MISSING THE SECOND
AND THIRD BEST THINGS IN LIFE.
HORTON.
WHERE DID YOU TAKE HIM, BEN?
DAMN YOU, BEN RUMSON.
WHAT ARE YOU GOING
TO TEACH THIS BOY NEXT?
HOW TO CHEAT AT CARDS
OR JUST PHYSICAL EDUCATION
WITH ONE OF WILLIE'S FLOOZIES?
THAT'S THE BEST ONE.
HORTON!
IS THAT WHAT YOU DID TODAY, BEN?
THAT'S WHAT HE DID TODAY.
THIS BOY'S GOT A
TALENT FOR DISSIPATION
THAT IS ABSOLUTELY UNIQUE.
OUT.
GET OUT!
I ORDER YOU OUT OF THIS HOUSE.
THIS IS NOT YOUR HOUSE.
THIS IS MY HOUSE.
THAT'S RIGHT. I
GIVE HER THE HOUSE.
AND IF YOU EVER CROSS
THIS THRESHOLD AGAIN,
I'LL SHOOT YOU DOWN
LIKE ANY OTHER MARAUDER.
WHAT'S SHE SO HET UP ABOUT?
SHE'S GOT A RIGHT TO BE.
YOU HAD TO TAKE YOUR REVENGE OUT
ON THE VIRTUE OF THIS BOY,
SHOW HIM WHAT AN
UGLY TOWN THIS REALLY IS.
WELL, IF WE LIVE HERE,
THEN WE'RE UGLY, TOO.
I COULD NEVER GO BACK
TO WHAT WE HAD BEFORE.
IT'S OVER, AND IT'S
DONE, AND IT'S FINISHED.
NOW GET OUT.
WAIT. IF BEN GOES,
I'D HAVE TO GO.
THEN YOU GO, TOO.
EVENING, MA'AM.
GOOD EVENING, MA'AM.
YOU MUTTON-HEADED CLUNK.
YOU KNEW SHE DIDN'T
WANT THEM TO KNOW.
ELIZABETH'S A SICK WOMAN.
YOU GOT NO RESPECT FOR ANYBODY
OR ANYTHING.
I DON'T HAVE YOUR
KIND OF RESPECT,
SITTING AT THE TABLE
WITH YOUR HANDS FOLDED
AND THAT PIOUS LOOK ON YOUR FACE
AFTER A HARD DAY'S THIEVING.
IT AIN'T THIEVING.
THEN WHY ARE WE HIDING IT?
WHY ARE WE TALKING ABOUT IT?
SHE'S BACK THERE ALL ALONE.
WHOSE FAULT IS THAT?
YOURS.
SHE THREW US OUT.
DON'T YOU SAY ANYTHING
AGAINST ELIZABETH AROUND ME.
I'LL SAY ANYTHING I WANT.
SHE'S MY WIFE,
BOUGHT AND PAID FOR,
AND DON'T YOU FORGET IT.
I NEVER DO FORGET IT.
I GOT NOTHING
MORE TO SAY TO YOU.
THEN YOU GOT
NOTHING I WANT TO HEAR,
AND IF I EVER CATCH YOU
SNEAKING BACK WITHOUT ME,
THEY'LL NEVER FIND
ALL OF YOU TO BURY.
BULL AND BEAR FIGHT!
SEE THE GREAT BULL THAT CUT UP
THE MOUNTAIN LION IN SONORA
AND TRIUMPHED
OVER 10 LARGE DOGS!
SAVE YOUR SOULS, HEATHEN SCUM!
ALLOW THIS BUTCHERY
TO TAKE PLACE ON SUNDAY,
AND GOD WILL WASH
HIS HANDS OF YOU.
THANK YOU, PARSON. NOW MOVE ON.
GOD IS GOING TO CAUSE
THE EARTH TO OPEN
AND SWALLOW UP
THIS NEST OF EVIL,
AND THE LORD AIN'T FOOLING.
[RUMBLING]
I HEAR STRANGE RUMBLINGS
IN THE EARTH BELOW.
YEAH, THEY'RE GOING
TO SELL A LOT OF TICKETS
TO THE BULL AND
BEAR FIGHT ON SUNDAY.
A LOT OF GOLD DUST
IS GOING TO FALL.
BUT WE DON'T HAVE A
TUNNEL UNDER THERE.
ARGHHH!
YOU BLOODY MANIAC!
WHY DIDN'T YOU BUILD ONE?
WE CAN GET UNDER THERE.
THERE'S NOTHING TO IT.
MAYBE SO...
BUT WE COULD SURE
USE A BIT OF HELP.
HEY.
WHAT ABOUT THAT YOUNG FARMER?
WHERE IS HE?
HORTON FENTY?
LITTLE DID I REALIZE IT,
BUT WHEN THAT BOY SET FOOT
ON THE SECOND STORY
OF WILLIE'S SALOON,
HISTORY WAS IN THE MAKING.
IS THAT WHERE HE IS?
THAT'S WHERE HE ALWAYS IS...
PUFFING ON A CIGAR,
DRINKING WHISKEY,
KNOCKING ON THEM DOORS.
IF THAT BOY DON'T SLOW DOWN,
THEM GIRLS ARE GOING TO
STRIKE FOR SHORTER HOURS.
I'LL SEE IF I CAN CATCH HIM
BETWEEN ROOMS TONIGHT.
IF WE COULD DIVERT HIS ENERGY,
WE COULD BE THROUGH BY MORNING.
YOUR BET.
I'LL BET 50.
I'LL SEE THAT AND RAISE YOU 50.
NOT FOR ME. I'M OUT.
HAVE YOU SEEN THE FUTURE
FATHER OF OUR COUNTRY?
YEAH. HE WENT HOME.
WHEN WILL HE BE BACK?
SOON AS HIS FOLKS ARE ASLEEP.
TELL HIM I WANT TO SEE HIM.
LEAVE YOUR DOOR OPEN
AND WAIT YOUR TURN.
HERE.
UH, PARDON ME, SIR.
COULD YOU LEND ME $10?
WHY DON'T YOU GO
HOME AND GO TO BED?
I WAS THINKING OF DOING IT
THE OTHER WAY AROUND.
THANK YOU, SIR.
I'LL SEE YOUR 50.
RED 7 WINS AGAIN!
PARDON ME.
HERE'S YOUR $10 BACK, SIR,
OH, AND 10 MORE.
RED 7.
YOU'RE LOSING A LOT
OF MONEY, PARDNER.
WHERE DO YOU GET IT ALL?
THIEVING.
♪ I WOULD GIVE
THE WORLD TO SEE ♪
♪ HOW I USED TO BE ♪
♪ WHEN I HAD NO AX TO GRIND ♪
♪ EXCEPT FOR CHOPPIN' WOOD ♪
♪ DAY WAS DAY, AND
NIGHT WAS NIGHT ♪
♪ WRONG WAS NEVER RIGHT ♪
♪ IT DIDN'T MATTER
WHERE I WENT ♪
♪ AS MUCH AS WHERE I STOOD ♪
♪ I HAD DREAMS ♪
♪ AVERAGE SIZE ♪
♪ THERE WERE STARS ♪
♪ IN THE SKIES ♪
♪ NOT MY EYES ♪
♪ THEN I GOT ♪
♪ GOLD FEVER ♪
♪ NO ROMPIN', ROLLIN'
GIRL-AND-FELLOW STUFF ♪
♪ CAN CURE THE ♪
♪ GOLD FEVER ♪
♪ NOTHIN' CAN HELP YOU ♪
♪ BUT THE YELLOW STUFF ♪
♪ WHAT ♪
♪ CAN STOP THAT ITCHIN' ♪
♪ AIN'T ♪
♪ AROUND THE KITCHEN ♪
♪ GOLD, GOLD ♪
♪ HOOKED AM I ♪
♪ SUSANNAH, GO AHEAD AND CRY ♪
♪ ONCE WE ALL DID HONEST WORK ♪
♪ FARMER, LAWYER, CLERK ♪
♪ MARRIED MEN AND SINGLE MEN ♪
♪ AND SOME WHO AIN'T TOO SURE ♪
♪ NOW I LOOK AT THEM AND SEE ♪
♪ DUPLICATES OF ME ♪
♪ CURED OF WHAT
WE SUFFERED FROM ♪
♪ AND SUFFERIN' FROM THE CURE ♪
♪ WHO CAN SAY ♪
♪ WHY WE CAME? ♪
♪ WHERE'S THE HOPE? ♪
♪ WHERE'S THE FLAME? ♪
♪ WE'RE THE SAME ♪
♪ WHEN YOU'VE GOT ♪
♪ GOLD FEVER ♪
♪ NO ROMPIN', ROLLIN'
GIRL-AND-FELLOW STUFF ♪
♪ CAN CURE THE ♪
♪ GOLD FEVER ♪
♪ NOTHIN' CAN HELP YOU
BUT THE YELLOW STUFF ♪
♪ WHAT ♪
♪ CAN STOP THAT ITCHIN' AIN'T ♪
♪ AROUND THE KITCHEN ♪
♪ GOLD, GOLD, HOOKED AM I ♪
♪ SUSANNAH, GO AHEAD AND CRY ♪
♪ GOLD FEVER ♪
♪ GOLD FEVER ♪♪
DEAL.
BY GOD, WE MADE IT.
WELL, NOW THEY CAN
OPEN THE BOX OFFICE.
[CROWD CHEERING]
HERE'S YOUR DAY'S EARNINGS, BEN.
AND HERE'S YOURS, PARDNER.
I WANT YOU TO TELL BEN
SOMETHING FOR ME, WILL YOU?
HE'S SITTING RIGHT THERE.
JUST TELL HIM THAT I'M MOVING ON
BEFORE WINTER SETS IN.
HE CAN GET HIMSELF
ANOTHER PARDNER.
YOU BUMMERS CAN, UH,
DIVIDE UP ANYTHING
I GOT COMING HERE.
WHERE YOU HEADING?
WELL, RED DOG.
I HEAR THEY'RE DIGGING IT
UP IN CHUNKS OVER THERE.
BY GOOM, THEY'RE ALWAYS
DIGGING IT UP IN CHUNKS
SOMEWHERE ELSE.
GOOD LUCK, MAN.
THANKS, JACK.
JACK, UH...
TELL BEN TO LOOK
IN ON ELIZABETH.
THE FENTYS ARE PULLING OUT.
SHE'LL BE ALONE.
[FANFARE]
YOU STINKIN', ROTTEN
HEATHEN SCUM!
SILENCE, JUDAS.
TODAY IS SUNDAY.
YOU ARE GOING TO
HEAR THE WORD OF GOD
WHETHER YOU LIKE IT OR NOT.
GET OUT OF HERE!
AND THE WORD OF
THE LORD IS DOOM,
DOOM!
SIC THE BULL ON HIM.
YOU CAN'T DO THAT.
LET HIM OUT!
BOO!
THIS TOWN OF LUST
AND CORRUPTION.
GET OUT OF HERE.
OUT, OUT, OUT.
[CHEERING]
YOU ARE NOT GOING TO FIGHT
THAT BEAR ON THE SABBATH.
I REPRESENT THE LORD,
AND THE LORD SAYS
GET OUT OF THIS ARENA.
OUT, OUT!
THE LORD WILL OPEN UP THE EARTH,
AND YOU WILL SINK INTO THE PIT.
I SAID, SINK INTO THE PIT.
I SAID, SINK INTO THE PIT!
WELL, I'LL BE GOD DAMNED.
HELLO, PARSON.
WELCOME TO HELL.
[CRASH]
[BULL ROARS]
AAH! AAH!
[GRRROOO]
YET THOUGH I WALK
THROUGH THE VALLEY
OF THE SHADOW OF DEATH...
YOU BETTER RUN THROUGH
THAT VALLEY, NOT WALK.
[GRRROOO]
AAH! AAH!
UHH!
WILL YOU KINDLY WATCH
WHERE THE HELL YOU'RE FALLING,
MY GOOD MAN?
AAH! AAH!
MACH SCHNELL!
NOW WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
ACH DU LIEBER
HIMMEL! NEIN, NEIN, NEIN!
NEIN, NEIN, NEIN!
HAVE YOU...
HAVE YOU SEEN PARDNER AND BEN?
PARDNER AND BEN?
WHERE'S BEN?
BEN RUMSON!
THY ROD AND THY STAFF,
THEY COMFORT ME.
AAH! [GRROO] AAH!
YOU BLOODY MANIACS, GO
DOWN THERE AND GET HIM!
BEN, WHERE YOU GOING?
♪ NO NAME CITY ♪
♪ THE LORD DON'T LIKE IT HERE ♪
♪ YOUR RECKONIN' DAY IS HERE ♪
♪ NO NAME CITY ♪
♪ HERE'S WHAT HE'S GONNA DO ♪
♪ GOBBLE UP THIS TOWN ♪
♪ AND SWALLOW IT DOWN ♪
♪ AND GOODBYE TO YOU ♪
♪ WILL YOU GO TO HEAVEN? ♪
♪ WILL YOU GO TO HELL? ♪
♪ GO TO HELL ♪
♪ EITHER REPENT
OR FARE THEE WELL ♪
♪ FARE THEE WELL ♪
♪ GOD'LL TAKE CARE
OF NO NAME CITY ♪
♪ COMES THE END,
IT WON'T BE PRETTY ♪
♪ HERE IT IS ♪
♪ I MEAN, HERE IT IS ♪
♪ I MEAN, HERE IT IS ♪♪
♪ LET ME LIVE UNTIL I DIE ♪
♪ IN NO NAME TOWN ♪
♪ LET ME LIVE UNTIL I DIE... ♪♪
I DON'T KNOW ABOUT YOU, FELLAS,
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
I THINK THIS PLACE IS CRUMBLING.
OH!
[WOMAN SCREAMS]
AAH!
OH!
BE CALM, MY DEAR.
AAH!
OH, PARDNER, WHERE'S BEN?
WHAT THE HELL ARE
YOU DOING THERE?
I DIDN'T LIKE THAT TOWN,
BUT IT'LL SEEM FUNNY
NOT HAVING IT THERE.
IT'S GOING TO BE A COLD...
LONG, HARD WINTER WITHOUT IT.
I'M NOT LEAVING
MY HOME, PARDNER.
I KNOW THAT.
DO YOU HAVE TO GO?
CAN'T WE ALL TRY... LIVING
THE WAY WE USED TO?
NO.
NO, I CAN'T.
YOU SEE, EVER SINCE THAT
NIGHT THE FENTYS CAME
AND WE WERE...
YOU AND I WERE LIKE
A REAL HUSBAND AND WIFE...
I...
COULDN'T LIVE WITH
YOU ANY OTHER WAY.
AND YOU BELONG TO BEN.
HE SHARED YOU WITH ME.
I DIDN'T SHARE YOU WITH HIM.
MA'AM...
WHOA, MULE.
DID YOU KNOW THEM
FARMERS WAS UNPACKING?
YOU MEAN THE FENTY PARTY?
WELL, THAT MIGHT SOUND
LIKE A PARTY TO YOU,
BUT IT AIN'T MY IDEA OF ONE.
HOP IN. YOU CAN'T GET
OUT OF TOWN THAT WAY.
WELL, COME ON.
GIDDUP, MULE.
I DIDN'T SEE THEY WAS BUILDING
A CHURCH AND COURTHOUSE
TILL THE REST OF THE
TOWN WENT UNDER.
NEITHER DID I.
YOU STILL HEADING UP TO RED DOG?
YEAH. STILL AM.
WELL, THAT'S ALL RIGHT WITH
ME. I DON'T CARE WHERE WE GO
AS LONG AS I STAY A HUNDRED
MILES AHEAD OF CIVILIZATION.
YOU MOVING OUT, BEN?
YOU WANT ME TO DIE?
WHY, I CAN JUST SEE THIS VALLEY
IN ABOUT A YEAR'S TIME...
ALL BROKE OUT IN A RASH
OF WHITE CLAPBOARD HOUSES,
SCHOOLS, CHURCHES,
COURTHOUSE, MUSEUM.
UGH. JUST ONE BIG, BAD DREAM.
WHAT ABOUT ELIZABETH?
I'M GOING TO MISS
THAT WOMAN, PARDNER,
BUT YOU CAN'T BLAST
HER OUT OF THAT CABIN.
FUNNY, HERE WE
GO AND BUILD A TOWN
JUST THE WAY WE LIKE IT,
AND THEN WE GO AND
SINK IT. GIDDUP, MULE!
COME ON. COME ON. GIDDUP.
COME ON.
PULL UP, BEN.
WHOA, MULE.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
I'M STAYING.
I HAVE TO.
I ALWAYS SAID YOU HAD
A FARMER'S MENTALITY,
BUT YOU'RE STILL THE BEST
PARDNER THERE EVER WAS.
WELL, YOU'RE THE ONLY
PARDNER THAT EVER WAS.
THEN THAT MAKES ME THE BEST.
AIN'T YOU GOING TO SAY
GOODBYE TO ELIZABETH?
NO. I DON'T THINK I'LL DO THAT.
I'LL GET MELANCHOLY
ENOUGH LATER ON AS IT IS
WITHOUT PICKING UP
AN EXTRA LOAD NOW.
YOU SAY SOMETHING
NICE TO HER FOR ME, PAR...
SAY, WHAT THE HELL
IS YOUR NAME ANYWAY?
SYLVESTER NEWEL.
YEAH, JUST ONE "L."
WELL, THAT'S A GOOD
NAME FOR A FARMER.
WELL...
SO LONG, PARDNER.
SO LONG, BEN.
NEVER LIKED A MAN
AS MUCH AS I LIKE YOU.
GIDDUP!
BEN SAYS GOODBYE, ELIZABETH.
AREN'T YOU GOING WITH HIM?
NO.
NO, I'M NOT GOING ANYWHERE.
DO YOU THINK HE'LL
BE ALL RIGHT, PARDNER?
WHERE'S HE GOING?
♪ WHERE AM I
GOIN'? I DON'T KNOW ♪
♪ WHERE AM I HEADIN'?
I AIN'T CERTAIN ♪
♪ ALL THAT I KNOW
IS I AM ON MY WAY ♪
♪ WHEN WILL I BE
THERE? I DON'T KNOW ♪
♪ WHEN WILL I GET
THERE? I AIN'T CERTAIN ♪
♪ ALL THAT I KNOW
IS I AM ON MY WAY ♪
♪ GOT A DREAM, BOY ♪
♪ GOT A SONG ♪
♪ PAINT YOUR WAGON ♪
♪ AND COME ALONG ♪
♪ WHERE AM I
GOIN'? I DON'T KNOW ♪
♪ WHEN WILL I BE
THERE? I AIN'T CERTAIN ♪
♪ WHAT WILL I GET? I
AIN'T EQUIPPED TO SAY ♪
♪ BUT WHO GIVES A DAMN? ♪
♪ I'M ON MY WAY ♪
♪ WHERE AM I
GOIN'? I DON'T KNOW ♪
♪ WHERE AM I HEADIN'?
I AIN'T CERTAIN ♪
♪ ALL I KNOW IS I AM ON MY WAY ♪
♪ WHEN WILL I BE
THERE? I DON'T KNOW ♪
♪ WHEN WILL I GET
THERE? I AIN'T CERTAIN ♪
♪ ALL THAT I KNOW ♪
♪ IS I AM ON MY WAY ♪
♪ GOT A DREAM, BOY ♪
♪ GOT A SONG ♪
♪ PAINT YOUR WAGON ♪
♪ AND COME ALONG ♪
♪ WHERE AM I GOIN'? ♪
♪ I DON'T KNOW ♪
♪ WHEN WILL I BE THERE? ♪
♪ I AIN'T CERTAIN ♪
♪ WHAT WILL I GET? ♪
♪ I AIN'T EQUIPPED TO SAY ♪
♪ BUT WHO GIVES A DAMN? ♪
♪ WE'RE ON OUR WAY ♪
♪ WHERE AM I
GOIN'? I DON'T KNOW ♪
♪ WHERE AM I HEADIN'?
I AIN'T CERTAIN ♪
♪ GOLD FEVER ♪
♪ WHEN WILL I BE
THERE? I DON'T KNOW ♪
♪ WHEN WILL I GET
THERE? I AIN'T CERTAIN ♪
♪ ALL I KNOW IS I AM ON MY WAY ♪
♪ GOLD FEVER ♪
♪ GOT A DREAM, BOY ♪
♪ GOT A SONG ♪
♪ PAINT YOUR WAGON ♪
♪ AND COME ALONG ♪
♪ AND GET ♪
♪ GOLD FEVER ♪
♪ NO ROMPIN', ROLLIN'
GIRL-AND-FELLOW STUFF ♪
♪ CAN CURE THE ♪
♪ GOLD FEVER ♪
♪ NOTHIN' CAN HELP YOU ♪
♪ BUT THAT YELLOW STUFF ♪
♪ WHAT ♪
♪ CAN STOP THAT ITCHIN' ♪
♪ AIN'T ♪
♪ AROUND THE KITCHEN ♪
♪ GOLD, GOLD ♪
♪ GOLD ♪
♪ THEY ♪
♪ CALL THE WIND ♪
♪ MARIA ♪
♪ AWAY OUT HERE ♪
♪ THEY GOT A NAME ♪
♪ FOR RAIN AND WIND ♪
♪ AND FIRE ♪
♪ THE RAIN IS TESS ♪
♪ THE FIRE'S JOE ♪
♪ AND THEY CALL THE WIND ♪
♪ MARIA ♪
♪ I WAS BORN ♪
♪ UNDER A WAND'RIN' STAR ♪
♪ WHEELS ARE MADE FOR ROLLIN' ♪
♪ MULES ARE MADE TO PACK ♪
♪ I'VE NEVER SEEN A SIGHT ♪
♪ THAT DIDN'T LOOK
BETTER LOOKIN' BACK ♪
♪ I WAS BORN ♪
♪ I WAS BORN... ♪
♪ A MILLION MILES ♪
♪ SEND BACK THE WORLD ♪
♪ THERE'S TOO
MUCH NIGHT FOR ME ♪
♪ THE SKY IS MUCH TOO
HIGH TO SHELTER ME ♪
♪ WHEN DARKNESS FALLS ♪
♪ FOUR CABIN WALLS ♪
♪ WOULD BE JUST RIGHT FOR ME ♪
♪ A MILLION MILES AWAY ♪
♪ BEHIND ♪
♪ THE DOOR ♪
[MEN'S CHORUS HUMS
I TALK TO THE TREES]
♪ WHERE AM I
GOIN'? I DON'T KNOW ♪
♪ WHERE AM I HEADIN'?
I AIN'T CERTAIN ♪
♪ GOLD FEVER ♪
♪ ALL THAT I KNOW
IS I AM ON MY WAY ♪
♪ YOU WANT TO SEE SIN
OF THE WICKEDEST KIND? ♪
♪ HERE IT IS ♪
♪ YOU WANT TO SEE
VIRTUE LEFT BEHIND? ♪
♪ HERE IT IS ♪
♪ SODOM WAS VICE
AND VICE VERSA ♪
♪ YOU WANT TO SEE WHERE
THE VICE IS WORSER? ♪
♪ HERE IT IS ♪
♪ I MEAN, HERE IT IS ♪
♪ YOU WANT TO SEE LIFE
IN THE ROTTENEST WAY? ♪
♪ HERE IT IS ♪
♪ WOMEN AND WHISKEY
NIGHT AND DAY ♪
♪ HERE IT IS ♪
♪ YOU WANT TO EMBRACE
THE GOLDEN CALF ♪
♪ ANKLE AND THIGH
AND UPPER HALF? ♪
♪ HERE IT IS ♪
♪ I MEAN, HERE IT IS ♪
♪ GOIN'? I DON'T KNOW ♪
♪ WHERE AM I HEADIN'?
I AIN'T CERTAIN ♪
♪ ALL THAT I KNOW
IS I AM ON MY WAY ♪
♪ GOLD FEVER ♪
♪ NOTHIN' CAN HELP YOU ♪
♪ BUT THE YELLOW STUFF ♪
♪ WHAT ♪
♪ CAN STOP THAT ITCHIN' ♪
♪ AIN'T ♪
♪ AROUND THE KITCHEN ♪
♪ GOLD, GOLD ♪
♪ HOOKED AM I ♪
♪ SUSANNAH, GO AHEAD AND CRY ♪
♪ A MILLION MILES AWAY ♪
♪ BEHIND ♪
♪ THE DOOR ♪♪