A fiddler on the roof.
Sounds crazy, no?
But here, in our
little village of Anatevka,
you might say every one of us
is a fiddler on the roof.
Trying to scratch out
a pleasant, simple tune
without breaking his neck.
It isn't easy.
You may ask why do we stay
up there if it's so dangerous?
Well, we stay because
Anatevka is our home.
And how do we keep our balance?
That I can tell you in one word:
Tradition.
~ Tradition ~
~ Tradition! ~
Because of our traditions,
we've kept our balance
for many, many years.
Here in Anatevka,
we have traditions for everything.
How to sleep. How to eat.
How to work.
How to wear clothes.
For instance,
we always keep our heads covered,
and always wear a little prayer shawl.
This shows our constant devotion to God.
You may ask,
how did this tradition get started?
I'll tell you.
I don't know.
But it's a tradition.
And because of our traditions,
every one of us knows who he is
and what God expects him to do.
~ Who, day and night,
must scramble for a living ~
~ Feed a wife and children,
say his daily prayers ~
~ And who has the right
as master of the house ~
~ To have the final word at home ~
~ The papa ~
~ Tradition ~
~ Who must know the way
to make a proper home ~
~ A quiet home, a kosher home ~
~ Who must raise a family
and run the home ~
~ So Papa's free to read the Holy Book ~
~ The mama ~
~ Tradition ~
~ At three I started Hebrew school ~
~ At ten I learned a trade ~
~ I hear they picked a bride for me ~
~ I hope she's pretty ~
~ And who does Mama teach
to mend and tend and fix ~
~ Preparing her to marry
whoever Papa picks ~
~ The daughters ~
~ Tradition ~
~ The papas
Mamas ~
~ Sons
The daughters ~
~ Tradition ~
And in the circle of our little village,
we've always had our special types.
For instance,
Yente, the matchmaker.
Reb Nachum, the beggar.
And, most important of all,
our beloved rabbi.
Rabbi, may I ask you a question?
Certainly, Leibesh.
Is there a proper blessing for the Tzar?
A blessing for the Tzar? Of course.
May God bless and keep the Tzar...
far away from us.
~ Dai dai dai dai ~
~ Dai dai dai dai
Dai dai dai dai dai ~
~ Dai dai dai dai ~
~ Dai dai dai dai
Dai dai dai dai dai ~
Then there are
the others in our village.
They make a much bigger circle.
We don't bother them
and, so far, they don't bother us.
And among ourselves,
we always get along perfectly well.
Of course, there was the time
when he sold him a horse
and told him it was only six years old
when it was really twelve.
But now it's all over.
And we all live
in simple peace and harmony.
- It was really twelve years old.
- It was six.
Tevye knows it was twelve.
Twelve.
It was twelve.
~ Tradition ~
~ Tradition! ~
~ Dai dai dai dai dai ~
~ Dai dai dai dai ~
Traditions, traditions.
Without our traditions,
our lives would be as shaky as... as...
As a fiddler on the roof.
Mama, Yente the matchmaker is coming.
Maybe she's finally found
a good match for you, Tzeitel.
From your mouth to God's ears.
Why is she here now?
It's almost Sabbath.
Out, all of you.
I want to talk to Yente alone.
But, Mama, the men she finds...
The last one was so old.
And he was bald.
He had no hair.
A poor girl without a dowry
can't be so particular.
You want hair, marry a monkey.
Even a poor girl
has to look at her husband sometimes.
A husband is not to look at,
a husband is to get.
- I'm not yet 20 years old. I don't think...
- Sha!
Do you have to boast about your age?
You wanna tempt the evil eye? Da, da, da.
Out, all of you. There's work
to be done before the Sabbath.
Golde. Golde.
I have such news for you.
And not every-day-in-the-week news.
Once-in-a-lifetime news.
Such diamonds, such jewels.
I'll find a husband for every one of them.
But you shouldn't be so picky.
Right? Of course, right.
After all, even the worst husband
is better than no husband. God forbid!
Who should know better than me?
Ever since my husband died,
I've been a poor widow.
All alone, no one to talk to,
nothing to say to anyone.
All I do at night is think of him.
And even thinking of him
gives me no pleasure.
- Is Tzeitel in the house?
- Why don't you go and find out?
Thank you, Bielke.
He never raised his voice.
Good afternoon.
Is Tzeitel in the house?
She's busy. Come back later.
There's something I'd like to tell her.
- Later.
- Later?
Hm.
What does that poor skinny tailor
want with Tzeitel?
They've been friends since
they were babies. They play...
- They play? What do they play?
- I don't know. They're children.
From such children come other children.
Motel is nothing.
Yente, you said you had news for me.
Ah, children, children...
They are your blessing in your old age.
But my Aaron, may he rest in peace,
couldn't give me children.
To tell you the truth, he hardly tried.
But what's the use complaining?
Other women enjoy complaining.
Not Yente.
Not every woman in the world is a Yente.
Well, I have to go home now
to prepare my poor Sabbath meal.
So, goodbye, Golde.
And it was a pleasure
talking our hearts out to each other.
You said you had news for me.
I'm losing my head.
Some day it will fall off altogether.
And a horse will kick it in the mud
and "Goodbye, Yente".
Of course, the news.
It's about Lazar Wolf, the butcher.
A good man. A fine man.
And I don't have to tell you
he's well off, no?
But he's lonely, the poor man.
He's been a widower all these years.
You understand? Of course you do.
To make it short, out of the whole town
he's cast his eye on Tzeitel.
- My Tzeitel?
- No, the Tzar's Tzeitel.
Of course your Tzeitel.
Such a match for my Tzeitel.
But Tevye wants a learned man.
He doesn't like Lazar.
Lazar won't marry him.
He wants the daughter, not the father.
Listen to me, Golde.
You send Tevye to him.
Don't tell him what it's about.
Let Lazar discuss it himself.
He'll win him over,
he's a good man and a wealthy man.
You'll let me know how it went.
And you don't have to thank me, Golde,
because, aside from my fee,
which Lazar will pay anyway,
it gives me satisfaction
to make people happy.
True? Of course, true.
So, goodbye, Golde,
and you're welcome.
Goodbye, Yente.
Come, children.
Get changed for the Sabbath.
Hurry with your work.
I wonder if Yente found a husband for you.
I'm not anxious for her to find me one.
- Unless it's Motel, the tailor.
- I didn't ask you.
Tzeitel, they have to make a match for you
before they can make one for me.
- Then after her, one for me.
- So if Yente...
Yente, Yente, Yente!
Somebody has to arrange the matches.
- She may bring someone wonderful.
- Interesting.
- And well off.
- And important.
~ Matchmaker, matchmaker,
make me a match ~
~ Find me a find,
catch me a catch ~
~ Matchmaker, matchmaker,
look through your book ~
~ And make me a perfect match ~
~ Matchmaker, matchmaker,
I'll bring the veil ~
~ You bring the groom,
slender and pale ~
~ Bring me a ring for I'm longing
to be the envy of all I see ~
~ For Papa, make him a scholar ~
~ For Mama, make him rich as a king ~
~ For me, well, I wouldn't holler
if he were as handsome as anything ~
~ Matchmaker, matchmaker,
make me a match ~
~ Find me a find,
catch me a catch ~
~ Night after night in the dark I'm alone ~
~ So find me a match of my own ~
Since when are you
interested in a match, Chava?
I thought you just had
your eye on your books.
And you have your eye
on the rabbi's son.
Why not?
We only have one rabbi
and he only has one son.
Why shouldn't I want the best?
Because you're from a poor family,
so whatever Yente brings, you'll take.
Right? Of course, right.
~ Hodel, oh, Hodel,
have I made a match for you ~
~ He's handsome, he's young -
all right, he's sixty-two ~
~ But he's a nice man, a good catch ~
~ True? True ~
~ I promise you'll be happy
and even if you're not ~
~ There's more to life than that -
don't ask me what ~
~ Chava, I found him,
will you be a lucky bride ~
~ He's handsome, he's tall -
that is, from side to side ~
~ But he's a nice man, a good catch, right? ~
~ Right ~
~ You heard he has a temper
He'll beat you every night ~
~ But only when he's sober -
so you're all right ~
~ Did you think you'd get a prince ~
~ Well, I'll find the best I can ~
~ With no dowry, no money ~
~ No family background ~
~ Be glad you've got a man ~
~ Matchmaker, matchmaker,
you know that I'm still very young ~
~ Please, take your time ~
~ Up to this minute I misunderstood ~
~ That I could get stuck for good ~
~ Dear Yente, see that he's gentle ~
~ Remember, you were also a bride ~
~ It's not that I'm sentimental ~
~ It's just that I'm terrified ~
~ Matchmaker, matchmaker,
plan me no plans ~
~ I'm in no rush,
maybe I've learned ~
~ Playing with matches,
a girl can get burned ~
~ So bring me no ring,
groom me no groom ~
~ Find me no find,
catch me no catch ~
~ Unless he's a matchless match ~
Dear God,
was that necessary?
Did you have to make him lame
just before the Sabbath?
That wasn't nice.
It's enough you pick on me.
Bless me with five daughters,
a life of poverty, that's all right.
But what have you got against my horse?
Really, sometimes I think,
when things are too quiet up there,
you say to yourself,
"Let's see. What kind of mischief
can I play on my friend, Tevye?"
Uh-huh. So you're finally here,
my breadwinner.
I'll talk to you later.
- Why are you late today?
- His foot went lame.
Hurry up. The sun won't wait.
I have something important to say to you.
I still have deliveries.
- You'll be late for the Sabbath.
- I won't be late.
- You'll be late.
- I won't be late. I won't be late.
- If you ever stop talking, I won't be late.
- You can die from such a man.
As the Good Book says "Heal us,
O Lord, and we shall be healed."
In other words, send us the cure.
We've got
the sickness already.
Well, I'm not really complaining.
After all, with your help...
I'm starving to death.
Oh, dear Lord.
You made many, many poor people.
I realise, of course,
it's no shame to be poor.
But it's no great honour either.
So what would have been so terrible
if I had a small fortune.
~ If I were a rich man ~
~ Yubby dibby dibby dibby dibby
dibby dibby dum ~
~ All day long, I'd biddy biddy bum ~
~ If I were a wealthy man ~
~ I wouldn't have to work hard ~
~ Yubby dibby dibby dibby dibby
dibby dibby dum ~
~ If I were a biddy biddy rich
idle deedle daidle daidle man ~
~ I'd build a big, tall house ~
~ With rooms by the dozen
right in the middle of the town ~
~ A fine, tin roof
with real wooden floors below ~
~ There would be
one long staircase just going up ~
~ And one even longer coming down ~
~ And one more leading nowhere,
just for show ~
~ I'd fill my yard
with chicks and turkeys and geese ~
~ And ducks for the town to see and hear ~
~ Squawking just as noisily as they can ~
~ And each agay and ago
and aga and aca ~
~ Will land like a trumpet on the ear ~
~ As if to say, here lives a wealthy man ~
~ If I were a rich man ~
~ Yubby dibby dibby dibby dibby
dibby dibby dum ~
~ All day long, I'd biddy biddy bum ~
~ If I were a wealthy man ~
~ I wouldn't have to work hard ~
~ Yubby dibby dibby dibby dibby
dibby dibby dum ~
~ If I were a biddy biddy rich
idle deedle daidle daidle man ~
~ I'd see my wife, my Golde ~
~ Looking like a rich man's wife
with a proper double chin ~
~ Supervising meals to her heart's delight ~
~ I'd see her putting on airs
and strutting like a peacock ~
~ Oh, what a happy mood she's in ~
~ Screaming at her servants
day and night ~
~ The most important men in town
will come to fawn on me ~
~ They will ask me to advise them
like a Solomon The Wise ~
~ If you please, Reb Tevye ~
~ Pardon me, Reb Tevye ~
~ Posing problems
that would cross a rabbi's eyes ~
~ Yah da-dee da da ~
~ Yah da da da ~
~ Da ~
~ And it won't make one bit of difference
if I answer right or wrong ~
~ When you're rich,
they think you really know ~
~ If I were rich
I'd have that time that I lack ~
~ To sit in the synagogue and pray ~
~ And maybe have a seat
by the eastern wall ~
~ And I'd discuss the Holy Books with
the learned men seven hours every day ~
~ And that would be
the sweetest thing of all ~
~ If I were a rich man ~
~ Yubby dibby dibby dibby dibby
dibby dibby dum ~
~ All day long, I'd biddy biddy bum ~
~ If I were a wealthy man ~
~ I wouldn't have to work hard ~
~ Yubby dibby dibby dibby dibby
dibby dibby dum ~
~ Lord, who made the lion and the lamb ~
~ You decreed I should be what I am ~
~ Would it spoil some vast eternal plan ~
~ If I were a wealthy man ~
Tevye, where's your horse?
It decided to take the day off.
- Have a good Sabbath.
- Thank you, Your Honour. Thank you.
- It's almost the Sabbath.
- You kept us all waiting.
Look at this.
Look what it says in the paper.
Quiet!
Will you stop braying like mules?
Let the man talk. Talk, Avram.
My paper came to the post office today,
like it does every week.
Usually on a Thursday, but sometimes...
Avram, that's not talking.
That's babbling.
The news, what does it say?
Quiet!
Talk, Avram.
I was reading my paper.
Nothing important, a story about
the crops in the Ukraine, and this and that.
Avram, talk.
And then I saw this.
All right. We all see it.
What does it say?
"In a village called Rajanka,
all the Jews were evicted,
forced to leave their homes."
For what reason?
It doesn't say. Maybe the Tzar
wanted their land. Maybe a plague.
- May he have his own personal plague.
Amen!
Why don't you ever bring us
some good news?
It's not my fault. I only read it.
"An edict from the authorities."
May the authorities grow like onions,
with their heads in the ground.
Amen!
What good will your cursing do?
You stand around, you curse and
you chatter, and you don't do anything.
- You'll all chatter your way into the grave.
- Excuse me.
- You're not from this village.
- No.
- Where are you from?
- Kiev. I was a student in the university.
Tell me, is that the place where you
learned how not to respect your elders?
That is where I learned
there is more to life than talk.
You should know what's
going on in the outside world.
Why break my head
about the outside world?
Let the outside world
break its own head. Well put.
He is right.
As the Good Book says,
"If you spit in the air,
it lands in your face."
Nonsense.
You can't close your eyes
to what's happening in the world.
- He is right.
- He's right and he's right?
They can't both be right.
You are also right.
He's too young to wipe his own nose.
Good Sabbath, Tevye.
- Here. Good Sabbath.
- Good Sabbath, Tevye.
- Tevye, Tevye?
- I'm sorry. I apologise.
Good Sabbath.
- Tevye, the rabbi's order.
- Of course.
So you're from Kiev, Reb?
- Perchik.
So you're a newcomer here, huh?
As Abraham said,
"I'm a stranger in a strange land."
Moses said that.
Forgive me.
As King David said,
"I'm slow of speech and slow of tongue."
That was also Moses.
For a man with a slow tongue,
he talked a lot.
Here, Reb Perchik.
Have a piece.
I have no money, and I'm not a beggar.
Take it.
It's a blessing for me to give.
Very well.
For your sake.
Thank you.
It's no crime to be poor.
It is the rich who are the criminals.
Some day, their wealth will be ours.
That would be nice.
If they would agree, I would agree.
And who will make
this miracle to come to pass?
Ordinary people.
- Like you?
- Like me.
Until your golden day comes,
Reb Perchik, how will you live?
By giving lessons to children.
Do you have children?
I have five daughters.
Five?
Daughters.
Girls should learn, too.
Girls are people.
- A radical.
- Go away.
I'd be willing to teach them,
open their minds to great thoughts.
I'd like them to know the Good Book.
The Bible has many lessons
for our times.
Perchik,
I'm a very poor man.
But, food for lessons, huh?
Good. Stay with us for the Sabbath.
Of course, we don't eat like kings,
but we don't starve either.
As the Good Book says,
"When a poor man eats a chicken,
one of them is sick."
- Where does the Book say that?
- All right, all right.
It doesn't exactly say that,
but some place, it mentions a chicken.
- Good Sabbath.
Good Sabbath, children.
Children, this is Perchik.
- Perchik, this is my eldest daughter.
- Good Sabbath.
- You have a pleasant daughter.
- I have five pleasant daughters.
This is mine.
And this is mine.
And...
Well, this is not mine.
Perchik, this is Motel Kamzoil.
So, you did us a favour and came home.
This is also mine.
Golde, this is Perchik from Kiev.
He's staying the Sabbath with us.
He's a teacher.
Would you like lessons from him?
- Yes, Papa.
- I'm a very good teacher.
I heard that the rabbi who must praise
himself has a congregation of one.
Your daughter has
a quick and witty tongue.
The wit she gets from me.
- As the Good Book says...
- The Good Book can wait. Get washed.
- The tongue she gets from her mother.
- Motel, you're also eating with us?
Of course. Another blessing.
Tzeitel, get the small table.
Chava, the chairs from outside.
Children, finish dressing.
You can wash at the well.
Hurry, it's almost the Sabbath.
Tevye.
Tevye, I've something to say to you.
Why should today be different?
I have something to tell you.
- I have something to tell you.
- Yente was here.
I saw her.
If they agree on a match,
it will be too late for us.
But I have found someone who will
sell me his used sewing machine.
In a few weeks, I'll be able to buy it.
- Then your father...
- It might be too late.
- Lazar Wolf wants to see you.
- The butcher? What about?
I don't know.
Only he says it's important.
What can be important?
I have nothing for him to slaughter.
After the Sabbath, talk with him.
About what?
If he's thinking about buying
my new milk cow, he can forget it.
- Tevye, I want you to talk.
- Shh.
Tevye. Tevye, I want you to talk to...
What else can I do?
You could ask my father
for my hand tonight. Now.
Why should he consider me now?
I'm only a poor tailor.
And I'm only the daughter
of a poor milkman.
- Just talk to him.
- If your father says no, that's it.
- He'll yell at me.
- Motel...
- I'm just a poor tailor.
- Motel!
Even a poor tailor
is entitled to some happiness.
That's true.
- Amen.
A man sends you an important a message,
at least you can talk to him.
All right, after the Sabbath I'll talk to him.
All right, I'll talk to him.
It's getting late.
- Where is everybody?
- I don't know, Papa.
Children, come down.
We are lighting the candles.
- Reb Tevye...
- Not now, Motel. Hurry up, children.
- Reb Tevye.
- Not now.
Golde, the sun is almost down.
- Reb Tevye...
- What is it?
- Yes?
- Reb Tevye...
- Yes? Yes? Yes?
Well, Motel, what is it?
Good Sabbath, Reb Tevye.
Good Sabbath. Good Sabbath.
Hurry up.
Hurry, children, hurry. It's getting late.
~ May the Lord protect and defend you ~
~ May he always shield you from shame ~
~ May you come to be
in Israel a shining name ~
~ May you be like Ruth and like Esther ~
~ May you be deserving of praise ~
~ Strengthen them, O Lord,
and keep them from the stranger's ways ~
~ May God bless you
and grant you long lives ~
~ May the Lord fulfil
our Sabbath prayer for you ~
~ May God make you
good mothers and wives ~
~ May he send you husbands
who will care for you ~
~ May the Lord protect and defend you ~
~ May the Lord preserve you from pain ~
~ Favour them, O Lord,
with happiness and peace ~
~ O hear our Sabbath prayer ~
~ Aa-aa-aa-aa-aa ~
~ Amen ~
Is Reb?
Is Reb Lazar Wolf at home?
- He's in the back.
- Oh.
May I... Hm?
- Come in.
- Thank you. Thank you.
And all this from killing
innocent animals?
- Don't touch anything.
- All right.
Well, Tevye.
You're here. Sit down. Sit down.
Thank you.
- Have a drink.
- I won't insult you by saying no.
How goes it with you, Reb Tevye?
- How should it go?
- You're right.
- And you?
- The same.
I'm sorry to hear that.
Uh...
How is your brother-in-law in America?
- He's doing very well.
- He wrote you?
- Not lately.
- How do you know?
If he was doing badly, he would write.
Ah, ah, ah, ah.
- Lechaim.
- Tevye.
- Yeah?
I suppose you know
why I wanted to see you.
Yes, I do, but...
There is no use talking about it.
Tevye, I understand how you feel,
but after all you have
a few more without her.
I see. Today you want one.
Tomorrow you may want two.
Two? What would I do with two?
The same as you do with one.
Tevye.
This is very important to me.
Why is it so important to you?
Frankly, because...
I'm lonely.
Lonely?
Reb Lazar,
what are you talking about?
How can a little cow keep you company?
Little cow?
- Is that what you call her?
- But that's what she is.
- What are you talking about?
- Don't you know?
Of course, I know. We are talking about
the milk cow you want to buy from me.
A milk cow.
A milk cow so I won't be lonely?
I'm talking about...
your daughter Tzeitel.
My daughter Tzeitel?
Of course, your daughter Tzeitel.
I see her every Thursday
in my butcher's shop.
And she's made
a very good impression on me.
A very good impression.
Reb Tevye,
I like her.
Why don't we just shake hands
and call it a match, huh?
And...
I will be good to her.
Tevye.
I...
I like her.
Well?
What do you think?
- What do I think?
- Huh?
I never really liked him.
Why should I? You can have
a fine conversation with him
if you talk about kidneys and livers.
On the other hand,
not everyone has to be a scholar.
And with a butcher, my daughter
will surely never know hunger.
Maybe I misjudged him.
He's a good man.
He likes her.
And he'll try to make her happy.
What do I think?
It's a match.
- You agree?
- I agree.
Tevye, you've made me a happy man.
- Let's drink on it.
- Why not?
- To you.
- No, my friend. To you.
- To the both of us.
- To our agreement.
To our prosperity.
To our good health and happiness.
And most important of all...
Well...
~ To life, to life, lechaim ~
~ Lechaim, lechaim, to life ~
~ Here's to the father I've tried to be ~
~ Here's to my bride-to-be ~
~ Drink, lechaim ~
~ To life, to life, lechaim ~
~ Lechaim, lechaim, to life ~
~ Life has a way of confusing us ~
~ Blessing and bruising us ~
~ Drink, lechaim, to life ~
~ God would like us to be joyful ~
~ Even when our hearts
lie panting on the floor ~
~ How much more can we be joyful ~
~ When there's really something
to be joyful for ~
~ To life, to life, lechaim ~
~ To Tzeitel my daughter
My wife ~
~ It gives you something to think about ~
~ Something to drink about ~
~ Drink, lechaim, to life ~
- Mordcha!
- Yes? What is it?
- Drinks for everyone.
- What's the big occasion?
I'm taking myself a bride.
- Who's the lucky one?
- Tevye's eldest, Tzeitel.
~ To Lazar Wolf ~
~ To Tevye ~
~ To Tzeitel your daughter
My wife ~
~ May all your futures be pleasant ones,
not like our present ones ~
~ Drink, lechaim ~
~ To life, to life, lechaim ~
~ Lechaim, lechaim, to life ~
~ It takes a wedding to make us say,
let's live another day ~
~ Drink, lechaim, to life ~
~ We raise a glass
and sip a drop of schnapps ~
~ In honour of the great good luck
that favoured you ~
~ We know that when good fortune
favours two such men ~
~ It stands to reason we deserve it, too ~
~ To us and our good fortune ~
~ Be happy, be healthy, long life ~
~ And if our good fortune never comes,
here's to whatever comes ~
~ Drink, lechaim, to life ~
~ Dai dai dai dai dai
Dai dai dai dai dai dai ~
~ Dai dai dai dai
dai dai dai dai ~
~ Dai dai dai! ~
~ Za vashe zdorovie ~
~ Heaven bless you both ~
~ Na zdrovie ~
~ To your health
and may we live together in peace ~
Thank you.
~ Za vashe zdorovie ~
~ Heaven bless you both ~
~ Na zdrovie ~
~ To your health
and may we live together in peace ~
~ May you both be favoured
with the future of your choice ~
~ May you live to see
a thousand reasons to rejoice ~
~ Za... ~
~ Va... ~
Hey!
I like it!
~ Dai dai dai dai
Hey! ~
~ Dai dai dai dai dai dai dai dai
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
Drinks for everybody. Mazel tov.
~ To life! ~
Mazel tov. Mazel tov.
Tevye?
Tevye, after the marriage,
- we will be related.
- Yeah?
You will be my papa.
Your papa.
Lazar Wolf,
I always wanted a son.
But I wanted one
a little younger than myself.
Good night.
I hear that congratulations
are in order, Tevye.
Thank you, Your Honour. Thank you.
Tevye.
Yes, Your Honour?
I have some news
I think I should tell you as a friend.
Yes, Your Honour?
I'm giving you this news
because I like you.
You're an honest, decent person,
even though you are a Jew.
Thank you, Your Honour.
How often does a man
get a compliment like that?
And the news?
Sometime soon this district is to have
a little unofficial demonstration.
What?
A pogrom here?
No, just a little unofficial demonstration.
Little?
How little?
Just some mischief.
So, if an inspector comes through,
he can see we did our duty.
I don't know why there has to be
this trouble between people.
But I thought I should tell you.
Thank you, Your Honour.
You are a good man.
If I may say so...
It's too bad you're not a Jew.
That's what I like about you.
You're always joking.
Congratulations again for your daughter.
Thank you, Your Honour.
Oh, about the other matter.
It won't be too bad. I wouldn't worry.
Of course not.
Dear God,
did you have to send me news
like that today of all days?
I know we are the chosen people.
But once in a while,
can't you choose someone else?
Anyway,
thank you for sending
a husband for my Tzeitel.
Lechaim.
Now, after Jacob had
worked for Laban for seven years,
do you know what happened?
Laban fooled him
and gave him his ugly daughter Leah.
So to marry Rachel, Jacob was forced
to work another seven years.
So, you see, the Bible clearly teaches us
you can never trust an employer.
And that is what the Bible teaches us?
That is the lesson of the story of Jacob
if you interpret it correctly.
- Is your papa up yet?
- No, Mama.
Enough lessons. Back to the house.
There's work to be done.
Go on, children.
Another story tomorrow.
That was a very
interesting lesson, Perchik.
- Do you think so?
- Mmm.
Although I don't know if the rabbi
would agree with your interpretation.
Neither, I suppose, would the rabbi's son.
My little sisters talk too much.
And what do you know about him,
except that he is the rabbi's son?
At least I know he has no strange ideas
about turning the world upside down.
Good day, Perchik.
You have wit, even some intelligence.
Perhaps, but what good is your brain?
Without curiosity, it is a rusty tool.
Good day, Hodel.
We have an old custom here.
A boy talks respectfully to a girl.
But that is too traditional
for an advanced thinker like you.
Our traditions. Nothing must change.
Everything is perfect as it is.
- We like our ways.
- Our ways are changing all over but here.
In the city boys and girls are affectionate
without the permission of a matchmaker.
They hold hands together.
They even dance together.
New dances like this.
I learned it in Kiev.
- Do you like it?
- It's very nice.
There.
We've just changed an old custom.
Yes.
I mean, thank you.
I mean, good day.
Go away.
Oh!
So, my prince is finally out of bed.
Open your eyes.
The day's half gone.
Well?
Well, what happened last night,
besides you drinking like a peasant?
Did you see Lazar Wolf?
Well? Well?
What did he say?
What did you say?
- Where's Tzeitel?
- She's in the barn.
Do you have news for me?
Did you talk with Lazar Wolf?
- What happened?
- Patience, woman, patience.
As the Good Book says,
"Good news will stay,
and bad news will refuse to leave."
- And another saying goes...
- You can die from such a man.
Did you see Lazar? How was it?
Are you still drunk or what?
Ah, here she is.
Tzeitel, my lamb. Come here.
You are to be congratulated.
- You are going to be married.
Married!
What do you mean, Papa?
Lazar Wolf has asked for your hand.
- I knew it.
- The butcher?
Dear God, I thank thee.
Why do you have to?
- What do you have to say, Tzeitel?
- What can she say?
- Let her say one word.
- My first-born a bride.
May you grow old with him
in fortune and honour.
Not like Fruma Sarah, his first wife.
She was a bitter woman,
may she rest in peace.
Not like my Tzeitel.
And now I must thank Yente.
My Tzeitel a bride. A bride!
I thank thee. I thank thee. Oh, a bride!
Well, Chava?
Mazel tov, Tzeitel.
"Mazel tov, Tzeitel."
What kind of a mazel tov is that?
And you, Reb Perchik,
aren't you going to congratulate her?
Congratulations, Tzeitel,
for getting a rich man.
Ah.
Again with the rich.
What's wrong with being rich?
It's no reason to marry.
Money's the world's curse.
May the Lord smite me with it.
And may I never recover.
World's curse.
My Tzeitel knows I mean only
her welfare. Am I right, Tzeitel?
- Yes, Papa.
- There, you see?
I see.
I see very well.
Well, my child?
Why are you so silent?
Aren't you happy with this blessing, huh?
Papa... Papa...
What is it? Tell me.
Papa, I don't want to marry him.
I can't marry him. I can't.
What do you mean, you can't?
If I say you will, you will.
If it's a matter of money,
I'll do anything.
I'll hire myself out as a servant...
But we made an agreement.
And with us,
an agreement is an agreement.
Is that more important than I am, Papa?
Papa, don't force me, please!
I'll be unhappy all my days.
- I don't want to marry him.
- All right. All right.
I won't force you.
Oh, thank you, Papa. Thank you.
"Thank you, Papa."
It seems it was not ordained that
you should have all the comforts of life.
- Reb Tevye, may I speak to you?
- Later, Motel.
- But I would like to speak to you.
- Not now. I have problems.
That's what I want to speak
to you about. I think I can help.
Like a bandage can help a corpse.
Goodbye, Motel.
At least listen to him, Papa.
All right, you have a tongue. Talk.
I hear you are arranging
a match for Tzeitel.
Ah, he also has ears.
Well...
- I have a match for Tzeitel.
- What kind of a match?
A perfect fit.
Like a glove.
This match was made
exactly to measure.
Perfect fit? Made to measure?
Stop talking like a tailor
and tell me, who is it?
- Please don't shout at me.
- All right. All right, I won't shout.
Who is it?
- Who is it?
Who is it?!
It's me.
Myself.
It's him.
Himself.
Either you're out of your mind
or you're crazy. He must be crazy.
Arranging a match for yourself?
What are you? Everything?
Bridegroom, matchmaker,
and guests rolled into one?
I suppose you'll perform
the ceremony, too?
Please don't shout at me.
As for being my matchmaker,
I know it's unusual.
Unusual? It's crazy.
Times are changing.
Over a year ago, Tzeitel and I gave each
other our pledge that we would marry.
You gave each other a pledge?
Yes, Papa.
We gave each other our pledge.
They gave each other a pledge?
Unheard of. Absurd.
~ You gave each other
a pledge - unthinkable ~
~ Where do you think you are,
in Moscow, in Paris? ~
~ Where do they think they are, America? ~
~ What do you think you're doing,
you're a stitcher, you're nothing ~
~ Who do you think you are,
King Solomon? ~
~ This isn't the way it's done,
not here, not now ~
~ Some things I will not,
I cannot allow ~
~ Tradition ~
~ Marriages must be arranged
by the papa ~
~ This should never be changed ~
~ One little time, you pull out a prop and
where does it stop? Where does it stop? ~
Where does it stop?
Do I still have something
to say about my daughter?
Doesn't anyone have to ask
a father any more?
I've wanted to ask you for a while, but first
I wanted to get my own sewing machine.
Stop talking nonsense.
You are just a poor tailor.
That's true, but even a poor tailor
is entitled to some happiness.
I promise you, Reb Tevye,
your daughter will not starve.
Ah. He's beginning to talk like a man.
On the other hand,
what kind of a match
would that be with a poor tailor?
On the other hand,
he is an honest, hard worker.
But on the other hand,
he has absolutely nothing.
On the other hand, things could never
get worse for him, only better.
They gave each other a pledge.
Unheard of. Absurd.
~ They gave each other
a pledge - unthinkable ~
~ But look at my daughter's face,
she loves him, she wants him ~
~ And look at my daughter's eyes ~
~ So hopeful ~
Tradition!
Well, children...
When shall we make the wedding?
Thank you, Papa.
Reb Tevye, you won't be sorry.
You won't be sorry.
I won't be sorry?
I'm sorry already.
Thank you, Papa.
- Thank you, Papa.
- All right, all right.
Papa.
They gave each other a pledge.
Golde.
What shall I tell Golde?
- Motel, you were wonderful.
- It was a miracle.
~ Wonder of wonders,
miracle of miracles ~
~ God took a Daniel once again ~
~ Stood by his side
and miracle of miracles ~
~ Walked him through the lion's den ~
~ Wonder of wonders,
miracle of miracles ~
~ I was afraid that God would frown ~
~ But like he did so long ago in Jericho,
God just made a wall fall down ~
~ When Moses softened Pharaoh's heart,
that was a miracle ~
~ When God made the waters of
the Red Sea part, that was a miracle, too ~
~ But of all God's miracles large
and small, the most miraculous one of all ~
~ Is that out of a worthless lump of clay
God has made a man today ~
~ Wonder of wonders,
miracle of miracles ~
~ God took a tailor by the hand ~
~ Turned him around
and miracle of miracles ~
~ Led him to the Promised Land ~
~ When David slew Goliath,
yes, that was a miracle ~
~ When God gave us manna
in the wilderness, that was a miracle, too ~
~ But of all God's miracles large
and small, the most miraculous one of all ~
~ Is the one I thought could never be ~
~ God has given you to me ~
- Good day.
- Hello, Sarah.
Mazel tov, Chava.
Soon it will be you.
- I hope so.
- Give my best wishes to Tzeitel.
- Mazel tov! Mazel tov!
- Goodbye.
- Mazel tov, Chava.
Don't run away...
No, don't.
Please, I just want... to get by.
All right, stop it.
- What's wrong with you, Fyedka?
- Stop it.
- We're just having a little fun, Fyedka.
- Goodbye, Sasha.
I said goodbye.
I'm sorry about that.
They mean no harm.
Don't they?
Is there something you want?
Yes, I'd like to talk to you.
I'd rather not.
I've often noticed you at the bookseller's.
Not many girls in this village like to read.
Would you like to borrow this book?
It's very good.
No.
- Thank you.
- Why?
Because I'm not Jewish?
Do you feel about me
the way they feel about you?
I didn't think you would.
And what do you know about me, eh?
Let me tell you about myself.
I'm a pleasant fellow.
Charming, honest,
ambitious, quite bright,
and very modest.
Go ahead. Take the book.
And after you return it,
I'll ask you how you like it.
And we can talk about it for a while.
Then we can talk about life.
How we feel about things.
Here.
Thank you.
- Good day, Chava.
- Good day.
Fyedka.
- Help! Help!
- Tell me, what's the matter with you?
Wake up. What is
the matter with you? Wake up!
- Where is she?
- Who?
- What are you talking about?
- Fruma Sarah.
Lazar Wolfs first wife
was standing here a minute ago.
What are you talking about?
Fruma Sarah has been dead for years.
Sha! You must have been dreaming.
Sha. Sha.
Now, tell me what you dreamt
and I'll tell you what it meant.
Ooh, it was terrible.
- Tell me.
- All right.
Only don't be frightened!
In the beginning, I dreamt that...
we were having
a celebration of some kind.
Everybody we knew,
all of our beloved departed were there.
All of them.
Even your Great Uncle
Mordechai was there.
And your cousin Rachel was there.
And in the middle of the dream,
in walks your grandmother Tzeitel,
may she rest in peace.
Grandmother Tzeitel?
How did she look?
For a woman who is dead 30 years,
she looked very good.
Naturally, I went up to greet her.
~ A blessing on your head
Mazel tov, mazel tov ~
~ To see a daughter wed
~ And such a son-in-law
like no one ever saw ~
~ The tailor Motel Kamzoil ~
Motel?
~ A worthy boy is he
Mazel tov, mazel tov ~
~ Of pious family
~ They named him after my
dear Uncle Mordechai ~
~ The tailor Motel Kamzoil ~
Tailor?
- She heard wrong. It's the butcher.
- I'll tell her.
~ You must have heard wrong, Grandma ~
~ There's no tailor ~
Huh?
~ You mean the butcher, Grandma ~
~ By the name of Lazar Wolf ~
~ No, no, no
I mean the tailor, Tevye ~
~ My great grandchild ~
~ My little Tzeitel, who you named for me ~
~ Motel's bride was meant to be ~
~ For such a match I prayed
Mazel tov, mazel tov ~
~ In heaven it was made
~ A fine, upstanding boy,
a comfort and a joy ~
~ The tailor Motel Kamzoil ~
But let me explain to you. Stop!
We announced it already.
We made a bargain with the butcher.
~ A blessing on your house
Mazel tov, mazel tov ~
~ Imagine such a spouse
~ And such a son-in-law
like no one ever saw ~
- Stop them.
Listen to me. But he is a butcher.
Tell them.
- His name is Lazar Wolf.
~ The tailor Motel Kam...
Sha! Sha! ~
~ Look
Who is this? ~
~ Who comes here?
Who? Who? Who? Who? Who? ~
~ What woman is this,
by righteous anger shaken ~
~ Could it be
Yes, it could ~
~ Why not?
Who could be mistaken? ~
~ It's the butcher's wife
come from beyond the grave ~
~ It's the butcher's dear, darling,
departed wife Fruma Sarah ~
~ Fruma Sarah
Fruma Sarah ~
Tevye!
~ What is this about your daughter
marrying my husband? ~
~ Yes, her husband ~
~ Would you do this to your friend
and neighbour Fruma Sarah? ~
~ Fruma Sarah ~
~ Have you no consideration
for a woman's feelings? ~
~ Woman's feelings ~
~ Handing over my belongings
to a total stranger ~
~ Total stranger ~
~ How can you allow it? How can
you let your daughter take my place? ~
~ Live in my house, carry my keys
and wear my clothes, pearls, how? ~
~ How can you allow your daughter
to take her place? ~
~ Pearls?
House? ~
Keys? ~
~ Pearls?
Clothes? ~
How? ~
Tevye!
~ Such a learned man as Tevye
wouldn't let it happen ~
~ Let it happen ~
~ Tell me that it isn't true
and then I wouldn't worry ~
~ Wouldn't worry ~
~ Say you didn't give your blessing
to your daughter's marriage ~
~ Daughter's marriage ~
~ Let me tell you what would follow
such a fatal wedding ~
~ Fatal wedding ~
Shh! Shh!
Sha!
~ If Tzeitel marries Lazar Wolf ~
~ I pity them both ~
~ She'll live with him three weeks ~
~ And when three weeks are up ~
~ I'll come to her by night ~
~ I'll take her by the throat ~
~ And this I'll give your Tzeitel,
that I'll give your Tzeitel ~
Jump!
Here's my wedding present
if she marries Lazar Wolf!
Evil spirit, away.
Such an evil spirit.
May it sink back into the earth.
Such a dark and horrible dream.
And to think it was brought on
because you went to see that butcher.
Tevye...
If my grandmother Tzeitel,
may she rest in peace,
took the trouble to come from
the other world to tell us about the tailor,
all I can say is that it's for the best
and couldn't possibly be any better.
- But, Golde...
- Amen.
Amen.
Cu-cu-cooo!
Do you like these troublemakers?
These Christ-killers?
Of course not.
I just meant that things
have been peaceful here.
I have other villages to visit.
If you don't want to follow orders,
we shall get someone else who will.
Oh, no, no, no, no, sir.
I'll take care of it. Of course.
Quiet down. Quiet down.
Quiet down.
~ Is this the little girl I carried? ~
~ Is this the little boy at play? ~
~ I don't remember growing older ~
~ When did they? ~
~ When did she
get to be a beauty? ~
~ When did he grow to be so tall? ~
~ Wasn't it yesterday
when they were small? ~
~ Sunrise, sunset,
sunrise, sunset ~
~ Swiftly flow the days ~
~ Seedlings turn overnight to sunflowers ~
~ Blossoming even as we gaze ~
~ Sunrise, sunset,
sunrise, sunset ~
~ Swiftly fly the years ~
~ One season following another ~
~ Laden with happiness and tears ~
~ What words of wisdom
can I give them? ~
~ How can I help to ease their way? ~
~ Now they must
learn from one another ~
~ Day by day ~
~ They look so natural together ~
~ Just like two newlyweds
should be ~
~ Is there a canopy in store for me? ~
~ Sunrise, sunset,
sunrise, sunset ~
~ Swiftly fly the years ~
~ One season following another ~
~ Laden with happiness ~
~ And tears ~
Mazel tov!
Quiet down. Quiet down.
Quiet down.
Take your places, everybody. Quiet!
Quiet down. Quiet down.
Quiet down.
Sha!
The newlyweds.
Friends, we are gathered here
to share in the joys of the newlyweds,
Motel and Tzeitel.
May they live together to a ripe old age.
- Amen.
Amen.
- And now I want to say...
- Ni, ni, ni, ni, ni...
Reb Nachum...
Please not here.
I'd like to announce the bride's parents
are giving the newlyweds the following:
A new feather bed, two pillows.
Goose pillows.
A Sabbath tablecloth.
And a pair of candlesticks.
Quiet!
Now,
we are just here on earth
for a short visit.
Even the great and wealthy must die.
In fact, if the rich could hire others
to die for them,
we, the poor, would all make a nice living.
Well put. Well put.
Lazar Wolf, talking about the rich,
there sits our good friend Lazar Wolf.
Lazar has everything in the world,
except a bride.
But Lazar has no ill feelings.
In fact, he told me he has a gift for the
newlyweds that he wants to announce.
Come on. Come on!
Just like he said, I have no ill feelings.
What's done is done.
I am giving the newlyweds five chickens.
One for each of the first five
Sabbaths of their wedded life.
Reb Lazar Wolf,
you are a decent man.
On behalf of my daughter
and her new husband,
I accept your gift.
There is a famous saying...
Reb Tevye,
I'm not marrying your daughter.
I don't have to listen to your sayings.
If you would only listen...
Why should I listen to you?
A man who breaks an agreement.
- I have a right to talk.
- What right? It's not your wedding.
- It should have been.
- It's not, thank goodness.
Sit down.
He shamed me
in front of the whole village.
Sha!
Rabbi, say something.
I say...
I say, let's sit down.
Yes, yes.
We all heard the words of the rabbi.
Let's sit down.
Now I'm going to sing a little song.
~ Dai-dai dai
deedle deedle dai-dai ~
I don't want your apple.
Leave me alone.
You can keep your diseased chickens.
You leave my chickens out of this.
- We made a bargain.
- The terms weren't settled.
- We drank on it.
- Terms weren't settled.
You just sit down, all right?
Once a butcher, always a butcher.
- Once a liar, always a liar.
- Sit down, all right?
Those happen to be my chickens...
- I had a sign.
- Quiet, I'm singing.
Quiet! Quiet! Quiet!
What's all the screaming about?
They drank on it. An agreement.
A sign. It's all nonsense.
Tzeitel wanted to marry Motel
and not Lazar.
A young girl decides for herself?
Why not? They love each other.
- Love?
- He's a radical.
Musicians, play.
It's a dance. Everybody, dance.
- It's a wedding.
Some wedding
- What is he doing?
- Perchik!
Who will dance with me?
- That's a sin.
- It's no sin to dance.
- With a girl?
- Yes!
That's what comes
from taking a wild man into your house.
He's not a wild man. His ideas are
a bit different, but... Perchik, come here.
- It's a sin.
- It's no sin!
Ask the rabbi. Go on, ask him.
Well, Rabbi?
Dancing?
Well, it's not exactly forbidden.
There you see. It's not forbidden.
And it's no sin. Now...
Who will dance with me?
- Hodel!
- It's only a dance, Mama.
Play.
- She's dancing with a man.
- I can see that she's dancing with a man.
- And I'm going to dance with my wife!
- Tevye!
- Mama, no.
- Golde.
Golde!
- No, I will not.
- Tzeitel!
Motel!
You see that?
You are responsible for that.
- And I can't stand it.
- I tried my best.
Everybody dance.
Come on. Dance, Rabbi, dance!
Hey!
Go on!
Perchik!
All right! Enough!
I said, enough! Come!
Orders are orders.
You understand?
Well...
Why are you all standing around?
Clean up.
Clean up!
~ Tradition ~
~ Tradition! ~
Troubles, troubles.
That's all you hear from me, right?
But who else can we simple people
take our troubles to?
You know, sometimes I wonder,
who do you take your troubles to?
Ah, go away.
Anyway, Motel and Tzeitel
have been married for some time now.
They work very hard.
And they're as poor as squirrels in winter.
But they're so happy,
they don't know how miserable they are.
Motel keeps talking about
a sewing machine.
I know. You are very busy now.
Wars, revolutions, floods, plagues.
All those little things
that bring people back to you.
But couldn't you take a second
and get him his sewing machine?
Yeah, and while
you are in the neighbourhood...
As you can see, my horse's leg...
Am I bothering you too much?
I'm sorry. As the Good Book says...
Why should I tell you
what the Good Book says?!
So you must go away?
Yes.
So soon?
Tomorrow morning.
Alone?
No, with a few friends.
And we will be joining others.
- Where?
- In the city, Kiev.
Hodel, there are some things
I cannot tell even you.
I see.
- Please don't be upset.
- If you must leave, you must.
- I do have to.
- So you told me.
Great changes are about to take place.
Tremendous changes.
But they can't happen by themselves.
- So you feel that you, personally, must...
- Not only me. Many people.
Jews, Gentiles, many people hate
what's going on. Don't you understand?
I understand, of course.
You want to leave.
Then, goodbye.
Hodel, listen to me.
I have work to do.
The greatest work a man can do.
Don't you understand?
Yes, Perchik.
Hodel... Hodel!
Hodel, wait.
Hodel, there's a certain question
I wish to discuss with you.
- Yes?
- It's a political question.
- What is it?
- The question of... marriage.
Is this a political question?
Well, yes.
Everything's political.
The relationship between a man and
a woman has a socioeconomic base.
Marriage must be
founded on mutual beliefs.
A common attitude
and philosophy towards society...
And affection?
Yes, of course.
That is also necessary.
Such a relationship
can have positive social values.
When two people face the world
with unity and solidarity...
- And affection?
- Yes, that is an important element.
At any rate, I...
I personally am in favour of
such a socioeconomic relationship.
I think...
you are asking me to marry you.
Well,
in a theoretical sense, yes, I am.
I was hoping you were.
I am very happy, Hodel.
I'm very, very happy.
- Good afternoon.
- Good afternoon, Reb Tevye.
- I have some bad news.
- What?
- I must leave here.
- When?
- Tomorrow morning.
- I'm sorry to hear that, Perchik.
- We'll all miss you.
- But I also have some good news.
- Good.
- You can congratulate me.
- Congratulations. What for?
- We are engaged.
- Engaged?
- Yes, Papa, we're engaged.
Oh, no, you're not.
I know you like him and he likes you.
But you're going away
and you're staying here.
So have a nice trip,
and I hope you'll be very happy
and my answer is no.
- Papa, you don't understand.
- I understand.
I gave my permission to Motel and
Tzeitel, so you feel you also have a right.
I'm sorry, Perchik, I like you.
But you're going away,
so go in good health,
and my answer is still no.
- You don't understand, Papa.
- And you are not listening. I said no.
Reb Tevye, we are not asking
for your permission.
Only for your blessing.
We are going to get married.
You are not asking for my permission?
But we would like your blessing, Papa.
I can't believe my own ears.
My blessing? For what?
~ For going over my head - impossible ~
~ At least with Tzeitel and Motel
they asked me, they begged me ~
~ But now, if I like or not,
you'll marry him ~
~ What do you want from me -
go on, be wed ~
~ And tear out my beard
and uncover my head ~
~ Tradition ~
~ They're not even asking permission
from the papa ~
~ What's happening to the tradition? ~
~ One little time, I pulled out a thread
and where has it led? Where has it led? ~
Where has it led? To this.
A man tells me he's getting married.
He doesn't ask me, he tells me.
But first, he abandons you.
He's not abandoning me, Papa.
As soon as I can,
I will send for her and marry her.
I love her.
He loves her.
Love. It's a new style.
On the other hand,
our old ways were once new,
weren't they?
On the other hand,
they decided without parents,
without the matchmaker.
On the other hand,
did Adam and Eve have a matchmaker?
Oh, yes, they did.
And it seems these two
have the same matchmaker.
They're going over my head.
Unheard of. Absurd.
~ For this, they want
to be blessed - unthinkable ~
I'll lock her up in her room.
I couldn't. I should.
~ But look at my daughter's eyes ~
~ She loves him ~
Tradition!
Well, children, I've decided to give you
my blessing and my permission.
Oh, thank you, Papa.
What else could I do?
Thank you, Papa.
"Thank you, Papa"?
What am I going to tell your mother?
Another dream?
Perhaps if you tell her
I am going to visit a rich uncle.
Perchik, please.
I can handle my own wife.
Golde! Golde!
- Gol...
- Hm?
- Hello, Golde.
- Have some soup.
Golde...
I have something
very important to tell you.
Have the soup. It's warm.
Golde.
I've just met Perchik and Hodel.
- Well?
- Well...
Well, uh...
Well, they seem to be
very fond of each other.
So? What do you mean?
So...
So, I've decided to give them
my permission to become engaged.
- I'll eat later.
- What?
Just like that, without even asking me?
Who asks you?
- I am the father.
- Who is he?
A pauper. He has nothing,
absolutely nothing.
I wouldn't say that.
I hear he has a rich uncle.
A rich uncle.
Golde...
Golde, he's a good man.
I like him.
He's a little crazy, but I like him.
And what's more important,
Hodel likes him.
Hodel loves him.
So what can we do?
It's a new world, Golde.
A new world.
Love.
Golde,
do you love me?
- Do I what?
- Shh.
~ Do you love me? ~
~ Do I love you? ~
Well?
~ With our daughters getting married
and this trouble in the town ~
~ You're upset, you're worn out,
go inside, go lie down ~
- Maybe it's indigestion.
- No, Golde, I'm asking you a question.
~ Do you love me? ~
- You're a fool.
- I know.
~ But do you love me? ~
~ Do I love you?
Well? ~
~ For 25 years, I've washed your clothes ~
~ Cooked your meals,
cleaned your house ~
~ Given you children, milked your cow ~
~ After 25 years,
why talk about love right now? ~
Golde.
~ The first time I met you
was on our wedding day ~
~ I was scared
I was shy ~
~ I was nervous
So was I ~
~ But my father and my mother said
we'd learn to love each other ~
~ And now I'm asking, Golde ~
~ Do you love me? ~
- I'm your wife.
- I know.
~ But do you love me? ~
~ Do I love him? ~
Well?
~ For 25 years, I've lived with him ~
~ Fought with him, starved with him ~
~ 25 years, my bed is his ~
Shh!
~ If that's not love, what is? ~
~ Then you love me? ~
I suppose I do.
~ And I suppose I love you, too ~
~ It doesn't change a thing ~
~ But even so ~
~ After 25 years ~
~ It's nice to know ~
Halt!
There is no authority
above the will of the people.
And we are the people.
We are Russia!
The time has come,
and the time is now.
We stand here before you.
Not one, but many.
Many like you.
Students, workers
striving for a better life.
And I urge you, fellow workers,
to band together with us.
Join our movement, in the factories.
In the schools.
In the army.
The winds of freedom
are beginning to blow all over Russia.
Halt!
Wait! Wait! Stand!
Good day to you, Esther.
Just a minute. Tzeitel. Tzeitel.
- Good day, Yente.
- Tzeitel.
I happened to stop in the post office
today, to say hello, see what's what.
It doesn't cost anything to be friendly.
So few people are like that.
- Ni, ni.
- People.
I tell you, if God lived on earth,
people would break his windows.
- So you went to the post office.
- Yes, and the postman told me
there was a letter for your sister Hodel.
- Thanks, I'll go get it.
- I got it.
It's from her intended - Perchik.
Hodel will be so happy.
She's been waiting to hear from him...
- But it's open.
- So it happened to be open.
You don't have to wait for the
train, Papa. You'll be late for customers.
It's all right.
They'll just have to wait for a while.
Is he in bad trouble,
that hero of yours?
Arrested?
- Convicted?
- Yes. But he did nothing wrong.
He cares nothing for himself.
Everything he does is for other people.
Yes, but if he did nothing wrong,
he wouldn't be in trouble.
Papa, how can you say that?
What wrongs did Joseph do,
and Abraham, and Moses?
And they had troubles.
Yes, but...
Why won't you tell me where he is now,
this Joseph of yours?
It is far, Papa.
Terribly far.
He is in a settlement in Siberia.
Siberia?
And he asks you
to leave your father and mother
and join him in that frozen wasteland
and marry him there?
No, Papa.
He did not ask me to go.
I want to go.
I don't want him to be alone.
I want to help him in his work.
- Hodel.
- Papa.
~ How can I hope
to make you understand? ~
~ Why I do what I do ~
~ Why I must travel to a distant land ~
~ Far from the home I love ~
~ Once I was happily content to be ~
~ As I was, where I was ~
~ Close to the people
who are close to me ~
~ Here in the home I love ~
~ Who could see that a man would come ~
~ Who would change
the shape of my dreams? ~
~ Helpless now I stand with him ~
~ Watching older dreams grow dim ~
~ Oh, what a melancholy choice this is ~
~ Wanting home, wanting him ~
~ Closing my heart to every hope but his ~
~ Leaving the home I love ~
~ There where my heart
has settled long ago ~
~ I must go ~
~ Who could imagine I'd be wandering so ~
~ Far from the home I love ~
~ Yet there with my love ~
~ I'm home ~
And who, my child, will there be
to perform a marriage in the wilderness?
Papa, I promise you,
we will be married under a canopy.
Yes. Yes.
No doubt a rabbi or two
were also arrested.
Papa!
God alone knows
when we shall see each other again.
Then we will leave it in his hands.
Take care of her.
See that she dresses warm.
Even though she only burned his cooking,
he is permitted to divorce her.
Just for supper?
I'm sorry, Rabbi.
Yes, of course.
What news of the outside world?
- Terrible, Rabbi.
- Then don't tell me.
If I want bad news,
I'll read about Noah and the flood.
Tell me, Avram,
surely somewhere
there are good things happening?
Can't you buy a paper
that prints those things?
It's not my fault, Rabbi. I only read it.
Rabbi, did you hear the news?
- More bad news?
- No, good news.
At Motel's and Tzeitel's, a new arrival.
A new arrival at Motel and Tzeitel's!
We just heard the good news. Mazel tov.
Thank you very much.
It's a nice thing.
Very nice.
- What is it?
- It's a sewing machine.
You can work twice as fast.
- You got it.
- I got it.
- It's beautiful.
- I know.
- Have you tried it yet?
- Look.
- Beautiful.
- I know.
And in less than a minute.
See how close and even the stitches are.
- It's beautiful.
- I know.
From now on, my clothes will be perfect.
Made by machine.
No more handmade clothes.
- Look, Mama. Look.
- Oh.
It's wonderful.
Mazel tov, Motel.
- The rabbi. The rabbi.
- Shh. Shh.
Rabbi, is there a blessing
for a sewing machine?
There is a blessing for everything.
That's your new arrival?
What is it, a boy or a girl?
Well put. Well put.
Yankela. Yankela.
Why isn't he asleep?
But he's wonderful.
He never cries or anything...
Sha! Do you want to invite bad luck?
Aaah! Well...
Well, Motel.
I never thought
you'd amount to anything.
But look at you.
A baby and a sewing machine.
You're a person.
- Look, I'll show you how it works.
Go, children.
First, you put the cloth in like this.
It's an amazing thing.
You work it with your foot and your hand.
Your father is coming.
Chava, let me tell him about us.
That would be the worst thing.
- But let me try.
- No.
I'll talk to him, I promise.
Good afternoon, sir.
Good afternoon.
It's a cold day, isn't it?
Mm.
Well, uh...
Good day, sir.
- Good day, Chava.
- Good day.
What were you and he talking about?
Nothing. We were just talking.
Good.
Papa.
Fyedka and I, we've known each other
for a long time now, and...
Chaveleh,
I would be much happier if
you would remain friends from a distance.
You must not forget
who you are and who that man is.
- He has a name, Papa.
- Of course.
All creatures on earth have a name.
Fyedka is not a creature.
Fyedka is a man.
Who says he isn't?
It's just that he's a different kind of man.
As the Good Book says,
"Each shall seek his own kind."
In other words, a bird may love a fish,
but where would they
build a home together?
- The world is changing.
- No, Chaveleh.
No.
Some things do not change for us.
Some things will never change.
We don't feel that way.
We?
Fyedka and I.
We want to be married.
What? Are you out of your mind?
What?
Don't you understand what that means,
marrying outside of the faith?
- But, Papa.
- No! I said no!
Never talk about it again.
Never mention his name again.
Never see him again.
Never.
Do you understand me?
Yes, Papa.
I understand you.
You're finally here.
It's late for supper.
- I want to see Motel's new machine.
- You'll see it another time.
Quiet, woman, because when
I get angry, even flies don't dare to fly!
I'm very frightened of you.
After we finish supper, I'll faint.
Golde, I am the man in the house.
I am the head of the family.
And I want to see
Motel's new machine now!
Now let's go home.
What are you doing here?
What do you want?
May I see His Honour, the priest?
- The Reverend Father?
- Yes.
Why do you want to see him?
It's a family matter. A personal matter.
- My daughter.
- Yes? What about your daughter?
Please, if I could speak with the p...
If I could speak
with the Reverend Father.
Please?
Wait here.
Tevye!
What is it?
It's Chava.
She left home this morning with Fyedka.
- What?
- I looked everywhere for her.
I even went to the priest.
He told me they were married.
Married?
Yes.
Well...
Go home, Golde.
We have other children at home.
You have work to do, I have work to do.
- Go home.
- But Chaveleh...
Chava is dead to us.
We'll forget her.
Go home.
Go home, Golde.
Oh...
~ Little bird, little Chaveleh ~
~ I don't understand
what's happening today ~
~ Everything is all a blur ~
~ All I can see is a happy child ~
~ The sweet little bird you were, Chaveleh ~
~ Chaveleh ~
~ Little bird, little Chaveleh ~
~ You were always
such a pretty little thing ~
~ Everybody's favourite child ~
~ Gentle and kind and affectionate ~
~ What a sweet little bird
you were, Chaveleh ~
~ Chaveleh ~
Papa.
Papa!
Papa, I've been looking
everywhere for you.
Papa, stop!
At least listen to me.
Papa...
I beg you to accept us.
Accept them?
How can I accept them?
Can I deny everything I believe in?
On the other hand,
can I deny my own daughter?
how can I turn my back on my faith,
my people?
If I try and bend that far,
I'll break.
On the other hand...
No, there is no other hand.
- No, Chava! No!
- But, Papa!
- No! No!
- Papa!
Papa!
Golde, here they are.
The boys I told you about.
Wonderful boys from good families.
Each of them a prize, a jewel.
You couldn't do better for your girls.
I don't know, Yente.
My girls are still so young.
So what do they look like, grandfathers?
True, the marriage can wait,
but meanwhile, their future
will be all signed and sealed.
Which one for which one?
What's the difference? Take your pick.
They're both wonderful boys.
Yankel, the fat one,
is apprenticed to a carpenter.
- I am Yankel.
- Did I ask you?
Yankel, the skinny one, is...
- Mama, is Reb Tevye in the house?
- He's in the barn. Is there trouble?
Stay inside, children.
What's the matter?
Tevye, have you seen
the constable lately?
- No. Why?
- There are some rumours in town.
We thought, since you knew him so well,
maybe he told you
what is true and what is not.
Rumours? What rumours?
Quiet! Talk, Avram.
Someone from Zolodin told me
an edict issued in St Petersburg...
Welcome, Your Honour.
What's the good news in the world?
I see that you have company.
They are my friends.
It's just as well.
What I have to say is for their ears also.
How much time do you need
to sell your house and household goods?
Why should I sell my house?
Is it in anybody's way?
I came to tell you
you have to leave Anatevka.
How did I come
to deserve such an honour?
Not just you, of course, but all of you.
At first, I thought you might be spared
because of your daughter's marriage.
My daughter is dead.
I understand.
At any rate, it affects all of you.
You have to leave.
But this corner of the world
has always been our home.
- Why should we leave?
- I don't know why.
There's trouble in the world.
Troublemakers.
- Like us?
- You aren't the only ones.
Your people must leave all
the villages - Zolodin, Rabalevka.
The entire district must be emptied.
I have an order here!
It says that you must sell your homes
and be out of here in three days.
And you?
You, who have known us all your life,
you'd carry out this order?
I've nothing to do with it.
Don't you understand?
I wish you wouldn't say me.
- I understand.
- Suppose we refuse to go?
- You will be forced out.
- We will defend ourselves.
- We'll stay in our homes.
- We will keep our land and fight.
Against our militia, our army?
I wouldn't advise that.
I have some advice for you.
Get off my land.
This is still my home, my land.
You have three days.
After a lifetime,
a piece of paper, and get thee out.
We should unite
with the people of Zolodin.
- Maybe they have a plan.
- We should defend ourselves.
- An eye for an eye, a tooth for a tooth.
- Very good
That way the whole world
will be blind and toothless.
Rabbi, we've been waiting
for the Messiah all our lives.
Wouldn't this be
a good time for him to come?
We'll have to wait for him someplace else.
Meanwhile, let's start packing.
Well, Anatevka hasn't exactly been
the Garden of Eden.
That's true.
After all, what have we got here?
~ A little bit of this, a little bit of that ~
~ A pot
A pan ~
~ A broom
A hat ~
~ Someone should have set a match
to this place years ago ~
~ A bench
A tree ~
~ What's a house?
Or a stove? ~
People who pass through Anatevka
don't even know they've been here.
~ A stick of wood
A piece of cloth ~
~ What do we leave? ~
~ Nothing much ~
~ Only Anatevka ~
~ Anatevka ~
~ Underfed, overworked Anatevka ~
~ Where else would Sabbath be so sweet? ~
~ Anatevka ~
~ Intimate, obstinate Anatevka ~
~ Where I know everyone I meet ~
~ Soon I'll be a stranger
in a strange new place ~
~ Searching for an old familiar face ~
~ From Anatevka ~
~ I belong to Anatevka ~
~ Tumbledown, workaday Anatevka ~
~ Dear little village ~
~ Little town of mine ~
It's just a place.
Our forefathers have been forced out of
many, many places at a moment's notice.
Maybe that's why
we always wear our hats.
Golde!
Golde, darling.
I had to see you before I left
because I have such news for you.
Remember, yesterday I didn't know where
to go, what to do with these old bones.
Now I know.
You want to hear? I'll tell you.
All my life,
I've dreamed of going to one place.
Guess where?
Nah, you'll never guess.
Every year at Passover, what do we say?
Next year in Jerusalem.
Next year in the Holy Land.
- You're going to the Holy Land?
- You guessed.
Goodbye, Yente.
Be well and go in peace.
And so, goodbye, Golde.
Sometime, maybe we'll meet
on a happier occasion.
Meanwhile, we suffer. Oh, we suffer.
We suffer in silence, right?
Of course, right.
Where are you going?
You don't know where you're going?
- Come, Golde, we have to leave.
- Leave. It sounds so easy.
Golde, we'll all be together soon.
Motel, Tzeitel and the baby,
they'll come too, you'll see.
This Motel is a person.
And Hodel and Perchik?
When will we ever see them again?
Do they come visiting us
from Siberia every Sabbath?
You know what she writes.
He sits in prison, she works.
But soon he'll be set free and together
they'll turn the world upside down.
She couldn't be happier,
and the other children will be with us.
Not all.
All.
Come, Golde.
I have to clean up, sweep the floor.
- Sweep the floor?
- I don't want to leave a dirty house.
Tevye.
Tevye, I am on my way.
Where are you going?
Chicago, in America.
Chicago, America?
We are going to New York, America.
We'll be neighbours.
My wife, Fruma Sarah,
has a brother there.
- That's nice.
- I hate him!
But a relative is a relative.
- Goodbye, Tevye.
- Goodbye, Lazar Wolf.
Well, my old friends,
it's time to say goodbye.
The farmer Bushenko
will be coming for you later.
He's not a bad sort.
If you are good to him,
he'll be good to you.
Take care of your leg, huh?
Thanks for everything.
Chava!
- Papa will see you.
- I want him to.
I want to say goodbye to him.
- He won't listen to you.
- But at least he will hear.
Maybe it would be better if I told Mama.
Chaveleh!
Papa.
We came to say goodbye.
We are also leaving this place.
We are going to Cracow.
We cannot stay among people
who can do such things to others.
We wanted you to know that.
Some are driven away by edicts,
others by silence.
Goodbye, Papa.
Mama.
Come, Chava.
Goodbye, Chava... Fyedka.
And God be with you.
- And God be with you.
- We will write to you in America.
We will be staying with Uncle Avram!
Yes, Mama.
"We'll be staying with Uncle Avram?"
The whole world
has to know our business.
Stop yelling and finish packing.
We have a long way to go.
Golde, I don't need your advice.
Tzeitel, don't forget the baby.
Goodbye, Papa.
Work hard, Motel,
and come to us soon.
I will, Papa.
I'll work hard.
All right, children.
Let's go.
Visiontext Subtitles:
Natasha Cohn