[Bell Tolling]
[Tolling Continues]
[No Audible Dialogue]
[Car Starts]
[People Speaking French]
[Baby Crying]
[Bell Jingles]
[TV: Man Speaking French]
[Chattering]
[Man]
Merry Christmas!
- What's your name, little boy?
- Eric.
Uh-huh. Eric.
What do you want for Christmas, Eric?
- Hmm?
- Johnny Lightning 500.
- Mm-hmm. Have you been a good little boy?
- Yes.
Have you? Good.
Do you like Santa Claus?
- Huh?
- Mm-hmm.
Oh, now, you like Santa Claus, right?
- ♪♪ [Jukebox: Funk]
- [Chattering]
All right, let's sing a little song.
"Jingle Bells."
[With Children]
♪Jingle bells, jingle bells ♪
♪Jingle all the way ♪
♪ Oh, what fun it is to ride ♪♪
- ♪♪ [Continues]
- [Chattering]
[Man]
Right on. Right on.
Get out of here. Get up.
Get up! Hold 'em up.
Don't move.
- [Man] Hold it! Freeze!
- [Man #2] Jimmy, watch it. He's got a knife.
Cloudy- Cloudy, watch him.
Aaah! Son of a-
[Panting]
[Horns Honking]
[Chattering]
Son of a bitch.
- [Grunts]
- Hold it, you son of a bitch!
No! No! No!
[Groaning]
That's enough. Don't kill him.
That's enough!
- Come on.
- Get up!
- Come on now.
- Give me a break!
- Please.
- Holy shit.
- I ain't done nothin', man.
- Break your ass!
Come on. Hey.
- Come on.
- Get up!
Stop it!
- Let me at him, goddamn you!
- Jimmy!
- Fuck you.
- Will you stop it?
I'm gonna bust you.
Get over here. Come on.
- Jimmy.
- Come on, let me-
Let me bust him.
I wanna bust him.
- I wanna bust him.
- Don't—
- Let me talk to him. Let me talk to him.
- Oh, you-
- You got a friend here, buddy.
- Just for a minute.
- You got a friend.
- Jimmy. You gonna tell us who your man is?
- When's the last time you picked your feet, Willie?
- Who's your connection?
- What's his name?
- What?
- Answer him!
- No! No, man. No. I ain't never-
Is it Joe the barber? Joe the barber, right?
That's who it is, isn't it?
- Aw, don't give us any shit. What's Joe's last name?
- I don't know, man.
Give him a chance.
Just give him a chance.
- Give him a chance.
- Man, all I know is he lives on 125th Street-
- Above the barbershop.
- What side of the street does he live on, huh?
North or south?
North or south, huh?
I don't know what you're talking about, man.
I don't know—
I'm asking you what side
of the street he lives on!
Hey, shithead, when was the last time
you picked your feet, huh?
- Man, what's he talkin' about?
- I've got a man in Poughkeepsie
wants to talk to you.
You ever been to Poughkeepsie?
Huh?
- Have you ever been to Poughkeepsie?
- Hey, man, give me a break.
- I don't know what you're talking about.
- Come on, say it.
Let me hear you say it.
Have you ever been to Poughkeepsie?
You've been to Poughkeepsie,
haven't you?
- I wanna hear it! Come on!
- Yes. Yes, I-
- You've been there, right?
- Yeah. Yeah.
You sat on the edge of the bed,
didn't you?
You took off your shoes, put your finger in
between your toes and picked your feet. Say it!
- Yes.
- You put a shiv in my partner.
You know what that means?
Goddamn it! All winter long I gotta listen
to him gripe about his bowling scores.
Now I'm gonna bust your ass
for those three bags...
and I'm gonna nail you
for pickin' your feet in Poughkeepsie.
[Speaking French]
[Man #2 Speaking French]
Merci.
- Bonjour.
- [Speaking French]
[Speaking French]
Merci, chéri.
[Giggles]
[Woman On P.A.]
13-80, 61. 13-80, 61.
- Who's detective for 13 Victor Six?
- Yes, ma'am.
How many fellas?
- Two?
...a family dispute.
- Do you have a description?
- [P.A. Continues, Indistinct]
Yes, ma'am.
Ha. Need a little help there, huh?
You dumb guinea.
- How the hell did I know he had a knife?
- Never trust a nigger.
- He could have been white.
- Never trust anyone.
- You goin' sick?
- No.
- Huh? Are you goin' sick?
- No!
What do you say we "popeye" down to the Chez
and have a couple of drinks?
- I'm beat. I'm gonna go home.
- All right. One drink.
- Drink this.
- Whip it out. [Laughs]
♪ How many times
have I been downhearted ♪
♪ Looked up and saw him
smiling like a shiny dime ♪
- ♪ Yeah ♪
- [Chattering]
♪ I hoped that he would stay
and tell me why ♪
- [No Audible Dialogue]
- ♪ He was so happy if he had the time ♪
♪ Oh, I wish there was a way
to race him ♪
♪ Catch a flying horse and chase him ♪
♪ Everybody's going to the moon ♪
Me and you.
♪ Everybody's going
It'll be quite soon ♪
♪ It's customary in songs like this ♪
♪ To use a word like spoon ♪
♪ By the light of the silvery ♪
♪ I'm flyin' to the silvery
You know ♪
- ♪ Everybody's goin' to the moon ♪
- [No Audible Dialogue]
♪ How many times while looking down ♪
♪ Has he heard us singing songs ♪
♪ And wondered who we were ♪
Hey!
♪ And envied us ♪
♪ Because the lady
in the moon is gone ♪
♪ And now he misses her ♪
♪ And then he wondered to himself
Now, why is it ♪
♪ No one ever pays a visit ♪
♪ Everybody gets to go to the moon
Yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Everybody's got to go
It'll be quite soon ♪
♪ Now, it's customary
in songs like this ♪
♪ To use a month like June ♪
♪ By the light of the silvery ♪
♪ We'll take a flight to the silvery
You know ♪
♪ Everybody's going to the moon ♪
Now, isn't it a miracle...
that we are the generation...
that's gonna touch that shiny bubble...
with our own two hands?
♪ And it's got to make you glad
to be alive ♪
♪ Yes, it's got to make you proud ♪
♪ To be alive ♪
♪♪ [Vocalizing]
[No Audible Dialogue]
Whoo!
I make at least two junk connections...
at that far table over there
in the corner.
- Right?
- [No Audible Dialogue]
And the guy in the striped
shirt and tie combo...
I know him too.
I thought we came here
to buy me a drink.
Who is that clown?
He's a policy guy from Queens.
Right.
[No Audible Dialogue]
Dig the creep that's coming
to the table now.
It's Jewish Lucky. He don't look the same
without numbers across his chest.
[Chuckles]
That table is definitely wrong.
♪ It's customary in songs like this ♪
♪ To use a word like spoon ♪
♪ By the light of the silvery ♪
♪ Flight to the silvery ♪
- ♪ Everybody's going to the moon ♪♪
- [Audience Applauds]
More.
What about the last
of the big-time spenders?
You make him?
No. You?
He's spreadin' it around
like the Russians are in Jersey.
Nice.
What do you say we stick around
and give him a tail?
Come on. Just for fun.
Give who a tail?
The greaser with the blonde.
What for? You wanna play
hide the salami with his old lady?
Yeah.
[Laughs]
[No Audible Dialogue]
Miss, uh, can I ask you
about those boots there? Uh-
[Exhales, Sniffles]
Monica.
- Who in the hell's that?
- Who keeps score?
- [Jimmy] Hey.
- Hmm?
- Kissy devil, isn't he? Look at him.
- Yeah.
- Well, they're all cousins. You know that.
- Yeah. All right.
- [Whistle Blows]
- Yeah, say good-bye. Come on.
What's he got now?
- Hudson Terraplane. That's what he got.
- No, no. Uh-uh.
- Easy, easy.
- Okay.
Go to work.
Cloudy, lay odds he takes us
to Dago town.
We'll take him, Popeye.
He's nothin'.
[Cloudy]
7:00 in the morning.
I don't believe this.
[Jimmy]
Relax. You're having fun, ain't you?
[Engine Starts]
[Jimmy]
Man, if that's not a drop...
I'll open up a charge for you
at Bloomingdales.
Make it Alexander's.
I like the toy department.
[No Audible Dialogue]
[Engine Starts]
He's coming back.
Pass him. Make a left.
[No Audible Dialogue]
[Outboard Engine Running]
[Speaking French]
[French]
[Chuckles]
Alain.
Bonjour.
Enchanté.
[Tapping]
[Cloudy]
Our friend's name is Boca—
Salvatore Boca. B-O-C-A.
They call him Sal.
He's a sweetheart.
He was picked up on suspicion
of armed robbery. Now, get this.
Three years ago
he tries to hold up Tiffany's...
on Fifth Avenue in broad daylight.
He coulda got two and a half to five...
but Tiffany's wouldn't prosecute.
Also, downtown they're pretty sure he pulled
off a contract on a guy named DeMarco.
[Jimmy]
What about his old lady?
Her name's Angie. She's a fast filly.
- She drew a suspended for shoplifting a year ago.
- [No Audible Dialogue]
She's only a kid. Nineteen,
according to the marriage license.
Mmm. Nineteen going on 50.
What else?
He's had the store a year and a half.
Takes in a fast seven grand a year.
So what's he doing with two cars...
and hundred-dollar tabs at the Chez?
The LTD's in his wife's name.
The Comet belongs to his brother Lou.
He's a trainee at the garbageman school
on Ward's Island.
He did time a couple of years ago...
assault and robbery.
The black Cadillac-
Uh, NewJersey plates.
RWN-264.
I know that one cat.
We saw him outside the Pike Slip Inn
the other day.
[Cloudy] I wanna get a blouse
like that for my girlfriend...
but I want you to model it for me.
Better not let my husband hear that.
I don't care if he hears it.
Will you do it for me?
Okay. How much you gonna pay?
- Fifty dollars an hour.
- Fifty an hour? I'll do it... 200.
[Cloudy]
Nah. Can't afford it.
I'll call you later.
All right. Bye-bye.
Hey, it's 1:30.
I didn't expect you till 2:00.
- [Angie] You work around here?
- Yeah. Across the street.
[Jimmy] That's the third time
he's come here this week.
[Cloudy]
Mm-hmm.
- You got anything on this building?
- The building's clean.
I checked the tenant list.
Remember Don Ameche, the actor?
He lives here.
Oh, yeah. And somebody else.
Does the name
Joel Weinstock ring a bell?
- Oh, you're kidding.
- No, sir. He lives right here.
[Chuckles]
He was the bank on a shipment out of Mexico...
What was it? Three years ago.
Yeah, so I hear.
[Radio Chatter]
[Cloudy] He's going to Ward's Island.
We're gonna be spotted there.
- What the hell is he doing that?
- Maybe he's gonna go down and see his brother.
- Shit.
- Well, maybe it's another drop.
Well, he gets a free ride.
- ♪♪ [Jukebox: Funk]
- [Indistinct]
- ♪♪ [Stops]
- All right, Popeye's here.
Get your hands on your heads.
Get off the bar and get on the wall.
Come on, move. Move!
- [Cloudy] Come on, sweetheart, move.
- Come on, move it!
- Face the window. Move!
- Face the wall.
- Turn around there. Turn around.
- Move! Come on, move!
- Hands outta your pockets.
- Turn around.
- Come on. Come on.
- Turn around, big man. Come on, turn around.
Get on the wall. Turn around.
You— Turn around.
- Hey. You drop that? Pick it up.
- Hold those hands up.
Pick it up! Come on, move.
What are you lookin' at?
All right, bring it here.
Get your hands out of your pockets.
- What's my name?
- Doyle.
- What?
- Mr. Doyle.
Come here. You pick your feet?
- What?
- Do you- Get over there.
Get your hands on your head.
[Cloudy]
Hold 'em up.
We told you people we were comin' back.
We're gonna keep comin' back here
until you clean this bar up.
Keep your eye on your neighbor.
If he drops something, it belongs to you.
What is this, a fuckin' hospital here? Huh?
- Turn around there, fella.
- What do we got here, huh? This belong to you?
Huh?
Stand up there, "noddy."
Get your hands on your fuckin' head.
Get in there!
- You wanna take a ride there, fat man?
- Oh, bullshit.
Huh?
Pay attention.
We're gonna ask questions later.
Turn around.
[Man Whispering]
Fuckin' bullshit.
All right, shut up there. Shut up!
Anybody want a milk shake?
All right, come over here.
You... and you.
Hey, whiskers! Come over here.
- Move ass when I call you.
- [Indistinct]
- Get out of here.
- You.
Come on, you, baldy.
Come on. Come on, move.
All right, put it on the bar.
- What are you pullin' on me for?
- Get it on the bar.
Get the hell in there.
Put your hands on your head.
All of it.
Smartass, you dropped something.
Pick it up.
You want that hand broken?
Get it up there.
What else you got here, huh?
[Cloudy]
Turn around.
You're under arrest. That goes for you too.
Get in that phone booth.
Come on, move. Move!
- Keep 'em up. Keep 'em up. That's good.
- Get in there.
All right, face the wall, put your hands
against the wall and lock yourself in.
Hey, you, haircut.
- Where are you going?
- You talkin' to me, baby?
Yeah, I'm talking to you.
Come here. Get out of there.
- Move.
- What's happening, baby?
- Where you been, huh?
- I've been in there.
- Can you stand a toss?
- Sure. I'm clean.
- You use shit?
- No, man.
Oh, man, who are you, Dick Tracy
or somebody? I said I was clean.
- I'm not gonna get stuck, am I?
- No. I said I'm clean.
- If I do, you know what happens, don't you?
- Yeah. I said I'm clean.
Aw, motherfucker, don't-
I'll break your motherfuckin' ass.
Fuck you.
- [Indistinct]
- Oh, yeah, in where?
- Gimme a nickel.
- Come on, man.
Gimme a nickel.
Come on. Come on!
I told you I'm clean. Why the fuck you
wanna come down on me like that for?
- Get your ass in there.
- Oh, man, would you-
This ain't nothin' but goddamn bullshit.
[Exhales]
- How's everything?
- Everything's everything, baby.
Hey, how come there's nothin' out there?
That stuff's all milk.
Ain't nothin' around.
Nobody's holding.
- I got a name for you. Sal Boca. Brooklyn.
- Boca?
Yeah. B-O-C-A.
- Never heard of him.
- What about his wife, Angie?
Doesn't register.
- There's been some talk.
- About what?
A shipment... coming in this week,
week after.
Everybody's gonna get well.
- Well, who's bringing it?
- Who knows?
Oh, shit.
[Exhales, Groans]
- Where do you want it?
- Huh?
- Oh, shit.
This side.
[Groans]
- Beat it.
- Damn. [Groans]
I'm gonna check on this address
in the Bronx...
and if they don't know you there,
it's your ass.
[Cloudy]
I thought I told you to stand there.
Get that hair done before Saturday.
We're going now. Good-bye.
[Cloudy]
Move ass.
Tell everybody we'll be back in an hour.
All that is great, but you belong in
Bedford-Stuyvesant, not out there in Ridgewood.
Why don't you detach us then, for Christ's sakes?
Give us a shot at it.
At least till we find out
if there's anything here or not.
Everybody wants Weinstock, right?
Well, maybe here's the lead we're looking for.
We deserve this.
You couldn't burn a three-time loser...
with this garbage you're bringing in here.
The man has done absolutely nothing.
The first thing you know, you'll wind up
in an entrapment rap— the both of you.
Brooklyn is loaded with guys...
that own candy stores, two cars,
and like to go to nightclubs.
Yeah, but you put
this little candy store hustler together...
with Joel Weinstock,
and maybe we got a big score.
Big score, my ass.
At best he's selling
nickel and dime bags.
I wouldn't be infringing
on your coffee break, Simonson...
if I thought it was a nickel-and-dimer.
Your hunches have backfired before, Doyle.
Or have you forgotten about that already?
Jesus Christ, Jimmy.
What's happened to you guys lately?
Every year you lead
the Narcotics Bureau in arrests.
What was it,
over a hundred again last year?
Terrific. But who?
What did you bring in?
- A high school kid
in short pants that had a twitch.
- Oh, Christ.
You grab a bellhop because
he's got three joints in his sock.
Walt, we got the information
there's no shit on the street, right?
It's like a goddamn desert
full of junkies out there.
- Everybody waiting to get well.
- Goddamn it.
This could be it.
This little candy store guy...
He's puttin' on a big show in a fancy nightclub
with known narcotics connections.
They were all over him.
And then, on our own,
after working a whole day and night...
we tail him to Brooklyn,
and we sat on him for practically a week.
Now, who do we come up with?
Joel Weinstock, for Christ's sake.
Now, you gotta let us have it.
Do you believe all this crap?
I go with my partner.
- What'll it take?
- A wire.
- No. Two wires.
- Two wires.
One on the store, one on the house.
You know I have to get a court order
for a wiretap, don't you?
But you'll try.
We know you can do it, Walt.
[Chuckles]
Popeye.
You still pickin' your feet
in Poughkeepsie?
[Chuckles]
[Man Speaking French]
[Ship's Horn Blows In Distance]
[Chattering]
[Woman] Mr. Devereaux,
is this your first trip to New York?
Uh, yes. It's my first trip.
Why did you choose to come by ship?
The next several weeks
will be very difficult for me...
and, uh, the middle of the ocean
is the only place...
where the telephone
isn't ringing all the time.
Mr. Devereaux, do you agree
with the recent survey finding...
that showed that Mayor Lindsay
was the sexiest man in the world?
[Man Speaking French]
- [Chuckles]
- To les femmes.
[Man On P.A., Indistinct]
Here's the rest of the warrants.
The court order's in there for the wiretaps.
Judge gave you 60 days on it.
Tell Doyle that Mulderig and Klein
will sit in for the feds.
They'll make all the buys.
Make sure you keep 'em informed
of everything that goes down.
You know Doyle there, don't you, Bill?
Yeah, I know Popeye.
- His brilliant hunches cost the life of a good cop.
- Hey, look.
If this is the way
you're comin' in on this...
why don't you stay home
and save us all a lot of grief?
- 'Cause that's my opinion.
- Shove it up your ass.
Whatever.
Bill, look. Please...
Do me a favor. Give them a chance.
He came in here
with a little basic information.
I know you worked with him before.
You had a little trouble.
- But don't get off on the wrong foot, huh?
- I'm not getting off...
- If you have any problems, come to me with 'em.
- Just keep him off my back.
- Just try and cool it with him.
- I will.
If you have any problems, come to me.
I'll handle him.
- Do me a favor.
- I'll be happy to work with him, believe me.
He's a good cop- basically a good cop.
- He's got good hunches every once in a while.
- Fine, fine, fine.
- Give him a chance.
- Keep him off my back.
[Man On Radio]
Florida's Mackel Brothers...
invite you to join the great escape.
You can say good-bye
to air pollution, commuting...
high prices, rising taxes
and cold, depressing winters.
Mackel Brothers will show you
the way to Florida...
and fresh, clean air,
warm and sunny year-round weather...
and a home that you'll be proud to own.
Call Mackel Brothers right now for—
[Horn Honks]
[Bell Dinging]
[Children Chattering]
[Man On TV, Muffled]
Popeye.
Popeye!
- [Jimmy] What?
- It's me, Cloudy.
Open the door.
I can't.
What do you mean, you can't?
You all right?
Yeah, I'm all right.
Let yourself in, will you?
[Baby Crying]
[Clicks]
What happened?
[Yawns]
Mmm, that crazy kid.
[Chuckles]
She locked me up with my own cuffs.
[Yawns]
Where's the keys?
[Mumbling]
Over there.
[Yawns]
[Gasps]
- Hi there.
- [Door Shuts]
[Yawns]
Anybody hurt in this wreck?
Thought I told you
to get plastic folders for this stuff.
[Yawns]
Your scrapbook is like you-
a mess.
Gimme my pants, will ya?
Come on.
- Did you get the warrants?
- Yeah.
I also got two feds-
Mulderig and Klein.
[Groans]
What do we need those pricks for?
Because our department's got
about 908 bucks to make buys...
and they can get all they want
from "Uncle Sap."
Hello.
These yours, darling?
[Man] Mike, take a look at this blue one
with the tan, on the right.
[Chattering]
[Man Speaking French]
[French]
[Woman Speaking French]
[Man]
You got an extra grand with you?
[Man #2]
A lot of this stuff is worth a grand, total.
- I got it. I got it if I need it.
- All right.
- Keep it good and ready.
- Did you look at the board, Mike?
[Whistle Blows]
Thirty over here from the general.
Okay, I got 30.
- Can I get 35? Anyone, 35.
- Thirty-five here.
- Thirty-five over here. How about 38?
- Yeah, right here.
Thirty-eight over here.
How about 40? Can I get 40?
- [Man] Forty.
- Forty over here. I got 40. Can I get 41?
Forty once. Forty twice.
Sold to the gentleman for $40.
All right, we come now
to the next number, 42-399.
- [Speaking French]
- Rambler four-door sedan.
- Do I hear $10?
- [Man] Ten bucks.
- I got $10 over here. Do I hear 12?
- Twelve.
- Twelve over here. Twelve. Can I get 14?
- Fourteen.
- Fourteen over here. How about 16?
- Can I hear 16? Sixteen?
- Sixteen.
- [Man] Eighteen dollars.
- Eighteen over there. How about 20? Can I get 20?
- Twenty.
- Twenty dollars over here.
How about 22? Twenty-two?
- Twenty-two.
- I got 22 over here. Can I get 24?
- Twenty-four.
- Twenty-four over here. How about 25?
- Twenty-five.
- Twenty-five. I got 25.
Can I get 26? Can I get 26?
Twenty-five once. Twenty-five twice.
Sold to the gentleman for 25.
Every car sold here today—
[Woman On Tape]
Where are you?
[Man On Tape]
Taking care of business.
What do you mean, taking care of business?
It's after midnight.
- You know, uh, I had to meet some people tonight.
- [Chuckling]
[Woman] Yeah, well, finish all your
meeting people and get back here now.
- And bring a pizza with you.
- Where am I gonna get a pizza this time of night?
[Laughing]
[Woman]
Well, try, okay?
Hey, I don't know where
I'm gonna find a pizza joint open.
- Sal?
- Yeah?
Don't forget— Anchovies.
- [Man On Tape] Salvatore?
- [Man #2 On Tape] Oh, yes. Yeah, yeah.
- Who is it?
- Hello. Hello. Yeah, this is Sal.
- How are you?
- Sounds like a foreigner.
You meet me Wednesday
at the hotel, okay?
- Good. Great.
- Sounds French.
- Will I expect you?
- Uh, yeah. What time?
- 12:00. Yes?
- Yeah. Uh, yes. Yeah.
- Ohh—
- Oh, ho!
[Whooping, Shouting]
Strictly small potatoes.
Sure can pick 'em, Doyle.
Still wearing your gun on your ankle?
You know, someone told me
the reason why you do that...
is when you meet a chick
and you rub up against her...
she can't tell you're a cop.
[Chuckles]
I said, "That's bullshit.
It's gotta be a fast-draw gimmick
or something."
Bill, why don't you knock it off, huh?
He's gettin' too far ahead.
You're gonna lose him.
[Horns Honking]
[Tires Squealing]
[Man]
For Christ's sake, move the car, huh?
- Jesus Christ!
- [Man #2] Move it!
- [Honking Continues]
- [Man #1] Move it, will you, mac?
Son of a—
What the hell is goin' on here?
Come on, Cloudy, move.
Klein, this is Cloudy.
Do you read me?
Bill, for—
Bill, come in, for Christ's sakes.
[Cloudy On Radio]
This is Cloudy. Do you read me?
Listen. We lost him on the bridge.
Right. I got him.
He's heading north on East River Drive.
[Chattering]
Excuse me. Excuse me.
[No Audible Dialogue]
[Jimmy]
You take Sal. I'll take the beard.
There goes Sal.
[No Audible Dialogue]
- [Chattering]
- ♪♪ [Piano: Soft Jazz]
[No Audible Dialogue]
[Sniffles]
Do you want the red or the white?
What year?
[No Audible Dialogue]
[Chattering]
- Yes, sir.
- Yeah, uh, the guy who just walked in-
What's his name?
[Brakes Screech]
[Cloudy]
Here.
I'm pretty sure that was the frog.
He made me too.
He lives on four. He went up to six.
He's cute. Real cute.
The other guy's a frog too.
He checked into the Edison.
- Had a hooker sent up.
- You could have collared him right there.
- Who's on him?
- Klein.
- How 'bout Sal?
- We put him to bed for the night.
Why don't you do the same, Doyle?
You look like shit.
- [Cloudy] Come on.
- Look. My partner and I made this case.
You know? Originally.
We don't want any feds screwin' it up.
Case? So far you haven't
showed me a damn thing.
You keep shootin' your mouth off, I'm gonna
knock you right in the middle of next week.
- Aw, get out—
- [Cloudy] Knock it off.
- Don't tell me to knock it off, goddamn it.
- We don't need this.
Now, cut it out, will ya?
For Christ's sakes!
There's nothing going down.
Get some sleep.
Blast off.
180.
200. Good Housekeeping
Seal of approval.
210. U.S. Government certified.
220. Lunar trajectory.
Junk of the Month Club sirloin steak.
230.
Grade "A" poison.
Absolute dynamite.
89% pure junk. Best I've ever seen.
If the rest is like this, you'll be dealing
on this load for two years.
- So you're telling me it's worth a half million?
- How many kilos?
- [Sal] Sixty.
- Sixty kilos?
Eight big ones a kilo, right?
This stuff'll take
a 7-to-1 hit on the street.
And by the time it gets down to nickel bags,
it'll be at least 32 million.
Thank you, Howard. Take what's
left there with you, and good night.
Uh-uh. Not that one.
The little one.
- I guess we got a deal, huh?
- What we got here, Sal, is a test.
A deal for half a million dollars?
Mmm. Maybe.
Maybe?
[Scoffs]
Come on, Joel. I know that guy's
in a hurry. Wants the bread.
He wants to go back to France. This guy's
not gonna hang around and play games.
Look, he's one of the shrewdest cats
I ever come across.
What am I, a schmuck?
What's the hurry?
He could see a couple of shows...
visit the top of the Empire State Building.
Don't jerk me, Weinstock.
I spent a lot of time settin' this one up.
So what do you want, a badge?
This is your first major league game, Sal.
One thing I learned-
Move calmly, move cautiously.
You'll never be sorry.
Look. I've been damn careful up to now.
This is why your phone lines are tapped and
the feds are crawling all over you like fleas.
Aah. Look, I'm telling you,
he'll take the deal somewhere else.
So let him take his 60 kilos
of heroin someplace else...
and find how easy it is
to put together a half a million in cash.
He wouldn't find there's any hurry
to do this kind of business.
The stuff is here!
We could make the switch in an hour!
Look, Weinstock, I'm telling you.
He'll split if we don't move!
This guy's got 'em like that.
He's everything they say he is.
What about you, Sal?
Are you everything they say you are?
I'll be a son of a bitch.
[Grunts]
[Grunting]
[Door Alarm Buzzes]
Come on!
Thank you. Hello.
This is Doyle.
I'm sittin' on Frog One.
Yeah, I know that.
We got the Westbury covered like a tent.
The Westbury, my ass!
I got him on the shuttle at Grand Central.
Now, what the hell's goin' on up there?
I make him coming out of the hotel,
free as a bird. There wasn't a soul awake.
What the hell are you talking about?
Yeah, well, uh-
Listen, I don't care how many bartenders
you got that are sick.
Nah, I'm not workin' that joint.
That's right.
Same to you, buddy.
Can I get a grape drink?
- [Man On Speaker] Watch the closing doors.
- [Alarm Buzzing]
You son of a bitch!
Hi. Can I have a, uh,
round-trip ticket to Washington?
- Washington? Cash or charge?
- Cash.
- [Woman] Cash is $54.
- Right.
Okay. Please print your name on both tickets
before you board the plane.
Yeah. Bye-bye.
Bye-bye. Have a nice flight.
- Yes, sir?
- Round trip to Washington, please.
[Car Door Closes]
So?
So everything's going great,
terrific, beautiful.
I'll need a few more days though.
The boys think we oughta
cool it for a while...
just to make sure there's no heat.
You must take me for an imbecile.
Why do you think I asked you
to meet me in Washington?
I haven't spent five minutes
in New York City...
without the company of a policeman.
Look, I'm leveling with you.
I need a little more time.
It's just that my people think we oughta
find a better time to make the switch.
- That's all.
- It has to be by the end of this week.
Look, Charnier.
You got to be reasonable.
It's your problem.
Well, it's your problem too.
It's so nice to have seen you again.
[Speaking French]
[French]
[Radio Chatter]
[Man, Indistinct]
[Horn Honks]
I don't want to get into this.
I gotta have time.
I can't get any more time.
- Give me some fuckin' time, will you?
- You're not gonna get it.
We found a set of works on the kid
driving the sports car over there.
His girlfriend's in the back of the car.
She's dead.
- Give the car a complete toss.
- I say we keep sittin' on Boca.
Jimmy, give it up. Give it up.
It's all over with.
If there was a deal, it's gone down by now.
We blew it.
We blew our warrants.
We blew our cover.
Walter, listen.
I know the deal hasn't gone down.
I— I know it. I can feel it.
I'm dead certain.
Last time you were dead certain,
we ended up with a dead cop.
Hey! Hold— Hold on! Hold on!
Break it up, both of you!
Will you two break it up?
Stop it now. Hold on to yourself!
What's the matter with you?
- Son of a-
- Jimmy, you wasted two months on this.
No collars are comin' in while you two guys
are runnin' around town, jerkin' off.
Now, go back to work!
You're off special assignment!
[Man On Radio]
10-4.
[Bell Dinging]
[Child]
Oh, there he is!
[Gunshots]
- Oh! Oh!
- [Screaming]
- Get down! Get down. Get out of the area!
Leave her alone! Get away!
Leave her alone!
There's a sniper up there!
[Children Crying]
[Crying Continues]
[Woman Screaming]
[People Chattering]
[Man]
Somebody should call the doctor.
[Speaking Spanish]
[Man]
Hey, there's a doctor right across the street.
- [Man #2] There must be a doctor.
- [Man #3] There is one.
[Chattering Continues]
[Panting]
[Train Approaching]
[Train Whistle Blows]
Hey!
- [Brakes Screeching]
- Hey!
Stop that man!
He's wanted by the police!
[Horn Beeps]
- What's the next stop into the city?
- 25th Avenue.
Hold it!
[Tires Screech]
Police emergency!
I need your car. I need your car.
- [Horn Honking]
- When am I gonna get it back?
[Horn Honking]
For Christ's sake!
[Horn Honks]
[Horn Honking]
[Horns Honking]
Hold it! Stop! Halt!
- [Grunts]
- [Screaming]
[Screaming Continues]
[Horn Honking]
- [Tires Squealing]
- [Horn Honking]
[Honking Continues]
- Don't stop. Don't stop, or I'll kill you!
- Hey, what? What—
I gotta stop in the next station.
Touch the brake,
and I'll blow you in half.
[Horn Honking Continues]
[Tires Screeching]
[Train Whistle Blows]
- What's going on?
- I don't know. Sit down, buddy. Relax.
Coke! Coke, you all right?
[Horn Honking]
Hey, Coke. You all right?
- [Pounding]
- Don't answer.
[Honking Continues]
[Mouths Words]
Hey, Coke. You all right?
- [Woman Screams]
- Get back!
- Relax. Now, put your gun down.
- Keep going!
[Woman]
Oh, my God! [Screams]
You're not gonna get away with this.
Put the gun down.
- Get back!
- Come on now-
- I said get back!
- You can't get away...
[Women Screaming]
Stop!
[Screaming]
[Horn Honking]
Hold it!
[Man]
Let's get out of here!
[Man Shouting]
Come on! Come on! Shake your ass.
It's getting cold.
I can't seem to find the damn ticket.
- Where's the guy?
- He's getting my car from the back.
[Horn Honks]
- Thank you.
- Sure.
- Can I help you?
- Uh, yeah. Uh— It's a convertible.
Do you have the ticket?
The top one. The top floor?
- What kind of ticket do you have?
- Never mind.
He's in the brown Lincoln,
foreign plates.
- All right. He's walking towards Front Street.
- [Klein On Radio] Got him.
Angie's parked over here in the LTD.
[Russo On Radio]
Cute.
You stay with her.
We're gonna sit on the Lincoln.
That car's dirty, Cloudy.
We're gonna sit here all night
if we have to.
[Shouting]
[Vehicle Approaching]
[Horn Honks]
What time is it?
Ten after 4:00.
- Huh?
- Ten after 4:00.
That's the third time
those guys have been around.
- All right. Let's hit 'em! Hit 'em!
- [Siren Wailing]
Freeze!
All right. Nobody move!
Put your hands in the air!
[Sirens Continue]
Get over... Get over there! Hey!
Get up there!
Spread those fucking legs!
Now stay right there!
You move,
I'll blow your fuckin' head off!
- What the hell's that?
- What are you doing? Turn around!
- Man, I have my rights.
- What do you mean, your rights?
Who's the boss here, huh?
Hey, who's running this outfit?
- I am.
- You are?
- What are you doing here? Who sent you down?
- Just runnin' around.
Don't talk back to me, man.
What are you doing here?
- We saw the car, man.
- You heist this car?
No. We was breaking down the tires.
That's all it was.
Lock 'em up.
Lock 'em up. Lock 'em up.
- All of you, come on.
- Come on! Come on!
Come on. Stop draggin' your ass.
Keep your hands on your head.
You dumb spics, get outta here!
Lock 'em up and throw away the goddamn key!
[Police Radio Chatter]
Nothin' but a bunch
of lousy spic car thieves.
- Nothin' in there except a New York City map.
- Are you bullshittin' me?
[Grunts]
That car's dirty.
Take it in and tear it apart.
[Jimmy]
Tear it right out. Tear it out!
Nothing here, Jimmy.
Look in here.
[Coughing]
This is all solid.
[Loud Hissing]
[Tire Bouncing]
[Whirring]
There's nobody been under that car
since it came from the factory.
That thing is clean.
I don't buy that, Irv.
The stuff is in that car.
Well, you find it. I can't.
[Indistinct]
[Speaking French]
Look, the car was lost
some time last night.
First, they send us to Pier 1,
then they send us here. Then what?
I don't understand why you parked the car
down by the waterfront.
You tell me you're staying at the Doral
in midtown Manhattan...
and you lose the car
out by the Brooklyn Bridge?
Look, Monsieur Devereaux is scouting
locations for a film for French television.
He probably left the car
to look at some point of interest.
We were told by the police commissioner's office
that the car was brought to this garage.
I demand its immediate return.
You're going to have to be patient, Mr. Devereaux.
We get 400, 500 cars here a day.
Monsieur Devereaux is
a very important guest of this country.
He's working with the absolute cooperation
and participation of your government.
Here are his credentials
from the French consulate.
Unless you wish to see this episode
portrayed in his film...
I suggest you locate the car immediately.
You're in a no-smoking area, sir.
Will you please
extinguish your cigarettes?
What was the weight of the car
when you got it, Irv?
4,795 pounds.
You sure?
That's what it was... 4,795 pounds...
when it came into the shop.
The owner's manual says 4,675.
It's 120 pounds overweight.
And when it was booked into Marseille,
it was 4,795.
That's still 120 pounds overweight.
Jimmy's gotta be right.
Listen, I ripped everything out of there
except the rocker panels.
Come on, Irv!
What the hell is that?
Uh-huh.
Well, shit!
Son of a bitch.
All right.
[Chuckles]
[Arguing In French]
It isn't the only car we have here.
Got it for you, Randy.
It just came in from downtown.
- Who's Devereaux?
- I am Mr. Devereaux. Why?
Oh, I'm sorry, Mr. Devereaux...
but we get a lot of cars here at night,
and sometimes it's hard to keep track...
- You mean the car is here now?
- Oh, yeah, yeah. It's right outside.
They, uh, stole it right
off the street from you, huh?
Goddamn.
You're gonna have to pay
the towing charge, you know.
I was told these things happen
in New York, but one never expects it.
Well, that's New York.
Is this your first trip over here?
- Yeah. Where's my car, please?
- It's right over here.
Oh.
But you're lucky this time.
It's in perfect shape. Not a scratch.
You must lead a charming life.
[Chattering]
[Indistinct Dialogue]
Henri.
Je vous attendais.
[Speaking French]
[Metal Clanging]
[Chattering]
[Engine Starts]
- [Man] Let's go!
- Bon voyage.
Merci.
- I would give you a ride, but-
- [Engine Revving]
- [Inaudible Dialogue]
- Tom, take care.
[Sal]
Take care, baby.
Lou!
- [Laughs] Yea!
- [Shouting]
[Laughing]
- Listen. I'll see you at Pop's tonight, huh?
- Okay, babe. Take care, huh?
- [Radio Chatter]
- [Tires Screech]
[Radio Chatter Continues]
- [Tires Screeching]
- [Sirens Wailing]
- [Chattering]
- We made a good strike, huh?
[Tires Screeching]
What happened with Sal?
What's the matter with him?
They got the bridge blocked off!
[Shouting]
[Sirens Approaching]
Let me in! Open the door.
[Sirens Wailing Loudly]
This is the police!
You're surrounded!
Come out with your hands up!
This is the police! You're surrounded!
[Door Bangs]
[Door Hinges Creaking]
[Gunshots]
Bring out the gas!
Hold your fire!
[Gunshots Continue]
Stop!
- [Rifle Cocks]
- Stop!
We're coming out! Hold your fire!
- Drop the guns!
- [Coughing]
Over here! Move it. Let's go!
[Cloudy]
Popeye?
It's me! It's me!
Frog One is in that room.
Drop it!
Mulderig.
- You shot Mulderig.
- [Panting]
The son of a bitch is here.
I saw him. I'm gonna get him.
[Gunshot]