The hills are alive
With the sound of music
With songs they have sung
For a thousand years
The hills fill my heart
With the sound of music
My heart wants to sing
Every song it hears
My heart wants to beat like the wings
Of the birds that rise
From the lake to the trees
My heart wants to sigh
Like a chime that flies
From a church on a breeze
To laugh like a brook
When it trips and falls
Over stones on its way
To sing through the night
Like a lark who is learning to pray
I go to the hills
When my heart is lonely
I know I will hear
What I've heard before
My heart will be blessed
With the sound of music
And I'll sing
Once more
[CHURCH BELLS RINGING ]
Oh. . . .
[NUNS SINGING IN LATIN]
Hallelujah, hallelujah
-Reverend Mother.
-Sister Bernice.
-I simpIy cannot find her.
-Maria?
She's missing again.
We shouId've put a cowbeII
around her neck.
Have you tried the barn? You know
how much she adores the animaIs.
I have Iooked everywhere.
In aII of the usuaI pIaces.
Sister, considering it's Maria. . .
. . .I suggest you Iook in somepIace
unusuaI.
WeII, Reverend Mother. . .
. . .I hope this new infraction ends
whatever doubts. . .
. . .you may stiII have
about Maria's future here.
I aIways try to keep faith
in my doubts, Sister Berthe.
After aII, the wooI of a bIack sheep
is just as warm.
We are not taIking about sheep,
bIack or white, Sister Margaretta.
Of aII the candidates for
the novitiate, Maria is the Ieast--
ChiIdren, chiIdren.
We were specuIating about
the quaIifications of our postuIants.
The Mistress of Novices
and the Mistress of PostuIants. . .
. . .were trying to heIp me
by expressing opposite points of view.
TeII me, Sister Catherine,
what do you think of Maria?
She's a wonderfuI girI,
some of the time.
-Sister Agatha?
-It's very easy to Iike Maria. . .
. . .except when it's difficuIt.
-And you, Sister Sophia?
-Oh, I Iove her very dearIy.
But she aIways seems to be
in troubIe, doesn't she?
ExactIy what I say.
She climbs a tree and scrapes her knee
Her dress has got a tear
She waltzes on her way to Mass
And whistles on the stair
And underneath her wimple
She has curlers in her hair
I've even heard her singing
In the abbey
She's always late for chapel
But her penitence is real
She's always late for everything
Except for every meal
I hate to have to say it
But I very firmly feel
Maria 's not an asset to the abbey
I'd like to say a word in her behalf
Say it, Sister Margaretta.
Maria makes me laugh
How do you solve a problem like Maria?
How do you catch a cloud
And pin it down?
How do you find a word
That means Maria?
A flibbertigibbet
-A will-o '-the-wisp
-A clown
Many a thing you know
You'd like to tell her
Many a thing she ought to understand
But how do you make her stay
And listen to all you say?
How do you keep a wave
Upon the sand?
How do you solve a problem like Maria?
How do you hold a moonbeam
In your hand?
When I'm with her I'm confused
Out of focus and bemused
And I never know exactly where I am
-Unpredictable as weather
-She's as flighty as a feather
-She's a darling
-She's a demon
She's a lamb
She'll out pester any pest
Drive a hornet from its nest
She can throw a whirling dervish
Out of whirl
-She is gentle, she is wild
-She's a riddle, she's a child
-She's a headache
-She's an angel
She's a girl
How do you solve a problem like Maria?
How do you catch a cloud
And pin it down?
How do you find a word
That means Maria?
-A flibbertigibbet
-A will-o '-the-wisp
A clown
Many a thing you know
You'd like to tell her
Many a thing she ought to understand
-But how do you make her stay?
-And listen to all you say?
How do you keep a wave
Upon the sand?
How do you solve a problem like Maria?
[DOOR SLAMS]
How do you hold a moonbeam
In your hand?
You may go in now, Maria.
Come here, my chiId.
Now sit down.
Reverend Mother, I'm sorry.
I couIdn't heIp myseIf.
-The hiIIs were beckoning and before--
-Dear.
I haven't summoned you for apoIogies.
PIease Iet me ask for forgiveness.
If you'II feeI better.
Yes, you see,
the sky was so bIue today. . .
. . .and everything was so green and
fragrant, I had to be a part of it.
The Untersberg Ied me higher Iike
it wanted me to go through the cIouds.
Suppose darkness had come
and you were Iost?
Mother, I couId never be Iost
up there.
That's my mountain.
I was brought up on it.
It was the mountain that Ied me
to you.
Oh?
When I was a chiId,
I wouId come down and cIimb a tree. . .
. . .and Iook in your garden.
I'd see the sisters at work
and hear them sing.
Which brings me to another
transgression, Reverend Mother.
I was singing out there today.
OnIy in the abbey do we have ruIes
about postuIants singing.
I can't stop wherever I am.
Worse, I can't seem to stop
saying things.
Everything I think and feeI.
Some caII that ''honesty. ''
Oh, but it's terribIe,
Reverend Mother!
You know how Sister Berthe makes me
kiss the fIoor after a disagreement?
LateIy, I kiss the fIoor when
I see her coming, just to save time.
Maria. . .
. . .when you saw us over the waII
and Ionged to be with us. . .
. . .that didn't mean you were prepared
for the way we Iive here, did it?
No, Mother, but I pray and I try.
And I am Iearning. I reaIIy am.
What is the most important Iesson
you have Iearned here?
To find out what is the wiII of God
and do it whoIeheartedIy.
Maria. . .
. . .it seems to be God's wiII
that you Ieave us.
-Leave?
-OnIy for a whiIe.
No, Mother!
PIease don't send me away!
This is where I beIong. It's my home,
my famiIy. It's my Iife.
-Are you truIy ready for it?
-Yes, I am.
If you go out into the worId for a time,
knowing what we expect of you. . .
. . .you wiII find out
if you can expect it of yourseIf.
I know what you expect, Mother,
and I can do it! I promise I can!
Maria.
Yes, Mother.
If it is God's wiII.
There is a famiIy near SaIzburg that
needs a governess untiI September.
-September?
-For seven chiIdren.
Seven chiIdren?!
Do you Iike chiIdren?
WeII, yes, but seven!
I wiII teII Captain von Trapp
to expect you tomorrow.
Captain?
A retired officer of the ImperiaI Navy.
A fine man and a brave one.
His wife died,
and he is aIone with the chiIdren.
I understand he has had a difficuIt
time keeping a governess there.
Why difficuIt, Reverend Mother?
The Lord wiII show you
in his own good time.
When the Lord cIoses a door. . .
. . .somewhere he opens a window.
What will this day be like?
I wonder
What will my future be?
It could be so exciting
To be out in the world
To be free
My heart should be wildly rejoicing
Oh, what's the matter with me?
I've always longed for adventure
To do the things I've never dared
Now here I'm facing adventure
Then why am I so scared?
A captain with seven children
What's so fearsome about that?
I must stop these doubts
All these worries
If I don 't, I just know I'll turn back
I must dream of the things
I am seeking
I am seeking the courage I lack
The courage to serve them
With reliance
Face my mistakes without defiance
Show them I'm worthy
And while I show them
I'll show me
So let them bring on
All their problems
I'll do better than my best
I have confidence
They'll put me to the test
But I'll make them see
I have confidence in me
Somehow, I will impress them
I will be firm but kind
And all those children
Heaven bless them
They will look up to me
And mind me
With each step, I am more certain
Everything will turn out fine
I have confidence
The world can all be mine
They'll have to agree
I have confidence in me
I have confidence in sunshine
I have confidence in rain
I have confidence
That spring will come again
Besides which you see
I have confidence in me
Strength doesn 't lie in numbers
Strength doesn 't lie in wealth
Strength lies in nights
Of peaceful slumbers
When you wake up, wake up
It's healthy
All I trust I leave my heart to
All I trust becomes my own
I have confidence in confidence alone
Oh, heIp.
Besides which you see
I have confidence
In me
Oh. Whoo.
HeIIo. Here I am.
I'm from the convent.
I'm the new governess, captain.
And I'm the oId butIer, fräuIein.
Oh.
WeII, how do you do?
You'II wait here, pIease.
[DOORS OPEN]
In the future, remember certain rooms
in this house are not to be disturbed.
Yes, captain, sir.
-Why do you stare at me that way?
-You don't Iook Iike a sea captain.
I'm afraid you don't Iook
very much Iike a governess.
-Turn around.
-What?
Turn.
Hat off.
Put on another dress
before meeting the chiIdren.
But I don't have another.
When we enter the abbey,
our worIdIy cIothes go to the poor.
What about this one?
The poor didn't want it.
Hmm.
There wasn't time to make a new dress.
I can make cIothes.
I'II see that you get some materiaI.
Today, if possibIe.
-Now, fräuIein. . . .
-Maria.
I don't know how much
the abbess toId you.
-Not much.
-You are the tweIfth governess. . .
. . .to Iook after my chiIdren
since their mother died.
I trust you wiII be an improvement
on the Iast one.
She stayed onIy two hours.
What's wrong with the chiIdren, sir?
Nothing is wrong with the chiIdren,
onIy the governesses.
They couId not maintain discipIine,
without which the house cannot be run.
-Yes, sir.
-DriII them in their studies.
I wiII not permit them to dream
away their summer hoIidays.
Each afternoon,
they march, breathing deepIy.
Bedtime is to be strictIy observed.
When do they pIay?
You wiII see to it that they conduct
themseIves with the utmost decorum.
-I am pIacing you in command.
-Yes, sir.
[BLOWS WHISTLE]
[THUDDING ]
VON TRAPP:
Now. . .
. . .this is your new governess,
FräuIein Maria.
Give your name at your signaI.
FräuIein, Iisten carefuIIy. Learn
their signaIs so you can caII them.
LiesI.
Friedrich.
Louisa.
Kurt.
Brigitta.
Marta.
GretI.
Now, Iet's see how weII you Iistened.
I won't need to whistIe for them,
Reverend Captain.
I mean, I'II use their names.
Such IoveIy names.
VON TRAPP: FräuIein, this is a
Iarge house. The grounds are extensive.
And I wiII not have anyone shouting.
You wiII take this, pIease.
Learn to use it.
The chiIdren wiII heIp you.
Now, when I want you,
this is what you wiII hear.
Oh, no, sir. I'm sorry, sir!
I couId never answer to a whistIe.
WhistIes are for animaIs,
not for chiIdren.
And definiteIy not for me.
It wouId be too humiIiating.
FräuIein, were you this much troubIe
at the abbey?
Oh, much more, sir.
Mmm.
I don't know your signaI.
You may caII me ''captain. ''
[GIGGLING ]
At ease.
Now that there's just us. . .
. . .wouId you pIease teII me aII your
names again and how oId you are.
I'm LiesI. I'm 1 6 years oId,
and I don't need a governess.
I'm gIad you toId me, LiesI.
We'II just be good friends.
I'm Friedrich. I'm 1 4.
I'm impossibIe.
ReaIIy? Who toId you that, Friedrich?
FräuIein Josephine.
Four governesses ago.
I'm Brigitta.
You didn't teII me how oId you are,
Louisa.
I'm Brigitta. She's Louisa.
She's 1 3 years oId, and you're smart.
I'm 1 0, and I think your dress
is the ugIiest one I ever saw.
-Brigitta, you shouIdn't say that.
-Why not?
-Don't you think it's ugIy?
-Of course.
But FräuIein HeIga's was ugIiest.
I'm Kurt. I'm 1 1 .
I'm incorrigibIe.
-CongratuIations.
-What's ''incorrigibIe''?
I think it means you want
to be treated Iike a boy.
Mm-hmm?
I'm Marta, and I'm going to be
7 on Tuesday.
I'd Iike a pink parasoI.
Pink's my favorite coIor too.
Yes, you're GretI.
And you're 5 years oId?
My, you're practicaIIy a Iady.
I have to teII you a secret.
I've never been a governess.
You don't know anything
about being a governess?
Nothing. I'II need Iots of advice.
The best way to start is to teII
Father to mind his own business.
Never come to dinner on time.
Never eat your soup quietIy.
[SLURPING ]
During dessert,
aIways bIow your nose.
Don't you beIieve a word they say,
FräuIein Maria.
-Oh, why not?
-Because I Iike you.
[CLAPPING ]
ChiIdren, outside for your waIk.
Father's orders. Hurry up.
Quick, quick, quick.
FräuIein Maria, I'm Frau Schmidt,
the housekeeper.
How do you do.
I'II show you to your room.
FoIIow me.
MARIA:
Poor IittIe dears.
[SCREAMING ]
You're very Iucky.
With FräuIein HeIga it was a snake.
MARIA:
Good evening.
-Good evening, chiIdren.
-Good evening, FräuIein Maria.
[SHOUTING ]
Enchanting IittIe rituaI.
Something you Iearned at the abbey?
No.
Rheumatism.
Excuse me, captain.
Haven't we forgotten to thank the Lord?
For what we receive,
may the Lord make us truIy thankfuI.
-Amen.
CHILDREN: Amen.
I'd Iike to thank you aII. . .
. . .for the precious gift
you Ieft in my pocket today.
Um, what gift?
It's a secret between
the chiIdren and me.
Then I suggest you keep it,
and Iet us eat.
Knowing how nervous
I must have been. . .
. . .a stranger in a new househoId. . .
. . .knowing how important it was
for me to feeI accepted. . .
. . .it was so kind and thoughtfuI of
you to make my first moments here. . .
. . .so warm and happy. . .
. . .and pIeasant.
[CRYING ]
-What is the matter, Marta?
-Nothing.
[CRYING ]
FräuIein. . .
. . .is it to be at every meaI
or mereIy at dinnertime. . .
. . .that you intend Ieading us through
this rare and wonderfuI new worId. . .
. . .of indigestion?
They're aII right, captain.
They're just happy.
-RoIfe, good evening.
-Good evening, Franz.
-I trust everything is under controI?
-Yes, yes.
Good.
-Are there any deveIopments?
-Perhaps.
-Is the captain home?
-He's at dinner.
-With the famiIy?
-Yes.
Give him this teIegram at once.
CertainIy.
-A teIegram for you, sir.
-Mmm.
Franz? Who deIivered it?
That young Iad RoIfe, of course.
-Father, may I be excused?
VON TRAPP: Hmm.
ChiIdren, in the morning
I shaII be going to Vienna.
Not again, Father!
How Iong wiII you be gone this time?
I'm not sure, GretI.
LOUISA:
To visit Baroness Schraeder?
Mind your own business!
As a matter of fact, yes, Louisa.
-Why can't we ever see the baroness?
KURT: Why wouId she want to see you?
You are going to see the baroness.
I'm bringing her back with me to visit.
CHILDREN:
Good.
And UncIe Max.
UncIe Max!
LIESL:
RoIfe!
Oh, RoIfe!
-No, LiesI. We mustn't!
-Why not, siIIy?
-I don't know--
-Isn't this why you're waiting?
Yes, of course.
-I've missed you, LiesI.
-You have? How much?
I even thought of sending a teIegram,
so I'd be abIe to deIiver it here.
Oh, that's a IoveIy thought!
Why don't you, right now?
-But I'm here!
-PIease, RoIfe. Send me a teIegram.
I'II start it for you.
''Dear LiesI. . . . ''
''Dear LiesI: I'd Iike to be abIe
to teII you. . .
. . .how I feeI about you. Stop.
UnfortunateIy, this wire
is aIready too expensive.
SincereIy, RoIfe. ''
-''SincereIy''?
-CordiaIIy.
-''CordiaIIy''?
-AffectionateIy?
Mmm.
ROLFE:
WiII there be any repIy?
''Dear RoIfe: Stop.
Don't stop! Your LiesI. ''
If onIy we didn't have to wait
for someone to send Father a teIegram.
How do I know when I'II see you again?
WeII, Iet's see. . . .
I couId come here by mistake.
With a teIegram for CoIoneI Schneider!
He's here from BerIin staying with--
No one knows he's here.
Don't teII your father.
-Why not?
-Your father's so Austrian.
We're aII Austrian.
Some think we ought to be German,
and they're very mad at those who don't.
They're getting ready to--
Let's hope your father
doesn't get into troubIe.
Don't worry. He's a big navaI hero.
He was even decorated by the emperor.
I know. I don't worry about him.
I worry about his daughter.
Me? Why?
-WeII, you're so--
-What?
-You're such a baby!
-I'm 1 6. What's such a baby about that?
You wait, little girl
On an empty stage
For fate to turn the light on
Your life, little girl
Is an empty page
That men will want to write on
To write on
You are 1 6 going on 1 7
Baby, it's time to think
Better beware
Be canny and careful
Baby, you're on the brink
You are 1 6 going on 1 7
Fellows will fall in line
Eager young lads
And roués and cads
Will offer you food and wine
Totally unprepared are you
To face a world of men
Timid and shy and scared are you
Of things beyond your ken
You need someone older and wiser
Telling you what to do
I am 1 7 going on 1 8
I'll take care of you
[THUNDER RUMBLING ]
I am 1 6 going on 1 7
I know that I'm naive
Fellows I meet
May tell me I'm sweet
And willingly I believe
I am 1 6 going on 1 7
Innocent as a rose
Bachelor dandies
Drinkers of brandies
What do I know of those?
Totally unprepared am I
To face a world of men
Timid and shy and scared am I
Of things beyond my ken
I need someone older and wiser
Telling me what to do
You are 1 7 going on 1 8
I'll depend on you
Whee!
[KNOCKING ]
Come in.
Frau Schmidt.
For your new dresses.
-The captain had these sent from town.
-Oh, how IoveIy!
These wiII make the prettiest
cIothes I've ever had.
Do you think he wouId
get me more materiaI if I asked?
-How many dresses do you need?
-Not for me, for the chiIdren.
I want to make them
some pIay cIothes.
The von Trapp chiIdren don't pIay.
They march.
SureIy you don't approve of that.
Ever since the captain
Iost his poor wife. . .
. . .he runs this house as if on
one of his ships.
WhistIes, orders.
No more music, no more Iaughing.
Nothing that reminds him of her.
Even the chiIdren.
But that's so wrong.
Oh, weII.
How do you Iike your room?
There'II be new drapes at the windows.
But these are fine.
New ones have been ordered.
-But I reaIIy don't need them.
-Good night, now.
Frau Schmidt, if I asked the captain
tomorrow about the materiaI. . .?
-He's Ieaving in the morning.
-Of course. How Iong wiII he be gone?
It depends. The Iast time he visited
the baroness, he stayed for a month.
Oh.
I shouIdn't be saying this to you.
I don't know you that weII.
But if you ask me,
the captain's thinking seriousIy. . .
. . .of marrying her before
summer's over.
WonderfuI! The chiIdren wiII
have a mother again.
Yes.
WeII, good night.
Good night.
Dear Father, now I know
why you sent me here.
To heIp these chiIdren
prepare for a new mother.
And I pray this wiII become
a happy famiIy in thy sight.
God bIess the captain.
God bIess LiesI and Friedrich.
God bIess Louisa, Brigitta,
Marta and IittIe GretI.
And I forgot the other boy.
What's his name?
WeII, God bIess what's-his-name.
God bIess the Reverend Mother
and Sister Margaretta. . .
. . .and everybody at the abbey.
And now, dear God, about LiesI.
HeIp her know that I'm her friend. . .
. . .and heIp her teII me
what she's been up to.
-Are you going to teII on me?
-Shh.
HeIp me to be understanding
so I may guide her footsteps.
In the name of the Father,
the Son and the HoIy Ghost.
I was out waIking and somebody
Iocked the doors earIy.
I didn't want to wake everybody,
so when I saw your window open. . . .
You're not going to teII Father,
are you?
Hmm.
How did you cIimb up?
It's how we aIways got in
to pIay tricks on the governess.
Louisa can make it with
a whoIe jar of spiders in her hand.
[WINDOW SLAMS]
Spiders?
Oh. LiesI, were you out waIking
aII by yourseIf?
If we wash that dress tonight,
nobody wouId notice it tomorrow.
You couId put this on.
Take your dress and put it
to soak in the bathtub.
Come back here and sit on the bed,
and we'II have a taIk.
I toId you today
I didn't need a governess.
WeII, maybe I do.
[THUNDER CRASHING ]
GretI, are you scared?
You're not frightened
of a storm, are you?
You just stay right here with me. Oh.
-Where are the others?
-They're asIeep. They're not scared.
Oh, no? Look.
AII right, up here on the bed.
-ReaIIy?
-WeII, just this once. Come on.
-Now we'II wait for the boys.
-You won't see them. Boys are brave.
You weren't scared, were you?
Oh, no. We just wanted
to be sure that you weren't.
-That's very thoughtfuI of you.
FRIEDRICH: It wasn't my idea.
It was Kurt's!
Kurt! That's the one I Ieft out!
God bIess Kurt.
Why does it do that?
The Iightning taIks to the thunder,
and the thunder answers.
-But Iightning must be nasty.
-Not reaIIy.
Why does the thunder get so angry?
It makes me want to cry.
Whenever I'm feeIing unhappy,
I just try to think of nice things.
What kind of things?
WeII, Iet me see. Nice things. . . .
DaffodiIs.
Green meadows.
Skies fuII of stars.
Raindrops on roses
And whiskers on kittens
Bright copper kettles
And warm woolen mittens
Brown paper packages
Tied up with strings
These are a few of my favorite things
Cream-colored ponies
And crisp apple strudels
Doorbells and sleigh bells
And schnitzel with noodles
Wild geese that fly
With the moon on their wings
These are a few of my favorite things
Girls in white dresses
With blue satin sashes
Snowflakes that stay
On my nose and eyelashes
Silver white winters
That melt into springs
These are a few of my favorite things
When the dog bites
When the bee stings
When I'm feeling sad
I simply remember my favorite things
And then I don 't feel so bad
-Does it work?
-Of course.
-What do you Iike?
-Pussy wiIIow!
-Christmas!
-Bunny rabbits!
KURT:
Snakes!
-ChocoIate icing!
-No schooI!
KURT:
PiIIow fights!
-TeIegrams!
-Birthday presents!
-Any presents!
GRETL: Ladybugs!
KURT:
A good sneeze!
Gesundheit!
See what fun it is?
Raindrops on roses
And whiskers on kittens
Bright copper kettles
And warm woolen mittens
Brown paper packages
Tied up with strings
These are a few of my favorite things
Cream-colored ponies
And crisp apple strudels
Doorbells and sleigh bells
And schnitzel with noodles
Wild geese that fly
With the moon on their wings
These are a few of my favorite things
Together.
Girls in white dresses
With blue satin sashes
Snowflakes that stay
On my nose and eyelashes
Silver white winters
That melt into springs
These are a few of my favorite things
When the dog bi--
Dog bites.
HeIIo.
FräuIein, did I not teII you that
bedtime is to be strictIy observed?
The chiIdren were upset
by the storm, so I--
You did, sir.
Do you, or do you not, have difficuIty
remembering such simpIe instructions?
OnIy during thunderstorms.
[GIGGLING ]
-LiesI?
-Yes, Father?
I don't recaII seeing you
after dinner.
ReaIIy? As a matter of fact--
Yes?
WeII, I was--
What she wouId Iike to say. . .
. . .is that she and I have
been getting acquainted tonight.
It's too Iate to go into that.
You heard your father. Go back to bed.
VON TRAPP:
FräuIein. . .
. . .you have managed to remember
I'm Ieaving in the morning?
Is it aIso possibIe you remember the
first ruIe in this house is discipIine?
Then I trust that before I return. . .
. . .you'II have acquired some?
Captain?
CouId I taIk to you about cIothes
for the chiIdren for when they pIay?
-If I couId have some materiaI.
-You are many things.
Not the Ieast of which is repetitious.
-But they're chiIdren!
-Yes.
And I'm their father.
Good night.
Girls in white dresses
With blue satin sashes
When the dog bites
When the bee stings
When I'm feeling sad
I simply remember my favorite things
And then I don 't feel
So bad
[CHILDREN LAUGHING ]
ChiIdren, over here. See!
MARIA:
Come on.
Ho.
LOUISA: FräuIein Maria?
MARIA: Mm-hmm?
LOUISA:
Can we do this every day?
-Don't you think you'd get tired of it?
-I suppose so.
Every other day?
I haven't had so much fun since we put
gIue on FräuIein Josephine's toothbrush.
I can't understand how chiIdren
as nice as you can pIay such tricks.
BRIGITTA: It's easy.
-But why do it?
How eIse can we get
Father's attention?
-Yes.
-Oh, I see.
We'II have to think about that one.
AII right, over here.
MARTA:
What are we going to do?
MARIA:
Think of a song for the baroness.
MARTA:
Father doesn't Iike us to sing.
Perhaps we can change his mind.
Now, what songs do you know?
FRIEDRICH:
We don't know any songs.
-Not any?
-We don't know how to sing.
LOUISA:
No.
Let's not Iose time. You must Iearn.
GRETL:
But how?
Let's start at the very beginning
A very good place to start
When you read you begin with
A, B, C
When you sing, you begin with
Do-re-mi
The first three notes
Just happen to be
Do-re-mi
Do-re-mi-fa-so-la-ti
Let's see if I can make it easier.
''Doe, '' a deer
A female deer
''Ray, '' a drop of golden sun
''Me, '' a name I call myself
''Far, '' a long, long way to run
''Sew, '' a needle pulling thread
''La, '' a note to follow sew
''Tea, '' a drink with jam and bread
That will bring us back to doe
Oh, oh, oh
-Doe!
-A deer, a female deer
-Ray!
-A drop of golden sun
-Me!
-A name I call myself
-Far!
-A long, long way to run
Sew, a needle pulling thread
-La!
-A note to follow sew
-Tea
-A drink with jam and bread
That will bring us back to
-Doe
-A deer, a female deer
Ray, a drop of golden sun
Me, a name I call myself
Far, a long, long way to run
Sew, a needle pulling thread
La, a note to follow sew
Tea, a drink with jam and bread
That will bring us back to doe
Do-re-mi-fa-so-la-ti-do, so-do
Do-re-mi-fa-so and so on are onIy
the tooIs we use to buiId a song.
Once you have them in your head
you can sing different tunes. . .
. . .by mixing them up. Like this:
So-do-la-fa-mi-do-re
Can you do that?
So-do-la-ti-do-re-do
Now, put it aII together.
So-do-la-fa-mi-do-re
So-do-la-ti-do-re-do
-Good.
-But it doesn't mean anything.
So we put in words.
One word for every note.
Like this:
When you know the notes to sing
You can sing most anything
Together!
When you know the notes to sing
You can sing most anything
-Doe
-A deer, a female deer
-Ray
-A drop of golden sun
-Me
-A name I call myself
-Far
-A long long way to run
-Sew
-A needle pulling thread
-La
-A note to follow sew
-Tea
-A drink with jam and bread
That will bring us back to doe
-Do, do
-Mi, mi
-Mi
-So, so
-Re
-Fa, fa
-La
-Ti, ti
-Do
-Mi, mi
-Mi
-So, so
-Re
-Fa, fa
-La
-Ti, ti
When you know the notes to sing
You can sing most anything
Doe!
A deer, a female deer
Ray!
A drop of golden sun
Me!
A name I call myself
Far!
A long long way to run
Sew!
A needle pulling thread
La!
A note to follow sew
Tea!
A drink with jam and bread
That will bring us back to
So-do-la-fa-mi-do-re
So-do-la-fa-ti
La-so
Fa
Mi-re
Ti-do
So-do!
The mountains are magnificent,
reaIIy magnificent.
-I had them put up just for you.
-Oh?
Even if it's to a height
of 1 0,000 feet. . .
. . .Georg aIways beIieves in
''rising to the occasion. ''
UnIess the jokes improve,
I'm taking back my invitation.
You didn't invite me.
I invited myseIf.
-NaturaIIy.
-You needed a chaperone. . .
. . .and I needed a pIace
where the cuisine is superb. . .
. . .the wine ceIIar unexceIIed. . .
. . .and the price perfect.
Max, you are outrageous.
Not at aII.
I'm a very charming sponge.
[CHOIR SINGING ]
Listen.
VON TRAPP:
That's the KIopmann Monastery Choir.
They're good.
Very good.
I must expIore this area
in the next few days.
Somewhere, a hungry singing group
is waiting for Max DetweiIer. . .
. . .to pIuck it out and make it famous
at the SaIzburg FoIk FestivaI.
-They get fame, you get money.
-It's unfair, I admit it.
But someday that'II be changed.
I shaII get the fame too.
[LAUGHING ]
[CHILDREN LAUGHING ]
[CHILDREN CHATTERING ]
BARONESS:
Good heavens, what's this?
It's nothing.
Just some IocaI urchins.
This reaIIy is exciting for me, Georg.
Being here with you.
Oh. . . . Trees, Iakes,
you've seen them before.
That is not what I mean,
and you know it.
-You mean me? I'm exciting?
-Is that so impossibIe?
No, just highIy improbabIe.
-There you go, running yourseIf down.
-WeII, I'm a dangerous driver.
[LAUGHING ]
You're much Iess of a riddIe
when I see you here, Georg.
-In my naturaI habitat?
-Yes, exactIy.
Are you saying that I'm more
at home. . .
. . .among the birds and the fIowers
and the wind that moves. . .
. . .through the trees
Iike a restIess sea?
How poetic.
Yes, it was rather, wasn't it?
More at home here than in Vienna
in aII your gIittering saIons. . .
. . .gossiping gaiIy with bores I detest,
soaking myseIf in champagne. . .
. . .stumbIing about to waItzes
by Strausses I can't even remember?
-Is that what you're saying?
-Yes.
Now whatever gave you that idea?
Oh, I do Iike it here, Georg.
It's so IoveIy and peacefuI.
How can you Ieave it so often?
Oh, pretending to be madIy active,
I suppose.
Activity suggests a Iife
fiIIed with purpose.
CouId it be running away
from memories?
Mm-hmm.
Or perhaps just searching
for a reason to stay.
I hope that's why you've been
coming to Vienna so often.
-Were there other distractions?
-I'd hardIy caII you a distraction.
WeII, what wouId you caII me, Georg?
Mmm. . . .
LoveIy. . .
. . .charming, witty, gracefuI,
the perfect hostess. . .
. . .and, you're going to hate me
for this. . .
. . .in a way, my savior.
Oh, how unromantic.
I'd be an ungratefuI wretch
if I didn't say. . .
. . .that you brought some meaning back
into my Iife.
I am amusing, I suppose.
I have the finest couturier in Vienna
and a gIittering circIe of friends.
-I do give some rather gay parties.
-Oh, yes.
But take aII that away. . .
. . .and you have just weaIthy,
unattached IittIe me. . .
. . .searching, just Iike you.
[VON TRAPP CHUCKLING ]
More strudeI, Herr DetweiIer?
-How many have I had?
-Two.
Make it an uneven three.
StiII eating, Max?
Must be unhappy.
That mixed quartet I've been trying
to steaI away from SoI Hurok.
-What happened?
-Sascha Petrie stoIe them first.
I hate thieves.
Max, you reaIIy must try
and Iearn to Iove yourseIf.
I had to caII Paris, Rome
and StockhoIm.
-On Georg's teIephone, of course.
-How eIse couId I afford it?
I Iike rich peopIe, the way they Iive
and how I Iive when I'm with them.
I wonder where the chiIdren are.
They must have heard
I was coming and hid.
I was hoping they'd be here
to weIcome you.
Max, do step out of character for
a moment and try and be charming.
WeII?
WeII what?
Have you made up his mind?
Do I hear wedding beIIs?
-PeaIing madIy.
-MarveIous.
-Not necessariIy for me.
-What kind of taIk's that?
None-of-your-business taIk.
I'm terribIy fond of him,
so don't toy with us.
But I'm a chiId. I Iike toys.
So teII me everything.
Come on. TeII me every teensy-weensy,
intimate, disgusting detaiI.
WeII, Iet's just say I have a feeIing
I may be here on approvaI.
-I approve of that. How can you miss?
-Far too easiIy.
If I know you, darIing,
and I do, you wiII find a way.
-He's no ordinary man.
-No, he's rich.
His wife's death gave him
a great heartache.
And your husband's death
gave you a great fortune.
Oh, Max, you reaIIy are a beast.
You and Georg are Iike famiIy.
That's why I want to see you married.
We must keep aII that IoveIy money
in the famiIy.
VON TRAPP: What are you doing there?
-Oh, Captain von Trapp.
I was just Iooking for. . . .
I didn't see, I mean,
I didn't know you were--
HeiI HitIer!
Who are you?
I have a teIegram for Herr DetweiIer.
-I am Herr DetweiIer.
ROLFE: Yes, sir.
You've deIivered your teIegram.
Now get out.
-Georg, he's just a boy.
-Yes, and I'm just an Austrian.
Things wiII happen.
Make sure they don't happen to you.
Max! Don't you ever say that again.
I have no poIiticaI convictions.
-Can I heIp it if other peopIe do?
-You can heIp it.
You must heIp it.
HeIIo?
You're far away. Where are you?
In a worId that's disappearing,
I'm afraid.
Is there any way I couId bring you
back to the worId I'm in?
[CHATTERING AND SINGING ]
-Father! Father!
-There's your father!
Oh, captain, you're home!
[SCREAMING ]
Come out of that water at once!
[LAUGHING ]
Oh, you must be Baroness Schraeder.
I'm soaked to the skin!
Straight Iine!
This is Baroness Schraeder.
And these. . .
. . .are my chiIdren.
How do you do?
Go inside, dry off, cIean up, change
your cIothes and report back here!
FräuIein, you wiII stay here, pIease!
I think I'd better go see
what Max is up to.
Now, fräuIein. . .
. . .I want a truthfuI answer.
Yes, captain.
Is it possibIe,
or couId I have just imagined it?
Have my chiIdren, by any chance,
been cIimbing trees today?
Yes, captain.
I see.
And where, may I ask,
did they get these. . .?
-PIay cIothes.
-Is that what they are?
I made them from the drapes
that used to hang in my bedroom.
-Drapes?
-They have pIenty of wear Ieft.
We've been everywhere in them.
Are you teIIing me that my chiIdren
have been roaming about SaIzburg. . .
. . .dressed up in nothing
but some oId drapes?
And having a marveIous time!
-They have uniforms.
-Forgive me, straitjackets.
I wiII not forgive you.
They can't be chiIdren
if they worry about cIothes--
VON TRAPP:
They don't compIain.
They don't dare.
They Iove you too much and fear--
Don't discuss my chiIdren.
You've got to hear,
you're never home--
I don't want to hear more!
I know you don't, but you've got to!
-LiesI's not a chiId.
-Not one word--
Soon she'II be a woman
and you won't even know her.
Friedrich wants to be a man
but you're not here to show--
Don't you dare teII me--
Brigitta couId teII you about him.
She notices everything.
Kurt acts tough to hide the pain
when you ignore him. . .
. . .the way you do aII of them.
Louisa, I don't know about yet.
The IittIe ones just want Iove.
PIease, Iove them aII.
I don't care to hear more.
-I am not finished yet, captain!
-Oh, yes, you are, captain!
FräuIein.
You wiII pack
your things this minute. . .
. . .and return to the abbey.
[CHILDREN SINGING ]
What's that?
It's singing.
Yes, I reaIize it's singing.
But who is singing?
The chiIdren.
The chiIdren?
I taught them something to sing
for the baroness.
My heart wants to sing
Every song it hears
Every song that it hears
My heart wants to beat like the wings
Of the birds that rise
From the lake to the trees
To the trees
My heart wants to sigh
Like a chime that flies
From a church on a breeze
To laugh like a brook
When it trips and falls
Over stones on its way
On its way
To sing through the night
Like a lark who is learning to pray
I go to the hills
When my heart is lonely
I know I will hear
What I've heard before
My heart will be blessed
With the sound of music
And I'll sing
Once more
EdeIweiss!
Oh.
You never toId me how enchanting
your chiIdren are.
Don't go away.
FräuIein.
I. . .
. . .behaved badIy. I apoIogize.
I'm far too outspoken.
It's one of my worst fauIts.
You were right.
I don't know my chiIdren.
There's stiII time, captain.
They want so much to be cIose to you.
And you brought music back
into the house.
I'd forgotten.
FräuIein.
I want you to stay.
I ask you to stay.
-If I couId be of any heIp.
-You have aIready.
More than you know.
[MUSIC PLAYING ]
MARIA:
Marta.
Curtain!
High on a hill was a lonely goatherd
Lay odl lay odl lay hee hoo
Loud was the voice
Of the lonely goatherd
Lay odl lay odl loo
Folks in a town
That was quite remote heard
Lay odl lay odl lay hee hoo
Lusty and clear
From the goatherd's throat heard
Lay odl lay odl loo
Ho ho lady odlee ho
Ho ho lady odl lay
Ho ho lady odl lee ho
Lady odl lee ho lay
Marta. Marta!
GretI, the prince!
A prince on the bridge
Of a castle moat heard
Lay odl lay odl lay hee hoo
Men on a road
With a load to tote heard
Lay odl lay odl loo
Men in the midst
Of a table d'höte heard
Lay odl lay odl lay hee hoo
Men drinking beer
With the foam afloat heard
Lay odl lay odl loo
[COUGHING ]
One little girl
In a pale pink coat heard
Lay odl lay odl lay hee hoo
She yodeled back
To the lonely goatherd
Lay odl lay odl loo
Soon her mama
With a gleaming gloat heard
Lay odl lay odl lay hee hoo
What a duet for a girl and goatherd
Lay odl lay odl loo
-Hm hm hm hmm
-Hm hm hmm
-Odl lay hee
-Odl lay hee hee
Odl lay hee
Ho ho lady odlee ho
Ho ho lady odl lay
Ho ho lady odl lee ho
Lady odl lee ho lay
One little girl
In a pale pink coat heard
Lady odl lady odl lay woo hoo
She yodeled back
To the lonely goatherd
Lady odl lady odl loo
Soon her mama
With a gleaming gloat heard
Lady odl lady odl lay hm hm
What a duet for a girl and goatherd
Lay odl lay odl loo
Happy are they
Lady ho lady lee ho
Ho lady ho lady lady ho
Soon the duet will become a trio
Lady odl lady odl loo
Odl lay hee
-Odl lay hee
-Odl lay hee hee
-Odl lay odl lay
Odl lay hee odl lay hee odl lay, hoo!
[VON TRAPP LAUGHING ]
-Bravo!
MAX:
Very good!
WonderfuI!
-Can we keep the puppets, UncIe Max?
MARTA: Yes, can we?
MAX:
Of course you may, my darIings.
Why eIse did I teII Professor Kohner
to send the biII to your father?
[CHILDREN CHATTERING ]
VON TRAPP:
WeII done, fräuIein.
I reaIIy am very much impressed.
They're your chiIdren, captain.
My dear, is there anything
you can't do?
WeII, I'm not sure
I'II make a good nun.
If you have any probIems,
I'd be happy to heIp you.
MAX:
Attention, everyone!
I have an announcement to make.
Surprise! Surprise!
Today, after a Iong
and desperate search. . .
. . .I have found a most exciting
entry for the SaIzburg FoIk FestivaI.
CongratuIations, Max.
And who wiII you
be expIoiting this time?
[CHUCKLING ]
-The Saint Ignatius Choir?
-Guess again.
Um. . . . WeII, Iet me see now.
The KIopmann Choir?
-No, no, no, no.
-No, no?
LIESL:
TeII us.
A singing group aII in one famiIy.
You'II never guess, Georg.
What a charming idea!
Whose famiIy?
-Yours.
-Ah.
-They'II be the taIk of the festivaI.
-Mmm.
[CHUCKLING ]
-WeII, now, what's so funny?
-You are, Max.
You're expensive, but very funny.
-They'II be a sensation!
-No, Max.
It's a wonderfuI idea.
Fresh, originaI.
Max! My chiIdren
do not sing in pubIic.
You can't bIame me for trying.
ChiIdren, who shaII we hear
from next?
Who?
Yes.
The vote is unanimous.
You, captain.
Me?
-I don't understand.
-PIease.
No, no, no, no.
I'm toId that you were quite good.
-That was a very, very Iong time ago.
-I remember, Father.
-PIay us something we know.
-Oh, pIease, Father.
WeII. . . .
-Why didn't you teII me?
-What?
To bring aIong my harmonica.
Edelweiss
Every morning you greet me
Small and white
Clean and bright
You look happy
To meet me
Blossom of snow
May you bloom and grow
Bloom and grow forever
Edelweiss
Bless my homeland forever
-Edelweiss
Every morning you greet me
-Small and white
-Clean and bright
You look happy
To meet me
Blossom of snow
May you bloom and grow
Bloom and grow forever
Edelweiss
Bless my homeland forever
Anytime you say the word, Georg,
you can be part of my new act:
The von Trapp FamiIy Singers.
I have a wonderfuI idea, Georg.
Let's reaIIy fiII this house
with music.
You must give a grand
and gIorious party for me.
VON TRAPP: A party?
-Yes, Father, pIease!
It's high time
I met aII your friends. . .
. . .and they met me.
Don't you agree?
-I see what you mean.
CHILDREN: Oh, pIease!
ChiIdren, it's bedtime.
Come now, say good night.
GRETL: Good night.
LOUISA: Good night, Father.
-Good night.
-Good night, Baroness Schraeder.
Good night, Father.
Good night, UncIe Max.
It'II be my first party, Father!
-Captain.
-Herr ZeIIer. Baroness Schraeder.
-Good evening, Herr ZeIIer.
-Baroness.
How do you do? Good evening.
Did you notice the obvious
dispIay of the Austrian fIag?
The women Iook so beautifuI.
I think they Iook ugIy.
You're just scared of them.
SiIIy, onIy grown-up men fear women.
-I think the men Iook beautifuI.
-How wouId you know?
LiesI, who are you dancing with?
Nobody.
Oh, yes, you are.
May I have this dance?
I'd be deIighted, young man.
Why didn't you teII me
you couId dance?
We feared you'd make us aII dance.
The von Trapp FamiIy Dancers.
GRETL:
What are they pIaying?
MARIA: It's the LaendIer.
An Austrian foIk dance.
-Show me.
-I haven't danced since I was IittIe.
You remember. PIease?
-WeII. . . .
-PIease.
AII right. Come on over here.
Now you bow and I curtsy.
-Like this?
-Fine. Now we go for a IittIe waIk.
One, two, three. One, two, three.
One, two, three, step together.
Now, step hop, step hop.
Now turn under. Not quite.
This way. Hop step, hop.
And under.
Kurt, we'II have to practice.
-Do aIIow me, wiII you?
KURT: Mm-hmm.
I don't remember anymore.
-Your face is aII red.
-Is it?
I don't suppose I'm used to dancing.
[CROWD CLAPPING ]
Why, that was beautifuIIy done.
What a IoveIy coupIe you make.
It's time the chiIdren
said good night.
We'II be in the haII.
-We have something speciaI prepared.
-Right!
FRIEDRICH:
Yes, come on!
AII that needIess worrying, Georg.
You thought you wouIdn't find
a friend at the party.
-A bit chiIIy out tonight, isn't it?
-Oh, I don't know.
It seemed rather warm to me.
[VON TRAPP WHISTLING ]
MARIA:
Ladies and gentIemen.
The chiIdren of Captain von Trapp
wish to say good night to you.
[MUSIC PLAYING ]
There's a sad sort of clanging
From the clock in the hall
And the bells in the steeple too
And up in the nursery
An absurd little bird
Is popping out to say ''coo-coo''
Coo-coo
-Regretfully, they tell us
-Coo-coo
-But firmly they compel us
-To say goodbye
-Coo-coo
To you
So long, farewell
Auf Wiedersehen, good night
I hate to go
And leave this pretty sight
So long, farewell
Auf Wiedersehen, adieu
Adieu, adieu
To you and you and you
So long, farewell
Au revoir, auf Wiedersehen
I'd like to stay
And taste my first champagne
-Yes?
-No.
[CROWD LAUGHING ]
So long, farewell
Auf Wiedersehen, goodbye
I leave and heave a sigh
And say goodbye
Goodbye
I'm glad to go
I cannot tell a lie
I flit, I float
I fleetly flee, I fly
The sun has gone to bed
And so must I
So long
Farewell
Auf Wiedersehen, goodbye
Goodbye
Extraordinary!
What they'd do at the festivaI.
Young Iady,
I must have a word with you.
Georg, you won't Iet this girI get away.
She must join the party.
-No, reaIIy I--
-Stop. Stop it now.
-Georg, pIease.
-You can if you want to, fräuIein.
I insist.
You wiII be my dinner partner.
This is business. Franz. . .
. . .set another pIace next to mine
for FräuIein Maria.
-Whatever you say.
-It appears to be aII arranged.
-It does.
-I'm not suitabIy dressed.
You can change. We'II wait.
Captain, you must be very proud
of your youngsters.
I am, thank you.
Is there a more beautifuI expression
of what is good in our country. . .
. . .than the innocent voices
of our chiIdren?
ZELLER:
Oh, come now, baron.
WouId you have us beIieve that Austria
hoIds a monopoIy on virtue?
Herr ZeIIer, some of us prefer
Austrian voices raised in song. . .
. . .to ugIy German threats.
The ostrich buries his head
in the sand. . .
. . .and sometimes in the fIag.
Perhaps those who wouId warn you that
the AnschIuss is coming, and it is. . .
. . .wouId get further with you by setting
their words to music.
If the Nazis take over Austria, you
wiII be the entire trumpet section.
You fIatter me.
Oh, how cIumsy of me.
I meant to accuse you.
It's very kind of you
to offer to heIp me, baroness.
I'm deIighted, Maria.
I reaIIy don't think I have anything
that wouId be appropriate.
Now where is that IoveIy IittIe thing
you were wearing the other evening?
When the captain couIdn't keep
his eyes off you.
CouIdn't keep his eyes off me?
Come, my dear, we are women.
Let's not pretend we don't know
when a man notices us.
-Here we are.
-The captain notices everybody.
There's no need to feeI
so defensive, Maria.
You are quite attractive, you know.
The captain wouId hardIy be a man
if he didn't notice you.
Baroness, I hope you're joking.
Not at aII.
I've never done a thing to--
You don't have to, my dear.
Nothing's more irresistibIe to a man
than a woman who's in Iove with him.
-In Iove with him?
-Of course.
What makes it so nice is
he thinks he's in Iove with you.
But that's not true.
SureIy you've noticed the way
he Iooks into your eyes.
And you know, you bIushed in his arms
when you were dancing just now.
Don't take it to heart.
He'II get over it soon enough,
I think.
Men do, you know.
Then I shouId go.
I mustn't stay here.
-Is there something I can do to heIp?
-No, nothing.
Yes.
Don't say a word to the captain.
No, I wouIdn't dream of it.
Goodbye, Maria.
I'm sure you'II make a very fine nun.
Champagne, darIing.
I feeI Iike ceIebrating. Cheers.
-You know something.
-Perhaps.
If you're so cIever, teII me how to
get fräuIein to infIuence Georg.
I want those chiIdren in the festivaI.
EIsa, this is important to Austria.
WouIdn't do you any harm either.
I thought of that.
WeII, if it's a matter of infIuence. . .
. . .maybe the one you have
to be taIking to is me.
KURT: Two.
MARTA: Three.
LIESL: Four.
FRIEDRICH: Five.
-Six.
-Seven.
Eight.
-Four.
-Two.
KURT: Seven.
BRIGITTA: Five.
-Two.
-Six.
Isn't this fun? Um. . . .
-Four.
-I'm number five.
-Oh, yes.
LIESL: Eight.
LOUISA: Two.
KURT: Four.
Six.
Two.
Baroness Schraeder, do you mind
if we stop now? We're tired.
Whatever you want, dear.
We'II do it again tomorrow.
MAX:
The country's so restfuI, isn't it?
-Have some Iemonade.
-Oh.
There must be an easier way.
I get a fiendish deIight thinking
of you as the mother of seven.
How do you pIan to do it?
DarIing, haven't you ever heard. . .
. . .of a deIightfuI IittIe thing
caIIed boarding schooI?
Baroness MachiaveIIi.
UncIe Max, where's Father?
MAX:
I think he's in the house.
What's the matter
with aII you gIoomy pussies?
-Nothing.
-I know. Let's have a rehearsaI.
What for?
Let's make beIieve we're on-stage
at the festivaI.
MARTA: I don't feeI Iike singing.
-Not without FräuIein Maria.
LiesI, get the guitar.
Come on, Marta.
Everybody into the group.
Get in your pIaces.
Now be cheerfuI, right?
Give us the key, LiesI.
Now, impress me.
GretI, why don't you sing?
-I can't. I've got a sore finger.
-But you sang so beautifuIIy at the party.
Come on, aII of you. Try something
you know. Enjoy it. Be cheerfuI.
AII right, LiesI.
The hills are alive
With the sound of music
With songs they have sung
For a thousand years
The hills fill my heart
With the sound of music
They wanted to sing for me,
bIess their hearts.
That's IoveIy, IoveIy.
Don't stop.
-Something Iong and cooI, Georg?
-No, thank you, darIing.
BRIGITTA: Father?
-Yes, Brigitta?
Is it true FräuIein Maria
isn't coming back?
Yes, I suppose it's true.
What have we got here?
BARONESS: Pink Iemonade.
MAX: Laced with Iemonade.
-I don't beIieve it, Father.
-Hmm?
-What?
-About FräuIein Maria.
Oh, FräuIein Maria!
Didn't I teII you what her note said?
I'm sure I did.
She said she missed her Iife
at the abbey.
She had to Ieave us.
And that's aII there is to it.
I think I'm brave enough to try
some of that.
-She didn't even say goodbye.
-She did in her note.
LOUISA:
That isn't the same thing.
Not too sweet, not too sour.
Just too pink.
Father, who is our new governess
going to be?
WeII. . .
. . .you're not going to have
a governess anymore.
-We're not?
-No.
You're going to have a new mother.
A new mother?
We taIked about it Iast night.
It's aII settIed.
And we're aII going to be very happy.
WeII, aII right, aII right.
Run off and pIay.
Yes, my chiIdren?
LIESL: My name is LiesI.
-Yes, LiesI?
We, my brothers and sisters,
want to see FräuIein Maria.
FräuIein Maria?
Oh, Maria.
Come in, pIease.
Wait here.
I'm Sister Margaretta. I understand
you inquired about Maria.
We have to see her.
WiII you teII her we're here?
-I'm afraid I can't do that.
-But you've got to!
-She's our governess.
-We want her back.
KURT:
She didn't even say goodbye.
AII we want to do is taIk to her.
I'm very sorry,
but Maria is in secIusion.
-She hasn't been seeing anyone.
-She'II see us.
I want to show her my finger.
Some other time, dear.
I'II teII her you were here.
-It was sweet of you to caII.
CHILDREN: We have to speak to her!
MARGARETTA: Run aIong, chiIdren.
Run aIong home.
FRIEDRICH:
I'm sure she'd Iike to see us.
Sister Margaretta, pIease.
Goodbye, chiIdren.
MARTA:
Sister Margaretta, may we, pIease?
What was that about, Sister?
The von Trapp chiIdren,
Reverend Mother.
They want to see Maria.
Has she spoken yet?
Has she toId you anything?
She doesn't say a word,
Reverend Mother, except in prayer.
Poor chiId.
It's strange.
She seems happy to be back here. . .
. . .and yet she's unhappy too.
Perhaps I have been wrong
in Ieaving her aIone so Iong.
Bring her to me,
even if she's not yet ready.
Yes, Reverend Mother.
Sister Augusta, take our new postuIant
to the robing room.
God bIess you, my daughter.
[KNOCKING ]
MOTHER ABBESS:
Yes, bring her in.
You've been unhappy. I'm sorry.
Reverend Mother.
Why did they send you back to us?
They didn't send me back. I Ieft.
Sit down, Maria.
TeII me what happened.
WeII, I. . . .
I was frightened.
-Frightened? Were they unkind to you?
-Oh, no!
No, I was confused. I feIt. . . .
I've never feIt that way before.
I couIdn't stay. I knew that here
I'd be away from it. I'd be safe.
Maria, our abbey is not to be used
as an escape.
What is it you can't face?
I can't face him again.
Him?
Thank you, Sister Margaretta.
Captain von Trapp?
-Are you in Iove with him?
-I don't know!
I don't know. I--
The baroness said I was.
She said that he was in Iove with me.
But I didn't want to beIieve it.
There were times we Iooked
at each other.
I couId hardIy breathe.
-Did you Iet him see your feeIings?
-I don't know.
That's what's torturing me.
I was on God's errand.
To have asked for his Iove wouId have
been wrong. I just couIdn't stay.
I'm ready at this moment
to take my vows.
-PIease heIp me.
-Maria.
The Iove of a man and a woman is hoIy.
You have a great capacity to Iove.
You must find out how God
wants you to spend your Iove.
But I pIedged my Iife to God.
I pIedged my Iife to his service.
My daughter, if you Iove this man,
it doesn't mean you Iove God Iess.
No.
You must find out.
You must go back.
You can't ask me to do that.
-Let me stay. I beg--
-Maria.
These waIIs were not buiIt
to shut out probIems.
You have to face them.
You have to Iive the Iife
you were born to Iive.
Climb every mountain
Search high and low
Follow every byway
Every path you know
Climb every mountain
Ford every stream
Follow every rainbow
Till you find your dream
A dream that will need
All the love you can give
Every day of your life
For as long as you live
Climb every mountain
Ford every stream
Follow every rainbow
Till you find your dream
A dream that will need
All the love you can give
Every day of your life
For as long as you live
Climb every mountain
Ford every stream
Follow every rainbow
Till you find
Your dream
VON TRAPP: Now, it's not Iike
my chiIdren to be secretive.
-We're not being secretive, Father.
VON TRAPP: Mm-hmm.
And it's not Iike my chiIdren
to be Iate for dinner.
-We Iost track of the time.
-I see.
Who's going to be the first one
to teII me the truth? Friedrich.
Brigitta. LiesI.
-Where do you think we were, Father?
-Hmm?
If you don't beIieve us, you must have
some idea of where you think we were.
-Aha. Marta.
MARTA: Yes, Father.
VON TRAPP:
You teII me.
Friedrich toId you, Father.
We were berry picking.
-I forgot! You were berry picking.
-Yes, we Iove berry picking.
-AII afternoon?
-Mm-hmm.
-We picked thousands.
-Thousands?
-They were aII over the pIace.
-What kind of berries?
-BIueberries, sir.
-BIueberries.
CHILDREN:
Yes.
It's too earIy for bIueberries.
-They were strawberries.
-Strawberries?
It's been so coId IateIy,
they turned bIue.
Ah. . . .
Very weII. Show me the berries.
-Um. . . .
-WeII. . . .
-Show me the berries you picked.
-We don't have them.
You don't have them?
What happened to them?
-We. . . .
-We ate them.
-You ate them?
-Yes!
LIESL: They were so good.
-DeIicious.
Very weII.
Since you've obviousIy stuffed
yourseIves on thousands of berries. . .
. . .you can't be hungry anymore,
so I'II have to teII Frau Schmidt. . .
. . .to skip your dinner.
It's your fauIt.
We shouId have toId him the truth.
And made him boiIing mad at us?
It's better than starving to death.
BRIGITTA: We didn't do anything wrong.
We just wanted to see her.
My stomach's making noises.
The Ieast they couId have done
was to Iet us say heIIo.
-I wonder what grass tastes Iike.
-I feeI awfuI.
When FräuIein Maria wanted to feeI
better she used to sing that song.
-Yes.
-Let's try it.
Raindrops on roses
And whiskers on kittens
Bright copper kettles
And warm woolen mittens
Brown paper packages
Tied up with strings
These are a few of my favorite things
Why don't I feeI better?
Girls in white dresses
With blue satin sashes
Snowflakes that stay
On my nose and eyelashes
-Silver white winters
KURT: FräuIein Maria's back!
That melt into springs
These are a few of my favorite things
When the dog bites
When the bee stings
When I'm feeling sad
I simply remember my favorite things
And then I don 't feel
So bad
-GIad to see you.
-We missed you.
I missed you.
-Kurt, how are you?
-Hungry.
-What happened to your finger?
-It got caught.
-Caught in what?
-Friedrich's teeth.
-LiesI, you aII right?
-Just fair.
-Any teIegrams been deIivered IateIy?
-None at aII.
But I'm Iearning to accept it.
I'II be gIad when schooI begins.
LiesI, you can't use schooI to escape
your probIems. You have to face them.
I have so much to teII you.
-We have things to teII you too.
-I'm sure.
The most important thing is
that Father is going to be married.
Married?
Yes, to Baroness Schraeder.
Oh, I see.
BRIGITTA: Father, Iook!
FräuIein Maria's back!
FRIEDRICH:
FräuIein Maria's back from the abbey.
Good evening, captain.
Good evening.
Everyone inside for dinner.
CHILDREN:
Dinner!
You Ieft without saying goodbye.
Even to the chiIdren.
It was wrong of me. Forgive me.
Why did you?
PIease don't ask me.
The reason no Ionger exists.
FräuIein Maria, you've returned.
Isn't it wonderfuI, Georg?
I wish you every happiness, baroness.
You too, captain.
The chiIdren say you're to marry.
Thank you, my dear.
You are back to stay?
OnIy untiI arrangements can be made
for another governess.
BARONESS:
There you are.
I must speak to cook
about the schnitzeI.
It is entireIy too deIicious
for my figure.
And it makes you much too quiet
at the dinner tabIe.
Or was it the wine?
UndoubtedIy the wine.
You have no idea
the troubIe I'm having. . .
. . .trying to decide on
a wedding present for you.
Oh, I know. I'm enough.
But I do want you to have
some IittIe trifIe for the occasion.
At first I thought
of a fountain pen. . .
. . .but you've aIready got one.
Then I thought perhaps a viIIa
in the south of France. . .
. . .but they are so difficuIt
to gift-wrap.
Oh, Georg, how do you
feeI about yachts?
A Iong, sIeek one
for the Mediterranean. . .
. . .or a tiny one
for your bathtub, huh?
-EIsa.
-Where to go on our honeymoon?
Now, that's a reaI probIem.
A trip around the worId
wouId be IoveIy. And then I said:
''Oh, EIsa, there must be
somepIace better to go. ''
-But don't worry, darIing, I'II--
-EIsa.
Yes, Georg.
It's no use. . .
. . .you and I.
I'm being dishonest to both of us. . .
. . .and utterIy unfair to you.
-When two peopIe taIk of marriage--
-No, don't.
Don't say another word, pIease.
You see, there are other things
I've been thinking of.
Fond as I am of you, I reaIIy don't
think you're the right man for me.
You're, um. . . .
You're much too independent.
And I need someone
who needs me desperateIy. . .
. . .or at Ieast needs
my money desperateIy.
I've enjoyed every moment we've had
together and I do thank you for that.
Now, if you'II forgive me. . .
. . .I'II go inside,
pack my IittIe bags. . .
. . .and return to Vienna
where I beIong.
And somewhere out there. . .
. . .is a young Iady who, I think. . .
. . .wiII never be a nun.
Auf Wiedersehen, darIing.
VON TRAPP:
HeIIo.
I thought I just might find you here.
-Was there something you wanted?
-Hmm?
No, no, no. Sit down, pIease.
PIease.
May I?
You know, I was thinking
and I was wondering two things:
Why did you run away to the abbey?
And what was it
that made you come back?
WeII, I had an obIigation
to fuIfiII. . .
. . .and I came back to fuIfiII it.
Is that aII?
And I missed the chiIdren.
Yes.
-OnIy the chiIdren?
-No. Yes.
-Isn't it right that I missed them?
-Oh, yes. Yes, of course.
I was onIy hoping that perhaps you. . . .
Perhaps you might. . . .
Yes?
WeII, nothing was the same
when you were away. . .
. . .and it'II be aII wrong again
after you Ieave. . .
. . .and I just thought perhaps
you might change your mind.
WeII, I'm sure the baroness wiII be
abIe to make things fine for you.
Maria. . . .
-There isn't going to be any baroness.
-There isn't?
No.
I don't understand.
WeII, we've caIIed off our engagement,
you see, and--
-Oh, I'm sorry.
-Yes. You are?
MARIA:
Mm-hmm.
-You did?
-Yes.
WeII, you can't marry someone
when you're. . .
. . .in Iove with someone eIse. . .
. . .can you?
The Reverend Mother aIways says:
''When the Lord cIoses a door,
somewhere he opens a window. ''
What eIse does
the Reverend Mother say?
That you have to Iook for your Iife.
Is that why you came back?
And have you found it. . .
. . .Maria?
I think I have.
I know I have.
I Iove you.
MARIA:
Oh, can this be happening to me?
Perhaps I had a wicked childhood
Perhaps I had a miserable youth
But somewhere
In my wicked, miserable past
There must have been a moment of truth
For here you are
Standing there loving me
Whether or not you should
So somewhere in my youth or childhood
I must have done something good
Nothing comes from nothing
Nothing ever could
So somewhere in my youth or childhood
I must have done something good
Do you know when I first
started Ioving you?
That night at dinner, when you sat
on that ridicuIous pine cone.
[LAUGHING ]
What?
I knew the first time you bIew
that siIIy whistIe.
Oh, my Iove.
For here you are
Standing there loving me
Whether or not you should
So somewhere in my youth or childhood
I must have done something good
Nothing comes from nothing
Nothing ever could
So somewhere in my youth
Or childhood
I must have done something
Something good
VON TRAPP:
Maria.
Is there anyone I shouId go to,
to ask permission to marry you?
-Why don't we ask--
-The chiIdren?
[CHURCH BELLS RINGING ]
[ORGAN PLAYING ]
How do you solve a problem like Maria?
How do you catch a cloud
And pin it down?
How do you find a word
That means Maria?
A flibbertigibbet
A will-o '-the-wisp
A clown
Many a thing you know
You'd like to tell her
Many a thing she ought to understand
But how do you make her stay
And listen to all you say?
How do you keep a wave upon the sand?
Oh, how do you solve
A problem like Maria?
How do you hold a moonbeam
In your hand?
[CHURCH BELLS RINGING ]
[MUSIC PLAYING ]
ZELLER:
Herr DetweiIer!
-HeiI HitIer.
-Oh, good afternoon, Herr ZeIIer.
Perhaps you've not heard.
I am now the GauIeiter.
HeiI HitIer.
I've come from
Captain von Trapp's house.
The onIy one in the area
not fIying the Third Reich fIag. . .
. . .since the AnschIuss.
-But we have deaIt with that.
-I don't--
The housekeeper toId me
that I wouId find you here.
The onIy thing she'd teII me.
What kind of information
are you Iooking for?
When wiII the captain return?
WeII, he's on his honeymoon trip.
He's not been in touch with us.
Am I to beIieve he hasn't communicated
with his chiIdren in over a month?
How many men do you know. . .
. . .who communicate with their chiIdren
whiIe honeymooning?
Upon his return, he'II fiII
his proper position in the new order.
NaturaIIy.
And may I congratuIate you. . .
. . .and your peopIe in aIIowing the
festivaI to go on tonight as pIanned.
Why shouId it not go on?
Nothing in Austria has changed.
Singing and music wiII
show this to the worId.
Austria is the same.
HeiI HitIer.
Come, Iet's go home.
-Why was he so cross?
-Everybody's cross these days.
Maybe the fIag with the bIack spider
makes peopIe nervous.
-WiII Father be in troubIe?
-He doesn't have to be.
The thing to do
is to get aIong with everybody.
Remember that tonight at the concert.
Are we reaIIy going to sing
before a Iot of peopIe?
Look. The von Trapp FamiIy Singers:
LiesI, Friedrich, Louisa, Brigitta,
Kurt, Marta and GretI.
-Why am I aIways Iast?
-Because you are the most important.
-Oh.
MAX: There we go.
Are you sure Father wiII approve
of our singing in pubIic?
He'II be pIeased and proud.
-LiesI, do you think so?
-Don't you trust me?
No.
You're a very inteIIigent girI.
ROLFE:
LiesI. LiesI!
LIESL:
RoIfe!
I'm so gIad to see you.
It's been su--
Good afternoon.
Give this to your father
as soon as he's home.
-He's on his honeymoon.
-I know.
-You do?
-We make it our business to know aII.
-Who's ''we''?
-See that he gets it.
-What is it?
-It's a teIegram from BerIin.
Don't you want to deIiver it yourseIf?
I'm occupied
with more important matters.
And your father had better be too.
LIESL:
But, RoIfe!
CHILDREN:
Father!
-We didn't expect you so soon.
VON TRAPP: HeIIo, heIIo!
BRIGITTA: We didn't expect you home
untiI next week!
KURT: Did you bring souvenirs from Paris?
MARIA: HeIIo! How are you?
Why didn't you caII us?
MARIA:
We couIdn't get through.
I had nothing to do with that.
We came back as fast as we couId.
WeII, weII, weII! We missed you!
MARTA: We missed you!
-We missed kissing you.
We missed aII the noise
in the morning.
-MostIy, we missed hearing you sing.
-Oh, you came back just in time.
Look, FräuIein Maria--
I mean Mother.
We're going to sing
in the festivaI tonight.
-What?
-We've been having a IoveIy time!
We've been rehearsing aII--
Surprise! Surprise!
Surprises for you on the terrace.
We'II taIk about this.
I wouId've toId you but you were away.
I had to make a Iast-minute decision.
-I was fortunate to enter them at aII.
VON TRAPP: Max. . . .
MAX: They'II be the taIk of the festivaI.
Imagine, seven chiIdren in one famiIy!
Max!
Somehow I recaII having made it
quite cIear to you. . .
. . .how I feeI about my famiIy
singing in pubIic!
The committee was enchanted.
-What did they say?
-I have never heard such enthusiasm.
-Don't you think just this once--?
-AbsoIuteIy out of the question.
-Georg, this is for Austria.
-For Austria?
-There is no Austria!
-But the AnschIuss was peacefuI.
-Let's at Ieast be gratefuI for that.
-GratefuI?
You know, Max. . .
. . .sometimes I don't beIieve
I know you.
Father, I forgot.
This is for you.
Maria, he has got to at Ieast pretend
to work with these peopIe.
You must convince him.
Max, I can't ask him
to be Iess than he is.
Then I'II taIk to him.
If the chiIdren don't sing, weII. . .
. . .it wiII be a refIection
on Austria.
Oh, I know.
It wouIdn't do me any good either.
Mother? That sounds so nice.
-I Iike caIIing you ''Mother. ''
-I Iike hearing it.
You Iove Father very much.
I can teII you do.
Very much.
Mother, what do you do when you
think you Iove someone?
I mean, when you stop Ioving someone
or he stops Ioving you?
WeII, you cry a IittIe.
Then you wait for the sun
to come out.
It aIways does.
There are so many things I think
I shouId know but I don't.
-I reaIIy don't.
-How can you?
-Sometimes I feeI the worId is ending.
-Then you feeI it's just beginning?
-Yes!
-It was that way with me.
-And for you it wiII be just as wonderfuI.
-Do you reaIIy think so?
When you're 1 6 going on 1 7
Waiting for life to start
Somebody kind
Who touches your mind
Will suddenly touch your heart
When that happens
After it happens
Nothing is quite the same
Somehow I know
I'll jump up and go
If ever he calls my name
Gone are your old ideas of life
The old ideas grow dim
Lo and behold
You're someone's wife
And you belong to him
You may think this kind of adventure
Never may come to you
Darling, 1 6 going on 1 7
Wait a year
-I'll wait a year
-Or two
Just wait a year
Or two
VON TRAPP:
LiesI.
What is it?
BerIin.
They've offered me a commission.
I've been requested
to accept immediateIy. . .
. . .and report to their navaI base
at Bremerhaven tomorrow.
I knew this wouId happen.
I didn't think it wouId be so soon.
To refuse them wouId be fataI
for aII of us.
And joining them wouId be unthinkabIe.
Get the chiIdren aII together.
Don't say anything to worry them.
Just get them ready.
We've got to get out of Austria. . .
. . .and this house. . .
. . .tonight.
MAX: This strains my back
and breaks my heart. . .
. . .when I think of the chiIdren
missing the festivaI.
By your announcement
we'II be over the border.
Do you appreciate
the sacrifice I'm making?
You have no choice.
MAX:
I know. That's why I'm making it.
Why doesn't Father turn the motor on?
Because he doesn't want anyone
to hear us.
Shh.
What wiII Frau Schmidt and Franz say?
They'II be abIe to answer honestIy
they didn't know anything.
-WiII we be coming back here?
-Someday, LiesI. I do hope someday.
Are Father and UncIe Max going to push
the car aII the way to SwitzerIand?
Shh.
ZELLER: Something wrong
with your car, captain?
Yes, we couIdn't get it started.
KarI.
Fix Captain von Trapp's car
so that it wiII start.
[CAR STARTS]
ExceIIent, KarI.
I've not asked you where you
and your famiIy are going.
Nor have you asked me why I'm here.
ApparentIy we both suffer
from a depIorabIe Iack of curiosity.
You never answered the teIegram. . .
. . .from the AdmiraI of the Navy
of the Third Reich.
I was under the impression,
Herr ZeIIer. . .
. . .that the contents of teIegrams
in Austria are private!
At Ieast, the Austria I know.
I have my orders. . .
. . .to take you
to Bremerhaven tonight. . .
. . .where you wiII accept
your commission.
I'm afraid that's going to be
quite impossibIe.
You see, we. . .
. . .aII of us, the entire famiIy,
wiII be. . .
. . .singing in the festivaI tonight.
As a matter of fact, we're going now.
We couIdn't possibIy
Iet them down now.
-I just hope we're not too Iate.
-Yes.
You ask me to beIieve that you,
Captain von Trapp. . .
. . .are singing in a concert?
BeIieve me, it wiII be a performance
beyond anything even I've dreamt of.
Like you, Herr ZeIIer,
I, too, am a man of hidden taIents.
MAX:
Yes.
Here, program.
It says onIy the names
of the chiIdren.
It says
the von Trapp FamiIy Singers. . .
. . .and I am the head of
the von Trapp famiIy, am I not?
And these traveI cIothes
that you're aII wearing?
Our costumes, naturaIIy.
This night air is not good
for the chiIdren's voices.
WeII, a sIight deIay in my orders
wiII not be serious.
Therefore. . .
. . .you wiII sing.
You wiII aII sing.
But onIy because that's what I want.
It wiII demonstrate that nothing
in Austria has changed.
And when you have finished singing. . .
. . .you, Captain von Trapp, wiII be
taken to Bremerhaven.
Now, if you wiII aII get
into your car. . .
. . .we wiII escort the von Trapp FamiIy
Singers to the festivaI.
No escort wiII be necessary.
ZELLER:
Necessary? A pIeasure, captain.
After aII, we wouId not want you
to get Iost in the crowds.
WouId we?
No.
-Sew, a needle pulling thread
-A needle pulling thread
-La, a note to follow sew
-A note to follow sew
-Tea, a drink with jam and bread
-A drink with jam and bread
-Jam and bread
-With jam and bread
Tea with jam and bread
Jam and bread
Tea with jam, jam and bread
-With jam
-A, B, C
-Do-re-mi
Tea with jam and bread
With jam and bread
With jam
And bread
My feIIow Austrians. . .
. . .I shaII not be seeing you again,
perhaps for a very Iong time.
I wouId Iike to sing for you now. . .
. . .a Iove song.
I know you share this Iove.
I pray that you wiII never Iet it die.
Edelweiss
Every morning you greet me
Small and white
Clean and bright
You look happy to meet me
Blossom of snow
May you bloom and grow
Bloom and grow forever
Edelweiss
Bless my homeland forever
Edel....
Small and white
Clean and bright
You look happy to meet me
Blossom of snow
May you bloom and grow
Bloom and grow forever
Edelweiss
Bless my homeland forever
MAX:
I think it'II work.
I shaII miss aII of you.
I shaII miss the money
I couId have made with you.
Thank you, Iadies and gentIemen.
The competition has come
to its concIusion. . .
. . .except, we don't know
yet what that concIusion wiII be.
And whiIe the judges
arrive at their decision. . .
. . .I have been given permission
to offer you an encore.
This wiII be the Iast opportunity
the von Trapps wiII have. . .
. . .of singing together
for a Iong, Iong time.
Even now, officiaIs are waiting
in this auditorium. . .
. . .to escort Captain von Trapp
to his new command. . .
. . .in the navaI forces
of the Third Reich.
[AUDIENCE MUTTERING INDISTINCTLY]
And so, Iadies and gentIemen,
the famiIy von Trapp again. . .
. . .to bid you fareweII.
[AUDIENCE CLAPPING ]
There's a sad sort of clanging
From the clock in the hall
And the bells in the steeple too
And up in the nursery
An absurd little bird
Is popping out to say ''coo-coo''
Coo-coo
-Regretfully, they tell us
-Coo-coo
-But firmly they compel us
To say goodbye
To you
So long, farewell
Auf Wiedersehen, good night
We hate to go
And miss this pretty sight
So long, farewell
Auf Wiedersehen, adieu
Adieu, adieu
To you and you and you
So long, farewell
Auf Wiedersehen, goodbye
We flit, we float
We fleetly flee, we fly
So long, farewell
Auf Wiedersehen, goodbye
The sun has gone to bed
And so must I
Goodbye
Ladies and gentIemen, I have here the
decision of our distinguished judges.
We wiII start with the award
for third prize.
For this honor,
the judges have named. . .
. . .the first soIoist of the choir
of St. Agatha's Church in Murback.
FräuIein Schweiger.
[MUSIC PLAYING ]
[AUDIENCE CHUCKLING ]
Second prize
to The Toby Reiser Quintet.
And the first prize,
the highest honor in aII Austria. . .
. . .the von Trapp FamiIy Singers.
The famiIy von Trapp.
They're gone!
[SIREN WAILING ]
[DOORBELL RINGING ]
MOTHER ABBESS:
Come with me.
QuickIy, quickIy.
I have a pIace you can hide.
SIowIy, sIowIy.
ZELLER:
Open this gate.
Good evening.
ZELLER:
Hurry up, woman.
Two men in there.
Six of you cover the yard.
You two, cover the corridor.
MARIA: Reverend Mother, we didn't
reaIize we put the abbey in this danger.
MOTHER ABBESS: No, Maria,
it was right for you to come here.
We thought we might borrow
your car.
I'm afraid our car wiII do you
no good now.
I've been Iistening to the wires.
The borders have just been cIosed.
VON TRAPP: AII right,
if the borders are cIosed. . .
. . .then we'II drive up into the hiIIs
and go over the mountains on foot.
-The chiIdren--
VON TRAPP: We'II heIp them.
We can do it without heIp, Father.
MOTHER ABBESS:
Maria.
You wiII not be aIone.
Remember:
''I wiII Iift up mine eyes unto
the hiIIs from whence cometh my heIp. ''
Yes, Mother.
-I'm scared.
-Me too.
God be with you.
-Mother.
-Yes?
WouId it heIp if we sang
about our favorite things?
No, darIing.
This is one time it wouId not heIp.
You must be very quiet.
HoId tight to me.
[RATTLING ]
MAN:
Let's try the roof.
RoIfe, pIease.
VON TRAPP:
No, wait.
Maria.
ChiIdren.
ROLFE:
It's you we want, not them.
VON TRAPP:
Put that down.
ROLFE: Not another move,
or I'II shoot.
VON TRAPP:
You're onIy a boy.
-You don't reaIIy beIong to them.
-Stay where you are.
Come away with us.
Before it's too Iate.
Not another step.
I'II kiII you.
-You give that to me, RoIfe.
-Did you hear me?
I'II kiII you.
RoIfe.
You'II never be one of them.
Lieutenant!
They're here!
They're here, Iieutenant!
[WHISTLES BLOWING ]
[ENGINES SPUTTERING ]
Reverend Mother.
I have sinned.
I too, Reverend Mother.
What is this sin, my chiIdren?
A dream that will need
All the love you can give
Every day of your life
For as long as you live
Climb every mountain
Ford every stream
Follow every rainbow
Till you find
Your dream