Break!
Let's move it.
Let's go.
Hut!
20!
29!
All right.
You take the inside.
On this one,
you take the inside.
54.
Ready, set...
2-85!
Hut! Hut!
Back! Back!
Throw! Throw!
Throw the ball!
Touchdown, Joe.
Looking good,
isn't he?
What?
Pendleton.
He's looking
awful good.
Mm-hmm.
Really fall into it.
All right, Joe.
Come on, baby.
Set...
Hike!
Good movement.
Let's try it again.
18...
Hike. Hike.
Have those men
go deep.
1-83!
Hut!
He's looking
awful good.
Here we go.
Hut! Hut!
Hustle back,
hustle back.
Come on, guys. Come on.
Opposite left,
play past 35. X-curl on 1.
Ready? Break.
4-3, set!
Play past 29...
2-81!
Hut! Hut!
Pass! Pass! Pass!
Ball! Ball! Ball!
Once again, we had
a foul-up on that scrimmage.
The fullback has been
slow on his block.
The guard almost ran
into that pole.
We got to do it
till it's right.
Formation left.
Screen right on 2.
Ready? Break!
Right, left!
4-3...
Set!
2-85!
Hut! Hut!
Looking
awful good.
Mm-hmm.
I'm thinking of
starting him on Sunday.
What about Jarrett?
Pendleton's
looking better.
2-81!
Hut!
Pass!
Pass! Pass!
Ball! Ball! Ball!
Come on!
Is he still
on cortisone?
No.
Darvon, xylocaine,
any kind of painkiller?
Nothing.
He's looking
awful good.
2-84!
Hut! Hut! Hut!
Hut!
Ball! Ball! Ball!
I never saw
a knee like that
heal without
surgery, coach.
He's looking awful good.
Thanks a lot.
Oh, hi, Joe.
How you doing?
Good. How's the knee?
Good.
What do you think
of the rams' chances?
I think we're going
to the super bowl.
We're going to win.
Off the record.
Think you got a chance?
Off the record? We're
going to the super bowl.
We're going to win.
What do you think
of your competition?
Jarrett.
My competition?
He's our
starting quarterback.
My competition's
25 other teams.
Ha ha ha ha.
Max?
Whew! Yeah!
How you doing?
What's in
this brown stuff?
Oh, that's mainly
whipped liver.
Liver?
Yep. I put
a little whey in it,
then mix it with a
little alfalfa sprouts,
some bean curd,
and spinach mold.
It's a--it's a liver
and whey shake.
* happy birthday to you
* happy birthday
to you *
* happy birthday,
dear Joe *
* happy birthday
to you *
I didn't think
anybody knew.
Thanks for
coming over, Max.
I hope you have
a lot more, kid.
That's--that's--
that's--
aw...
What's this?
Aw.
Ahem.
Yay! Ha ha ha!
You want
to know something?
At my age, in any other
business, I'd be young.
Look at it
this way--
soon you can get
into another business
and have a real life.
Yeah?
Yeah.
I don't know
what that means.
This is the only
business I know.
I'm stuck.
What do you mean,
stuck?
I've been working
my whole life
to get a chance
to do something, and...
I don't know
if I'm ever
going to get
a chance to do it.
Hey.
No, it's all right.
I'm going
to fix your neck.
Don't do that, Joe.
Wait a minute. Wait.
Oh!
How's that?
Oh, boy. Yeah,
but it scares
the hell out of me
every time you do that.
If you don't pay
more attention to how
your trapezius goes up
into your deltoids,
you're going to throw
off your entire cervical
and your lumbar areas.
Only I can fix it.
You ought to start
listening to me.
Maybe you ought
to trade places.
You be the trainer.
I'll start on Sunday.
Yeah...what?
I'm starting
against Dallas?
They don't want
to go with Jarrett.
They want
to go with you.
Happy birthday, Joe.
Hey, my watch stopped.
Look at that.
It keeps flashing
the same time.
I'm dreaming, huh?
Well, I...
Hey...
This is
an airplane dream.
I forget what they're
supposed to mean.
I think they're a good sign,
aren't they?
Mr. Pendleton.
Mr. Pendleton,
you must wait for me.
I'm your escort.
Wait for me, please,
Mr. Pendleton.
The end of the line,
Mr. Pendleton, please.
Hi. How you doing?
Hey, you want to
hear a little music?
You have to wait in line.
What? This is
my dream, isn't it?
You mustn't get out
of line. Really!
Chamberlain,
Paul r.
All right. I think
I've brought the, uh...
I've escorted
the final--
asterisk this manifest
as complete.
Hi.
You cannot board
before your turn.
I don't need a turn.
I'm not boarding.
I don't think
you understand.
This isn't your
ultimate destination.
This is a way station.
That will take you to your
ultimate destination.
I'm not going.
I'm going to run
around till I wake up.
I'm afraid I haven't
fully explained the basis
on which this system
is organized.
This way station's rules
derived from yours.
They're a product
of your image
and the image of those
who share your image.
Violate the rules,
question the principles--
you want to see a trick?
I do this
once in a while
to keep my abductor
pollicis limber.
You want to feel that?
That's a perfectly solid
50-cent piece.
I just throw that
into that hand, you see.
I say the magic words,
abracadabra.
And then presto,
it's gone.
You probably think
I still have it.
You're wrong,
'cause I can see it
coming out of your ear.
That's
the only trick I know.
Mr. Pendleton!
Gentlemen.
Gentlemen,
what's the delay?
Sir, we've received
a new arrival
who refuses
to board.
But that's impossible.
Have you explained
the rules to him?
Yes, sir.
Quite clearly?
And what
was his rebuttal?
He took a coin
out of my ear.
Did he?
Perhaps I should
have a word with him.
Yes, sir.
Mr. Pendleton!
He's right
over there, sir.
Mr. Pendleton!
Yeah. Hey,
you can call me Joe.
How you doing?
Mr. Pendleton,
you know where
you are, don't you?
I'm in the middle of
a really weird dream.
You see the problem?
Joe, come here.
Look at me
and listen carefully
to what I'm saying.
Yeah?
This is not a dream.
Yeah.
Life has a certain
quality all its own,
a certain feeling,
and so do dreams.
You know that this
is not life,
and you know now that
this is not a dream.
This is a place
that comes after life
and after dreams.
I'm sure
you're aware of that
and that you'll take
your place with the others.
Are you trying
to tell me...
I'm not supposed
to be here.
But you are here.
Well, you guys
made a mistake.
This is insupportable.
You're talking
to Mr. Jordan.
Anybody can make a mistake.
Mr. Jordan, we're
due to take off.
Yes, I have
the situation in hand.
Joe, if you don't
take your place,
the others can't
complete their journey.
Do you think that's fair?
If this
is really heaven,
you're
supposed to be fair.
I didn't
make any mistake.
This is not heaven.
It's a way station.
There is no mistake.
I want a check-out
on Joseph Pendleton.
When is he due to arrive
at this way station?
Sir,
I don't understand.
A check-out? Why?
The likelihood of one
individual being right
increases
in direct proportion
to the intensity
with which others
are trying
to prove him wrong.
Pendleton,
Joseph--
due to arrive
10:17 A.M.
March 20th of
the year 2025.
Sir, I really
can't believe it. I--
I took him out--i--
I took him out
just before the accident.
You did what?
That car couldn't
have missed him.
You're supposed to wait
for the outcome.
But I was so sure,
and it looked like
it would be painful.
Wait. Are you saying--
is this your first
assignment as an escort?
Yes, sir.
Haven't you learned
the rules of probability
and outcome?
Every question
of life and death
remains a probability
until the outcome.
So he jumped
the gun.
Put me back
where you found me,
and we'll forget
the whole thing.
This man must be put back
into his body at once.
Yeah.
Thanks, Mr. Jordan.
Hey, I'll see you
in about 50 years.
Hey, hey, Max.
Max, I'm back.
I'm back.
He can't hear you,
Mr. Pendleton.
I hope they got...
The best football team
in America in heaven,
and I hope god
makes you first-string.
Aw...
Max, I'm going
to get my body back.
Where's my body?
Where do they keep--
oh, dear.
Cremated. I see.
I'm starting against
Dallas on Sunday.
Joe, the body
you occupied on earth
has been cremated.
Well, uncremate me,
that's all.
You must be able
to do something right.
Does "not being
a good sport"
mean anything
to you?
Joe, we can put you
into another man's body,
provided his death
has not yet been discovered.
Are you kidding?
Put me into
another man's body?
I just got my body
back in shape.
Joe, the only way
you can return to life
is in the body
of another man.
I shall have to take charge
of this case personally.
Incredibly graceful.
He's about your age
and in perfect condition.
He's too short. He'd never
see over the line.
Aah!
You know what kind of
shape you gotta be in
to get to
the super bowl?
Yes, Joe.
I understand.
He's not talking
english.
I told you
he was German.
Hey, you talk
any english?
We can't be seen
or heard, Joe.
Well, I don't want
to talk German.
I got to be able to call
plays in english.
Joe, if you could
not so much lower
but broaden
your standards.
We've seen
many bodies,
and the choices
are becoming limited.
Julia, please,
I beg of you.
I want a drink.
There's plenty--
I've got to have
a drink.
No, no, no.
Mr. Farnsworth loathes
cold cucumber soup.
Hey, this is some house.
Who lives here?
Leo Farnsworth,
a man of enormous power.
We should make the arrangement
later this afternoon.
Thank you, sisk.
Just leave the door open
as you leave, sisk.
Thank you very much.
The more servants
who see us, the better.
This guy?
Are you kidding?
That's not Farnsworth.
Give me a drink.
Don't drink.
Who are they?
Farnsworth's wife and
his confidential secretary.
You hate me.
Don't be ridiculous.
I love you.
I want a drink!
Tony--
it would be better
if you didn't drink.
How long will it be
before they find him?
I don't know,
darling.
It shouldn't be long,
my dearest.
I'm glad we did it.
We couldn't help it.
Julia,
it would be better
if you'd try
not to unravel now.
Thank you, Julia.
Is Farnsworth
dead yet?
Not yet.
What's the matter
with him?
He can't
keep his eyes open.
He's been drugged
by those two downstairs.
This is a murder.
You see how he's slowly
sliding into the water?
Hey, somebody, get--
hey, hey, get a doctor.
There's a guy--
hey, get a doctor.
You got a guy
drowning in the bathtub.
You left a bare pot
on the carpet.
I can't hold everything
at once.
Mrs. Farnsworth
would kill you
if she saw that.
Hey, somebody!
You got, uh--
give me a drink.
I'd like a drink!
Try not to go
overboard, dear.
He was a lecherous,
sadistic son of a bitch.
Everyone wanted him dead.
I should be canonized!
Perhaps one drink.
Where can
the man be?
I'm sorry,
miss Logan.
What harm
can that do him?
We did it,
but that man
deserves to be dead.
Please.
They're murderers.
What's going on
out there?
I'm sorry, sir.
It's that miss Logan
here to see
Mr. Farnsworth.
Show her in.
Yes, sir.
Oh, my god.
No. It's
the perfect alibi.
She insists
on seeing him.
Let's look for
another body.
A servant
will find the body.
Keep sisk with you
at all times
to establish
your whereabouts.
Let's get
out of here.
Miss Logan, sir.
Oh, miss Logan.
I'm Tony abbott.
This is the library.
That's
Mrs. Farnsworth.
Hello.
I'm going
into the living room.
Want to come, sisk?
Oh, yes.
Certainly, madam.
I'm Mr. Farnsworth's
personal and private
executive secretary.
I didn't know
whether you knew that.
I'm sorry
he's not down yet.
That's all right.
I'll wait.
Would you
take a seat?
No, thank you.
Perhaps you'd like to
tell me what it's about.
Mr. Farnsworth has been sent
hundreds of letters
from a town in England
called Pagglesham.
The people who live there--
1,600, including my father--
are about to be forcibly
evicted from their homes
to make way for the proposed
exo-grey refinery.
Not only will hundreds
of families
be forced to find
other homes,
but the few who remain will
have their health endangered
by the inevitable poisoning
of their air and water,
the documented evidence
for which I have here,
along with a petition
signed by the 1,673 citizens
of that area.
This is what I'm here
to see Mr. Farnsworth
about.
You're aware
Mr. Farnsworth
conducts business
at his office?
I've been to his office.
He refused to see me.
I seriously doubt
he'd see you here.
He'll have to,
because I'm not leaving.
I'm sorry?
I'm not leaving.
I've come 8,000 miles,
Mr. Abbott,
to do something about
a terrible injustice
that this man Leo Farnsworth
has perpetrated
on hundreds of innocent,
defenseless people.
Somebody ought
to help her.
You can help her, Joe.
You can be Farnsworth.
If Mr. Farnsworth
doesn't see me,
I don't know
what I'll do.
Is that a threat?
Yes.
I don't want
to be Farnsworth.
The decision is yours.
Miss Logan, you
give me no choice.
Sisk!
If I had to be
Farnsworth,
could we
do it temporary?
Yes.
We could arrange that
if you wish it.
Sisk!
Sisk, please
tell Mr. Farnsworth
miss Logan is here
and refuses
to leave.
Yes, sir.
If you really
want to help her,
you'd better hurry.
Well, it's only
temporary, right?
That's correct.
Only Farnsworth
can help her.
Once the body's discovered,
it'll be too late.
Hey.
That's me.
I haven't changed.
It's just me.
Mr. Farnsworth?
Now what do we do?
Mr. Farnsworth,
are you there, sir?
I'll never get away
with this.
What will we do now?
Are you all right?
Answer him.
People can hear me now?
Of course.
But he knows
the other guy's voice.
Mr. Farnsworth, is everything
all right in there?
Answer him.
Ahem. Um, will you
take it easy?
I'll be out
in a minute.
Very good, sir.
It works.
Of course. Inwardly,
you haven't changed.
You're still
Joe Pendleton.
That's what
you and I see.
But outwardly,
you're Leo Farnsworth,
and that's what
everyone else will see.
Miss Betty Logan
is downstairs, sir.
She insists
upon seeing you.
Do you wish
to dress, sir?
Oh, uh, sure, sure.
Very good, sir.
You mean I'm going to
sound like this guy,
no matter
what I talk like?
I beg your pardon,
Mr. Farnsworth?
You see?
Ha ha ha ha.
Heh heh heh heh.
Well...
Ahh.
Whoa.
Julia, Julia, Julia,
please, please, dear.
Please, dear,
not now. Not now.
I want a sip.
You're sorry you
helped, aren't you?
You wish
he were alive.
Why don't you say
it's not true?
You didn't say
it's not true.
It's not true.
Say it again.
Darling, darling,
it's not true.
I don't hate you.
I love you.
There, sir.
Thank you. Thank you.
Ahem.
Your helmet, sir.
Huh?
Your Polo helmet, sir.
Oh, thanks. Thanks.
Uh, do I play Polo?
Oh, not really, sir.
Sir?
Thank you. Thank you.
This Logan girl
is a godsend.
What's taking so long?
Pick up the fountainhead.
Pretend you're reading.
Right. All right.
You go up.
All right.
Miss Logan, sir.
Hi. How you doing?
I'm not leaving until you've
heard what I have to say.
Uh, oh, yeah.
Well, good.
You've been sent
hundreds of letters
from a town in England
called Pagglesham.
I know about
that situation.
Have you read
the letters?
Well...
Uh...
Well, no.
No, you haven't.
I suspected as much.
That's why
I've flown over here.
I and the 1,673 people
whom I represent
and whose names
are on this petition
are not going to
allow their futures
to be determined
by mindless bureaucrats
at the Beck and call
of certain so-called
industrialists
for whom elderly men
and women and children
are just figures
to be entered
in your ledgers'
profit and loss column.
Do I make myself clear?
Yeah, but--
there are no buts.
You can have me dragged out.
It would be bad publicity
for exo-grey industries.
Why don't you just
sit down?
I prefer to stand.
We can stand up.
I've made it my business
to find out about
exo-grey industries.
Facts that would make
interesting newspaper copy.
Ah. Well...
Your tea,
Mr. Farnsworth.
Oh, right. Uh, yeah.
My--my--my tea.
Uh...
Anything else,
Mr. Farnsworth?
Uh, no. I think
that's about it.
Uh, thanks a lot.
Thank you. Uh,
you want some tea?
I want to know what you're
going to do about Pagglesham.
Pagglesham! Pagglesham!
It's what
we're talking about!
These people
care very much
that their community
doesn't become destroyed
in the name
of free enterprise.
They care because
they are a community
where hundreds of families
have lived for generations.
I know.
These people are not
going to allow you
to intimidate
and frighten them.
I don't
frighten anybody.
Aah! Aah! Aah!
Mmmf!
Oh, my god!
What in god's name
is that?
Well, that--
that was m--
uh, my--
my Mrs. Farnsworth.
Sorry to disturb you,
Mr. Farnsworth.
Mrs. Farnsworth
saw a mouse,
but she's better now.
She just saw a mouse?
No. Before. Outside.
But she relives it.
I'll be in the other room
if you need me, sir.
Excuse me.
What's the matter
with her?
Well, listen, uh...
I don't know.
It's really none
of my business.
Your wife's none
of your business?
Wait. You don't
understand.
I understand one thing.
We will never allow you
to build that refinery.
All right.
I'll build my refinery
in some other place.
Very funny.
If you think I'm going back
to Pagglesham, you're wrong.
I know you're not
afraid of me.
You think a schoolteacher
from a small town
is no challenge for
a world-famous industrialist.
Will you please listen?
Just be quiet a minute.
Just let me say
one thing.
What is it?
Sit down.
Why?
If you'd just sit down,
I think I can explain
something to you
that'll clear
this whole thing up.
I'm not really
Leo Farnsworth.
What?
My name is Joe.
Very funny,
Mr. Farnsworth.
I'm sure you enjoy playing
these insulting little games.
However, I happen
to know about
your board meeting
on Thursday,
which may mean
nothing to you,
but if you think
you can treat women
with the same contempt
your company treats the world,
you've got a lot
to learn about
the strength and persistence
of people like myself.
Don't think you're going
to get away with this.
You got till that board
meeting on Thursday
to find me a body that
can play quarterback.
Darling,
I'm going to let you go.
I'm going
to let you go now.
Listen. There is nothing
to be frightened of.
There's plenty
to be worried about,
but there is nothing
to be frightened of.
Are you all right?
Can I trust you?
Yes, dearest?
Hmm.
You locked me
in a closet.
Only for a moment.
What did you tell him?
You saw a mouse.
I'm not good at spur-
of-the-moment alibis.
He's probably
got enough evidence
to lock us away forever.
I don't understand this.
I saw him inhale
the nose spray.
He never
really inhaled it.
He overheard us somehow.
Maybe he's got us
bugged right now.
An electronics expert
sweeps the place daily.
He's afraid
of being bugged, too.
He's playing with us.
He's playing
a game with us,
that's what it is.
You locked me
in a closet. Why?
Aah!
Hello.
Mr. Farnsworth would
like to see you now.
Yes, indeed. Yes.
Would you excuse me,
Mrs. Farnsworth?
Yes, of course,
Mr. Abbott.
We could take it up
at the board meeting,
but I'm sure it's legal.
Can't you do something
legal and be wrong?
In what sense?
Bad for
somebody else.
What are
you referring to?
Like this refinery
in Pagglesham.
Was that
the living room?
No. That
was my office.
My coordination
is shot, huh?
Yes, sir.
Just not my day.
No, sir.
I wanted to discuss
the Haitian arrangement,
the 2 1/2 million acres.
What 2 1/2 million
acres?
The sugar deal.
It's no good.
The deal?
No. Sugar.
It's bad for the body.
Want me to speak
to the Haitian ambassador?
Check on that
Pagglesham thing.
See if we're
hurting anybody.
If we're
hurting anybody?
Yeah.
Is the wicket bugged?
We certainly wouldn't
want to hurt anybody.
That's the last thing
exo-grey would ever want
to do, isn't that right?
Yeah. We don't want
to hurt anybody.
Thank you.
Ah. "Pagglesham."
He pretended not to know
what a stockholder was.
I can't tell whether
he's toying with me
or if he'd precipitate
a crisis in the company.
Of course he's toying.
Think he'll forget
being drugged?
Why would he pretend?
For the same reason
he pretended to inhale
the nose spray--to bait us.
He's waiting
for us to crack.
Do you actually think
he's playing that saxophone?
There's a tape inside.
That's why we hear
the same song over and over.
It's like those
idiot costumes of his.
You are dumb, aren't you?
Thanks.
Thank you.
Their magic number
is now just one,
meaning
a ram victory Sunday
or next week
against the falcons
or a 49er loss,
and the rams clinch
the NFL western division title.
The way
they've been playing,
the team feels
this is the rams' year
to go
to the super bowl.
Jarrett has completed
an astounding 62%
of his passes
for 18 touchdowns.
The defense has given up
but 10 points a game,
while the offense is
scoring 21 points a game.
The rams' record
is the best...
What you're saying
is that, um...
Nobody should have
that information,
because if 2 big
companies get together,
they're worth
more money, huh?
Yes, sir.
That's why the rumor
of a merger
makes the price
of the stock rise.
If it's supposed
to be a secret,
how does
the rumor start?
Well, sir,
wrong as it seems,
they leak it.
But that's
dishonest, isn't it?
Yes, it is.
Well...
If I got a board
meeting tomorrow,
I got to do a lot
of studying tonight.
Yes, sir.
How you doing
down there?
Oh, I'm doing fine.
Thank you very much.
Yeah?
Thanks.
Thanks a lot.
Say, uh,
thanks for dinner.
I think we should
do it right away.
Sisk, may we have some
more coffee, please?
And now
for your hat, sir.
Do you wish the homburg
or the bowler, sir,
or something that makes
more of a statement?
Whatever you say.
Why have I got so many
of these sailor outfits?
Oh, sir, you have
always fancied the sea.
Uh-huh. Do I sail?
Not really, sir.
Uh-huh.
Ok, ok.
Mr. Farnsworth, I'm
Helen rich from the times.
I've this petition from
the citizens of Pagglesham.
Do you plan to do
anything about it?
We're taking that
under consideration.
We really
have to be going.
Mr. Farnsworth,
is it true
that 3 newly proposed
exo-grey factories
will displace
11 communities?
11?
Is it that many?
They granted the permits
to build them.
I guess so,
if we got 'em.
How did exo-grey
get those permits?
Beats me. I guess
we bribed somebody.
He's joking.
Really,
we must be going.
Mr. Farnsworth,
what about
acrilonitrile?
What about what?
Acrilonitrile--
the toxic substance
released
by the plastic bottles
your company markets
despite the consumer
protection league's lawsuit
forcing you
to delay distribution
until the effects
have been tested.
I've been studying
this thing.
Why don't you
come inside
and see what's
going on yourselves?
You can't have
outsiders--
sure, we can.
Come on in,
everybody.
Hi.
Hi. How you doing,
everybody? I, uh...
These people are reporters
from some of the newspapers.
I thought it would be good
if they saw
how we did things.
Leo, this is a very
dangerous precedent.
We have a very full
agenda today already.
I don't see that we
have time for a press--
couldn't an accident in your
west coast nuclear plant
stimulate seismic activity
in the San Andreas fault,
which could destroy most
of Southern California?
I think you'd have
to define "destroy."
Excuse me,
ladies and gentlemen.
I'd like to make
something perfectly clear.
The exo-grey
nuclear facility
has a foolproof
built-in safety system
that guarantees
no danger of any kind.
That's rubbish.
If there's no danger,
why are
we in a lawsuit?
It's a protest,
not a lawsuit.
That's not the point.
We're doing
something wrong.
Everybody's suing us.
We got a lawsuit
from a refinery,
a nuclear lawsuit.
A guy named porpoise
is suing us.
Uh, Mr. Farnsworth,
that's an ecological suit
brought against
our canning factory
for destroying
porpoises.
Ahem. Uh...
For god's sake,
he knows that.
We can porpoises?
Our San Diego
fleet is...
As everybody
here knows,
we can tuna.
In netting the tuna,
we kill a number
of porpoises.
Since they're mammals of
alleged high intelligence,
there's been
an outcry.
Yeah...well...
Uh...
Yeah.
I would just like
to ask you a question.
Why is he bringing
the press in here?
You know Leo Farnsworth.
Maybe I don't know
Leo Farnsworth.
Exactly.
We have a corporate
responsibility
extending to thousands
of shareholders
of moderate means,
people who are
less well off
than the ecological
groups fighting us.
If we were
a football team,
would you say we had
a winning season so far?
Leo, I haven't the faintest
idea what you're--
just generally.
Would you say
we got a winning season?
I would say on balance
we have had
an extremely good year.
We've got a winning season.
What do you do when
you're ahead in the game?
I don't know
what you want.
I'll tell you,
you don't make mistakes.
You don't gamble
unnecessarily.
You got
to protect your lead.
You don't pass
from your own end zone.
You make sure
nobody gets hurt.
You got to use these
guys in the next game.
We won this game.
We got to stay in shape
for the rest of the game.
That's the responsible
thing to do.
It's like when
everybody was supposed
to stop eating grapes.
I didn't
'cause I didn't know
about it.
A lot of guys
will keep eating tuna.
But I was thinking,
what if we had
a good-guy tuna company
on the porpoise team?
Guys would buy that
so kids wouldn't
get mad at them.
I don't think they're
taking in account...
The expense.
We don't care
how much it costs,
just how much it makes.
If it costs too much,
we charge a penny more.
Would you pay more
to save fish who thinks?
And we handle
all the lawsuits that way.
Let other teams
build power plants
in the wrong places.
Let the other quarterback
throw a gurgle out
so newspapers
get ahold of it.
Let's be the team
that makes the rules.
Let us be the team
that plays fair.
Let's be
the popular players.
We'll have to forget
these nuclear power plants
until we know
they're safe.
That refinery
in Pagglesham,
we'll have
to relocate it.
It'll cost us $35 million,
but we're going
to come out ahead.
Whatever that stuff is
we're making, that plastic,
we'll have to stop.
We're not in here
for just one game, are we?
We're going all the way.
Let's get
to the super bowl!
When we get there,
let's already have won!
Hi. How you doing?
Oh, just fine.
Thank you.
Very well. Mm-hmm.
I'm just...
What is happening?
...And give the rams
home field advantage
through the playoffs
and the super bowl.
This super bowl
is set for the coliseum.
If he weren't going
to be dead soon,
he'd need years
of psychiatric help.
Let's do it tonight.
The rams will probably
face Dallas
in the opening round
of the playoffs.
If they win--
Mr. Pendleton.
Hey!
...Championship
on the 26th.
Am I glad
to see you.
Line up
any bodies yet?
We haven't got
a lot of time--
uh...the, uh...
...And only
4 measly field goals.
Uh, hi.
I--I'm just...
They're home
against Cincinnati...
What's up?
We have a number of
interesting probabilities.
I kept my word
to Betty Logan.
Did you find a body
in good shape?
I want to see
some bodies.
Ahem.
Somebody with
good legs, good arms.
The super bowl's
coming up.
You must have checked
a lot of bodies--
who is it?
It's sisk, sir.
Come in, sisk.
Sorry to disturb you,
Mr. Farnsworth,
but miss Betty Logan
is downstairs
and asks if she might have
a moment of your time.
Betty l--
uh...
Tell her
I'll be right down.
Ah. Very good, sir.
Do you, uh...
Do you wish
the door closed, sir?
Uh...
Closed is fine.
Thank you.
Do the best
you can do.
I got to see
what she wants.
Hi.
Um...
Mr. Farnsworth,
I don't know what
you must think of me
after my behavior
at our first meeting,
but I feel
I must tell you
what an extraordinary thing
it is you did today.
You don't
have to say--
no, it's...
Because i--i--
you know what? Uh...
You look
a little pale.
You want
something to eat?
I'll be right back.
Bentley. Everett.
Miss Logan's going to
have dinner with us,
so put on another plate.
Whip up
a liver and whey shake.
Where you going?
Oh, I thought...
You thought
I meant to go out.
Sisk, we're going out.
Come on.
Bentley! Everett!
We're going out and eat.
Which hat
would you prefer?
Look, I don't want
to wear a hat.
I'm sick of hats.
Don't show me
any more hats.
Yes, sir.
No more hats.
It's, uh...
Do you eat here often?
Are you--nah, look...
I didn't think
you'd want people
to see you out
with a guy like me.
I see.
Pick up 24.
Pick up 28.
I'm sorry.
I just can't
stop staring at you.
I seem to be staring
at you, too.
Even when I was
trying to hate you,
I couldn't help
seeing something else,
something...
What?
In your eyes.
Does that sound silly?
When you see
something like that,
it doesn't matter
what a person looks like
or who they are
or anything.
What is it?
This isn't what I thought
was going to happen to me.
Listen, I got to talk
to somebody right away.
Would you mind
if I took you home?
Uh...
I, uh...
Good night.
Good--good night.
Oh, hey, by the way,
I'm getting a divorce.
But you and your wife
aren't even separated.
Oh, sure, we are.
It's a big house.
Oh.
Hey! How you
doing, Bentley?
Fine, sir.
Mr. Pendleton?
Oh.
Hi.
Uh...
I don't
want that body
we've been
talking about.
Something
happened tonight.
This is an outrage.
We've gone to
enormous difficulties
to find you an athlete.
I wanted it,
but that was before.
Something happened
with Betty Logan.
I changed my mind,
that's all.
I'll get Farnsworth's
body into shape.
I'll get corkle
to help me...
Back in there, eh?
Oh, yes.
I can do it.
I know more about getting
into shape than anybody.
So hold up on that body.
Hold up on the body?
Tell Mr. Jordan
not to worry about it.
Thank him.
I'm very sorry.
I want to get into shape
with this body.
You leave me speechless.
I have nothing
to say to that.
I can't even think
how to retort
to something as ridiculous
as turning down a body
we've gone
to such extremes to find,
and an athlete at that,
in prime condition.
I don't
know what to say.
What do I do
with his cocoa?
I don't want
to disturb him,
but it'll get cold.
I notice
there are 2 cups.
Sisk felt since
he was pretending
to talk to somebody,
he might want to pretend
to give him cocoa, too.
Hey, how you doing, Everett?
How you doing, Bentley?
Hurry up. Hurry up.
Wait a minute.
Just a minute, please.
All right.
I'm sorry to bother you,
but we don't love
each other,
so let's get divorced.
Leo, I don't know
what you're talking about.
Come on. Yes, you do.
Abbott, there's
a trainer for the rams
named Max corkle.
Could you call and ask
him to come see me?
Yes, Mr. Farnsworth.
Thank you.
Good night.
You idiot! You idiot!
Why did you answer him?
I couldn't resist.
His will is too strong.
That's
our weekend forecast.
Now here's Bryant gumbel
with tonight's sports.
Leach and char
will have to--
he's dead.
It's over with.
...Left for Philadelphia
this morning,
hoping to play
their last road--
at last,
at last.
At last,
my dearest.
It's incredible.
Yes! Just a minute. Yes!
Yes, sisk.
And, uh, abbott,
corkle's number
is 654-1654.
Yes, Mr. Farnsworth.
Ok.
Oh, my god.
Right this way.
Mr. Farnsworth
is waiting for you
in the ballroom.
Follow me, please.
Mr. Corkle, sir.
Max.
How you doing?
Fine.
Max...
Hey, lost a little
weight, huh?
Have we met?
Uh, sort of. Yeah.
Thanks, sisk.
Hey.
Max, ha!
I hear you got
all Joe Pendleton's
athletic equipment.
Yeah. How'd you
know that?
I'd like to buy it
from you.
I'd like to
bring it in here.
No, I'm sorry,
Mr. Farnsworth.
That's not for sale.
No?
What do you want it for?
I'd like you
to help me train.
Oh, train?
Yeah. As soon as
I'm ready...
I want you to get me
a tryout with the rams.
I don't understand.
What are you trying out for?
Quarterback.
Yeah, well, the point is,
Mr. Farnsworth,
we already got a quarterback
working with the team.
We got a couple
of pretty good backups.
You call Hodges
good, huh?
The point is we don't
need a quarterback.
Look, why don't you try
one of the other teams?
The Oakland raiders
are pretty close to L.A.
Give them a call
and see what they say.
I want to
get in shape
in time
for the super bowl.
What would it cost
to try out?
Look, Mr. Farnsworth,
no team wants a crazy trainer,
and only a crazy trainer
would arrange a tryout for you.
You keep your money,
I'll keep my job,
and we'll keep this little
misunderstanding to ourselves.
Hey, listen--
that's all right.
I'll finish that up.
What would you say
if I told you
I was a professional
football player?
Boy, hey, these--
these are nice.
Max...
You know
how people die?
Yeah. Why?
And after they die,
they go to heaven?
I guess,
if--if they're good.
I mean, why not?
You know how it
works in heaven?
Not exactly.
It's probability
and outcome.
Probability
I never knew that.
Let's say there's
a probability
that some guy's
going to die.
What happens is
an escort
from his way station
gets a signal.
He goes down and waits
for the outcome.
If the guy lives,
he wasted a trip.
If he dies,
he picks him up
and takes him back
to his way station.
He puts him in line for
his final destination.
Mind if I smoke?
Go ahead.
Let's say there's
a new escort.
He gets a signal.
He takes off
and sees a guy
riding a bicycle
into a tunnel.
The car's coming
the other way.
He's supposed to wait
for the outcome,
but he's new and figures
the guy's a goner.
He figures, why should I
have the car hit him?
Why not take him out
a few seconds early
and take him
up to his way station?
Listen, I, uh...
Need a match.
That clock,
that's a lighter.
So the thing is,
the guy he takes up
to the way station
isn't just
some ordinary guy.
He's an athlete with
fantastic reflexes.
He wouldn't have hit
the car at all, see?
How do you
light this?
The guy
wasn't really dead.
His number
wasn't up for years.
He would have
missed the car.
Look at the time.
Is this lighter right?
They're supposed to put
him back in his body,
but they can't 'cause
he's been cremated.
They have to find
another body for him.
Now, look, Mr. Farnsworth,
I'm just a trainer.
What you need is
like a really good doctor.
Don't you understand
what I'm trying to say?
Sure. That's
a hell of a story.
Max, you--
Mr. Jordan.
I'm so glad
to see you.
I'm trying to
get Farnsworth
into shape for
the super bowl.
I want corkle
to help me.
Somebody with us?
Who are you talking to?
Mr. Jordan. He runs
the way station.
You can't see him.
You're still alive.
You probably got
a lot to talk about.
I'll be on my way.
Wait a second, Max.
Tell him
who you are, Joe.
He's never going to
believe me.
He's the only
person I know
who can get me
a tryout with the rams.
You can make him
believe you.
Max! I'm not Farnsworth.
I'm Joe Pendleton.
Farnsworth's wife and
secretary murdered him.
This is just a body
they found for me.
They drugged him,
stuck him in a bathtub,
then I stepped in.
It's not bad material.
I can get it into shape.
Max, please.
Look, I really
want to get out of here.
I won't tell
a word to anybody.
I promise. It'll be
our little secret.
Like what you said
about your sister
and the Coca-Cola
salesman?
What about
that scar you got
on the bottom
of your tongue?
What did you do at
your uncle's wedding?
What about
the first time
I fixed your neck
in Pittsburgh?
Now do you
believe me, Max?
Please say
you believe me.
They don't have
a football team in heaven,
so god couldn't
make me first-string.
He doesn't believe me,
Mr. Jordan.
Try a little
music, Joe.
That's a great
persuader.
Joe, you never could
play that thing.
Joe.
You all right, Max?
Max...
You all right?
Sisk!
Everett!
Bentley!
Whip up a liver and whey
shake right away!
I'm gonna play quarterback
in the super bowl.
And nothing can change that,
right, Mr. Jordan?
If that's what you've
got coming to you.
He's still here?
Right there.
Max, listen to me.
Farnsworth isn't
in bad shape.
I still know
the moves.
Just help me
with the body.
Thanks, Mr. Jordan.
Sisk! How about that
liver and whey shake?
Hurry up. Hurry up.
I need it
for Mr. Corkle.
Yes, sir.
Right away.
I want the whole staff
to suit up.
We're going
into training.
Uh, listen,
Mr., uh...Jordan, is it?
Huh?
You still there?
Uh, anytime
you want to chime in...
Why, just feel free.
Feel free. I'm telling you
to feel free.
You got to help me
talk Joe out of this.
If I do get him a tryout,
that team will put him
out of commission like that.
Christ, I can't even
snap my fingers anymore.
Oh, sorry.
He's not there, Max.
Don't get crazy on me.
I'm counting on you.
This just
isn't going to work.
These are the L.A. rams
we're fooling with.
It--it's just--
well, all right.
I'm still figuring out
what I'll say. I...
You're playing football
with a bunch of butlers.
We're in the super bowl.
This won't work.
Don't worry.
I fixed all that.
How?
I bought the rams.
Leo Farnsworth has
bought this team,
and he wants
to play quarterback.
Shit!
Crazy son of a bitch.
We won't take
this bullshit, coach.
Wait a minute.
Listen, fellas.
This is the way it is.
He'll play quarterback
in Wednesday's scrimmage.
At which time, he and
the coach will decide
whether he's qualified
for the job or not.
Mr. Farnsworth says,
"tell no one to hold back."
These were his words.
"Let's play that scrimmage
like the super bowl."
Take him at his word.
Let's kill him.
My team.
That son of a bitch
got my team.
What kind of pressure
did he use, milt?
Well, I asked for
67 million, and...
He said, "ok."
Ruthless bastard.
Well, very, very nice.
Very, very, impressive.
I'm Tony abbott,
Mr. Farnsworth's
personal secretary.
Very nice.
Very...Very nice.
Don't let any
of Mr. Farnsworth's
racial statements
offend you,
for god's sakes.
Nice--nice talking
to you.
Get rid of that ball
fast, all right?
Good luck,
Mr. Farnsworth.
All right, don't worry
about the plays.
I think I got them down
last night.
I want to run
a split right, x-go,
z-curl, a y-straight.
Like the super bowl.
Break.
Ready? Break.
Look at gorman
and kowalsky.
That's how they look
when they eat.
4-3, set!
Hut!
2-85!
Hut.
Sorry, Mr. Farnsworth.
Nice.
Let's try it again,
Mr. Farnsworth.
Ok, get him
back in there.
Let's go!
Try it with the ball!
Come on, positions!
Playing football
is so much fun.
Set!
Come on now!
2-81!
Hut!
Hut--
I'm terribly sorry,
Mr. Farnsworth.
This is really
embarrassing.
Help him up.
I guess
you went offsides.
Come on, guys,
get him,
get him, get him.
Give me a little
more room, Billy.
Set!
Let's all try
and stay onsides.
2-85!
Hut!
Better get a stretcher.
Jesus!
Look, Harry,
he's an eccentric.
We've always known that
about Farnsworth.
Buying a football
team for 67 million
that has
a book value of 19?
3 weeks ago,
the stock sold at 56.
This morning
it opened at 14.
You want a rest,
Mr. Farnsworth?
No, no, it's ok.
Mr. Leo Farnsworth intends
to take the Los Angeles rams
to the super bowl this season
as their quarterback.
No sign of aberration
in his behavior?
Nothing in his personal
life bothering him?
I think this statement
speaks for itself.
All right,
I'm going to save you guys
some trouble.
Want me to quit?
Give me the ball once.
If I don't hit Evans,
I'll quit.
Ready? Break!
Hey, now!
On 3!
Set!
Hut!
Beautiful! Ha ha ha!
There's a potential there,
huh? He's...
Ok, ok.
Take it easy,
Mr. Farnsworth.
I know.
Shit, man,
what you doing?
What's he doing?
Ready? Break.
Red right, red right.
Watch the pass.
4-3.
Set! 3!
Hut!
1-81!
I think we got us
a rich quarterback.
He's looking
awful good.
Boy,
you pulled it off.
You really
pulled it off.
Yeah? I don't know.
I think I can do it.
Hey, Mr. Farnsworth,
play any college ball?
No. I played
a little Polo.
Look, look, look.
He brought the whole
goddamn team home.
That's not
a football team.
There are older men
and skinny younger men.
Look at the women.
That's
the ecology group
that exo-grey
is funding.
He's getting ready to
spring some kind of a trap.
This whole thing--
the football team gag,
the ecology crap,
the divorce bit--
it's all part
of some plot.
The minute he announces
our divorce,
I'll be the first suspect
when we kill him.
Darling, perhaps
I'm just being silly,
but I'd be
much more comfortable--
have I offended you
in some way?
Don't put your hand
over my mouth again.
I'm sorry, darling.
You used to like it.
If we don't do something,
we'll lose it all.
I should have
my head examined
for signing
a prenuptial agreement.
I'll wind up with my wardrobe
and some allowance.
You'll be fired
without references.
We'll still have
each other.
Not after the last 2 murders.
Don't you try it.
The problem is,
if a neighbor's tree
is in the way
of the sewer...
Want to make a wish?
Yes.
All right.
There.
Go ahead.
Hey, very good.
Hey.
Uh...
Tell me, do you
think it's silly,
me trying to be
a football player?
Of course not.
That's what you want.
You think
I can do it?
I think you could do
anything you wanted.
Anything you committed
to do you could do.
'Cause I'm a big wheel
at exo-grey.
It's 'cause you're
not afraid of things.
Afraid of things?
Why would I be
afraid?
Well, you know,
most people are afraid
of something, aren't they?
You want to know the
only thing I'm afraid of?
How I'd feel if I
couldn't be with you.
Then there's nothing
to be afraid of, is there?
Got to go.
Wait a minute.
I'd--the--
how would you feel
about marrying me?
It's crazy, huh?
No, it doesn't sound crazy.
You know, if--if I...
What is it?
Could you wait here?
I'll be right back.
What do you want?
I'm sorry,
Mr. Pendleton.
I'm afraid you won't
be able to use
Mr. Farnsworth's body
any longer.
What are you
talking about?
Just what I said--
your time is up.
You don't fit.
You said I'd get
to the super bowl.
You can't do it with
Mr. Farnsworth's body.
Why not?
It wasn't meant to be.
Don't keep saying
"why not?"
You think I'll pay
for your mistake?
Look, Mr. Pendleton--
I'm not talking
to you.
Tell Mr. Jordan I'd
like to talk to him.
We'll settle this
once and for all.
Get out of here.
You're bad news.
Is something wrong?
Um, no, it's--
I just got to straighten
something out.
Maybe I better
walk you to the car.
Oh.
Something is wrong,
isn't it?
I was just thinking,
Betty.
We got a great life
ahead, you and me,
and nobody's going to
take that away from us.
Why are you looking
at me like that?
I'm just
memorizing your face.
I want to memorize
everything about you.
No matter what happens,
I won't forget you.
What's going to happen?
Nothing's
going to happen.
You'd never forget me
either, would you?
No.
That thing you said
you saw in me...
It was something in
my eyes. Remember?
If someday somebody
came up to you--
maybe
a football player--
and he acted like
he'd seen you before,
you'd notice
that same thing, right?
You'd give him
a chance, right?
He could even be
a quarterback.
I don't understand
what you're saying.
Ahh, I'm just
acting crazy.
Betty?
It's all right.
There's nothing
to be afraid of.
You must abide
by what is written.
Why? I don't understand.
There's a reason
for everything.
There's always a plan.
How can I give up
Farnsworth now?
I'm sorry, Joe.
You said we'd get
to the super bowl.
If it's meant to be.
I'm not leaving.
Sorry.
I'm not leaving,
Mr. Jordan.
Joe, you yourself asked for
a temporary arrangement.
I never went back
on a deal,
but I'm doing it now.
Your destiny
is not in my hands.
Please don't make it
more difficult.
I won't. I'm just
not going to do it.
Joe, you must abide
by what is written.
She loves me,
Mr. Jordan.
Joe, you must abide
by what is written.
Don't be afraid, Joe.
There is a plan.
There's always a plan.
Mr. Farnsworth?
Hello, Bentley.
Have you seen
Mr. Farnsworth?
No, sir, I haven't.
Guess I'll just
have to keep looking.
Yes, sir.
Joe?
Joe, you in here?
Are you in there,
Mr. Farnsworth?
Yes.
Yes!
Listen, your highness,
I'm telling you
what I told
the mayor last week.
By the end of the week,
I'll crack this case.
Right.
Another arab.
Son of a bitch Farnsworth
was into everything,
and now he's vanished,
disappeared.
This is
the craziest nut
I've ever had
to deal with.
If he was alive,
he'd be here.
You're asking me
to believe
Leo Farnsworth
asked you to marry him?
Yes. He was going
to get a divorce.
He said he'd call me,
but something happened.
How do you know?
Because he didn't call me,
and he would have
kept his word.
Hmm.
With less than 24 hours
before the big game,
the whereabouts
of Leo Farnsworth
remains a mystery.
Farnsworth said
his wife and Tony abbott
were trying to kill him,
and he told me how.
Let me talk to abbott.
I can make him crack.
Ok.
Take corkle to the
Farnsworth house.
The game.
And if you win this one...
You're going to be
champions of the world.
And they can take away
the money and the cheers.
They can...
Take away
the good looks,
but nobody will ever
take that away from you.
Let's go.
Let me get this straight.
You're saying you saw
no specific changes
in Mr. Farnsworth's
behavior?
No, sir. A bit
more talkative,
but other than
that, normal.
And that's your opinion,
too, Mr. Sisk?
Yes. I did notice
he seemed to take a
dislike to his hats,
but it
was never violent.
Why don't you ask me
whatever you want and--
Mr. Corkle, please.
Mr. Everett.
Oh. Uh, y-y-yes?
You had cocoa
with him every night.
Uh, yes.
What did you talk about?
Well, he'd say
something like,
uh, "this cocoa
is good, isn't it?"
And I'd say, uh,
"yes, it is."
And then he'd say
something like, uh,
"I wish the marshmallow
would last longer."
And I'd say,
uh, "so do I."
Uh...
Sometimes he talked
about cookies.
Thank you,
Mr. Everett.
Oh, did he ever mention
disliking his hats?
What difference
does it make--
I'm following a line
of questioning here.
Did he ever say anything
to you about his hats?
Never, sir.
Thank you,
Mr. Everett.
What did you discuss
the last time you saw him?
He was considering
buying Haiti.
Yes, sir.
The country?
Thank you, Mr. Abbott.
Nothing about hats?
No.
Thank you, Mr. Abbott.
Mrs. Farnsworth,
what was your relationship
with your husband?
Very, very close.
Very, very special.
Miss Logan claims
he was getting a divorce
and that he asked her
to marry him.
I don't doubt that.
My husband loved me
very, very much,
but he was a man.
He would say or do anything
to make a conquest,
but, lieutenant, it never
touched our marriage.
That's what made it
so special.
They're trying
to pin it on Betty.
Miss Logan, I am sorry
if I've said anything
that's hurt you.
I don't know you well
enough for you to hurt me.
I hope you don't
doubt my word.
I don't. I'm absolutely
sure that you're lying.
I assume
if Mr. Farnsworth
told you anything
about disliking his hats,
you'd let us know.
You want to know
about his hats?
He didn't care,
but he wouldn't
wear socks with a suit!
Every time
he crossed his legs,
you could see
his ankles were bare!
And he thought hats
looked funny without socks!
But he never told you
he disliked them.
What?
His hats.
What kind of questions
are you asking?
All right. Sit down.
Conway,
turn that thing on.
Let him watch the game.
Everything's going
to be all right.
We're getting
a clearer picture
of Mr. Farnsworth's
patterns.
There's a reason
for everything.
There's got to be.
It's a demanding defense.
You don't need
to worry about her.
Tom Jarrett,
the rams' quarterback,
back to pass.
Looking, scrambling.
He's in trouble.
And he's hit hard!
Down he goes!
What you're telling me,
Mr. Abbott,
is that Mr. Farnsworth
never carried any money
or credit cards, right?
And no identification
papers, right?
Right, sir. Yes.
Then what
we have here...
The score, 24-24.
Overtime.
The way he was hit,
Tom Jarrett is hurt.
We can see the ram players
are concerned
and they're calling
for the stretcher.
Jarrett has not moved.
It'll be a miracle,
frankly,
and I hope he's well.
He really got hit.
Now they order
Jerry Hodges
to start warming up
on the sidelines.
The Pittsburgh defense
has been brilliant.
They've stopped
the rams with--
the Haitian
ambassador's here.
Oh, yes. Yes,
thank you, sisk.
Give him a coke.
Tell him to wait.
Who do you
think you are?
You have a nerve to call
this an investigation!
Now!
How'd you do it
this time, huh?
Did you drug him
like you did before?
This one has seesawed
back and forth.
Lieutenant, I will not
be spoken to in this way
in my house.
Why did it have
to be Jarrett?
Because it's
his time, Joe.
It's his destiny.
Look at the pupils!
Bill, bill!
Get that ambulance!
And Jarrett's coming
back into the game.
Joe...
Oh, my god!
It's his jacket!
So it's you, Mr. Abbott!
I should have known
I couldn't trust you.
Lieutenant,
here's your murderer!
She did it!
I'll sign a confession
that she did it!
She's been planning
it for years!
Corkle, where
are you going?
I'm going
to the coliseum.
I'm conducting
an investigation here.
I'm going to the game.
Take this investigation
and shove it
up your ass!
3-23. Hut! Hut!
It's sudden death
overtime!
Jarrett's sending
this crowd into delirium!
The crowd watching Jarrett.
He was sacked hard.
He's getting up.
He's ok.
2-3...set!
2-85! 2-85!
Hut! Hut!
A remarkable comeback
by Jarrett.
Jarrett trying to get them
into field goal position.
Set!
2...
All right!
We're number one!
We did it!
Joe!
Hi, Max.
I am right.
It is you, isn't it?
Yeah.
Ha ha ha ha!
I knew it!
I was watching the TV,
and I said,
"that's him! That's him!"
The rams are
super bowl champions!
Here's the star,
Tom Jarrett.
He led his team
to victory.
How do you feel?
Good.
I mean, can you
describe your feelings?
World champions!
I, uh, I feel good.
Please, please.
I have
to go now, Joe.
It's time.
I can't stay here
any longer.
What do you mean?
How does it feel
to be Tom Jarrett?
And when I've gone,
you won't remember me.
You'll be Thomas Jarrett
with no memory
of Joe Pendleton
or Leo Farnsworth or
anything that's happened.
This is
your destiny, Joe.
You're back on
your own road now.
What do you mean,
I won't remember?
Good-bye, Joe.
There's a lot
of confusion.
Wait. I got to talk
to you. Wait.
Good-bye.
Tom, congratulations.
Here he is--
coach of...
You ok, Tom?
You ok?
Here's Lamar Crawford,
the man who caught
one of those key passes.
I'm just happy
that we won.
In September, I told you
the beginning of this season!
Ha ha!
Hey, Benny!
Hey, Joe! Uh, Tom!
Hey, doc.
Did Tom leave?
He's putting
some ice on his eye.
He'll be all right.
That's something about
Farnsworth, isn't it?
Poor son of a bitch.
Yeah, isn't it?
Hey. Corkle.
What are you doing,
closing up the joint?
I didn't know you
played that thing.
What are you
talking about?
Hmm? Is that yours?
What are you
talking about?
What do you mean?
You know what I mean.
I mean, what are you
talking about, Joe?
Am I missing
something?
Come on.
What are you trying
to do to me, huh?
Hey, I'm the guy that
got hit in the head.
You sure you're
all right, corkle?
Huh? Huh?
Hey, play something
for me on this thing, huh?
That's the way it is
with champagne, huh?
You just keep
swallowing it
'cause it doesn't
taste like anything,
and all of a sudden,
you're drunk.
You going
to the party, corkle?
I'll give you a ride.
Hey, you--
a little fresh air
wouldn't hurt.
Hey, look.
Just do me one favor.
Uh, look at me.
Just--just...
Just look at me.
What?
Joe.
Uh...
You want to tell me why
you're calling me Joe?
I guess it has
something to do with...
Joe Pendleton.
Hey, uh...
I'm sorry.
I didn't think, corkle.
You sure you
don't want a ride?
No, I'll just, uh...
I'm going to sit
here for a minute.
Ok.
Hey, son, you--
you played
a hell of a game.
Oh, thanks, corkle.
You all right?
Yeah.
Ok.
Oh, excuse me.
Where might I
find Max corkle?
I believe
he's here somewhere.
Yeah. He's in
the locker room.
Go back up there
the way you came
or take a right
and then a left.
It's the second door
on the right.
I see. Thank you.
Thank you.
He's not
expecting me.
Is it ok if
I just walk in?
Sure. He's the only guy
in there, uh...
Have we met?
No. I don't think so.
No, I guess
we haven't.
I'm sorry, uh...
What did you think
of the game?
I--i didn't see it.
Does your eye hurt?
No, no, I...
Listen, my name's
Tom Jarrett.
Hello. I'm Betty Logan.
Yeah. Well, it's
nice to meet you.
You must play
for the rams.
You're interested
in football?
A friend of mine was.
Was?
Leo Farnsworth.
I'm sorry. Was
he a close friend?
Yes, he was
very close.
Oh, that's too bad.
I'm sorry.
Have you put
some ice on that?
What's that?
They're just
closing up the place.
Here, give me your hand.
It's all right. There's
nothing to be afraid of.
Uh...you can--you--
what did you say?
What?
Just then,
when you said--
"there's nothing
to be afraid of,"
your voice sounded
so familiar.
Yeah?
Well, like I said,
I thought
I knew you, too.
People are always thinking
they knew somebody before.
Yes, they are.
Uh, I was going to
meet a bunch of people.
We're having a party,
and I'm a little late.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Oh, no, no, no, uh...
I mean, all of a sudden,
I don't feel like going
to a big party, and--
and, uh,
I thought maybe if--
I mean...
You want to have
a cup of coffee?
Well, I guess not.
You're the quarterback.
Yeah.
How'd you know that?
Yes, I'd love to have
a cup of coffee with you.
Captioning made possible by
Paramount pictures corporation
captioning performed by
the national captioning
institute, inc.
Captions copyright 1998
Paramount pictures corporation