This will begin to make things right.
I travelled too far and seen too much to
ignore the despair in the galaxy.
Without the Jedi, there can
be no balance in the Force.
Because of you, now we have a chance.
The General has been
after this for a long time.
The General?
To me she is royalty.
Well she certainly is that.
We've got company.
You have to hide.
You have to leave.
Go!
Come on BB-8, hurry!
Shoot him that X-wing!
There! There!
I see them.
You take this.
It's safer with you than it is with me.
You get as far away
from here as you can.
Did you hear me?
I'll come back for you.
It'll be all right.
Keep moving!
Stay here.
Look how old you've become.
Something far worse has happened to you.
You know what I've come for.
I know where you come from.
Before you called yourself Kylo Ren.
The map to Skywalker.
We know you found it.
And now you're going to
give it to the First Order.
The First Order arose
from the dark side.
You did not.
I'll show you the dark side.
You may try.
But you cannot deny the truth
that is your family.
You're so right.
So who talks first?
Do you talk first? I talk first?
The old man gave it to you.
It's very hard to understand
you with all those
Search him.
Apparatus.
Nothing, sir.
Bring him on board.
Sir, the villagers?
Kill them all!
On my command.
Fire!
No Please!
Nothing here! Keep moving!
All right, all right!
FN-2187.
Send your blaster for inspection.
Yes, Captain.
And who gave you permission
to remove that helmet?
I'm sorry, Captain.
Report to my division at once.
What you brought me today is worth ...
one quarter portion.
Tal'ama parqual!
Parqual! Zatana!
Noma!
Shh!
That's just Teedo.
Wants you for parts.
He has no respect for anyone.
Your antenna is bent.
Where do you come from?
Classified, really?
Me too. Big secret.
Niima Outpost is that way.
Stay off Kelvin Ridge.
Keep away from the sinking fields in the north.
You will drown in the sand.
Don't follow me.
The town is that way.
No!
In the morning you go.
You are welcome.
I had no idea we had the best
pilot of the Resistance on board.
Are you comfortable?
Not really.
I'm impressed.
No one has been
able to get out of you
What did you did with the map.
Might want to rethink
your technique.
Where is it?
The Resistance will not
be intimidated by you.
Where is it?
It's in a droid. A BB unit.
Well then, if it's on Jakku,
we'll soon have it.
I'll leave it to you.
Don't give up hope.
He still might show up.
Whoever it is your
waiting for, Classified.
I know all about waiting.
My family.
They'll be back.
One day.
Come on.
These five pieces are worth ...
Let me see...
One half portion.
Last week they were
a half portion each.
What about the droid?
What about him?
I'll pay for him.
60 portions.
Actually...
The droid is not for sale.
Come on.
Follow the girl and get that droid.
Ren wants the prisoner.
Turn here.
Listen carefully. If you do exactly
as I say, I can get out of here.
What?
This is a rescue.
I'm helping you escape.
Can you fly a TIE fighter?
Are you with the Resistance?
What? No no.
I'm breaking you out.
- Can you fly a TIE fighter?
- I can fly anything.
Why? Why are you helping me?
Because it is the
right thing to do.
You need a pilot.
I need a pilot.
We're gonna do this.
Yeah?
Okay, stay calm.
Stay calm.
I am calm.
I'm talking to myself.
Not yet.
Okay, go. This way.
I always wanted to fly one of these things.
- Can you shoot?
- Blasters, I can.
Okay, same principle.
Use the toggle on the left to switch between
missiles, cannons and pulses.
Use the sight on the right to aim.
The triggers to fire.
This is very complicated.
I can fix this.
An unsanctioned departure from bay 2.
Alert General Hux.
And stop to that fighter.
14, missed 18 ...
I got it.
This really moves.
All right we gotta take out as many of these
cannons as we can if we're going to get very far.
All right.
I'm gonna get us in position.
Just stay sharp!
Up ahead! Up ahead!
You see it?
I got us dead center.
It's a clean shot.
- Yeah!
- Yes!
You see that? Did you see that?
I saw it!
Hey, what's your name?
FN-2187.
F ... what?
It's the only name they ever gave me.
Well, I ain't using it.
F-N, huh?
Finn. I'm gonna call you Finn.
That all right?
Finn. Yes. Finn, I like that.
I like that.
I am Poe. Poe Dameron.
- Good to meet you, Poe.
- Good to meet you too, Finn.
Sir, they've taken out
our turbolasers.
Use the ventral cannons.
Yes sir. Bringing them online.
General Hux, is it
the Resistance pilot?
Yes, and he had help.
From one of our own.
We are checking the registers now
to identify which Stormtrooper it was.
The one from the village.
FN-2187.
Sir, ventral cannon's hot.
Fire.
It's coming towards you!
On my right. Your left. See it?
Hold on. I see it!
Nice shot!
Where we going?
We're going back to Jakku.
That's where.
Oh no, we can't go back to Jakku.
We need to get out of this system.
I got to get my droid before
the First Order does.
Your droid?
- That's right.
It's a BB unit, orange and white.
One of a kind.
I do not care what color he is!
No droid can be as important.
This one is, pal!
We have to move as far away
from the First Order as we can.
If we go back to Jakku, we die.
The droid has a map that
leads straight to Luke Skywalker.
You got to be kidding me!
FN-2187 reported to my division,
was evaluated and sent to reconditioning.
No prior signs of nonconformity?
This was his first offense.
General!
They've been hit.
- Destroyed?
- Disabled.
They were heading back to Jakku.
The fighter's projected to crash
in the Goazon Badlands.
They were going back for the droid.
Send a squad to the wreckage.
Poe!
Poe! I got you.
Supreme Leader Snoke was explicit.
Capture the droid if we can,
but destroy it if we must.
How capable
are your soldiers, General?
I won't have you question my methods.
Who are obviously skilled at
committing high treason.
Perhaps Leader Snoke should
consider using a clone army.
My men are exceptionally trained.
Programmed from birth.
Then they should not have problem
retrieving the droid.
Unharmed.
Careful Ren. That your personal interests
not interfere with orders from Leader Snoke.
I want that map.
For your sake, I suggest you get it.
Water. Water.
There is no water.
Water.
Where's water?
What?
Get away!
Hey!
They work for Unkar.
That guy you wanted.
He must be very interested in you.
Him?
What's your hurry thief?
What? Thief?
Hey! What?
The jacket.
This droid says you stole it.
I've had a pretty messed up day, all right?
So I'd appreciate if
would stop accusing me of ...
- Stop it!
- Where did you get it?
It belongs to his master.
It belonged to Poe Dameron.
That was his name, right?
He was captured by the First Order.
I helped him escape,
but our ship crashed.
Poe didn't make it.
I tried to help. I'm sorry.
So you're with the Resistance?
Obviously.
Yes I am.
I'm with the resistance.
Yeah, I am with the resistance.
I've never met a Resistance fighter before.
Well, this is what we look like.
Some of us. Others look different.
BB-8 says he is on a secret mission.
He has to get back to your base.
Apparently he has a map that
leads to Luke Skywalker
and everyone's after it.
Luke Skywalker?
I thought he was a myth.
What?
- What do you doing?
- Come on.
Come on BB-8!
- Let go of me.
- No, we gotta move!
I know how to run without
you holding my hand!
BB-8, stay close!
This way.
They were shooting at both of us.
Yes, they saw you with me.
You're marked.
Well, thanks for that.
Hey! I'm not the one who
chased you down with a stick.
Does anyone have blasters around here?
Are you okay?
Stop taking my hand!
Hey.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Follow me.
We can't out run them!
We might!
In that quad jumper!
We need a pilot!
We got one.
You?
What about that ship?
That one's garbage!
Garbage will do.
The gunner's position is down there!
You ever fly this thing?
No! This ship hasn't flown in years.
Great.
I can do this.
Hey!
That's mine!
Wait, stay low.
Stay low.
- What?
- Stay low!
That confuses their tracking.
BB-8, hold on!
I'm going low!
What are you doing back there?
Are you ever going to fire back?
I'm working on it!
- Are the shields up?
- Not so easy without a copilot.
Try sitting on this thing.
We need cover, quick!
We're about to get some!
I hope.
Dammit!
Come on!
- Nice shot!
- I'm getting pretty good at this.
The cannon is stuck in forward position.
I can't move it.
You got to lose them.
- Get ready!
- Okay. For what?
Are we really doing this?
Oh no.
- Nice shooting.
- Nice flying.
Thanks.
- How did you do it?
- I don't know.
No one trained you?
I've piloted ships,
but I've never left the planet.
- Your last shot was great.
- That was amazing.
- You got him on the first blast!
- You set me up good.
- It was perfect.
- That was pretty good.
You are okay.
He's with the Resistance.
He's going to get you home.
We both will.
I don't know your name.
Finn. What's yours?
I am Rey.
Rey...
Help me with this. Quick!
What's going on?
Sir, we were unable to
acquire the droid on Jakku.
It escaped capture aboard a
stolen Corellian YT model freighter.
The droid ...
Stole a freighter?
Not exactly, sir.
It had help.
We have no confirmation
but we believe that FN-2187
May have helped him escape.
Anything else?
The two were accompanied by a girl.
What girl?
It's the motivator.
Grab me a Harris wrench, check in there.
How bad is it?
If we want to live it is not good.
They're hunting for us now.
We've got to get out of this system!
BB-8 said the location of the
Resistance base is "need to know."
If I'm taking you there,
I need to know.
This?
You gotta tell us where your base is.
I don't speak that.
Okay, between us,
I'm not with the resistance, okay?
I'm just trying to get away
from the First Order.
But you tell us where your base is,
I'll get you there first.
Deal?
Droid, please!
Pilex driver, hurry.
- So where's your base?
- Come on, BB-8 tell her.
Please.
- The Illenium system?
- Yeah, the Illenium System, that's the one.
Get us there as fast as you can.
I'll drop you two at the Ponemah Terminal.
I need the bonding tape, hurry!
What about you?
I've got to get back to Jakku.
Back to Jakku...
Why does everyone want to go back to Jakku?
Not that one.
- That place is ...
- No no.
Then one I am pointing to.
No no no!
If we don't patch this up, the
propulsion tank will overflow
and flood this ship with poison gas.
- This?
- Yes.
Rey, you are a pilot. You can fly
anywhere. Why go back?
Do you have family?
Do you have a boyfriend? Cute boyfriend?
None of your business, that's why.
- That can't be good.
- Can't be.
Someone is locked onto us.
All controls are overridden.
Get off! Get off!
You see anything?
Oh no.
It is the First Order.
What do we do?
There must be something.
- You said poisonous gas.
- I fixed that.
Can you unfix it?
Come on, BB-8.
I've got it.
I'm okay.
Do you think this will work
on the Stormtroopers?
Yeah, their masks filter
out smoke, not toxins.
- Hurry!
- I'm hurrying.
Chewie...
We're home.
Where are the others?
Where is the pilot?
- I'm the pilot.
- You?
No, it's true.
We are the only ones on board.
You can understand this thing?
And that thing can also
understand you too, so watch it.
Come on out.
- Where'd you get this ship?
- Niiman Outpost.
Jakku? That junkyard?
Thank you! Junk yard.
I told you we should have
double-checked the Western Reaches.
Who had it? Ducain?
I stole. From Unkar Plutt.
He stole it from the Irving boys,
who stole it from Ducain.
Who stole it from me!
Well you tell him that Han Solo just stole
back the Millennium Falcon for good.
This is the Millennium Falcon?
You're Han Solo?
I used to be.
Han Solo, the Rebellion general?
No, the smuggler.
Wasn't he a war hero?
This is the ship that made the
Kessel Run in 14 parsecs?
12!
14.
Hey!
Some moof-milker put a
compressor on the ignition line.
Unkar Plutt did.
I thought it was a mistake too.
Puts too much stress
- on the hyperdrive.
- Stress on the hyperdrive.
Chewie, throw them a pod.
We'll drop them at the
nearest inhabited planet.
Wait. No, we need your help.
My help?
This droid has to go to the
Resistance base as soon as possible.
He's carrying a map to
Luke Skywalker.
You are the Han Solo
that fought with the Rebellion.
You knew him?
Yeah, I knew him. I knew Luke.
Don't tell me a rathtar's gotten loose.
Wait, what?
Did you just say rathtars?
Hey!
You're not hauling rathtars
in this freighter, are you?
I'm hauling rathtars.
Oh great. It's a Guavian Death Gang.
Must have tracked
us from Nantoon.
What is a rathar?
They're big and they're dangerous.
Have you heard of the Trilla Massacre?
- No.
- Good.
I got three of them going to King Prana.
Three? How'd you get them on board?
We used to have a bigger crew.
Get below and stay
there until I say so
and don't even think
about taking the Falcon
What about BB-8?
He stays with me until I get rid of gang.
You can have him back and then be on your way.
And the rathtars?
Where you keeping them?
There's one.
What are you going to do?
Same thing I always do.
Talk my way out of it.
Yes I do! Every time.
Han Solo. You're a dead man.
Bala-Tik. What's the problem?
The problem is that we
loaned you 50,000 for this job.
Can you see them?
No.
I heard also borrowed
50,000 from Kanjiklub.
You know you can't
trust those little freaks.
How long have we known each other?
They have blasters.
A lot of them.
Not long.
We want our money back now.
Do you think hunting rathtars is cheap?
I spent that money.
Kanjiklub wants their
investment back too.
I never made a deal with Kanjiklub!
Tell that to Kanjiklub.
Tasu Leech. Good to see you.
Wrong again, Solo.
It's over for you and your associate.
Boys, you're both going
to get what I promised.
Have I ever not delivered for you before?
Yes.
Twice.
What was the second time?
Your game is old.
There's no one in the galaxy
left for you to swindle.
Nowhere left for you to hide.
That BB unit.
The First Order is looking
one just like it.
And two fugitives.
First I've heard of it.
Search the freighter.
Wait wait.
If we close the blast doors in that
corridor, we can trap both gangs.
You can close them from here?
Reset the fuses should do it.
I got a bad feeling about this.
Oh no.
'Oh, no "what?
Wrong fuses.
Kill them!
And take the droid!
That was a mistake!
Huge!
What do they look like?
They look like that.
- This way.
- Are you sure?
No! No!
Finn!
Rey!
Get out!
Finn!
Get off!
Rey!
Get off! Get off!
Finn!
It had me! But the door ...
That was lucky.
I got the door. Cover us!
Chewie!
You okay?
Wow.
Come on! Come on!
- Han.
- You shut the door behind you.
You, take care of Chewie!
Where are you going?
Unkar Plutt installed a fuel pump too.
If we don't prime that, we're not going anywhere.
I hate that guy.
- And you can use a co-pilot.
- I've got one, he's back there.
Watch the thrust.
We're going out of here at light speed.
From inside the hangar?
Is that even possible?
I've never asked that question
until after I've done it.
This is not how I thought
this day was going to go.
Angle the shield.
Hang on back there!
No problem!
Come on, baby, don't let me down.
What?
The compressor.
Inform the First Order that
Han Solo has the droid they want.
And it's on board the Millennium Falcon.
The droid will soon be
delivered to the Resistance
leading them to the last Jedi.
If Skywalker returns,
the new Jedi will rise.
Supreme leader,
I take full responsibility.
General!
Our strategy must now change.
The weapon. It is ready.
I believe the time has come to use it.
We shall destroy the government
that supports the Resistance:
The Republic.
Without their friends to protect them,
the Resistance will be vulnerable.
And we will stop them
before they reach Skywalker.
Go.
Oversee preparations.
Yes. Supreme Leader.
There has been an awakening.
Have you felt it?
Yes.
There's something more.
The droid we seek
is aboard the Millennium Falcon.
In the hands of your father ...
Han Solo.
He means nothing to me.
Even you, master of the
Knights of Ren.
Have never faced such a test.
By the grace of his training,
I will not be seduced.
We shall see.
Electrical overload.
I can fix that.
Coolant leak.
Try transferring the auxiliary power
- to the secondary tank.
- Secondary tank.
I got it.
Chewie, come on!
I need help with
this giant hairy thing!
Stop it!
Chewie!
If you hurt Chewie,
you're going to deal with me.
Hurt him?
He almost killed me six times.
Which is fine!
If this hyperdrive blows there's gonna be
pieces of us in three different systems.
What did you do?
I bypassed the compressor.
Huh?
Move, ball.
Don't say that.
You did great. You just rest.
Good job, kid.
Thanks.
You're welcome.
So.
Fugitives, huh?
The First Order want that map.
Finn is with the Resistance.
I'm just a scavenger.
Let's see what you got.
Go ahead.
This map is not complete.
It's just a piece.
Ever since Luke disappeared
people been looking for him.
Why did he leave?
He was training
a new generation of Jedi.
One boy, an apprentice,
turned against him, destroyed it all.
Luke felt responsible.
He just walked away from everything.
Do you know what happened to him?
A lot of rumors. Stories.
People who knew him best,
think he went looking for
the first Jedi Temple.
The Jedi were real.
I used to wonder about that myself.
I thought it was a bunch of mumbo jumbo.
A magical power holding together good
and evil, the dark side and light.
The crazy thing is
it's true.
The Force. The Jedi.
All of it.
It's all true.
No, you rest.
You want my help?
You're getting it.
We're gonna see an old friend.
She'll get your droid home.
This is our stop.
I didn't know there was this
much green in the whole galaxy.
Hey, Solo, I'm not sure
what we're walking into here
Did you just call me Solo?
Sorry, Han. Mr. Solo.
You should know that I'm
a big deal with the Resistance.
What puts a real target on my back.
Are there any conspirators here?
First Order sympathizers?
Listen, Big Deal.
You got another problem.
Women always figure out the truth.
Always.
You might need this.
I think I can handle myself.
I know you do.
That's why I'm giving it to you.
Take it.
You know how to use one of those?
Yeah. You pull the trigger.
Little bit more to it than that.
You got a lot to learn.
You got a name?
Rey.
I've been thinking about bringing
on some more crew, Rey.
A second mate.
Someone to help out.
Someone who can keep up with Chewie
and me and appreciates the Falcon.
Are you offering me a job?
I wouldn't be nice to you.
Doesn't pay much.
You're offering me a job.
I'm thinking about it.
Well?
If you were, I'd be flattered.
But I have to go home.
Where Jakku?
I've already been away too long.
Chewie, check out the ship
the best you can.
It's too bad.
Chewie kind of likes you.
So, why are we here again?
To get your droid
to a clean ship.
Clean?
Do you think it was luck that
Chewie and I found the Falcon?
If we could find it on our scanners,
the First Order's not far behind.
Want to get BB-8 to the Resistance,
Maz Kanata is our best bet.
We can trust her, right?
Relax, kid.
She's run this watering hole
for a thousand years.
Maz is a bit of an acquired taste,
So let me do the talking and
whatever you do, don't stare.
At what?
Any of it.
Han Solo!
Oh boy.
Hey, Maz.
Where is my boyfriend?
Chewie is working
on the Falcon.
I like that Wookiee.
I assume you need something.
Desperately.
Let's get to it.
Alert the Resistance
their lost droid is here!
Inform the First Order.
I've found the droid.
Forgive me.
I feel it again.
The call to the light.
The Supreme Leader senses it.
Show me again.
The power of darkness.
And I will let nothing stand
on our way.
Show me ...
Grandfather...
and I will finish what you started.
A map.
To Skywalker himself?
You're right back in this whole mess.
Maz, I need you to bring
this droid to Leia.
No.
You've been running away
from this fight for too long.
Han.
Go home.
Leia doesn't want to see me.
Please, we came here for your help.
What fight?
The only fight.
Against the dark side.
Through the ages, I've seen evil
take many forms.
The Sith. The Empire.
Today it is the First Order.
Their shadow spreading
across the galaxy.
You must face them.
Fight them.
All of us.
There is no fight
against the First Order.
Not one we can win.
Look around.
There is no chance we haven't
been recognized already.
I bet you the First Order
is on their way right...
What's this?
What are you doing?
Solo, what is she doing?
I don't know. But it ain't good.
If you live long enough, you see
the same eyes in different people.
I am looking into the eyes of a man
who wants to run.
You don't know a thing about me.
Where I'm from. What I've seen.
You don't know the
First Order like I do.
They will slaughter us.
We all need to run.
Do you see those two?
They will trade work for
transportation to the Outer Rim.
There, you can disappear.
Finn?
Come with me.
What about BB-8?
We're not done here.
We have to get him back to your base.
I can't.
Keep it, kid.
Who's the girl?
I was told you could get
me to the Outer Rim.
What do you doing?
Don't leave without me.
You can't just go.
I won't let you.
I'm not who you think I am.
Finn, what are you talking about?
I'm not Resistance.
I'm not a hero.
I am a Stormtrooper.
Like all of them, I was taken from
a family I will never know.
And raised to do one thing.
But in my first battle,
I made a choice.
I wasn't going to kill for them.
So I ran. Right into you.
And you look at me
like no one ever had.
I was ashamed of what I was.
But I am done with the First Order.
I am never going back.
Rey, come with me.
Don't go.
Take care of yourself.
Please.
No!
No! Come back!
Come back!
No!
His energy ...
It surrounds us ... and binds us.
The Force will ...
No!
Come back!
Quiet, girl.
Don't!
Rey?
These are your first steps.
What was that?
I shouldn't have gone in there.
That lightsaber was Luke's.
And his father's before him.
And now, he calls to you.
I have to go back to Jakku.
Han told me.
Dear child, I see your eyes.
You already know the truth.
Whomever you are waiting for on Jakku.
They're never coming back.
But there is someone
who still could.
Luke.
The belonging you seek
is not behind you
it is ahead.
I am no Jedi, but I know the Force.
It moves through and
surrounds every living thing.
Close your eyes.
Feel it.
The light...
It's always been there.
It will guide you.
The saber. Take it.
I'm never touching that thing again.
I don't want any part of this.
Today is the end of the Republic.
The end of a regime
that acquiesces to disorder.
At this very moment,
in a system far from here
the New Republic
lies to the galaxy
while secretly
supporting the treachery
of the loathsome Resistance.
This fierce machine
which you have built
upon which we stand,
will bring an end to the Senate!
To their cherished fleet!
All remaining systems
will bow to the First Order!
And will remember this!
As the last day of the Republic!
Transfer to manual control.
Configure!
Fire!
No. What is it?
It was the Republic.
The First Order.
They've done it.
Where is Rey?
What are you doing?
You have to go back.
I'm leaving.
BB-8
You can't. You have to go back,
you're too important.
They will help you.
I've had this for ages.
Kept it locked away.
Where'd you get that?
A good question.
For another time.
Take it. Find your friend!
Those beasts. They're here.
FN-417, hold position.
Oh, safety.
Sir.
The droid was spotted heading west.
With a girl.
You have to keep going,
Stay out of sight.
I'll try to fight them off.
I hope so too.
Come on, Chewie!
Rey and BB-8! They need you!
Now! Go!
I need a weapon!
You have one!
Can I try that?
I like this thing.
Traitor!
You okay, Big Deal?
Thanks.
Don't move!
TK-338, we have targets in custody.
We have incoming in 28.6.
Move it! Move it!
Deploy all squads,
repeat, scramble all squads!
Get to your cover
and seek new positions!
It's the Resistance.
Straight ahead.
Don't let these guys scare you.
- Copy that.
- We're with you, Poe.
Quick!
Yeah!
That's one hell of a pilot!
The girl I've heard so much about.
The droid.
Where is it?
Requesting air support.
The map.
You have seen it.
Sir, Resistance fighters.
We need more troops.
Pull the division out.
Forget the droid.
We have what we need.
Get back into the trees!
No!
No no!
Don't! Don't!
Rey!
He took her, did you see it?
He took her. She's gone.
Yeah, yeah, I know.
Let's go.
Goodness!
Han Solo! It is I, C-3PO.
You probably don't recognize
me because of the red arm.
Look who it is,
Did you see who...?
Excuse me, Prince ... General.
I'm sorry.
Come BB-8, quickly.
Yes, I must get my
proper arm reinstalled.
You changed your hair.
The same jacket.
No, new jacket.
I saw him.
Leia, I saw our son.
He was here.
Hey!
BB-8, my friend.
Good to see you.
Finn saved you?
Where is?
Poe?
Oh no.
Poe Dameron, you're alive?
- So are you!
- What happened to you?
What happened? I got thrown from the crash and I
woke up at night and no you, no ship, no nothing.
BB-8 says that you saved him.
No, no. It wasn't just me.
You completed my mission, Finn...
That's my jacket.
No no no no.
Keep it. It suits you.
You're a good man, Finn.
Poe, I need your help.
PZ-4CO, report to
communications.
General Organa
Sorry to interrupt.
This is Finn.
He needs to talk to you.
And I need to talk to him.
That was incredibly brave what you did.
Renouncing the First Order,
saving this man's life.
Thank you ma'am.
But a friend of mine was taken prisoner.
Han told me about the girl.
I'm sorry.
Finn's familiar with the weapon
that destroyed the Hosnian System.
He worked on the base.
We're desperate for
anything you can tell us.
That's where my friend was taken.
I've got to get there fast.
And I will do everything I can to help,
but first you need to tell us all you know.
That sounds very scary.
You must be so brave.
General...
I regret to inform you that the map recovered
from BB-8 is only partially complete.
And even worse, it matches
no charted system on record.
We simply do not have enough
information to locate Master Luke.
I can't believe I was so foolish to think
I could find Luke home and bring him home.
Leia.
Don't do that.
Do what?
Anything.
Princesses.
I'm trying to be helpful.
When did that ever help?
And don't say the Death Star.
BB-8.
You're wasting your time.
It is very doubtful that R2 would have
the rest of the map in his backup.
I am afraid not.
R2-D2 has been in low power
mode Master Luke went away.
Sadly, he may never be his own self again.
Listen to me, will you?
I know every time you...
Every time you look at me
you're reminded of him.
You think I want to forget him?
I want him back.
There's nothing more we could have done.
There's too much Vader in him.
That's why I wanted
him to train with Luke.
I just never should have sent him away.
That's when I lost him.
That's when I lost you both.
We both had to deal
with it in our own way.
I went back to the only
thing I was ever any good at.
We both did.
We lost our son.
Forever.
No.
It was Snoke.
He seduced our son to the dark side.
But we can still save him.
Me...
You.
If Luke couldn't reach him,
How could I?
Luke is a Jedi.
You're his father.
There's still light in him,
I know it.
General, the reconnaissance report
on the enemy base is coming.
Where I am?
You are my guest.
Where are the others?
You mean the murderers, traitors
and thieves you call friends?
You'll be relieved to hear
I have no idea.
You still want to kill me.
That happens when you're being
hunted by a creature in a mask.
Tell me about the droid.
He's a BB unit with a selenium drive
and a thermal hyperscan vindicator.
He's carrying a section of navigation chart.
And we have the rest.
Recovered from the archives of the Empire,
but we need the last piece.
Somehow you convinced
the droid to show it to you.
You.
A scavenger.
You know I can take
whatever I want.
You are so lonely.
So afraid to leave.
At night,
desperate to sleep.
Imagine an ocean.
I see.
I see the island.
And Han Solo.
You feel like he's the
father you never had.
He would have disappointed you.
Get out of my head.
I know you've seen the map.
It's in there.
And now you'll give me.
Don't be afraid.
I feel it too.
I'm not giving you anything.
We'll see.
You.
You're afraid.
That you'll never be as
strong as Darth Vader.
The scavenger.
Resisted you?
She is strong with the Force.
Untrained, but stronger than she knows.
And the droid?
Ren believed it was no valuable to us.
That the girl was all we needed.
As a result, the Droid has most likely
been returned to the hands of the enemy.
They may have the map already.
Then the Resistance
must be destroyed
before they get to Skywalker.
We have their location.
We tracked their reconnaissance
ship to the Illenium system.
Good.
Then we will crush
them once and for all.
Prepare the weapon.
Supreme Leader,
I can get the map from the girl.
I just need your guidance.
If what you say about this girl
It is true...
Bring her to me.
You will remove these restraints
and leave this cell with the door open.
What did you say?
You will remove these restraints
and leave this cell
with the door open.
I will tighten those restraints
scavenger scum.
You will remove these restraints
and leave this cell with the door open.
I will remove these restraints
And you'll drop your weapon.
And I'll drop my weapon.
No.
Guards!
Begin charging the weapon.
Yes sir.
Weapon charging.
The scan data from Snap's reconnaissance
flight confirms Finn's report.
They've somehow created a hyper-lightspeed weapon
built within the planet itself.
A laser cannon?
We're not sure how to
describe a weapon of this scale.
It's another Death Star.
I wish that were the case, Major.
This was the Death Star.
And this is Starkiller Base.
So it's big.
How is it possible to power
a weapon of that size?
It uses the power of the sun.
As the weapon is charged,
the sun is drained until it disappears.
Ma'am.
The First Order are charging
the weapon again now.
Our system is the next target.
Oh my. Without the Republic
fleet, we're doomed.
How do we blow it up?
- There's always a way to do that.
- Han's right.
In order for that amount of
power to be contained
that base has to have some
kind of thermal oscillator.
There's one. Precinct 47.
Here.
If we can destroy that oscillator
it might destabilize the core
and cripple the weapon.
Maybe the planet.
We'll go in and we'll hit that oscillator
with everything we've got.
They have defensive shields
that our ships cannot penetrate.
We disable the shields.
Kid, you worked there.
What do you got?
I can do it.
I like this guy.
I can disable the shields,
but I have to be there. On the planet.
- We'll get you there.
- Han, how?
If I told you, you wouldn't like it.
So we disable the shields,
we take out the oscillator
and we blow up the big gun.
All right. Let's go.
Chewie, check the thermal capitador.
Come on. Let's go.
Finn, be careful with those.
They're explosives.
Now you tell me?
You know?
No matter how much we faught
I always hated watching you leave.
That's why I did it.
So you'd miss me.
I did miss you.
Wasn't all was bad, was it?
Huh?
Some of it was...
Good.
Pretty good.
Some things never change.
True.
You still drive me crazy.
If you see our son,
bring him home.
Sir, sensors triggered in Hangar 718.
We're searching the area.
She is just beginning
to test her powers.
The longer it takes to find her,
most dangerous she becomes.
How are we getting in?
Their shields have a fractional refresh rate.
Keeps anything travelling slower than
lightspeed from getting through.
We're making our landing
approach at lightspeed?
Chewie, get ready.
And now!
I am pulling up!
If I get any higher, they'll see us!
Sir, she was not found in hangar 718.
But all troops are on alert.
Put every hangar on lockdown.
She's going to try to steal a ship to escape.
Han Solo.
The flooding tunnel
is over that ridge.
We'll get in that way.
What was your job
when you were based here?
Sanitation.
Sanitation?
Then how do you know
to disable the shields?
I don't.
I'm just here to get Rey.
People are counting on us.
The galaxy is counting on us.
Solo, we'll figure it out.
We will use the Force.
That's not how the Force works!
Oh really? You're cold?
Come on.
Report.
Weapon charged in 15 minutes, sir.
Hey!
The longer we're here,
the less luck we're gonna have.
Shields.
I have an idea about that.
Remember me?
FN-2187
Not anymore.
My name is Finn and I'm in charge.
I'm in charge now, Phasma.
I'm in charge.
Bring it down.
Yeah.
Follow me.
Have you seen the new T-17s?
The T-17s, as far as I know,
they are a great improvement.
Yes. That's what they say.
But believe me, I can't stand.
- Do not?
- Do not.
You want me to blast that bucket
off your head? Lower the shields.
You're making a big mistake.
Do it.
Solo if this works, we're not going to
have a lot of time to find Rey.
Don't worry, kid.
We won't leave here without her.
You can't be so stupid just
to think that this will be easy.
My troops will storm this
block and kill you both.
I disagree. What we do with her?
Is there a garbage chute?
Trash compactor?
Yeah, there is.
General,
their shields are down.
Thank the Maker!
Han did it. Send them in.
Give Poe full
authorization for attack.
Black leader,
go to sub-light speed.
Roger base.
Red squad, Blue squads, take my lead.
Dropping out of light speed.
Almost in range.
Leave the target dead center.
As many runs as we can get.
Approaching target.
Fighters incoming!
Arriving at 28.336
4. 5! Shields up!
Dispatch all squadrons.
Yes, General.
All right. Fire it up.
Direct hit.
But no damage!
Yeah, we gotta keep hitting it.
Another bombing run.
Remember, when the sun is gone,
that weapon will be ready to fire.
But as long as there's light,
We got a chance.
Guys, we got
a lot of company!
We believe they
may be splitting up.
Heading to the quadrants 4 and 5.
We use the charges
to blow that blast door.
I'lll go in and draw fire,
but I'm gonna need the cover.
You sure you're up for this?
Hell, no.
I'll go in and try to find Rey.
The troopers will be off our tail.
We have to be
ready for that.
Oh, there's an access
tunnel that leads...
Why are you doing that? Hm?
Why are you doing this?
I'm trying to come up with a plan.
You all right?
Yeah.
All right.
What happened to you?
Did he hurt you?
Finn, what are you doing here?
We came back for you.
What did he say?
That was your idea.
Thank you.
How did you get away?
I can't explain it.
And you would't believe it.
Escape now,
hug later.
I got one behind me.
- You see it?
- Yeah. I'm on it.
Burillo's been hit.
Watch out for ground fire.
We're in trouble.
We can't leave.
My friend's got a bag
filled with explosives.
Let's use them.
General, are you seeing this?
Two more X-wings down.
That's half our
fleet destroyed.
And their weapon will be fully
charged in 10 minutes.
It would take a
miracle to save us now.
That girl knows her stuff.
We'll set the charges
against every other column.
You're right.
That's a better idea.
You take the top,
I'll go down below.
Detonator.
We'll meet back here.
Find them.
Ben!
Han Solo.
I've been waiting for
this day for a long time.
Take off that mask.
You don't need it.
What do you think you will see if I do?
The face of my son.
Your son is gone.
He was weak and foolish like his father.
So I destroyed him.
That's what Snoke
wants you to believe.
But it's not true.
My son is alive.
No.
The Supreme Leader is wise.
Snoke is using you for your power.
When he gets what he wants,
he'll crush you.
You know it's true.
It's too late.
No, it's not.
Leave here with me. Come home.
We miss you.
I'm being torn apart.
I want to be
free of this pain.
I know what I have to do,
but I don't know if I have the strength to do it.
Will you help me?
Yes. Anything.
No!
Thank you.
The oscillator has been damaged
but it is still functional.
Admiral, the weapon
will fire in two minutes.
The Hawk is this way.
We're not done yet.
You're a monster.
It's just us now.
Han Solo can't save you.
Rey!
Rey. Rey!
Oh no. No no. Rey.
Traitor!
That lightsaber.
It belongs to me.
Come get it.
We just lost
Star-1.
We're overwhelmed.
What do we do?
It isn't working.
Black leader, there's a brand
new hole in the oscillator.
Looks like our friends got here.
Red-4, Red-6, Cover us.
- I'm on it.
- Roger.
Everybody else, hit the target hard.
Give it everything you got.
I need some help here.
I need help!
- I'm here!
- Watch out!
They got me!
All teams
I'm going in.
Pull up and cover me.
Copy that, Black Leader.
Good luck, Poe.
The weapon will be fully
charged in 30 seconds.
Prepare to fire.
You need a teacher.
I could show you
the ways of the Force.
The Force?
Lieutenant! Get back to your station!
Just look! We won't survive this.
Even Hux has gone.
Supreme Leader.
The fuel cells erupted.
The collapse of the
planet has begun.
Leave the base at once
and come to me with Kylo Ren.
It is time to complete
his training.
Finn!
Finn.
All teams
I'm got eyes on them.
Yes!
Our job's done here.
Let's go home.
Easy. He's hurt.
Get a heartbeat.
R2-D2!
You've come back.
You found what?
How dare you call me that!
Find the Master Luke.
How?
Come R2. We must go
tell the others at once!
General.
Excuse me, General.
R2-D2 may contain some
much needed good news.
Tell me.
Alright buddy, hold on.
The map it is complete.
Luke.
Oh my dear friend,
how I missed you.
We'll see each other again.
I believe that.
Thank you my friend.
Rey.