PUKCH`ONG COAST, NORTH KOREA
Look, what is this? I`m supposed to...
Colonel Tan-Sun Moon`s HQ
De-Militarised Zone, North Korea
Open the bag.
That will teach you to lecture me.
Retract the blast doors.
Find me a new anger therapist.
I am Zao.
You are late.
Mr Van Bierk. l`ve been
looking forward to this meeting.
Me, too.
My African military friends
owe you many thanks, Colonel Moon.
Few men have the guts to trade
conflict diamonds since the UN embargo.
I know all about the UN.
I studied at Oxford and Harvard.
Majored in Western hypocrisy.
From your modest little collection of cars,
I would never have guessed.
- Show me the diamonds.
- Show me the weapons.
Bring the weapons.
Hiding weapons in the demilitarised zone.
It`s a bit of a minefield out there.
America`s cultural contribution.
One million land mines,
and my hovercrafts float right over them.
RPGs, flamethrowers, automatic weapons
and enough ammunition
to run a small war.
My diamonds?
Check it over quick.
- Don`t blow it all at once.
- I`ve special plans for this consignment.
His name is James Bond.
A British assassin.
Mr Van Bierk,
let me show you something.
Our new tank buster.
- Depleted uranium shells, naturally.
- Naturally.
And how do you propose to kill me now...
Mr Bond?
It`s pathetic that you British still believe
you have the right to police the world.
But you will not live to see the day
all Korea is ruled by the North.
Then you and I
have something in common.
Who is it?
Where`s my son?
It`s the General.
Hello, Father.
Why is there a fire?
I`ll be there in five minutes.
Get the weapons out of here...
and kill the spy.
Saved by the bell.
My son is dead.
1 4 months later
I don`t condone what they do here.
Tell it to the concierge.
Still you jest.
Defiant to the last.
Your people have abandoned you.
Your very existence denied.
Why stay silent?
It doesn`t matter any more.
Things are out of my hands.
We reach the end, Mr Bond.
Spare me the unpleasantries.
50 years after the superpowers
carved Korea in two.
And then you arrive.
A British spy. An assassin.
And now the hardliners have their proof
we cannot trust the West.
You...
You took away my son.
Your firing squad
should have done the job for me.
I hoped a Western education would help
him become a bridge between our worlds.
But all it did was to corrupt him.
Let`s get this over with, shall we?
My son had an ally in the West.
For the last time, who was it?
Who made him betray
his country and his name?
The same person who betrayed me.
Turn around!
Start walking.
Keep walking, please.
Keep moving.
Zao!
I`m being traded.
- For you.
- Keep moving. Keep walking, please.
Your time will come.
Not as soon as yours.
Keep walking, please.
Look at him.
You`d think he was some kind of a hero.
OK, hold him tight.
- Watch his legs now.
- All right, let`s go.
No biological agents
in the prelim scan. He`s clean.
Pulse 72.
Blood pressure 120 over 80.
Indications of neurotoxins, histamine,
serotonin, enzyme inhibitors.
Scorpion venom.
Also traces of a venom antiserum.
They`d sting him,
then administer the antidote.
Yet his internal organs seem unaffected.
Liver not too good.
It`s definitely him, then.
Morning.
Welcome back.
Such hospitality.
You don`t seem too pleased to see me.
If I`d had my way,
you`d still be in North Korea.
Your freedom came at too high a price.
Zao.
He tried to blow up a summit
between South Korea and China.
Took out three Chinese agents
before he was caught.
And now he`s free.
I never asked to be traded.
- I`d rather die in prison than let him loose.
- You had your cyanide.
Threw it away years ago.
What the hell is this about?
The top US agent in the North Korean
High Command was executed last week.
The Americans intercepted a signal
from your prison naming him.
- And they think it`s me?
- You were the only inmate.
They concluded you cracked
and were haemorrhaging information.
We had to get you out.
And what do you think?
With drugs, you wouldn`t know
what you did or didn`t say.
I know the rules.
And number one is no deals.
Get caught and you`re given up.
The mission was compromised.
Moon got a call exposing me.
He had a partner in the West.
Even his father knew about it.
- Whether that`s true or not, it`s irrelevant.
- No, it isn`t.
The same person who set me up then
has just set me up again to get Zao out.
So I`m going after him.
The only place you`re going
is our evaluation centre in the Falklands.
- Double-O status rescinded.
- Along with my freedom?
For as long as I deem necessary, yes.
You`re no use to anyone now.
- He`s gone into cardiac arrest.
- Crash trolley. Notify his superiors. Now!
He`s flatlining on the ECG.
200 joules. 300.
Get me some atropine. We`re losing him!
Stand by. Clear.
I`m checkin` out.
Thanks for the kiss of life.
Security breach on level three.
All personnel defensive, code red.
Apprehend and detain with force.
Security breach on level three.
All personnel defensive, code red.
Apprehend and detain with force.
Security breach on level three.
All personnel defensive, code red.
My usual suite, please.
Do you have a credit card?
Or even any luggage, sir?
Mr Bond, so good to see you.
It`s been a long time.
Mr Chang.
Open the Presidential Suite.
Could you send up my tailor
and some food?
The lobster`s good,
with quails` eggs and sliced seaweed.
- And if there`s any left, a `61 Bollinger.
- Of course.
Do it quickly.
Been busy, have we, Mr Bond?
Just surviving, Mr Chang.
Just surviving.
I am Peaceful Fountains of Desire.
The masseuse.
I come with compliments of the manager.
I`m sure you do. Come in.
On the bed, please. Face down.
Yes, of course.
I`m not that kind of masseuse.
I`m not that kind of customer.
You think I haven`t always known
you`re Chinese Intelligence, Chang?
- Hong Kong`s our turf now, Bond.
- Don`t worry. I`m not here to take it back.
Put your hands down.
What the hell do you want?
Just to help you settle a score.
Zao killed three of your men.
You get me into North Korea,
I`ll take care of him for you.
What`s in it for you?
Chance to get even.
Zao has information I need.
- I`ll have to ask Beijing.
- Do it.
Now get out. Unless you
really want to give me a massage.
Ah, Mr Bond.
A little ``thank you`` from us.
- Cuba?
- It seems Mr Zao`s lost himself in Havana.
If you find him, say goodbye from us.
With pleasure.
HAVANA
- »Sí?
- I`m here to pick up Delectados.
Delectados? We haven`t
made Delectados in 30 years.
I`m from Universal Exports.
Check with your boss.
Follow me.
Your passport, señor.
I`d come to think the Delectados
would never be smoked.
They are particularly hazardous
for one`s health, Mr...
Bond.
Mr Bond.
- D`you know why?
- It`s the addition of the Volado tobacco.
Slow-burning.
It never goes out.
- Just like a sleeper.
- Sorry for the rude awakening.
I love my country, Mr Bond.
I`d never ask you to betray your people.
I`m after a North Korean.
- A tourist?
- A terrorist.
One man`s terrorist
is another man`s freedom fighter.
Zao has no interest
in other people`s freedom.
I still have some friends in high places.
Favours called in.
Some dollars spread about.
We find your friend is here,
on an island in Los Organos.
There is a strange clinic
run by Doctor Alvarez.
He leads the field in gene therapy.
Increasing the life expectancy
of our beloved leaders.
And, of course, the richest Westerners.
We may have lost our freedom
in the revolution, but...
we have a health system second to none.
You don`t seem to have done
badly out of the revolution.
We all have our ways of getting by.
You`d be surprised how many
government officials come to me
for reminders of the decadent times.
Ah, yeah, well.
- Mind if I borrow these?
- Please.
My sources tell me this Zao is dangerous.
I wish I could give you more help.
I could use a fast car.
Mojito, por favor.
Mr Krug, your admittance papers
for the Alvarez Clinic tomorrow.
About bloody time, Fidel.
Now round up some more girls
and take them to room 42.
Unless you want to be
known as Fidel Castrato.
Magnificent view.
It is, isn`t it?
Too bad it`s lost on everybody else.
Mojito?
You should try it.
Giacinta Johnson.
My friends call me Jinx.
My friends call me James Bond.
Jinx, you say.
Born on Friday the 13th.
Do you believe in bad luck?
Let`s just say
my relationships don`t seem to last.
I know the feeling.
Predators usually appear at sunset.
- And why is that?
- It`s when their prey comes out to drink.
Too strong for you?
I could learn to like it, if I had the time.
How much time have you got?
- Until dawn. What about you?
- Oh, I`m just here for the birds.
Ornithologist.
Ornithologist, huh?
Wow. Now there`s a mouthful.
So you`re gonna be busy tonight
with the owls then, huh?
No owls in Los Organos.
Nothing to see till the morning.
Not out there, anyway.
So what do predators do...
when the sun goes down?
They feast...
like there`s no tomorrow.
Are you always this frisky?
I`ve been missing the touch
of a good woman.
Who says I`m good?
What the hell do you want?
I don`t need a wheelchair.
No?
You do now.
- »Buenos días!
- »Hola!
Seòor.
- OK.
- Gracias.
Isla Los Organos
»Buenos días!
So you are to have
DNA replacement therapy.
Let me explain the two phases.
First, we kill off your bone marrow,
wipe the DNA slate clean.
Phase two: introduction of new DNA
harvested from healthy donors -
orphans, runaways,
people that won`t be missed.
I like to think of myself as an artist.
And this is when I create.
Thank you.
It is a painful process, I`m afraid.
But... all great art is.
I`ll certainly enjoy working on you.
Of course, you know,
most artists are only truly appreciated
after they`re dead.
My father was a sergeant.
We lived in Hampshire.
I have fond memories of the countryside.
Oh, good.
Got your attention.
Who`s bankrolling
your makeover, Zao? Hm?
Same person who
set me up in North Korea?
James? What`s goin` on?
Jinx, you`ve gotta get out of here now!
Move! Move!
Vamos! Vamos!
Vamos!
Move it! Move it! Let`s go!
See, my friend, the chemical composition
shows this is from Sierra Leone.
- Conflict diamonds.
- Yeah.
There`s some kind of marking here.
- ``GG.``
- Let me see.
Oh, yes.
From the Graves Corporation in Iceland.
That`s his laser signature.
A man called Gustav Graves discovered
diamonds there a year or so ago.
Yet they`re identical to conflict diamonds.
What an amazing coincidence.
How can he escape from a British warship
in Hong Kong right under your nose?
- Interesting station, Moneypenny?
- All I got was a storm warning.
You were supposed to throw away
the key, not leave the door wide open.
Are you implying I had a hand
in his escape, Mr Falco?
Well, Bond got away real fast, didn`t he?
It is what he`s trained to do.
Your boy`s been busy in his training. He
showed up in Cuba and torches a clinic.
Listen, you put your house in order,
or we`re gonna do it for you.
Your drink, sir.
Lucky I asked for it shaken.
- When`s he coming?
- I don`t know.
- Looks like your man won`t make it.
- Actually, he`s right on time.
- Wonderful day to become a knight.
- Will you use your title, Mr Graves?
I`m proud of my adopted nation,
but I`d never stand on ceremony.
After that entrance,
you can`t be surprised to be called
- a self-publicising, adrenaline junkie.
- I prefer the term ``adventurer``.
There are rumours about the Icarus
space programme. What`s the secret?
It`s not a secret, it`s a surprise.
You`ll soon be enlightened.
You seem to work 24-seven.
Is it true you don`t need sleep?
You only get one shot at life.
Why waste it on sleep?
Are you trying out for the British Olympic
fencing team? You`ve trained furiously.
I never get furious. As they say in fencing,
``What`s the point?``
Thank you very much. We don`t want
to keep Her Majesty waiting any longer.
- Mr Graves?
Hit.
That`s a hit.
Verity?
James Bond.
Your lesson.
I see you handle your weapon well.
I have been known to keep my tip up.
Do you mind? I think I`ve come undone.
Why not?
Hit. Positions.
Play.
Feast your eyes on the club`s finest blade.
- Gustav Graves?
- His publicist, Miranda Frost.
Et lá!
My protégée.
Gorgeous, isn`t she?
She took the gold at Sydney.
- By default, if I remember.
- Default?
The one who beat her OD`d on steroids.
Miranda deserved that gold.
Now she`s teaching Graves
how to win one.
He only plays for cash.
He`s won so much,
nobody else wants to fight him.
You wanna meet him?
Absolutely.
Lead on.
- Gustav.
- Verity.
- And Mr...?
- Bond.
James Bond.
Have we met before?
Oh, I think I`d remember.
Of course you would. My mistake.
- Are you a gambling man, Mr Bond?
- If the stakes are right.
L1 ,000 a point too much for you?
Care to place a bet, Verity?
No, thanks.
I don`t like cockfights.
Shall we?
Excuse me.
Best of three hits?
Positions.
Ready. Play.
En garde.
Hit. Positions.
Play.
Et lá!
Hit.
2-0.
- D`you want to continue?
- D`you want to up the wager?
How much can you afford?
Let`s play for this.
I picked it up in Cuba.
I believe it`s one of yours.
My, my.
They do get around.
But, then, diamonds are for everyone.
Brilliant specimen. Completely flawless.
And chemically identical
to African conflict diamonds.
Then you`re about to lose
something very precious.
Positions.
Ready. Play.
En garde.
Oh, dear.
You want to continue?
Of course I want to bloody continue!
But since we`re upping the wager,
let`s up the weapons, shall we?
Yeah.
Let`s do this the old-fashioned way.
First blood drawn from the torso.
Steady on!
That is enough!
It`s just a little sport, Miranda.
It seems you beat me, Mr Bond.
Settle downstairs, shall we?
Miranda.
You`re a rare challenge, Mr Bond.
I`m putting on a scientific demonstration
in Iceland at the weekend. Icarus?
Join us. Miranda, make the arrangements.
Once I`ve smoothed
things over with the club.
What would I do without you?
Can I expect the pleasure of you
in Iceland?
You`ll never have that pleasure, Mr Bond.
Excuse me, Commander Bond.
Someone left this for you.
Place needed redecorating anyway.
I heard of this place.
Never thought I`d find myself here.
Some things are best kept underground.
An abandoned station
for abandoned agents.
- Your calling card.
- So what have you got on Graves?
You burn me.
- And now you want my help.
- What did you expect, an apology?
Oh, I know you`ll do
whatever it takes to get the job done.
- Just like you.
- The difference is I won`t compromise.
Well, I don`t have the luxury
of seeing things as black and white.
- While you were gone the world changed.
- Not for me.
You`re suspicious of Graves,
or I wouldn`t be here right now.
- So, what do you have?
- Nothing beyond the official biography.
Orphan working in an Argentinian
diamond mine learns engineering.
Makes a huge find in Iceland
and gives half of it to charity.
From nothing to everything
in no time at all.
- And his demonstration this weekend?
- Probably just another publicity stunt.
Now, tell me what you know
about this Cuban clinic.
Gene therapy. New identities
courtesy of DNA transplants.
So-called ``beauty parlour``.
We`d heard rumours of such a place.
I didn`t think it really existed.
It doesn`t any more.
Zao got away.
But he left these behind.
All from Gustav Graves`s mine.
I think it`s a front for laundering
African conflict diamonds.
We need to tread carefully.
Graves is politically connected.
- Lucky I`m on the outside, then.
- It seems you`ve become useful again.
Then maybe it`s time
you let me get on with my job.
Forgive my mentioning it, 007,
but a perfect marksman isn`t really
supposed to shoot his own boss.
Check the replay.
You`ll find he`s dead
and she`s only got a flesh wound.
There`s always an excuse,
isn`t there, Double-O Zero?
Give me the old firing range any day,
Quartermaster.
Yes, but it`s called the future,
so get used to it.
So, this is where they keep
the old relics then, eh?
I`ll have you know this is where our most
cutting-edge technology is developed.
- Point taken.
- Must you touch everything?
Does this still work?
- Now, look...
- So where is this cutting-edge stuff?
I`m trying to get to it.
Weapon, please.
One pane unbreakable glass,
one standard-issue ring finger.
Twist so, et voilá.
Ultra high-frequency,
single-digit, sonic agitator unit.
You`re cleverer than you look.
Better than looking cleverer than you are.
Follow me, please.
- Now, a new watch. Your 20th, I believe.
- How time flies.
Yes, well, 007, why don`t you establish
a record by actually returning this one?
Your new transportation.
You`ve been down here too long.
- The ultimate in British engineering.
- You must be joking.
As I learnt from my predecessor, Bond,
I never joke about my work.
Aston Martin call it the Vanquish.
We call it the Vanish.
- Oh, very good.
- Adaptive camouflage.
Tiny cameras on all sides
project the image they see
onto a light-emitting polymer skin
on the opposite side.
To the casual eye,
it`s as good as invisible.
Plus the usual refinements:
ejector seat, torpedoes,
target-seeking shotguns
to shoot down mobile objects.
Acquaint yourself with the manual. Should
be able to shoot through it in two hours.
Just took a few seconds, Q.
Wish I could make you vanish.
Come in.
Before you leave
on your mission for Iceland,
tell me what you know of James Bond.
He`s a double-O.
And a wild one, as I discovered today.
He`ll light fuses on any explosive situation
and be a danger to himself and others.
Kill first, ask questions later.
He`s a blunt instrument whose primary
method is to provoke and confront.
A man nobody can get close to.
A womaniser.
Well, you`re going to be seeing
a lot more of him in Iceland.
With great respect,
a man like him could blow my cover.
Miss Frost, you volunteered for this, but
in three months you`ve turned up nothing.
Graves seems to be clean.
Well, Bond thinks differently, so I`m going
to let him do what you so ably described -
mix things up a little with Mr Graves.
And with you there,
things won`t be able to get out of hand.
In your three years in Cryptology, you`ve
kept business and pleasure separate.
You haven`t fraternised
with any of your fellow agents,
despite several advances.
I think it would be foolish to get involved
with someone within the community.
Especially James Bond.
I`m Mr Kil.
Well, there`s a name to die for.
324 miles an hour.
That`s a new personal best, boss.
Thruster two cut out again.
Get it fixed, will you?
Glad you could make it, Mr Bond.
How did you like my run?
You looked on the edge of losing control.
It`s only by being on the edge that we
know who we really are. Under the skin.
Take your Donald Campbell -
1967, the Bluebird, water speed record.
- Campbell died on his return run.
- Yeah, but he died chasing a dream.
- Isn`t that the way to go?
- I`d rather not go at all.
- You don`t chase dreams, you live them.
- One of the virtues of never sleeping.
I have to live my dreams. Besides,
plenty of time to sleep when you`re dead.
Mr Bond.
- Ah, Miss Frost.
- I`ll show you your room.
A palace of ice.
You must feel right at home.
This place was built
for tonight`s demonstration.
The human element necessitates
a precise balance of heat and cold.
Built on a lake?
I hope Graves got things right.
- What`s that property I noticed next door?
- The diamond mine.
And Gustav`s quarters.
Thank you.
This is you.
Wonderful.
Would you like to show me more?
Vodka martini.
Plenty of ice, if you can spare it.
Mojito?
James.
Here for the penguins this time,
or for the view again?
Now I`m only interested
in endangered species.
- Oh, well, does that include me?
- Depends on what you`re up to this time.
So I left you in an explosive situation.
You`re a big boy who can handle himself.
- No wonder your relationships don`t last.
- I`m a girl who hates to get tied down.
You look terrible.
You aren`t looking too good yourself.
You are still feeling the side effects?
The insomnia is permanent for me.
An hour on the Dream Machine
keeps me sane.
- What happened to you?
- Bond.
He knows nothing. I`ve been this close
to him and he still didn`t know who I was.
- You saw my father after your exchange?
- Yes.
General Moon still mourns your death.
My death.
Mr Bond.
- And Miss...?
- Swift. Space and Technology magazine.
Really? I take it Mr Bond`s been
explaining his big-bang theory.
Oh, yeah, I think I got the thrust of it.
I see.
Well, the demonstration`s about to begin
in five minutes. So shall we?
Shall we?
Not Jinx any more?
Oh, I`ll always be a jinx to you.
As you know, I try to give the planet
something in return for what it`s given me.
Those little shards of heaven
known as diamonds.
Now, diamonds aren`t just expensive
stones. They are the stuff of dreams.
And the means to make dreams real.
Imagine being able to bring light and
warmth to the darkest parts of the world.
Imagine being able to grow crops
the year round, bringing an end to hunger.
Imagine a second sun,
shining like a diamond in the sky.
Let there be light.
I give you Icarus!
Icarus is unique. Its miraculous
silver skin will inhale the sun`s light
and breathe it gently
upon the earth`s surface.
You have no idea how much Icarus
is about to change your world.
And now let us brighten this night
with our inner radiance.
- Vlad, show me the modifications.
- Yeah.
Here is the self-defence mechanism
you asked me to build in.
50,000 volts?
100.
Armed.
- And very dangerous.
- Oh, very.
M warned me this would happen.
Ah. That`s why you tried so hard
not to be interested in me.
Oh, God, you`re even worse
than your file says.
They don`t look too convinced.
Come on. Put your back into it, eh?
I know all about you, 007.
Sex for dinner, death for breakfast.
It won`t work with me.
- No?
- No.
- You`re getting good at this.
- Oh, stop it. Are we still being watched?
- Oh, they left ages ago.
- Oh, God, you`re impossible.
Come on, let`s get out of here.
You better stay here tonight.
Keep up the charade of being lovers.
All right.
I admire your restraint. You were here
a full two hours before anything blew up.
The way you`re going,
you`ll get us both killed.
James, tell me what really happened
in North Korea.
I was betrayed. That was all.
Occupational hazard.
This is crazy. You`re a double-O.
It`s only a number.
James.
Be careful.
Go back to your room.
I`ll come back for you.
Why do you want to kill me?
I thought it was the humane thing to do.
Who sent you?
Your mama. And she told me to tell you
she`s really disappointed in you.
I`ll let you in on a little secret.
This mine is fake.
But the lasers...
are real.
She won`t talk.
Let`s make it permanent.
I`ll use the laser.
Don`t leave a mess.
- Jinx.
- James! James! No, no, turn it off! Off!
Off!
James, I could use a little help here!
Switch if off!
Or I`m gonna be half the girl I used to be!
So, the girl who hates
to be tied down, huh?
- Are you gonna get me off this thing?
- What are you? CIA?
NSA. Hello? We`re on the same side.
- Doesn`t mean we`re after the same thing.
- Sure it does.
World peace, unconditional love, and
your little friend with the expensive acne.
- Zao?
- Yeah, Zao.
He`s back there with some
weird psychedelic light mask.
Probably brought it from the Cuban clinic.
He couldn`t have brought it.
It was already here.
It belongs to another Korean.
His boss.
- Kil can give us a hand to get out of here.
- I got a better idea.
- I`m going to get backup.
- Wait.
Go to Miranda first. She`s MI6.
Warn her to get out.
And what are you gonna do?
Unfinished business.
So you live to die another day...
Colonel.
At last. I was beginning
to think you`d never guess.
Was it painful?
- The gene therapy?
- You couldn`t possibly imagine.
Oh, good. I`m glad to hear that.
Oh, but there have been compensations.
Like watching you
flail around in your ignorance.
Granting you life day by day
just to see if you`d get wise. It`s been fun.
Well, the fun is about
to come to a dead end.
We only met briefly, you and I.
But you left a lasting impression.
When your intervention forced me
to present the world with a new face,
I chose to model
the disgusting Gustav Graves on you.
Oh, just in the details.
That unjustifiable swagger.
Your crass quips - a defence mechanism
concealing such inadequacy.
My defence mechanism is right here.
So... Miss Frost isn`t all she seems.
Looks can be deceptive.
Yes.
By the way, did you find out
who betrayed you in North Korea?
Only a matter of time.
You never thought of looking
inside your own organisation?
She was right under your nose.
It was so good of you
to bring your gun to bed with us.
Yes. Occupational hazard.
You see, I have a gift.
An instinct for sensing
people`s weaknesses.
Yours is women. Hers and mine
is winning whatever the cost.
So when I arranged for that fatal
overdose for the true victor at Sydney,
I won myself my very own MI6 agent,
using everything at my disposal -
her brains, her talent,
even her sex.
The coldest weapon of all.
Hello?
Miranda?
- There will be others after me, you know.
- You mean your American friend Jinx.
Soon to be the victim of a tragedy.
An ice palace can be
such a treacherous place.
Hand over the toys.
Oh, yeah.
You know, I`ve missed
your sparkling personality.
How`s that for a punch line?
Kill him.
I enjoyed last night, James.
But it really is death for breakfast.
Kill him quietly.
Kill him! Now!
- He got away.
- No matter.
The pleasure of the kill is in the chase.
Bring me the generals.
Gentlemen,
I promised you a demonstration.
Now you will see the true power of Icarus.
The Western spy runs, but he cannot hide.
Icarus will lock onto the heat signature
and concentrate the sun`s power.
Hey, boss, he beat your time.
Time to draw the line.
Global warming is a terrible thing.
Yeah, nice moves. Just like Bond.
He was pretty vigorous last night as well.
He did you?
I didn`t know he was that desperate.
He won`t come back for you. He just died
running, trying to save his own skin.
Yeah.
That`s pretty good tailoring.
I hope it doesn`t shrink when it gets wet.
Soon we will be victorious.
We`ve got one hour to wrap this up.
Let`s move.
Come on, Jinx. Where are you?
All units report. Now!
Warning. Adaptive camouflage failure.
Time to give the American her bath.
Adaptive camouflage restored.
Vlad, does the word ``ergonomics``
mean anything to you? Man? Machine?
This is still a suitcase.
Finish it, will you?
Come on. It`s warm in here. Come on.
The cold kept you alive, huh?
Must have kept you alive. Come on.
That`s it.
What took you so long?
Agent Johnson.
- James.
- Charles.
OK. Bring us up to speed on this.
Another division`s been mobilised
north of the DMZ.
- That`s 80,000 troops and counting.
- And another million in reserve.
Moon`s father won`t let it turn into a war.
Moon`s under arrest.
Hardliners staged a coup last night.
The fact remains you deliberately
misled me by implicating Bond.
- If you`d told us of your agent in Cuba...
- She`d be dead, betrayed by your mole.
We wouldn`t have had a mole
if you`d told us Miss Frost and Moon
were on the Harvard
fencing team together.
Knowing who to trust
is everything in this business.
Well, well. James Bond.
- Just in time for the fireworks.
- Let`s get down to business.
We`re at DEFCON 2.
And if the North goes South,
they`re gonna go south big time.
You don`t just stroll through
the world`s biggest minefield.
You need some kind of an edge. Icarus.
We`re taking care of that
with an ASAT launch in one hour.
- Where`s Graves?
- In the middle of a North Korean air base.
Right where we can`t touch him.
You can`t... but I can.
Look, we`re here in case things escalate,
not to make sure that they do.
No incursions into the North.
The president gave me a direct order.
And when did that ever stop you?
You make your own decision.
I`m sending in 007.
You think I`d leave this
in the hands of the British?
You go with him.
Approaching drop zone!
OK, let`s go!
- They`ve entered North Korean airspace.
- Relax, Robinson.
If our radar can`t see those switchblades,
the North Koreans sure as hell can`t.
Hey, boss, they launched against Icarus.
Leave it on automatic.
I hope nobody here is superstitious. That
is one big mirror we`re about to break.
My God.
Mobilise the South Korean troops.
And get me the president, now!
Still no news of Bond?
Vehicles.
Some big shots.
It`s him.
- 300 metres.
- Windage: one and a half.
We`ve gotta get on that plane.
You. Have my father brought down.
Father.
I regret our meeting
had to be like this.
You can`t tell it`s me?
I don`t know you.
You`ve always found it difficult
to accept me.
That made my exile easier to bear,
but I never forgot what you taught me.
``In war the victorious strategist
only seeks battle...
..after the victory has been won.``
You see, Father,
I remember my Art of War.
And this is what guarantees that victory.
My son...
What have you done to yourself?
Come, Father.
Watch the rising of your son.
The second that hits the 38th parallel,
we`ll hit them with everything we got.
That may not be enough.
Do you see, Father?
Icarus is clearing the minefield,
creating a highway for our troops.
If the Americans don`t run,
Icarus will destroy them.
Japan is a bug waiting to be squashed.
And the West will shake with fear.
- America will send nuclear warheads.
- Icarus will swat them from the sky.
You will destroy us.
You would kill your own son?
The son I knew died long ago.
Father, you disappoint me.
Caution. Caution.
Manual. Manual.
Up! Up!
Come on.
OK, guys.
OK.
I got it.
My, my. You get around.
Let`s see your gun.
Uh-uh. Left hand.
That`s it.
That`s it. Now drop it.
Looks like your friends have bailed.
Put it on autopilot.
Come on.
That`s it. Good girl.
Drowning you didn`t seem to work. I`ll
have to try something more to the point.
1 ,000 metres and closing.
I can read your every move.
Read this.
Bitch!
Oh, look! Parachutes for the both of us.
Whoops. Not any more.
You see, Mr Bond,
you can`t kill my dreams.
But my dreams can kill you.
Time to face destiny.
Time to face gravity.
I think I broke her heart.
Looks like we`re going down together.
Not yet.
- Get the back open!
- OK!
Come on!
- Come on. Come on.
- I told you I was a jinx.
I should have warned you.
My relationships don`t last either.
- At least we`re gonna die rich.
- Huh?
Come on. Come on, come on.
Come on. Come on.
Now...
you said something about
going down together?
James.
Moneypenny.
Oh, James.
Moneypenny?
I was... just testing it out.
It`s rather hard, isn`t it?
Yes. Very.
Wait. Don`t pull it out.
I`m not finished with it yet.
See? It`s a perfect fit.
- Leave it in.
- Well, it`s gotta come out sooner or later.
No, leave it in, please.
A few more minutes.
We really have to get these back.
Still the good guys, huh?
I`m still not quite sure...
how good you are.
I am so good.
Especially when you`re bad.
I need to lay down.