Where are they?
I don't know.
Dad!
Uncle Merrill!
Morgan!
Bo? Bo?
Bo, where's Morgan?
Bo?
Are you in my dream,
too?
...This is not a dr...
... Dad!
Hey...
Honey...
Morgan?
What's happening?
The dogs were barking...
woke us up.
Are you hurt?
I think God did it.
Did what, Morgan?
Look, Lee, I don't even care
if it was him.
And you can just have
a word with him,
and that'd be enough for me.
See, it was strange
finding the crops that way.
The kids were confused by it,
and, uh, it'd sure take
the strangeness away
if I knew it was just Lionel and the
Wolfington brothers messing around,
that's all.
At the movies?
Are you sure?
Alright, then.
Uh, thanks for
your patience, Lee.
Yeah. Bye.
Houdini peed.
I think he's sick.
Why don't you
take him outside?
I'll call Dr. Crawford.
He doesn't treat animals.
Well, he'll know
what to do.
Oh. That was quick,
Caroline.
I only called you folks
two hours ago.
Old Mrs. Kendleman
twisted her ankle,
as she puts it,
diving for her life
when a bunch of school kids rode
down the sidewalk on skateboards.
She went down to Thornton's
store this morning
and started spitting
on the new skateboards.
Spitting!
By the time I got there,
Mrs. Kendleman had sprayed
the whole damned place.
And she must have had
a cold or something.
I'm telling you,
I won't eat for a week.
So, what happened
to your crops?
Dad's gonna burn these
again.
It's contaminated.
You don't even know
what that word means.
It's not contaminated.
It's just tap water.
Pour it in his bowl.
It tastes funny.
It does not.
And besides, he licks
his butt every day.
I don't think
he'll mind.
Houdini?
Bo, don't run.
What's wrong, boy?
Stop it, Houdini.
Look at where
it's bent over, Father.
It's not broken.
Now, what kind of machine can bend a
stalk of corn over without breaking it?
Can't be by hand.
It's too perfect.
It doesn't sound much like Lionel
Prichard and the Wolfington brothers.
They can't take a piss
without wetting
the front of their pants.
I don't think anyone else
around here has had any problems.
I was over at Theo Henry's
farm yesterday afternoon,
and he would have
mentioned something.
Why were you
at Theo's place?
Some animals around the county
have been acting funny...
and some of them
violent.
What is it, a virus?
I don't think so,
Father.
They're more edgy,
you know, and alert.
It's almost like they act when
they smell a predator around...
peeing on themselves
and everything.
Caroline...
please stop calling me
"Father. "
What's wrong?
I don't hear my children.
He fell on me.
He wanted to kill Bo.
Did he hurt you?
No.
I'm so sorry, Morgan.
Where were you?
Houdini's sick.
Tie Isabel up to the
back of the shed, please,
and make sure
the knot's very tight.
What's the matter?
There's a monster
outside my room.
Can I have
a glass of water?
What's wrong with the water
next to your bed?
It tastes old.
What are you thinking
about?
Why do you talk to Mom
when you're by yourself?
Makes me feel better.
Does she ever
answer back?
No.
She never answers me
either.
What?
Lionel Prichard and the
Wolfington brothers are back.
It's time for
an arse-whupping.
This is not an intelligent
way to approach this.
Lee is a friend of mine.
This is his son.
Yeah, we'll be doing Lee
a favour.
Alright, listen...
we both go outside,
move around the house
in opposite directions.
We act crazy,
insane with anger...
make them crap
in their pants,
force them around till we
meet up on the other side.
Explain "act crazy. "
You know,
curse and stuff.
You want me to curse?
You don't mean it.
It's just for show.
What?
Well, it won't be
convincing.
It doesn't sound natural
when I curse.
Just make noises, then.
Explain "noises. "
Are you gonna do this
or what?
No, I'm not.
Alright, you want them stealing
something in the house next time?
On the count of three...
...1...
... Alright.
2... 3!
Aaah!
I'm insane with anger!
We're gonna beat
your arse, bitch!
We're gonna tear
your head off!
I'm losing my mind!
It's time for
an arse-whupping!
I cursed.
I heard.
How did he get...
Are you sure
this is Lionel Prichard?
You like that?
You got an old
baby monitor around?
Bo had an old
baby monitor.
You can use Bo's baby monitor
as a walkie-talkie.
...You can?
... Mm-hmm.
It only works one way,
but that'll do fine.
That is, until someone gets you an old
walkie-talkie left over at the station.
Stop! It's hideous!
Get it off!
I- I know what to do.
Hey, Bo...
turn that down till
Officer Paski leaves.
Doy-da!
You're too old
to still be doing this.
You take a glass of water,
and you finish it.
Now, what's wrong
with this one?
It has dust in it.
This one?
A hair.
Morgan took a sip, and
it has his amoebas in it.
My turn.
So, how are you, Merrill?
Fine.
How is work at
the gas station?
Stimulating.
I never got a chance
to tell you,
but I-I thought your moving in
here with your brother after...
it was a nice thing
to do.
Well, I don't think
I'm helping much.
You are.
Sorry.
Okay, so far I have,
"It was very dark. "
Yes, it was.
You can't describe him
at all?
Don't you think
that's kind of odd?
A little.
I don't know whether to look
for a giant or a midget.
No, he definitely
wasn't a midget.
Okay.
So he was tall?
I- I would say so, yes.
Probably.
Over 6 feet?
It was very dark.
Yes, it was.
How certain are you
that this was a male?
Oh, I don't know... I don't know
any girls who could run like that.
I don't know, Merrill.
I've seen some of those women
on the Olympics.
They can run like
the wind.
This guy got on our roof
in, like, a second.
O- Our roof
is 10 feet high.
They have women's high jumping
in the Olympics.
They got these
Scandinavian women
who can jump clean over me.
Caroline, I know you're
making a point here,
but I just don't know
what it is.
An out-of-town woman stopped by
the diner yesterday afternoon
and started yelling
and cussing
because they didn't have
her favourite cigarettes
at the vending machine.
She scared a couple
of the customers.
No one's seen her since.
And my point is,
we don't know anything
about the person you saw,
and we should just keep
all possibilities available.
Dad, where's the remote?
I don't know, baby.
Why don't you check
in the sofa cushions?
Excluding the possibility
that a female Scandinavian
Olympian
was running around outside
our house last night,
what else might be
a possibility?
I'm not done asking
questions,
and I don't appreciate
sarcasm.
Do you two have anyone
who might have a grudge
or something against you...
maybe a-a church member
who... who might
not have liked
the fact that
you left the church?
I don't think so.
Okay, I was out of line
with the whole female-
Scandinavian-Olympian thing.
It's just,
I'm pretty strong,
and I'm pretty fast.
And I was running
as fast as I could,
and this guy, he was...
he was just toying with us.
There's only food
under the sofa.
Baby, why don't you
just change the channel
on the television?
I did.
And?
Same show's
on every station.
Every station?
Bo, turn up the volume.
Crop signs first emerged
in the late '70s
with renewed interest
in extraterrestrial life.
They died out
by the early '80s,
dismissed as hoaxes.
This new resurgence
is wholly different.
The speed and the quantity
in which it has appeared
implies the coordination
of hundreds of individuals
over many countries.
There are only a limited
number of explanations.
Either this is one of the most
elaborate hoaxes ever created,
or basically...
it's for real.
Extraterrestrials.
What in God's name
is going on?
I did some research
after I saw your crops.
Two or three guys can make a design the
size of the one in your field overnight
using just
boards and ropes.
Really?
That's how these things
have been done in the past.
But there are
so many now.
How could so many people
be in on it?
I can't think straight.
I'm... I'm gonna go back
to the station
and have a cup of Edgar's coffee
and... and try to think clear.
And after that, I'll...
I might make some calls.
But I'll tell you something...
what I said in there, it still goes.
Your... your family
has been through a lot.
And the last thing
these children need to do
is worry about some crazy
things happening in the world.
Now, take them into town
and get their minds and your
mind on everyday things, hmm?
Good medicine.
That's good advice.
And you take care
of yourself...
Graham.
The footage you're watching
was shot yesterday afternoon
by a 34-year-old local
cameraman in Bangalore,
a southern city of India.
It's the 18th reported
crop sign
found in that country
in the last 72 hours.
Uncle Merrill, will you
turn on the radio?
They are signs intended
to be seen from the sky...
No radio either.
Just for a while.
Book money?
Sure.
Just one.
Be back for pizza
in 15.
It's just a bunch
of crock.
They're trying to sell sodas.
It's plain and simple.
Been watching these reports
since morning.
I have seen 12 soda
commercials so far...
12!
You have any books
on extraterrestrials?
Now, don't tell me you believe
this horse manure.
As a matter of fact,
I think we have one.
Came by mistake
in a shipment...
decided to keep it
for the city people.
Last row, third book
on the left, honey.
Why is no one
saying the obvious?
These are just copycats.
Someone somewhere does
the first one...
It was asthma medicine,
right, Father?
For Morgan Hess.
And it's not "Father"
anymore.
In less than an hour, a couple hundred
people get the same brilliant idea,
and here we are, on
the verge of mass hysteria.
Can I ask you a favour,
Father?
I need to clear
my conscience.
Will you listen to me?
Tracey... I am not
a reverend anymore.
I haven't been
for six months.
You know this.
All this stuff on TV...
two girls came in here talking
about the end of the world...
I'm just a little scared.
Please, I need to clear
my conscience.
I've got it figured.
You do?
I've had two separate
folks tell me
there have been strangers around
these parts last couple nights.
Can't tell
what they look like
'cause they're staying
in the shadows... covertlike.
Nobody's been hurt,
mind you.
And that's the giveaway.
I see.
It's called "probing. "
It's a military procedure.
You send out a
reconnaissance group...
very small...
to check things out.
Not to engage but
to evaluate the situation...
evaluate the level
of danger,
make sure things
are all clear.
Clear for what?
For the rest of them.
Yeah?
You got a pamphlet or
something I can read?
Sure.
Thanks.
You didn't used to play
baseball, did ya?
Shit, I know you.
You're Merrill Hess.
I was there the day
you hit that 507-footer
over the left-field wall...
set the record.
Man, that thing had
a motor on it.
It's still the record,
right?
Got the bat at home
o- on the wall.
You've got two minor-league
home-run records, don't ya?
Five.
Why weren't you in the pros
making stacks of cash
and getting your toes licked
by beautiful women?
'Cause he has another record
most people don't know about.
He has the minor-league
strikeout record.
Hello, Lionel.
Merrill's a class-A
screw-up.
He would just swing that bat
as hard as he could every time.
Didn't matter what
the coaches said,
didn't matter
who was on base.
He would just whip that bat
through the air as hard as he could.
Looked like a lumberjack
chopping down a tree.
Merrill here has more
strikeouts than any two players.
You really got
the strikeout record?
Felt wrong not to swing.
It's contaminated.
Carl, there's something wrong
with our water.
Your water's fine.
Bo has this thing
about her drinking water.
She had it
her whole life.
It's like a tick people
have, except it's not a tick.
Is that right?
13!
¶ Don't give me
that so-so-soda ¶
¶ That same old cola ¶
¶ I wanna pop ¶
...¶ Pop, pop I wanna...
Shasta ¶... I'll take it.
I cursed
37 times last week.
I said the "F" word a couple
times, but mostly... "shits"
and... "bastards. "
Is "douche bag"
a curse?
I suppose that would
depend on its usage.
How about, "John, you're a
douche bag for kissing Barbara"?
It's a curse.
Then it's not 37.
It's 71.
Pharmacy crowded?
I don't want
any one of you
spending time with
Tracey Abernathy alone.
Is that understood?
Is that him?
Yeah.
Who is he?
What is it?
It's Bo's baby monitor.
I found it in the basement.
I'm gonna use it
as a walkie-talkie.
What if it's catching
a signal from them?
It's not.
But it wasn't working.
Morgan, this crop stuff
is about a bunch of nerds who never
had a girlfriend in their lives.
They're, like, 30, and they
work up little codes together,
and they analyse Greek mythology
and make up secret societies
where other guys who never had
girlfriends before can join in.
They do stupid crap
like this to feel special.
It's a scam.
Nerds were doing it
25 years ago,
and new nerds
are doing it again.
It's just static, Morgan,
alright.
Turn it up. See.
It's a code.
Why can't they get
girlfriends?
Can I see that, please?
It's noise.
It's broken, Morgan. It's
just gonna keep doing this.
Maybe some new
batteries...
We might lose the signal.
This is exactly
what the nerds want.
I'm getting out now.
Nobody move.
Voices.
Did you hear that?
Not English, though.
You heard the voices,
right, Uncle Merrill?
I heard them, Morgan.
Probably picking up
another baby monitor.
That's right.
Let me see it.
Stop!
See, this is why
we're not watching TV.
People get obsessed.
I'm letting go now.
No, Dad!
Don't do it!
You'll lose the signal.
Don't let go.
It gets clearer
the higher you hold it.
I got it.
Bo, honey, I don't want
you climbing on the car.
Come here.
Stop!
There's two of them
talking.
Isabel, you're gonna
feel very silly
when this turns out to be
all just make-believe.
You're wasting your time here!
I'm not gonna report this or
anything you do to my crops
to the news or TV or anybody!
You're not going to get famous!
Okay.
Let's turn on the TV.
It first
appeared 52 minutes ago.
Mexico City officials
as well as U.S. officials
have confirmed
that these are not aircraft
from either government's
air force.
The first sighting was made
by an Air Mexico 747
en route from Mazatlán
to New York
as the unidentified crafts
entered Mexico City air space.
They were not detected by
radar by either country.
The nerds were right.
We have to tape this.
My ballet recital.
Listen, Bo, this
is very important.
Everything people have written about
in science books is going to change.
The history of the world's
future is on the TV right now.
We need to record this so you
can show your children this tape
and say you were there.
For your children, Bo.
My ballet recital.
Dad!
Find another tape.
Uncle Merrill,
I'm using your tape.
You are seeing a live feed
from our affiliate
down here in Mexico City.
This image has not been
adjusted or enhanced in any way.
What you're seeing is real.
It's unbelievable.
Everything they wrote
in science books
is about to change.
I told you.
Some people
are probably thinking
this is the end
of the world.
That's true.
Do you think it could be?
Yes.
How can you say that?
That wasn't
the answer you wanted?
Couldn't you pretend to be
like you used to be?
Give me some comfort.
People break down
into two groups
when they experience
something lucky.
Group number one sees
it as more than luck,
more than coincidence.
They see it as a sign...
evidence that there
is someone up there
watching out for them.
Group number two sees
it as just pure luck,
a happy turn of chance.
I'm sure the people
in group number two
are looking at those 14 lights
in a very suspicious way.
For them, the situation
isn't 50-50.
Could be bad, could be good.
But deep down,
they feel that
whatever happens,
they're on their own.
And that fills
them with fear.
Yeah,
there are those people.
But there's a whole lot of
people in the group number one.
When they see
those 14 lights,
they're looking at a miracle.
And deep down, they feel that
whatever's going to happen,
there'll be someone
there to help them.
And that fills
them with hope.
See, what you have to ask yourself
is, what kind of person are you?
Are you the kind who
sees signs, sees miracles?
Or do you believe that
people just get lucky?
Or look at the question
this way...
is it possible that there
are no coincidences?
I was at this party once.
I'm on the couch
with Randa McKinney.
She was just sitting there
looking beautiful,
staring at me.
I go to lean in
and kiss her...
...and I realise
I have gum in my mouth.
So I turn,
take out the gum,
stuff it in a paper cup
next to the sofa,
and turn around.
Randa McKinney throws up
all over herself.
I knew the second it happened
it was a miracle.
I could have been kissing
her when she threw up.
That would have
scarred me for life.
I may never have recovered.
I'm a miracle man.
Those lights are a miracle.
There you go.
So, which type are you?
Do you feel comforted?
Yeah, I do.
Then what does it matter?
I never told you
the last words
that Colleen said
before they let her die.
She said, "See. "
Then her eyes glazed a bit.
And then she said,
"Swing away. "
You know why she said that?
Because the nerve endings in her
brain were firing as she died,
and some random memory of us at one of your
baseball games just popped into her head.
There is no one watching
out for us, Merrill.
We are all on our own.
What do you know?
Well, there was an accident...
drunk driving, they weren't sure...
He wasn't drunk.
Ray fell asleep at the wheel.
...Is he okay?
... Yeah.
That was the first thing
Colleen asked, too.
She's talking.
What ambulance is she in?
She's not in an ambulance,
Father.
For the kids' protection.
All they were doing was
watching TV from 5.00 a. m.
I felt like they were getting
obsessed, like you said.
They should be playing furry, furry
rabbit or tea party or something.
What's furry, furry rabbit?
It's a game, isn't it?
Anyways, they closed
the schools.
And there's been some
interesting developments.
What time is it?
11.00 a. m.
They're gone, but they're
not really gone.
We just can't see them.
Early this morning,
a bird flew into the area
where the lights were
hovering last night.
It stopped dead in the air
and fell straight down.
They caught it on tape. They've
been playing it all morning.
The footage looks like the bird
flew into a wall in the sky.
They found the bird. His...
his head was crushed in.
They think they have some kind of invisible-shield
thing going, I- like an optical illusion.
They're still there,
hovering.
Some people think there's
more of them now...
all over the place,
over us, even.
There's a theory about
the c... the crop circles.
They could be
some kind of...
some kind of landmark,
visual mapping system
so they could navigate,
coordinate...
makes sense.
Want to hear a story?
Is it true?
So the aliens can't
read our minds.
Oh.
Oh, of course.
They tell you everything
in this book.
It says they're probably
very small, like my height,
because as their
brains develop,
there was no use
for physical development.
It also says they're
probably vegetarians
because they would have realised
the benefits of such a diet.
Who wrote this book?
Scientists who have been
persecuted for their beliefs.
That means
they're unemployed.
If you're gonna make fun
of it, then forget it.
This is serious.
I don't know
what got into me.
There are pictures.
Dr. Bimbu, one of the
authors of the book...
...Bimbu?
... Dad.
I just asked his name.
You had a tone.
He said there are two reasons why
extraterrestrials would visit us...
to make contact in
the spirit of exploration
and furthering the
knowledge of the universe,
or the other reason...
they're hostile.
They've used up all the
resources on their planet,
and they're looking to
harvest our planet next.
Here.
Looks a little like
our house, doesn't it?
Same windows.
That's weird.
Yeah, oh, yeah.
That's enough from
Dr. Bimbu for now.
Everybody in this house
needs to calm down
and eat some fruit
or something.
Hello?
Father?
Hello?!
I'm going out
for a few minutes.
No one leaves this house...
no one.
Where you going?
...Ray Reddy's house.
Why?
I think
he just called here.
You don't think
something bad will happen,
do you, Morgan?
Why? You have one of
your feelings again?
Is it bad?
I won't let anything bad
happen to you.
I don't want you to die.
Who said I was gonna die?
Hello, Ray.
What happened?
I wrote your number
down to call you.
It's been sitting next to
the phone for 6 months.
When I knew it was
inside the house...
I couldn't think of any other
number to call. I panicked.
Thank you for coming,
Father.
You're welcome, Ray.
I worked so long
that night.
I've never fallen asleep
driving before...
never since.
Don't.
Most of the ride home,
there wasn't a car in sight
in either direction.
If I'd have
fallen asleep then,
I would have ended up in
a ditch with a headache.
And it had to be at that
right moment...
that 10, 15 seconds when
I passed her walking.
It was like
it was meant to be.
I guess if this is
the end of the world,
I'm screwed, right?
People who kill
reverends' wives
aren't exactly ushered to the
front of the line in Heaven.
Wh... Where
are you going, Ray?
To the lake.
The way I see it...
these places marked
in crops and such...
none of them are
really near water.
I don't think
they like water.
Can't be any worse
than here.
Did you see something, Ray?
I know what I've
done to you.
I made you question
your faith.
I'm truly sorry for what
I've done to you and yours.
Alright.
And don't open
my pantry, Father.
I found one of them in
there and locked him in.
The startling footage
we're about to show you
was photographed by a
42-year-old, Romero Valadarez.
This video was taken
yesterday afternoon
at his son's 7 th birthday
in the city of
Passo Fundo, Brazil.
It was sent to the local
news bureau there
and sent to us via satellite
just a few minutes ago.
All initial opinions are
this is genuine.
What you're about to see
may disturb you.
Oh!
Hello?
The police are here.
I am with them.
I am a police officer.
I just want to
talk with you.
We know all about the hoax.
We already took some of your
friends downtown in a paddy waggon.
Just tell us your name
and why you did it,
and we'll give you the same
deal we gave the others.
Don't throw your
life away, son.
Oh! Ah!
Oh!
Their skin changes colours.
That's why we couldn't
see them that night.
Tell me something, Morgan.
Uh... in this
book of yours...
did they happen to detail
what would happen
if they were hostile?
Yes.
It said they would
probably invade.
They would use ground
tactics... hand-to-hand combat.
They wouldn't use our technology
or fight an airborne battle
'cause they know eventually
we would use nuclear weapons.
Then the planet would
be useless to them.
How could anyone possibly know
that information? It's ridiculous.
What else did it say?
They said there are one of
two outcomes of an invasion.
One, they fight and are
defeated and have to return again
with full forces hundreds, maybe
even thousands, of years later.
What's two?
They win.
I'm sorry, what...
what book is this?
Is this really
happening?
I heard a theory that,
uh,
they don't like
places near water.
Maybe we'd be safe from them
near a lake or something.
Sounds made-up.
I saw one of them
at Ray Reddy's house.
I can't be sure,
but I got the distinct feeling
he wanted to harm me.
So...
we can choose to believe this
lake idea, pack up, and go,
or we can stay here, hide
inside our home, wait it out.
We might be overreacting, but
I'm willing to live with that.
Either way, at least
we'll be together.
All those in favour of
the lake idea, raise your hand.
Yeah.
All those in favour of home,
raise your hand.
Okay.
My vote counts as two.
That's bullshit!
You're cheating!
Morgan, calm down.
I get two votes because
I represent two parents here.
We don't know anything yet.
We'll be safe here anyway.
I don't want to leave home.
This is where
we lived with Mom.
That's got nothing
to do with this.
I change my vote.
You can't change your vote.
All those in favour of home,
raise your hand.
This is ridiculous.
You lose, 3-2.
We're going to board up
every window in this house.
How do we know boards
will do anything?
Because they seem to have
trouble with pantry doors.
The information we're receiving
comes from our affiliates
across the world.
Dad, Uncle Merrill!
Amman joins Nairobi,
Beijing, and Jerusalem
as the latest to confirm
the appearance of lights.
There are lights
in over 274 cities.
They think it'll be
400 within the hour.
They're appearing at or within
one mile of crop signs.
They were for navigation.
They made a map.
They're gonna be
within a mile of us.
Dad?
Yes?
They think
these are staged
immediately preceding
an attack manoeuvre.
I was wrong.
They're hostile.
It's like "War of the Worlds. "
Ground forces
have been assembled
in countries
throughout the globe.
Hundreds of thousands
have flocked to temples,
synagogues, and churches.
God be with us all.
I'm going to get back
to the windows.
Hey, you guys okay?
Some guy had a sign saying
it was the end of the world.
Don't worry.
You won't let anything
happen to us, right?
No way.
I wish you were my dad.
What did you say?
Don't you ever say anything
like that again.
Ever.
There's too many windows
in the bedrooms.
We don't have enough
boards.
We'll board up
the bedroom doors.
Where are we
gonna sleep?
In the family room.
What about Isabel?
We'll tie her up in the garage
after dinner.
I'll make some sandwiches.
I want spaghetti.
We'll just eat fast, Bo.
Spaghetti sounds great.
What do you want, Morgan?
Anything?
French toast...
and mashed potatoes.
Now we're talking.
How about you, Merrill?
Chicken teriyaki.
Good choice.
I'm going to have
a cheeseburger with bacon.
Extra bacon.
What's the matter
with everyone? Eat.
Maybe we should say
a prayer.
No.
Why not?
We're not saying a prayer.
Bo has a bad feeling.
I had a dream.
We aren't saying a prayer.
Eat!
I hate you.
That's fine.
You let Mom die.
Morgan.
I am not wasting one more minute
of my life on prayer.
Not one more minute.
Understood?
Now we are going
to enjoy this meal.
No one can stop us from enjoying
this meal, so enjoy it!
...Stop crying!
...Graham...
... Don't yell at her!
Alright, since you're
all not gonna eat.
I'm gonna try
some of everything.
It's happening.
Graham, hurry.
Did I ever tell you
what everyone said
when you were born, Bo?
You came out of your mama,
and you didn't even cry.
You just opened your eyes,
and you looked around
the room at everybody.
Your eyes
were so big and gorgeous.
All the ladies in the room
just gasped.
I mean,
they literally gasped.
And they go,
"Oh, she's like an angel. "
And they said, "We've never
seen a baby so beautiful. "
And then... you know
what happened?
They put you on the table
to clean you up,
and you looked up at me
and you smiled.
They say babies that young
can't smile.
You smiled.
Let's go down now.
We forgot Isabel.
Should we turn off
the lights?
They already know
we're here.
Dad...
Do you know what happened
when you were born, Morgan?
You came out, and your mama
kept bleeding,
so the doctors rushed you
out of the room
before I even had time
to see you.
They're on the roof.
While they
were fixing her up,
all she kept asking about
was you.
They're in the house.
I wanted your mama
to see you first
because she had dreamt
about you her whole life.
Then she got feeling better,
they brought you in,
and they placed you
in her arms,
and she looked at you,
and you looked at her,
and you just stared at each
other for the longest time.
And then she said real soft,
"Hello, Morgan.
I'm your mama.
You look
just how I dreamt. "
The attic door.
Let's go.
Come on.
We forgot
our foil helmets.
Have we got anything to wedge
against the door knob?
They'll read our minds.
You're scaring
your sister.
I'm already scared.
Merrill.
I'm looking!
They'll know
our secret thoughts.
I'm not ready.
Merrill!
Got it!
...Dad!
Where's Bo?
I'm okay.
What's happening out there?
I can't even imagine.
I hope they're doing better
than we are.
We don't even have helmets.
They're only making noises.
They're not trying to get in.
Why would they do that?
They want our attention
on the door?
They're distracting us.
From what?
The book says they're probably
very good problem solvers.
They'll find a way in.
Morgan,
give me your flashlight.
They used to pour coal
down in this basement.
There's a coal chute
in here.
I can feel air.
Me too!
It's getting stronger.
I'm close.
What?
Hold him!
I got him!
We don't have
his medicine.
Don't be afraid, Morgan.
We'll slow this down
together.
Feel my chest.
Feel it moving
in and out.
Breathe like me.
Come on.
I dreamt this.
Stay with me.
I know it hurts.
Be strong, baby.
It'll pass.
Don't do this to me
again.
Not again.
I hate you.
The fear is feeding him.
Don't be afraid
of what's happening.
Believe it's going to pass.
Believe it.
Just wait.
Don't be afraid.
The air is coming.
Believe.
We don't have to be afraid.
It's about to pass.
Here it comes.
Don't be afraid.
Here comes the air.
Don't be afraid, Morgan.
Feel my chest.
Breathe with me.
Together. The air
is going in our lungs.
Together.
We're the same.
We should save
the flashlights.
Ray's truck
swerved off the road
and hit Colleen
and then a tree,
and she was pinned
between the two.
What does that mean...
pinned?
The truck...
the truck has severed
most of her lower half.
What did you say?
She won't be saved.
Her body is pinned
in such a way
that it's alive when it
shouldn't be alive,
and the truck is
holding her together.
And she doesn't feel much,
and she's... she's talking
almost like normal,
and we didn't
pull the truck out
'cause we... we wanted you
to come down here
and be with her
as long as she's awake.
And that won't be very long.
Now, Father, do you understand
what I've told you?
Caroline...
is this the last time I'm
gonna talk with my wife?
Yes, it is.
People think they came here
to take over the planet.
That's bull.
I don't think that.
My friend and I saw them.
...I found a pack
of light bulbs.
They poisoned his family.
They dragged them away.
Nobody believes it, but they
didn't come here for our planet.
This is a raid.
They came here for us,
to harvest us.
We're lucky as hell
they're leaving here.
They're leaving?
That's what they're saying.
How long
have we been sleeping?
12 hours or so.
He said
they had poison gas...
they secrete
in small amounts.
A lot of people died.
But they're leaving.
They left real fast
this morning,
like something
scared them off.
They left some
of their wounded behind.
Why are they going?
People must have figured out
a way to beat them.
Everyone has a weakness,
right?
You didn't think we'd make it
through the night, did you?
No.
Listen...
there's things I can take
and a couple things I can't.
One of them I can't take
is when my older brother,
who's everything
I want to be...
starts losing faith
in things.
I saw your eyes last night.
I don't want to ever see
your eyes like that again.
Okay?
I'm serious.
Okay.
He's been like that
for a while.
He needs his medicine.
Have they said anything
about our area?
Philadelphia and its outlying
counties are cleared...
but who knows for sure?
He's not strong enough.
If he has another attack
right now...
I know.
We'd have to be sure before
we opened up that door, Graham.
It's good enough for me.
Me too.
Get the syringes' well.
We may need to give him
an epinephrine shot.
The atmosphere here is
cautiously optimistic.
...They're doing this on TV.
... People are celebrating.
There's a great sense
of relief.
...They're dancing.
... Yeah, like this.
As we begin evaluating
the loss of life,
...Do you want to see it?... we
will be left with a lot of questions.
...I'll bring the TV in here.... I
see the same expression on every face.
We know the battle turned
around in the Middle East.
Three small cities there found a
primitive method to defeat them.
We have no further details
at this time.
Hi, sweetie.
Hi, baby.
I was... just taking a walk
before dinner.
You love walks.
It was meant to be.
Does it hurt?
I don't feel much.
Good.
Tell Morgan...
to play games.
It's okay to be silly.
I will.
Tell Bo to listen
to her brother.
He'll always take care
of her.
I will.
And tell Graham...
I'm here.
Tell him...
see.
Tell him to see.
And tell Merrill
to swing away.
See, what you have to ask yourself
is, what kind of person are you?
Are you the kind that sees
signs, sees miracles?
Or do you believe that
people just get lucky?
Is it possible...
there are no coincidences?
Swing away, Merrill.
Merrill...
swing away.
That's why he had asthma.
It can't be luck.
His lungs were closed.
No poison got in.
Don't touch him.
Give him a minute.
Graham...
Give him a second.
D- Daddy...
Don't touch him.
Graham...
Don't... don't.
Dad?
What happened?
Did someone save me?
Yeah, baby,
I think someone did.