Senator: Today
is a day for truth
The world needs to know what happened
and to know what he stands for
That kind of power is very dangerous
Let the record show that this committee
holds him responsible
Alfred: That's how it starts
the fever,
the rage,
that turns good men cruel
This Bat vilgilante
is like a one man reign of terror!
Perry: You don't get to decide what the right thing is
Nobody cares about Clark Kent taking on Batman
Lois Lane: This means something
it’s all some people have, it’s all that gives them hope
Martha Kent: People hate what they dont understand
Be their hero Clark
Be their angel,
Be their monument,
Be anything they need you to be,
Or be none of it
You dont owe this world a thing
You never did.
Lex Luthor: Do you know the oldest line of Murphy Senator?
Devil's dont come from hell beneath us!
Senator: They come from the sky
Batman: Twenty years in Gotham. How many good guys are left?
How many stayed that way?
He has the power to wipe out the entire human race
and I have to destroy him
Alfred: Your'e gonna begin a war
He is not our enemy
Lex Luthor: Black and Blue
God vs Man
Day vs Night
The Red Capes are coming
~~==Made by Ultron59==~~