FANTASTIC BEASTS AND WHERE TO FIND THEM
Subtitle by Bambula
Dougal... you settle down now, please.
It won’t be long.
Next.
British, huh? -Yes.
-First trip to New York? -Yes.
Anything edible in there?
-No.
Livestock?
Must get that fixed... ahh, no.
Let me take a look.
Welcome to New York.
-Thank you.
Next!
And it was like a... like a
wind or like a... like a ghost...
but dark... and I saw its eyes.
Shinin’ white eyes...
A dark wind... with eyes.
-Like a dark mass,
and it dove down there, down underground.
Someone ought do something about it.
It's everywhere this thing.
It's out of control.
Hey, did you get anything?
-Dark wind, blah blah.
It’s some atmospheric hooey.
Or electrical.
Hey, you thirsty? -Nah, I’m on the
wagon. Promised Martha I’d lay off.
It's atmospheric.
This great city sparkles with
the jewels of man’s invention!
Movie theaters, automobiles,
the wireless, electric lights.
All dazzle and bewitch us!
-So sorry.
But where there is light
there is shadow, friend.
Something is stalking our city, wreaking
destruction and then disappearing without a trace.
Listen to me.
We have to fight, join us,
the Second Salemers, in our fight!
-Excuse me, doll. -You hear me?
Just trying to get to the bank.
-We have to fight together...
Excuse me, trying... -Watch it!
-So sorry, my case.
No harm done.
Excuse me!
-You, friend!
What drew you to our meeting today?
Oh... I was just passing.
-Are you a seeker?
A seeker after truth?
I’m more of a chaser, really.
Hear my words and heed my warning.
And laugh if you dare.
Witches live among us!
We have to fight together for the sake
of our children, for the sake of tomorrow!
What do you say to that, friend?
Excuse me.
Can I help you, sir?
No, I was just... just... waiting.
Hi.
What brings you here?
-Same as you...
You’re here to get a loan
to open up a bakery? -Yes.
What are the odds of that?
Well, may the best man win, I guess.
-Excuse me.
Hey, mister... Hey, mister!
Hey, fella! -Mr. Kowalski,
Mr. Bingley will see you now.
Okay... Okay.
You are currently working
in a canning factory?
That’s the best I can
do... I only got back in ’24.
Got back?
-From Europe, sir.
Yeah... I was part of the
Expeditionary Forces there.
All right. -Mr. Kowalski. -You
gotta try the paczki. Okay?
It’s my grandmother’s
recipe, the orange zest... just...
Mr. Kowalski, what do you propose
to offer the bank as collateral?
Collateral?
-Collateral.
There are machines now that can
produce hundreds of doughnuts an hour...
I know, I know, but they’re
nothing like what I can do.
The bank must be
protected, Mr. Kowalski.
Good day to you.
Hey, Mr. English guy!
I think your egg is hatching.
What? What just happened?
But...
Excuse me...
I was... over there. I was... over there?
In you hop...
-Hello?
No. Everyone settle down. Stay.
Dougal, don’t make me come in there.
Don’t make me come down there.
Absolutely not!
Alohomora!
Oh, so you’re gonna steal the money, huh?
Petrificus Totalus!
Mr. Bingley!
Kowalski!
Really?
No... Look at that.
Look.
Oh no... No, no, no.
Don’t shoot. Don’t shoot!
What? For the last time, you pilfering
pest... paws off what doesn’t belong to you.
I’m awfully sorry about all that.
What the hell was that?
-Nothing that need concern you.
Now unfortunately you have seen far
too much, so if you wouldn’t mind...
if you just stand there, this
will be over in a jiffy. -Sure, yeah.
Sorry...
Bugger.
Who are you?
-I’m sorry?
Who are you? -Newt Scamander. And you
are? -What’s that thing in your case?
That’s my Niffler.
You’ve got something on your... -Why in the name
of Deliverance Dane did you let that thing loose?
I didn’t mean to, he’s incorrigible, you
see, anything shiny, he’s all over the place.
You didn’t mean to? -No. -You could not have
chosen a worse time to let that creature loose!
We’re in the middle of a situation here!
I’m taking you in.
-You’re taking me where?
Magical Congress of the
United States of America.
So, you work for MACUSA?
What are you, some kind of investigator?
Can you please tell me you
took care of the No-Maj?
The what? -The No-Maj!
No-magic... the non-wizard!
Oh, sorry, we call them Muggles.
-You wiped his memory, right?
The No-Maj with the case?
That’s a Section 3A, Mr.
Scamander. I’m taking you in.
Come on.
Er... sorry, but I do have things to do,
actually. -Well, you’ll have to rearrange them!
What are you doing in New York anyway?
-I came to buy a birthday present.
Couldn’t you have done that in London?
No, there’s only one breeder
of Appaloosa Puffskeins
in the world and he lives in New York, so no.
I got a Section 3A.
By the way, we don’t allow the breeding
of magical creatures in New York.
We closed that guy down a year ago.
Hey, Goldstein.
-Hey, Red.
Major Investigation Department.
-I thought you was...
Major Investigation Department!
I got a Section 3A!
The International Confederation
is threatening to send a delegation.
They think this is related to
Grindelwald’s attacks in Europe.
I was there. This is a beast.
No human could do what this thing
is capable of, Madam President.
Whatever it is, one thing’s
clear, it must be stopped.
It’s terrorizing No-Majs and when
No-Majs are afraid, they attack.
This could mean exposure.
It could mean war.
I made your position here
quite clear, Miss Goldstein.
Yes, Madam President, but I...
-You are no longer an Auror.
No, Madam President, but...
-Goldstein.
There’s been a minor incident... -Well, this office
is currently concerned with very major incidents.
Get out.
-Yes, ma’am.
So, you got your wand permit? All
foreigners have to have them in New York.
I made a postal application weeks ago.
Scamander... And you were
just in Equatorial Guinea?
I’ve just completed a year in the field.
I’m writing a book about magical creatures.
-Like... an extermination guide?
No. A guide to help people understand why
we should be protecting these creatures
instead of killing them.
-Goldstein! Where is she?
Where is she? Goldstein!
Goldstein!
Did you just butt in on the
Investigative Team again?
Where’ve you been?
-What?
Where’d she pick you up?
-Me?
Have you been tracking them Second
Salemers again? -Of course not, sir.
Afternoon, Mr. Graves, sir!
-Afternoon, Abernathy.
Mr. Graves, sir, this is Mr. Scamander.
He has a crazy creature in that case
and it got out and caused
mayhem in a bank, sir.
Let’s see the little guy.
But, sir...
Tina...
I’m sorry, Grandma.
My momma, your momma,
gonna catch a witch.
flying on a switch.
My momma, your momma,
witches never cry.
witches gonna die!
Witch number one, drown in
a river!
Witch number two,
gotta noose to give her!
Witch number three,
gonna watch her burn.
Witch number four, flogging
take a turn.
Collect your leaflets before
you get food, children.
Is it a witch’s mark, ma’am?
No. He’s okay.
I can’t believe you
didn’t obliviate that man!
If there’s an inquiry, I’m finished! -So why
would you be finished? I’m the one that’s...
I’m not supposed to go
near the Second Salemers!
What was that?
Er... moth, I think. Big moth.
Hey, quiet down. I’m trying to get a statement.
-I’m telling you it’s a gas explosion again.
I ain’t taking the kids back
up there until it’s safe. -Sorry, ma’am.
There ain’t no smell of gas.
-It wasn’t gas, Officer, I seen it!
It wuzza... a gigantic...
a huge hippopotto gas. Gas.
I don't know.
Mr. Scamander.
It was open?
Just a smidge... -That crazy
Niffler thing’s on the loose again?
It might be.
-Then look for it! Look!
His neck’s bleeding, he’s hurt!
Wake up, Mr. No-Maj.
Mercy Lewis, what is that?
-Nothing to worry about. That is a Murtlap.
What else have you got in there?
You!
-Hello.
Easy, Mr...
-Kowalski... Jacob.
You can’t obliviate him!
We need him as a witness.
I’m sorry, you’ve just yelled at me the length
of New York for not doing it in the first place.
He’s hurt! He looks ill!
-He’ll be fine. Murtlap bites aren’t serious.
I admit that is a slightly more
severe reaction than I’ve seen,
but if it was really serious,
he’d have...
What?
Well, the first symptom
would be flames out of
his anus...
-This is balled up!
It’ll last forty-eight hours at most!
I can keep him if you want me to.
Oh, keep him? We don’t
keep them! Mr. Scamander,
do you know anything about the wizarding community
in America? -I do know a few things, actually.
I know you have rather backwards laws
about relations with non-magic people.
That you’re not meant to befriend
them, that you can’t marry them,
which seems mildly absurd to me.
-Who’s going to marry him?
You’re both coming with me.
-I don’t see why I need to come with you.
Help me!
-I’m dreaming, right?
Please. -Yeah, I’m tired,
I never went to the bank.
This is all just some big nightmare, right?
-For the both of us, Mr. Kowalski.
And so this is the newsroom.
Let's go.
Hey, how are you? Make
way for the Barebones!
Now, they’re just putting the
papers to bed, as they say.
Mr. Shaw, sir, he’s with the senator.
Never mind that, Barker,
I wanna see my father!
I’m so sorry, Mr. Shaw, but your son insisted.
-Father, you’re going to want to hear this.
I’ve got something huge!
Your brother and I are busy here,
Langdon. Working on his election campaign.
We don’t have time for this.
This is Mary Lou Barebone from
the New Salem Preservation Society,
and she’s got a big story for you!
-Oh, she has, has she?
There’s strange things
going on all over the city.
The people behind this,
they are not like you and me.
This is witchcraft, don’t you see.
-Langdon. -She doesn’t want any money.
Then either her story is worthless,
or she’s lying about the cost.
Nobody gives away anything valuable
for free, Langdon. -You are right, Mr. Shaw.
What we desire is infinitely more
valuable than money: It’s your influence.
Millions of people read your newspapers and
they need to be made aware about this danger.
The crazy disturbances in the
subway, just look at the pictures!
I’d like you and your friends to leave.
-No, you’re missing a trick here.
Just look at the evidence.
-Really. -Langdon.
Just listen to Father and go. And...
Take the freaks with you.
-This is Father’s office, not yours. -Okay.
And I’m sick of this every time I
walk in here... -That's it. Thank you.
We hope you’ll reconsider, Mr. Shaw.
We’re not difficult to find.
Until then, we thank you for your time.
Hey, boy.
You dropped something.
Here you go, freak. Why don’t you put
that in the trash where you all belong.
Take a right here.
Okay, before we go in... I’m not
supposed to have men on the premises.
In that case, Mr. Kowalski and I can easily
seek other accommodation. -Oh no, you don’t!
Watch your step.
That you, Tina?
Yes, Mrs. Esposito!
-Are you alone?
I’m always alone, Mrs. Esposito!
Teenie, you brought men home?
Gentlemen, this is my sister.
You want to put something on, Queenie?
-Sure.
So, who are they?
-That’s Mr. Scamander.
He’s committed a serious infraction
of the National Statute of Secrecy.
He’s a criminal?
-Uh-huh.
And this is Mr. Kowalski, he’s a No-Maj.
-A No-Maj?
Teen, what are you up to?
-He’s sick, it’s a long story.
Mr. Scamander has lost something,
I’m going to help him find it.
You need to sit down, honey.
Hey, he hasn’t eaten all day.
That’s rough, he didn’t get
the money he wanted for his bakery.
You bake, honey?
I love to cook.
-You’re a Legilimens?
Uh-huh, yeah. But I always have trouble
with your kind. Brits. It’s the accent.
You know how to read minds?
-Don’t worry, honey.
Most guys think what you was
thinking, first time they see me.
Now, you need food.
Hot dog... again? -Don’t read my
mind! -Not a very wholesome lunch.
Hey, Mr. Scamander,
you prefer pie or strudel?
I really don’t have a preference.
You prefer strudel, huh, honey?
Strudel it is.
Well, sit down, Mr. Scamander.
We’re not going to poison you.
You’re upset. It’s your mother again.
Somebody’s said something,
what did they say? Tell me.
Do you think I’m a freak? -No, I
think you’re a very special young man
or I wouldn’t have asked
you to help me, now would I?
Have you any news?
-I’m still looking.
Mr. Graves, if I knew
whether it was a girl or boy...
My vision showed only
the child’s immense power.
He or she is no older than ten,
and I saw this child in close
proximity to your mother.
She I saw so plainly.
That could be any one of hundreds.
-There is something else.
Something I haven’t told you.
I saw you beside me in New York.
You’re the one that gains this child’s trust.
You are the key, I saw this.
You want to join the wizarding world.
I want those things too,
Credence. I want them for you.
So find the child. Find the
child and we’ll all be free.
The job ain’t that glamorous. I
mean, I spend most days making coffee,
unjinxing the john.
Tina’s the career girl.
Nah. We’re orphans. Ma and Pa died
of dragon pox when we were kids.
You’re sweet. But we got each other!
Could you stop reading
my mind for a second?
Don’t get me wrong,
I love it.
This meal, it’s insanely good!
This is what I do, I’m a cook.
And this is, like, the greatest
meal I have ever had in my life.
Oh, you slay me! I ain’t never really
talked to a No-Maj before.
Really?
I am not flirting!
I’m just saying, don’t go getting attached,
he’s going to have to be obliviated!
It’s nothing personal.
Hey, you okay, honey? -Miss Goldstein, I think
Mr. Kowalski could do with an early night.
And besides, you and I will need to be up
early tomorrow morning to find my Niffler, so...
What’s a Niffler?
-Don’t ask.
Okay, you guys can bunk in here.
I thought you might like a hot drink?
Hey, Mr. Scamander...
Look, cocoa!
The toilet’s down the hall to the right.
-Thanks...
Very much.
Come on.
For the love of...
Will you sit down?
-Good idea.
That’s definitely the Murtlap. You
must be particularly susceptible.
See, you’re a Muggle. So our
physiologies are subtly different.
Stay still. Now that
should stop the sweating.
And one of those should sort the twitch.
Take that.
Come on...
What you got there? -This
the locals call “Swooping Evil”,
not the friendliest of names.
It’s quite an agile fellow.
I’ve been studying him. And
I am pretty sure his venom
could be quite useful if properly diluted.
Just to remove bad memories, you know.
Probably shouldn’t let
him loose in here, though.
Come on.
Come on. Down you come.
Oh, thank Paracelsus.
If you’d have got out that could
have been quite catastrophic.
You see, he’s the real
reason I came to America.
To bring Frank home.
No, sorry, stay there, he’s a
wee bit sensitive to strangers.
Here you are, here you are.
He was trafficked, you see.
I found him in Egypt, he was all chained up.
Couldn’t leave him there,
had to bring him back.
I’m going to put you back where
you belong, aren’t I, Frank?
To the wilds of Arizona.
Here they come. -Here
who comes? -The Graphorns.
You’re all right. You’re all right.
Hello, hello!
So they’re the last
breeding pair in existence.
If I hadn’t managed to rescue them, that
could have been the end of Graphorns, forever.
All right.
What, you rescue these creatures?
-Yes, that’s right.
Rescue, nurture, and protect them,
and I’m gently trying to educate
my fellow wizards about them.
Come on.
Titus? Finn? Poppy, Marlow, Tom?
He had a cold. He needed some body warmth.
Right, on you hop.
See, he has some attachment issues.
-Now, come on, Pickett.
Pickett. No, they’re not going
to bully you. Now, come on.
Pickett!
All right. But that is exactly
why they accuse me of favoritism.
I wonder where Dougal’s gone.
All right, I’m coming, I’m
coming, Mum’s here. Mum’s here.
Hello, you, let me take a look at you.
-I know these guys.
Your Occamy.
-What do you mean? My Occamy?
Yes, do you want to...
Yeah, sure. Okay.
Hey.
-No, sorry, don’t pet them.
They learn to defend themselves early. See, their
shells are made of silver so they’re incredibly valuable.
Okay. -Their nests tend to
get ransacked by hunters.
Thank you.
Mr. Scamander?
-Call me Newt.
Newt, I don’t think I’m dreaming.
What gave it away?
-I ain’t got the brains to make this up.
Actually, would you mind throwing some of
those pellets in with the Mooncalves over there?
Yeah, sure.
-Just over there...
Bugger, Niffler’s gone. Of
course he has, little bugger.
Any chance to get his
hands on something shiny.
What did you do today, Jacob?
I was inside a suitcase.
Hey. Hello, fellas. All right, all right.
Take it easy, take it easy.
Cutie. There it is.
Step back.
-Jeez...
Step back. -What’s the matter
with this? -I said step away. -Yeah.
What the hell is this thing?
-It’s an Obscurus.
I need to get going, find everyone
who’s escaped before they get hurt.
Before they could get hurt? -Yes, Mr. Kowalski.
They’re currently in alien terrain,
surrounded by millions of the most
vicious creatures on the planet.
Humans.
So where would you say that a medium-sized
creature that likes broad, open plains,
trees, water holes, that kind
of thing, where might she go?
In New York City?
-Yes. -Plains?
Central Park? -And where is that
exactly? -Where is Central Park?
Well, look, I would come and show you,
but don’t you think it’s
kind of a double cross?
The girls take us in,
they make us hot cocoa.
You do realize that when they see you’ve stopped
sweating, they’ll obliviate you in a heartbeat.
What does “Bliviate” mean? -It’ll be like
you wake up and all memory of magic is gone.
I won’t remember any of this?
-No.
All right, yeah, okay, I’ll help you.
Come on, then.
Credence, where have you been?
I was looking for a place
for tomorrow’s meeting.
There’s a corner on
Thirty-Second Street that could...
I’m sorry, Ma. I didn’t realize it was so late.
I was watching you at dinner. -Yeah.
-People like you, don’t they, Mr. Kowalski?
Well, I’m sure people like you too, huh?
-No, not really. I annoy people.
Why did you decide to be a baker?
Well, because I’m dying
in that canning factory.
Everyone there’s dying. It just crushes the
life outta you. You like canned food? -No.
Yeah. Me neither. That’s why I want to make pastries, you
know. It makes people happy. We’re going this way.
So did you get your loan?
No, I ain’t got no collateral. Stayed in
the army too long, apparently, I don’t know.
You fought in the war? -Of course I fought in the war,
everyone fought in the war. You didn’t fight in the war?
I worked mostly with dragons,
Ukrainian Ironbellies,
Eastern Front.
Finestra.
Accio!
All right? Happy?
One down, two to go.
They went that way, Officer.
-Hands up!
What the hell is that?
Lion...
You know, New York is considerably
more interesting than I’d expected.
Put this on. -Why would I have
to wear something like this?
Because your skull is susceptible
to breakage under immense force.
But we made ’em cocoa.
Right.
Okay, if you just, pop this on.
-Okay.
Now, there’s absolutely
nothing for you to worry about.
Tell me, has anyone ever believed
you when you told them not to worry?
My philosophy is that worrying
means you suffer twice.
She’s in season. She needs to mate.
Erumpent musk,
she is mad for it.
Good girl...
Come on, into the case.
Oh, no.
Repar...
Merlin’s beard!
They’re exactly the same.
Same thing.
-Newt!
No, no, no, don’t!
I’m so sorry.
Good show, Mr. Kowalski!
Call me Jacob.
Two down, one to go.
In you hop.
Ladies and gentlemen,
tonight’s keynote speaker
needs no introduction from me.
He’s been mentioned
as a future president.
And if you don’t believe me,
just read his daddy’s newspapers.
Ladies and gentlemen, I give you
the senator for New York, Henry Shaw!
Thank you. Thank you!
Thank you.
And it’s true we have made some progress,
but there is no reward for idleness.
So just as the odious
saloons have been banished...
What's going on?
So now the pool halls, and
these private parlors...
What is that?
Witches!
Our American friends have permitted
a breach of the Statute of Secrecy,
that threatens to expose us all.
I will not be lectured by the man who let
Gellert Grindelwald slip through his fingers.
Madam President, I’m so sorry to
interrupt, but this is critical.
You’d better have an excellent excuse
for this intrusion, Miss Goldstein.
Yes, I do.
Ma’am. Yesterday a wizard
entered New York with a case.
This case full of magical creatures,
and unfortunately, some have escaped.
He arrived yesterday?
You have known for twenty-four
hours that an unregistered wizard
set magical beasts loose in New York
and you see fit to tell us
only when a man has been killed?
Who has been killed?
-Where is this man?
Scamander?
Hello, Minister.
-Theseus Scamander? The war hero?
No, this is his little brother.
And what are you doing in New York?
I came to buy an Appaloosa
Puffskein, sir. -Right.
What are you really doing here?
Goldstein, and who is this?
This is Jacob Kowalski, Madam President,
he’s a No-Maj who got bitten by
one of Mr. Scamander’s creatures.
No-Maj?
-Obliviated?
Merlin’s beard.
You know which of your creatures
was responsible, Mr. Scamander?
No creature did this.  Don’t pretend!
You must know what that
was, look at the marks...
That was an Obscurus.
You go too far, Mr. Scamander.
There is no Obscurial in America.
Impound that case, Graves!
-Wait. No. Give that back. -Arrest them!
Don’t hurt those creatures.
Please, you don’t understand, nothing
in there is dangerous, nothing!
We’ll be the judges of that!
Take them to the cells!
Don’t hurt those creatures, nothing
in there is dangerous!
Please, don’t hurt my creatures! They aren't
dangerous! Please, they are not dangerous!
They are not dangerous!
I am so sorry about your
creatures, Mr. Scamander.
I truly am.
Can someone please tell me what this
Obscurial—Obscurius thing is? Please?
There hasn’t been one for centuries.
I met one in Sudan three months ago.
There used to be more of
them but they still exist.
Before wizards went underground,
when we were still
being hunted by Muggles,
young wizards and witches sometimes
tried to suppress their magic
to avoid persecution.
Instead of learning to harness
or to control their powers,
they developed what
was called an Obscurus.
It’s an unstable, uncontrollable Dark
force that busts out and attacks...
And then vanishes.
Obscurials can’t
survive long, can they?
There’s no documented case of any
Obscurial surviving past the age of ten.
The one I met in Africa
was eight when she...
She was eight when she died.
What are you telling me here, that
Senator Shaw was killed by a kid?
My momma, your momma,
flying on a switch.
witches never cry.
My momma, your momma,
witches gonna die!
Witch number one, drown in
a river!
Witch number two,
gotta noose to give her!
Hand out your leaflets!
-Witch number three...
I’ll know if you dump ’em. Tell
me if you see anything suspicious.
It was good to make your acquaintance,
Jacob, and I hope you get your bakery.
You’re an interesting man, Mr. Scamander.
-Mr. Graves...
You were thrown out of Hogwarts
for endangering human life...
That was an accident!
-With a beast.
Yet one of your teachers argued
strongly against your expulsion.
What makes Albus
Dumbledore so fond of you?
I really couldn’t say.
So setting a pack of dangerous
creatures loose here was...
Was just another accident, is that right?
-Why would I do it deliberately?
To expose wizardkind.
To provoke war between the
magical and non-magical worlds.
Mass slaughter for the
greater good, you mean?
Yes. Quite.
I’m not one of Grindelwald’s
fanatics, Mr. Graves.
I wonder what you can tell
me about this, Mr. Scamander?
It’s an Obscurus.
But it’s not what you think.
I managed to separate it from the
Sudanese girl as I tried to save her.
Wanted to take it home, to study it.
But it cannot survive outside that
box, it could not hurt anyone, Tina!
So it’s useless without the host?
"Useless?" "Useless?"
That is a parasitical magical force that killed
a child. What on earth would you use it for?
You fool nobody, Mr. Scamander.
You brought this Obscurus into the city of New
York in the hope of causing mass disruption,
breaking the Statute of Secrecy
and revealing the magical world.
You know that can’t hurt anyone, you know that!
-You are therefore guilty of a treasonous betrayal
of your fellow wizards
and are sentenced to death.
Miss Goldstein, who has
aided and abetted you...
No, she’s done nothing of the kind.
-She receives the same sentence.
Just do it immediately. I will inform
President Picquery myself. -Tina.
Please.
Don’t do this, Bernadette, please...
It don't hurt.
Tina...
-Momma... -Tina...
Come on, pumpkin, time
for bed. Are you ready?
Don’t that look good?
You wanna get in? Huh?
Hey, Sam! -Hey, Queenie.
-They need you downstairs.
I’ll obliviate this guy.
-You ain’t qualified.
Hey, Sam, does Cecily
know you been seeing Ruby?
How’d you... -Let me obliviate this guy
and she’ll never hear about it from me.
What are you doin’? -Shh! Teen’s
in trouble, I’m trying to listen...
Jacob, where’s Newt’s case?
-I think that guy Graves took it.
Okay, come on. -What? You’re
not gonna obliviate me?
Of course not, you’re one of us now!
It’s okay.
Alohomora.
Aberto...
He would know a fancy
spell to lock his office.
Okay, let’s get the good stuff out of you.
Witch!
It's just gonna eat me! -Don't panic!
-What do you suggest I do instead?
Jump.
Are you crazy?
-Jump on him.
Tina, listen to me. I’ll catch you.
Tina!
I’ll catch you.
I’ve got you, Tina. Go!
Come on!
Coming through!
-Move!
Leave his brains, come on!
Come on!
What is that thing? -Swooping
Evil. -Well, I love it!
Get in.
Queenie!
Where you going?
I’m sick, Mr. Abernathy.
Again?
Well, what’ve you got there?
-Ladies’ things.
You wanna take a look? I don’t mind.
Good gravy, no! I...
You get well now!
-Thanks.
Credence. Have you found the child?
I can’t.
-Show me.
Shh. My boy, the sooner we find this child, the sooner
you can put that pain in the past where it belongs.
I want you to have this, Credence.
I would trust very few with it.
Very few.
But you...
You’re different.
When you find the child, touch this symbol
and I will know, and I will come to you.
Do this and you will be
honored among wizards. Forever.
The child is dying,
Credence.
Time is running out.
Your grandfather kept
pigeons? Mine bred owls.
I used to love feeding ’em.
-Graves always insisted
the disturbances were caused by a beast.
We need to catch all your creatures
so he can’t keep using
them as a scapegoat.
There’s only one still
missing. Dougal, my Demiguise.
Dougal?
-Slight problem is that...
He’s invisible.
Invisible?
-Yes, most of the time... He does...
How do you catch something that?
-With immense difficulty.
Gnarlak!
-Excuse me?
Gnarlak, he was an informant
of mine when I was an Auror!
He used to trade in magical
creatures on the side.
He wouldn’t happen to have an
interest in paw prints, would he?
He’s interested in anything he can sell.
How do I get a drink in this joint?
What? Ain’t you ever
seen a house-elf before?
No, no, of course I have.
I love house-elves.
My uncle’s a house-elf.
Yeah...
Six shots of gigglewater
and a lobe blaster, please.
Are all No-Majs like you?
No, I’m the only one like me.
I’ve arrested half of the people in here.
You can tell me to mind my own
business, but I saw something
in that death potion back there.
I saw you hugging
that Second Salem boy.
His name’s Credence.
His mother beats him.
She beats all those kids she adopted,
but she seems to hate him the most.
And she was the No-Maj you attacked?
That’s how I lost my job.
I went for her in front of a
meeting of her crazy followers.
They all had to be obliviated.
It was a big scandal.
It’s him.
So...
You’re the guy with the
case full of monsters, huh?
News travels fast.
I was hoping you’d be able to tell
me if there have been any sightings.
Tracks. That sort of thing.
You’ve got a big price on
your head, Mr. Scamander.
Why should I help you
instead of turnin’ you in?
I take it I’ll have to
make it worth your while?
Let’s consider it a cover charge.
MACUSA’s offerin’ more’n that.
Lunascope?
I got five.
Frozen Ashwinder egg!
-You see, now we’re...
Wait a minute.
That's Bow...
That’s a Bowtruckle, right?
No. -Come on.
They pick locks, am I right?
You’re not having him.
-Well,
good luck gettin’ back alive,
Mr. Scamander, what with the
whole of MACUSA on your back.
All right.
Pickett...
Somethin’ invisible’s been
wreakin’ havoc around Fifth Avenue.
You may wanna check out
Macy’s department store.
Might help with what you’re looking
for. -Dougal... One last thing.
There’s a Mr. Graves
who works at MACUSA.
I was wondering what you
knew of his background.
You ask a lot of
questions, Mr. Scamander.
That can get you killed.
MACUSA are coming!
-You tipped them off!
Sorry, Mr. Gnarlak...
Reminds me of my foreman!
What are you doin’, Credence?
Where’d you get this?
-Give it back, Credence. It’s just a toy!
What is this?
Take it off!
Ma...
-I am not your Ma!
Your mother was a
wicked, unnatural woman!
It was mine.
-Modesty...
What is this?
So Demiguises are
fundamentally peaceful,
but they can give a
nasty nip if provoked.
You two, head that way.
And try very hard not to be predictable.
Was that the Demiguise?
No, I think it might be the
reason that the Demiguise is here.
Its sight operates on probability,
so it can foresee the most
likely immediate future.
So what’s it doing?
-It’s babysitting.
What did you just say?
-This is my fault.
I thought I had them all,
but I must have miscounted.
It was babysitting that?
Occamies are choranaptyxic.
So they grow to fill available space.
Mummy’s here.
We need an insect, any
kind of insect and a teapot!
Find a teapot!
I got it. I got it!
Teapot!
Roach in teapot...
Choranaptyxic.
They also shrink to
fit the available space.
Tell me the truth.
Was that everything that came out
of the case? -That’s everything.
And that’s the truth.
Here she comes.
-Happy to be home?
Bet you’re exhausted, buddy. Come
on. There you go, that’s right.
Right. I think we need to talk.
I wouldn’t have let
him keep you, Pickett.
Pick, I would rather chop off
my hand than get rid of you.
After everything you have
done for me, now come on.
Pick, we’ve talked about
sulking before, haven’t we?
Pickett...
Come on, give me a smile.
Pickett, give me a...
All right. Now, that is beneath you.
Newt.
Who is she?
-That’s no one.
Leta Lestrange? I’ve heard of that family.
Aren’t they kinda, you know?
-Please don’t read my mind.
Sorry, I asked you not to.
-I know, I’m sorry.
I can’t help it.
People are easiest to read when
they’re hurting. -I’m not hurting.
Anyway, it was a long time ago.
That was a real close
friendship you had at school.
Neither of us really fitted in at school.
So we became quite...
-You became real close.
For years.
She was a taker. You need a giver.
What are you two talking about?
-Nothing.
School.
-School.
Did you say school? Is there a school?
A wizardry school here? In America?
Of course, Ilvermorny! It’s only the
best wizard school in the whole world!
I think you’ll find the best wizarding
school in the world is Hogwarts!
Hogwash!
Danger.
He senses danger.
The Obscurial was here?
Where did she go?
Help me. Help me.
Didn’t you tell me
you had another sister?
Please help me.
Where’s your other sister, Credence?
-Please, help me. -The little one?
Where did she go?
-Please...
Your sister’s in grave danger.
We need to find her.
What is this place?
-Ma adopted Modesty out of here.
From a family of twelve.
She misses her brothers and
sisters. She still talks about them.
Where is she?
I don't know.
-You’re a Squib, Credence.
I could smell it off
you the minute I met you.
What?
-You have magical ancestry, but no power.
But you said you could teach me.
-You’re unteachable.
Your mother’s dead. That’s your reward.
I’m done with you.
Modesty?
Modesty.
There’s no need to be afraid.
I’m here with your brother, Credence.
Out you come, now.
Credence, I owe you an apology.
I trusted you.
I thought you were my friend.
That you were different.
You can control it, Credence.
But I don’t think I want to, Mr. Graves.
Jeez. Is that the Obscuriathing?
That’s more powerful than any
Obscurial I have ever heard of.
If I don’t come back,
look after my creatures.
Everything that you
need to know is in there. -What?
They’re not killing it.
Newt! You heard him, look after them!
Keep holda that, honey.
-No, no, no!
I can’t take you. Please let go of me, Jacob!
You’re the one that said I was one
of youse, right? -It’s too dangerous.
To survive so long, with
this inside you, Credence,
is a miracle. You are a miracle.
Come with me, think of what
we could achieve together.
Newt! -It’s the Second Salem
boy. He’s the Obscurial.
He’s not a child.
His power must be so strong,
he’s somehow managed to survive.
Newt! Save him.
Mr. Graves.
Tina. You’re always turning
up where you are least wanted.
Contain this, or we are
exposed and it will mean war.
Credence! Credence, I can help you.
Bar the area. -Yes, sir.
-I don’t want anyone else down there!
Credence...
It’s Credence, isn’t it?
I’m here to help you, Credence.
I’m not here to hurt you.
I’ve met someone just like you, Credence.
A girl.
A young girl who’d been imprisoned,
she had been locked away and
she’d been punished for her magic.
Credence...
Can I come over to you?
Can I come over?
That thing killed my son.
I want justice!
I’ll expose you for who you
are and what you’ve done.
Look! Take... Take photos.
Credence.
Credence, no!
Don’t do this.
Please.
Keep talking, Tina.
Keep talking to him, he’ll
listen to you. He’s listening.
I know what that woman did to you.
I know that you’ve suffered.
You need to stop this now.
Newt and I will protect you.
This man... He is using you.
-Don’t listen to her, Credence.
I want you to be free.
It’s all right.
-That’s it.
Don’t, you’ll frighten him.
-Wands down!
Anyone harms him, they’ll
answer to me. Credence! -Credence...
No. No!
Credence...
You fools.
Do you realize what you’ve done?
The Obscurial was killed on
my orders, Mr. Graves. -Yes.
And history will surely
note that, Madam President.
What was done here tonight was not right!
He was responsible for
the death of a No-Maj.
He risked the exposure
of our community.
He has broken one of
our most sacred laws.
A law that has us scuttling
like rats in the gutter!
A law that demands that
we conceal our true nature!
A law that directs those under
its dominion to cower in fear
lest we risk discovery!
I ask you, Madam President.
I ask all of you...
Who does this law protect?
Us?
Or them?
I refuse to bow down any longer.
Aurors, I’d like you to
relieve Mr. Graves of his wand
and escort him back to...
Accio.
Revelio.
Do you think you can hold me?
We’ll do our best, Mr. Grindelwald.
Will we die, just a little?
I figured somebody oughta
keep an eye on this thing.
Thank you. -We owe you
an apology, Mr. Scamander.
But the magical community is exposed!
We cannot obliviate an entire city.
Actually, I think we can.
I was intending to wait
until we got to Arizona,
but it seems like now you
are our only hope, Frank.
I’ll miss you too.
You know what you’ve got to do.
They won’t remember anything.
That venom has incredibly
powerful obliviative properties.
We owe you a great
debt, Mr. Scamander.
Now, get that case out of New York.
Yes, Madam President.
Is that No-Maj still here?
Obliviate him. There can be no exceptions.
I’m sorry, but even one witness.
You know the law.
I’ll let you say good-bye.
This is for the best.
Yeah, I was, I was never
even supposed to be here.
I was never supposed to know any of this.
Everybody knows Newt only
kept me around because...
Newt, why did you keep me around?
Because I like you.
Because you’re my friend
and I’ll never forget
how you helped me, Jacob.
I’ll come with you.
We’ll go somewhere, we’ll go anywhere.
See, I ain’t never gonna find anyone like.
There’s loads like me.
-No. No.
There’s only one like you.
I gotta go.
Jacob!
-It’s okay. It’s okay.
It’s okay.
It’s just like waking up, right?
So sorry, sorry!
Dear Mr. Kowalski, You are
wasted in a canning factory.
Please take these Occamy eggshells
as collateral for your bakery.
A well-wisher.
It’s been...
-Hasn’t it?
Listen, Newt, I wanted to thank you.
What on earth for?
Well, you know, if you hadn’t said all
those nice things to Madam Picquery about me,
I wouldn’t be back on the
investigative team now.
Well, I can’t think of anyone that
I’d rather have investigating me.
Try not to need
investigating for a bit. -I will.
Quiet life for me from now on.
Back to the Ministry. Deliver my
manuscript. -I’ll look out for it.
Fantastic Beasts and Where to Find Them.
Does Leta Lestrange like to read?
Who?
-The girl whose picture you carry.
I don’t really know what Leta likes
these days because people change.
Yes.
-I’ve changed.
I think. Maybe a little.
I’ll send you a copy of my book, if I may.
-I’d like that.
I’m so sorry. How would you feel
if I gave you your copy in person?
I’d like that.
Very much.
Where do you get your ideas from, Mr. Kowalski?
-I don’t know.
I don't know.
They just come.
Here you go. Don’t forget this. Enjoy.
Hey, Henry, storage, all right?
Thanks, pal.
Subtitle by Bambula