♪ The sun'll come out tomorrow ♪
♪ Bet your bottom dollar
That tomorrow ♪
♪ There'll be sun ♪
♪ Just thinking about tomorrow ♪
♪ Clears away the cobwebs
And the sorrow ♪
♪ Till there's none ♪
♪ When I'm stuck with a day
That's gray and lonely ♪
♪ I just stick out my chin ♪
♪ And grin and say ♪
♪ Oh, the sun'll come out tomorrow ♪
♪ So you gotta hang on till tomorrow ♪
♪ Come what may ♪
♪ Tomorrow, tomorrow ♪
♪ I love ya, tomorrow ♪
♪ You're only a day away ♪
♪ Tomorrow, tomorrow ♪
♪ I love ya, tomorrow ♪
♪ You're only a day ♪
♪ Away ♪♪
♪ Maybe far away ♪
♪ Or maybe real nearby ♪
♪ He may be pouring her coffee ♪
♪ She may be straightening his tie ♪
♪ Maybe in a house ♪
♪ All hidden by a hill ♪
♪ She's sitting playing piano ♪
♪ He's sitting paying a bill ♪
♪ Betcha they're young
Betcha they're smart ♪
♪ Bet they collect things ♪
♪ Like ashtrays and art ♪
♪ Betcha they're good
Why shouldn't they be? ♪
♪ Their one mistake
Was giving up me ♪
♪ So maybe now it's time ♪
♪ And maybe when I wake ♪
♪ They'll be there calling me baby ♪
♪ Maybe ♪♪
Annie.
Annie!
Shh. It's okay.
Everything's gonna be all right.
There, there.
It was only a dream, Molly.
It's all right.
How am I supposed to
get any sleep around here?
It was only a dream.
Everything's all right.
Molly shouldn't be in this room.
- She's a baby.
- Ow!
- She cries all the time.
- Come on.
- She wets the bed.
I do not!
You're the one who shouldn't be in here!
Brat, stop! We're gonna get in trouble.
Go, Duffy! Go!
Oh, my goodness! Oh, my goodness!
Cut it out! Cut it out!
I mean it! Do you want
Miss Hannigan to come in here?
Go back to bed.
Now. Or you'll have me to deal with.
Ah, blow it out your old wazoo.
Close your eyes. Think about your folks.
You're the only one who has folks.
Mine are dead.
Think about folks who want to adopt you
because they want a little girl
with brown hair and brown eyes.
♪ Betcha he reads
Betcha she sews ♪
♪ Maybe she's made me
A closet of clothes ♪
♪ Maybe they're strict ♪
♪ As straight as a line ♪
♪ Don't really care
As long as they're mine ♪
Oh, my goodness.
♪ So maybe now this prayer's ♪
♪ The last one of its kind ♪
♪ Won't you please
Come get your baby? ♪♪
Did I hear singing in here?
All right. Fine.
Since we're all so wide awake!
Get up! Get out of bed!
Clean up this mess! Get dressed!
This room had better be regulation
before breakfast,
my little pig droppings,
or kill, kill, kill!
But it's in the middle of the night.
"But it's in the middle of the night."
If this floor don't shine like
the top of the Chrysler Building,
your backsides will.
Understand?
Yes, Miss Hannigan.
- What do we say, Annie?
- I love you, Miss Hannigan.
♪ It's the hard-knock life for us ♪
♪ Instead of treated
We get tricked ♪
♪ Instead of kisses
We get kicked ♪
♪ It's the hard-knock life ♪
♪ Got no folks to speak of so ♪
♪♪ It's the hard-knock row we hoe ♪
♪ Cotton blankets instead of wool ♪
♪ Empty bellies instead of full ♪
♪ It's the hard-knock life ♪
♪ Don't it feel like the wind
Is always howling? ♪
♪ Don't it seem like
There's never any light? ♪
♪ Once a day, don't you want
To throw the towel IN? ♪
♪ It's easier than putting up a fight ♪
♪ No one's there
When your dreams at night get creepy ♪
♪ No one cares if you grow
Or if you shrink ♪
♪ No one dries
When your eyes get red and weepy ♪
♪ From the crying you would think
This place would sink ♪
♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ Empty belly life ♪
♪ Rotten smelly life ♪
♪ Full of sorrow life ♪
♪ No tomorrow life ♪
♪ Santa Claus
We never see ♪
♪ Santa Claus, what's that?
Who's he? ♪
♪ No one cares for you a smidge ♪
♪ When you're in an orphanage ♪
♪ It's the hard-knock life ♪
You'll stay up till this dump
shines like the top
of the Chrysler Building.
Kill, kill.
♪ Yank the whiskers from her chin ♪
Little pig droppings.
♪ Jab her with a safety pin ♪
Rotten orphans.
♪ Make her drink
A Mickey Finn ♪
- Nobody loves you.
- I love you, Miss Hannigan.
- Get to work!
- Ooh!
Strip that bed!
Scrub that floor!
Polish my shoes!
And I mean...
Start now!
♪ It's the hard-knock life for us ♪
Mud in your eye!
♪ No one cares for you a smidge ♪
♪ When you're in an orphanage ♪
♪ It's the hard-knock life ♪
♪ The hard-knock life ♪
We better get out of here
or we'll get Killed.
- Cover me up good.
- All you ever do is run away.
Oh, my goodness! Oh, my goodness!
She'll put you in the cellar.
You'll get whipped again.
You're gonna get us in trouble.
- Molly, shut up!
- I'm gonna tell.
And I'm gonna
rearrange your teeth!
Stomp on her foot!
What are you all
just standing around here for?
You're supposed to clean
the bathroom and kitchen
before lunch, my little pig droppings.
And if you skip the corners,
there will be no lunch.
And we're not having hot mush today.
Yay!
We're having cold mush.
Aw!
- What?
- We love you, Miss Hannigan.
Wonderful.
Where's Annie?
She had to go bathroom.
"She had to go bathroom.”
Miss Hannigan.
Oh.
- Mr. Bundles.
Miss Hannigan!
Yoo-hoo.
It's time for a tumble with a bundle.
Not today. I'm behind...
- Ooh! My schedule, I mean.
- Schedules?
What are schedules in the storms
of passion, Mr. Bundles?
Just so much flotsam and jetsam.
Oh, Miss Hannigan, please!
Mr. Bundles.
- What are you doing out here?
- Helping you.
It's heavy today.
It's a lot heavier than usual.
Shh!
- It shouldn't be. What's in there?
- Miss Hannigan.
Mr. Bundles.
- Yes?
- You're my kind of woman.
- Oh, yes. Yes.
Till next month, Miss Hannigan.
I'll be right here.
Mr. Bundles, I'm in here!
- Thank you, Mr. Bundles.
- Good luck.
Get his tail!
Poor dog.
Leave him alone.
What's he ever done to you?
Amscray!
All right, who's next?
Anybody else?
- Scram, man!
- Let's go!
- Then get lost.
- Let's get a move on!
- Let's hotfoot it!
- Shake a leg! Come on!
Let's go! Come on!
Hey, you're all right.
I didn't do nothing
any decent person wouldn't have done.
Dumb dog.
♪ Dumb dog
Why are you following me? ♪
♪ I ain't got a crumb, dog ♪
♪ How about letting me be? ♪
♪ I ain't gonna feed you ♪
♪ Ain't got a scrap for you
Need you? ♪
♪ Don't give a rap for you
Dumb dog ♪
♪ Dumber than they come, dog ♪
♪ You're the most presuming dog ♪
♪ That a human could know ♪♪
Hey, mister, that's my dog!
Oh, yeah? Where's his license?
Where's his leash?
He's no more your dog
than I am your father.
I left his license at home.
Please don't take him to the pound.
Please. My father's blind.
This dog leads him to work.
If he can't get to work, we'll starve.
What's his name?
My father's name?
- The dog's name.
- Oh, the dog's name!
Uh, his name's Sandy.
Right, that's it. Sandy.
Call him.
Call him?
Go over there and call him.
You mean by his name?
By his name. The dog's name.
Sandy! Come here, Sandy.
Sandy! Come here, Sandy!
- Come here, boy.
- Here, Rover. Come here, boy.
Rin Tin Tin! Come here.
Come to Daddy.
- Sandy, come here.
- Rin Tin Tin, come here.
Sandy!
Come here, Sandy.
Come here, Sandy. Come here.
Good old Sandy!
You've got yourself a dog.
Get him a collar and a leash.
Yes, sir.
Miss Hannigan! Miss Hannigan!
What?!
Annie!
Look what I found under a paving stone.
Oh, Annie!
Annie, my little peach fuzz,
are you all right?
- I was worried sick.
- I knew you would be.
A big-hearted woman like you.
How can I ever thank you enough?
I'm sure we can think of something
if we get our heads together.
Kissy, kissy, kissy.
Kill! Kill!
- We love you, Miss Hannigan.
- Sure.
- Oh, my goodness!
He smells.
- What's his name, Annie?
- Guess.
Uh, Fifi?
That ain't a name for this mutt.
♪ So how about Champion ♪
♪ Champion
You're anything but ♪
- ♪ We could call him Tiger ♪
- ♪ But there's no bite in him ♪
♪ Tiger
Kittens would frighten him ♪
♪ Rover
When you think it over ♪
Shh!
♪ Rover is the perfect name
For this dumb-looking dog ♪
Rover!
♪ Sandy, Sandy's his name ♪
♪ If you please ♪
♪ If you don't believe me ♪
♪ Ask any one of the fleas ♪
♪ Residing on Sandy ♪
♪ True he ain't pedigreed, Sandy ♪
♪ There ain't no better breed ♪
♪ And he really comes in handy ♪
♪ Especially when you're all alone
In the night ♪
♪ And you're small
And terribly frightened ♪
♪ It's Sandy ♪
♪ Sandy who'll always be ♪
♪ There ♪♪
She's coming. She's coming.
Hide him!
I love you, Miss Hannigan.
And you will love
the paddle closet, Annie.
And this...
will love the sausage factory.
- Oh!
- What?
We love you, Miss Hannigan.
Shut up.
Apples, a nickel. Apples here.
Yes, ma'am.
Here you go. Thank you.
God bless you.
Apples here.
Big, delicious apples here.
All right! All right!
Yeah?
Miss Hannigan, I'm Grace Farrell.
The New York Board of Orphans
sent me.
Oh!
My goodness, won't you come in?
- Thank you.
- Right this way.
Well, welcome.
- Welcome to our happy home.
- Off my foot, Molly!
- Thank you.
- Ladies.
Smell that perfume.
- And your name was?
- Grace Farrell.
She wants a girl
to clean her house.
Aptly named.
- I bet it's gonna be me!
- I'm here to inquire about an orphan.
Grace, I can explain the whole thing.
What happened was
the child bribed Mr. Bundles
to smuggle her out in a laundry basket.
I should have called Mr. Donatelli,
but the truth is
I just saw red,
so I called the cops instead.
Anyway, she's back, everything's fine.
All's well that ends well.
No harm, no foul, my little scissors legs?
Miss Hannigan, what are you talking about?
Hold it, sister,
are you peddling beauty products?
'Cause I don't need no beauty products.
If that's what you're doing,
you can peddle yourself right out of here.
Miss Hannigan, I am the private secretary
to Oliver War bucks.
The Oliver War bucks?
- Oliver War bucks the millionaire?
- No, the billionaire.
Holy Mary, Mother of God.
Mr. War bucks would like to invite
an orphan to spend a week with him.
I'm here to select one.
Well, that's just wonderful.
What kind of orphan did he have in mind?
Oh. Well, um...
friendly.
Intelligent.
M-I-S-S-I-S-S-I-P-P-I.
And happy.
Oh!
How old?
Well, age doesn't really matter.
Uh-huh.
- Seven?
- Seven.
- Eight.
- Nine?
- Nine.
Ten?
Yes, 10 is just fine.
Ten? Ten.
Oh, oh.
I'm so sorry, I almost forgot.
- Mr. War bucks prefers redheaded children.
- A 10-year-old redhead, huh?
Nope. Sorry, ain't got it.
What about this child?
- Annie?
- Yes.
You wouldn't...
You don't want Annie.
Why not?
She's, uh...
She's a drunk.
Oh, fiddle-faddle, Miss Hannigan.
Annie, how'd you like to spend a week
with Mr. War bucks at his house?
Oh, boy. I would love to.
I would really, really love to.
Wait, slow down, hold on, there!
You can have any orphan
in the whole orphanage except Annie.
Well, why?
Because she's got it coming to her,
and I don't mean a week of luxury.
This brat's got to learn
to know her place.
Her place?
And Annie is entirely too cheeky.
- Well, Mr. War bucks likes cheeky orphans.
- Tough!
I assume your resistance has to do with
Mr. Donatelli and the Board of Orphans.
Don't assume nothing, sweetheart.
Well, Mr. War bucks knows Mr. Donatelli.
- Is that a fact?
- Yes, it is.
It's also a fact that he said how many
people he had lined up for your job.
- Is that a fact?
- Yes.
It's an awful time to be out of work,
isn't it, Miss Hannigan?
Just terrible.
Leaping lizards!
"Leaping lizards."
Come alone, Annie,
the limousine is waiting.
- My dog.
- What?
Here, Sandy. Come here.
He's really nice. Really, really good.
- He never jumps up on people.
- Oh, no? Oh!
Annie, he's a very sweet dog, but really,
I don't think Mr. War bucks...
- Then I'm not coming.
- What?
She's going to send him
to the sausage factory.
- She said so herself.
- I'm not zoned for dogs.
- We'll take the dog.
- Oh, boy!
Bye, Annie!
I'll be back.
I'll bring everybody presents.
Bye, Molly! See you soon!
Bye, Pepper! Bye, Duffy!
Is this a train station?
Are we going on a train?
No, dear, this is Mr. War bucks' house.
Leaping lizards.
Wow!
Annie, this is Punjab. He and the Asp
are Mr. War bucks' bodyguards.
Come along, dear. Let's get you settled.
Been to the zoo, Miss Farrell?
Not recently, Drake.
- Has the organ been tuned?
- Yes, miss.
- Pool heated?
- Yes.
- Tennis net up?
- French doors fixed?
- Yes.
- Elevator oiled?
- Typewriter repaired?
- Yes.
- Second Teletype installed?
- Are you allergic to dogs, Drake?
- No, filth.
- Is dinner underway, Mrs. Pugh?
- Yes, miss.
I'm preparing his favorite.
Texas grapefruit, Virginia ham,
Idaho potatoes, Wisconsin cheese,
Washington apples, and baked Alaska.
I have an announcement to make, everybody.
This is Annie, and she'll be
staying with us for a week.
Miss.
And this is her dog, Sandy.
He'll be staying with me.
May I take your sweater, miss?
- Will I get it back?
- Of course, miss!
Annie, what would you like to do first?
The windows, then the floors,
that way if I drip...
No. No. Annie.
You don't understand.
You don't have to do any cleaning here.
I won't?
How am I gonna earn my keep?
Why, you're our guest, Annie.
♪ Cecilie will pick out all your clothes ♪
Blue is her best color. No, red, I think.
♪ Your bath is drawn by Mrs. Greer ♪
Soap. No, bubbles, I think.
♪ Annette comes In
To make your bed ♪
The silk? No, the satin sheets, I think.
♪ I think I'm gonna like it here ♪
Ooh! Oh!
♪ The swimming pool
Is down the stairs ♪
Inside the house? Oh, boy!
♪ The tennis court is in the rear ♪
- I never even picked up a racket.
- What?
♪ Have an instructor here at noon ♪
And get that Don Budge fellow,
if he's available.
♪ I think I'm gonna like it here ♪
♪ When you wake, ring for Drake ♪
♪ Drake will bring your tray ♪
♪ When you're through
Mrs. Pugh comes to take it away ♪
- Annie!
- Come on, Annie! Come on!
♪ No need to pick up any toys ♪
That's okay, I haven't got any anyway.
♪ No finger will you lift, my dear ♪
♪ We have but one request ♪
♪ Please put us to the test ♪
♪ I know I'm gonna like it here ♪
♪ Used 10 room in a tomb
Where I'd sit and freeze ♪
♪ Get me now, holy cow ♪
♪ Could someone pinch me please? ♪
Hold still. Hold still!
You mutt!
Hi, Annie!
Got something for you.
Here you are, Annie.
♪ We've never had a little girl ♪
♪ We've never had a little girl
We've never had a little girl ♪
♪ I'm very, very, very glad
To volunteer ♪
♪ I'm glad she's glad
♪ We hope you understand ♪
♪ Your wish is our command ♪
- ♪ I know I'm gonna like it here ♪
- ♪ We know you're gonna like it here ♪
It's Mr. War bucks. Don't worry now.
- Welcome home, sir.
- Did the painting arrive?
They're just uncrating it, sir.
Hmm.
I don't like it. Send it back.
Any messages?
President Roosevelt called
three times. He said it was urgent.
Everything's urgent to a Democrat.
What else?
Uh, uh, Mr. Rockefeller, Mr. Vanderbilt,
Mr. DuPont, Mr. Carnegie.
Wait! There's something interesting
in that woman's smile.
I might learn to like her.
Hang that in my bathroom.
Uh, Mr. War bucks...
No time for dinner tonight. Send out
for an American cheese sandwich.
Come, let's get started.
- Aah!
- Oh!
Oh, no! No!
What the devil's going on here?
Oh, Mr. War bucks, this is the
press representative. Your image.
- Oh. Oh, yes.
- Uh-huh.
Pick him up, Punjab.
Get him another camera.
Why do I smell wet dog?
Because we gave Sandy a bath.
What's this?
This is Annie, sir,
the orphan who will be staying with us.
Orphan? What are you talking about?
Well, they wanted to take photos of you
sharing your home with an orphan.
Only for a week.
This doesn't look like a boy!
Orphans are boys.
You didn't say a boy.
You just said an orphan, so I got a girl.
I want a boy!
I've got an interesting smile too, sir.
Don't you think
you could learn to like me too, sir?
Hang me in the bathroom?
- Take them back now.
- Oh, sir, she just got here.
That's okay, Miss Farrell. We'll be okay.
It was nice meeting you anyhow.
I sure do like your place.
- Thank you, Annette.
- Annie. I've had a swell time already.
The Asp drove us here
in a car the size of a train.
And Punjab put a spell on Sandy.
And we made Drake sneeze.
And I played your pipe organ.
And Sandy got a bubble bath. And, well,
I've had enough fun
to last me for years.
It's a really swell idea
to have an orphan for a week.
A really terrific idea.
Even if it's only for your image,
even if I'm not the orphan,
I'm glad you're doing it.
I'm glad you approve.
Let's get to work!
Are you sure you need a boy?
Couldn't she stay?
Whatever, but just for the week.
- You know what?
- What?
- I love you.
- Ha-ha-ha. I know.
- Kiss me as only you can.
- You devil.
Get away!
♪ Little girls, little girls
Everywhere I turn ♪
♪ I can see them ♪
♪ Little girls, little girls ♪
♪ Night and day
I eat, sleep and breathe them ♪
♪ I'm an ordinary woman ♪
♪ With feelings ♪
♪ I'd like a man to nibble on my ear ♪
♪ But I'll admit, no man has bit ♪
♪ So how come
I'm the mother of the year? ♪
♪ How I hate little shoes, little socks ♪
♪ And each little... ♪
Mama!
♪ ...bloomer ♪
♪ I'd have cracked years ago ♪
♪ If it weren't for
My sense of humor ♪
♪ Some women are dripping
With diamonds ♪
With pearls ♪
♪ Lucky me, lucky me
Look at what I'm dripping with ♪
♪ Little girls ♪
Oh.
Ugh.
Ah.
♪ Little cheeks, little teeth
Everything around me is ♪
♪ Little ♪
♪ If I wring little necks ♪
♪ Surely I would get an acquittal ♪
♪ Someday I'll step on their freckles ♪
♪ Some night
I'll straighten their curls ♪
♪ Send a flood, send the flu ♪
♪ Anything that you can do
To little, little, little ♪
♪ Little, little, little ♪
♪ Little girls ♪
♪ Someday I'll land in the nuthouse ♪
♪ With all the nuts and the squirrels ♪
♪ There I'll stay, tucked away
Till the prohibition of ♪
♪ Little ♪
♪ Girls ♪♪
- Rooster!
- Sis.
You're supposed to be in jail.
- They let me out early.
- On account of good behavior.
I want you to meet
a little friend of mine. Lily St. Regis.
- Named from the hotel.
- Room service.
This afternoon, I put 10 on the nose
of a beautiful horse at 8-1.
Sure enough, the scum-bum
took off and whipped the pack.
No kidding?
The thing is, I got delayed,
and the joint was closed
before I could cash in.
Eighty bucks, sis, first thing
in the morning, guaranteed.
All I need is 5 to tide me over.
Not even a nickel for the subway.
Oh, come on, sis.
I bet Miss Sticky-Fingers here
can loan you a lousy 5 bucks.
I beg your pardon, I'm sure.
But I don't stoop
to what you're incinerating.
Give me back my goods, toots.
Okay, Rooster.
If I loan you 5 bucks, will you take
this dumb hotel out of here?
I'm sorry, sis. Lily.
Not even a nickel for the subway.
You and her have the same mother?
Rooster!
♪ Betcha he reads
Betcha she sews ♪
♪ Maybe she's made me
A closet of clothes ♪
♪ Maybe they're strict
As straight as a line ♪
♪ Don't really care
As long as they're mine ♪
♪ So maybe now this prayer's ♪
♪ The last one of its kind ♪
♪ Won't you please come
Get your baby? ♪
♪ Maybe ♪♪
This room's bigger than Grant's tomb.
Me too.
Come on, Sandy. Come on!
In conclusion,
because your country has raised
its voice loud and clear for democracy,
I will extend to you a credit line
for the acquisition
of 35 of my new fighter-bombers.
That will come with a year's supply
of spare parts, ammunition, and...
What's this?
Sandy's not used to sleeping by himself.
He gets lonesome.
Ah. Uh, where were we?
Oh, um, um, um...
- "Ammunition," sir.
- Are you getting a lot done?
I'd get a lot more done
if certain people...
If Franklin Delano Roosevelt
would leave me alone.
- Six calls since I got home.
- What's he want?
My support for the New Deal.
It's laughable.
- He is our president, sir.
- Hmm.
Punjab!
Remove this animal
and its young mistress along with it.
Dear Richie, this letter will serve
as confirmation of correspondence
concerning the details
of your extended deferment.
...On or before September 1.
If you cannot meet that deadline,
you will be charged interest.
That is, six percent.
Cordially, et cetera.
P.S. One of my companies
is developing a bomb-proof glass.
This may be of interest to you if
the international situation deteriorates.
♪ Rise up, ye victims of... ♪
- What was that?
- Well done, Sandy.
Was that man trying to kill you?
That will be all.
Yes, sir. Come along, dear.
- Who'd want to kill Mr. War bucks?
- Uh, the Bolsheviks, dear.
He's living proof
that the American system works
and the Bolsheviks
don't want anyone to know.
The Bolsheviks? Leaping lizards!
Get your blasted dog out of my pool!
He thought you were drowning.
He was trying to save your life.
- Go on, you mutt. Get out of here.
- Come on.
Yeah.
Like my suit?
What? Oh, yes.
Miss Farrell picked it out.
- Never thought I'd get used to a girl.
- Girls are easier to get used to.
Like Miss Farrell,
she does all the work around here.
- You don't even know her first name.
- I do. It's Grace.
She thinks you're the greatest thing
since sliced bread.
I beg your pardon.
I know it's none of my business,
but you never notice anything.
Sliced bread.
Wilhelm, please offer your son
my congratulations on his engagement.
Hold on, Wilhelm. Buy copper.
Yes. And tell the crown prince
that my yacht in Monte Carlo
is entirely at his disposal for the...
Hold on, Wilhelm. More copper.
- Don't encourage her, Punjab!
- Maybe I should take her out.
- Good idea. Where do you want to go?
- To meet President Roosevelt. Ha, ha.
- How about a movie?
- Pepper went to a movie once.
Before she came to the orphanage.
She said it was swell,
and Miss Hannigan goes all the time.
Splendid.
- Take her to the Radio City Music Hall.
- Aren't you going to take me?
Me? Ha. Annie, you may think
that Miss Farrell does all the work,
but it's not entirely true.
I'm a busy man, a very busy man.
I know. I didn't mean
to get in the way, Mr. War bucks.
Nobody has to take me anywhere.
I'll go practice my backhand.
Pepper lies a lot. She probably
hasn't been to a movie either.
Actually, I think it's better
when you don't know what you're missing.
Punjab, buy out the 8:00 show.
Let's all go to the movies.
You should leave your hair down.
It looks so pretty.
No, Annie, I couldn't.
Miss Hannigan says
a man don't look at your brains.
Oh, really? My goodness.
Come on, Annie, let's go to the movies.
Let's go see the stars.
♪ Cowboy heroes ♪
♪ Cops and robbers ♪
♪ Glamour and strife ♪
♪ Bigger than life ♪
♪ Sitting in the darkness ♪
♪ What a world to see ♪
♪ Let's go to the movies, Annie ♪
♪ Wait and see ♪
♪ Bette Davis is probably lying ♪
♪ And Greta Garbo is probably crying ♪
♪ While Robert Taylor
Is locked in her dying embrace ♪
♪ Chico and Groucho and Chaplin
And Lloyd are all super ♪
♪ Sweet Mickey Mouse
Shirley Temple ♪
♪ And dear Jackie Cooper ♪
♪ Let's go to the movies ♪
- ♪ Let's go see the stars ♪
♪ Fred and Ginger ♪
♪ Spinning madly ♪
♪ Anything you can imagine ♪
♪ Songs and romance ♪
♪ Life is a dance ♪
♪ Sitting in the darkness ♪
♪ Popcorn on your knee ♪
♪ Give the maid the night off ♪
Turn the kitchen light off.
♪ Let's go to the movies, Annie ♪
♪ You and me ♪
♪ Welcome to the movies ♪
♪ Welcome to the stars ♪
♪ Welcome to this
Grand illusion ♪
♪ All of it's yours ♪
♪ Right through these doors ♪
♪ Every plot's a dilly ♪
♪ This we guarantee ♪
♪ Welcome to the movies ♪
♪ Wait and see ♪
♪ Let's go to the movies ♪
♪ Let's go see the stars ♪
♪ Headlines holler ♪
♪ Big depression ♪
♪ What do we care? ♪
♪ Movies are there ♪
- ♪ Only happy endings ♪
- ♪ Boy gets girl ♪
♪ That's our recipe ♪
♪ Welcome to our lovely ♪
♪ M-O-V-I-E ♪
♪ We love to go to RKO ♪
♪ Columbia, Universal ♪
♪ Jack Warner and
Sam Goldwyn and ♪
♪ MGM and Zanuck
Here's to ♪
♪ Dreams of glory ♪
♪ Cast of thousands ♪
♪ Bigger than life ♪
♪ Only happy endings ♪
♪ That's our recipe ♪
♪ So welcome ♪
♪ To the movies ♪
♪ Wait ♪
♪ And ♪
♪ See ♪
For the "lady of the camellias.”
- They're twice as large as usual.
- I'll have twice as many as usual.
Twice as many?
I know what those things cost.
And when she orders her hats
and dresses from you?
They're an investment.
You won't be young forever.
It's time you settled your future.
And I know the very man for you.
- Really?
- Yes, really.
- No one has ever loved you as I do.
- True, but what can I do about it?
You should go away
and not see me anymore.
Don't go in anger. Laugh at yourself
a little, as I laugh at myself.
Come and talk to me once in a while
in a friendly way.
That's too much and not enough.
Believe in love, Marguerite.
So you do love him.
Dare to tell me that you love him,
and you're free of me forever.
I love him.
Come in here, all of you.
See this woman? You know her.
Listen to what I'm going to say.
I accepted her favors
because I thought she loved me.
Let her make sacrifices
when others had more to give.
But bear witness, I owe her nothing.
Take it. Go on, take it.
Buy camellias. Buy diamonds.
Buy carriages. Buy a grave.
You know how to treat a woman as she
deserves. Like the cheat this one is.
Marguerite.
Armand.
Oh, it's you.
I've been down in the street
half the night,
walking back and forth under your window,
wanting to come up,
but not daring to. I felt so guilty.
Shh. Don't think such things, Marguerite.
Even if we can't
go to the country today,
think of how happy we were once
and how happy we'll be again.
Think of the day
you found a four-leaf clover
and all the good luck
it's going to bring us.
Think of the vows that
we're going to make to each other.
This is for life, Marguerite.
Marguerite.
No.
No, don't leave me.
Marguerite, come back.
Get her nightgown
behind the bathroom door.
Certainly. Certainly.
- Miss Farrell.
- It's all right.
- How did you learn that?
- Learn what?
- That.
- What?
- You put her to bed.
- You put her to bed too.
- I did?
- Yes, you did.
Good heavens.
That was a wonderful evening
you gave her last night.
I'm gonna have to close
a factory in Pittsburgh.
- About Annie...
- What about Annie?
Could we keep her?
You haven't seen that orphanage.
I can't bear to send her back there.
Get a hold of yourself.
What's come over you?
I'd take care of her.
You have plenty of room here.
The staff adores her.
- We could take her on as your ward.
- Absolutely not.
I'm a businessman. I love money.
I love power. I love capitalism.
I do not now, or never will,
love children.
Watching you with her last night,
I thought maybe...
Grace.
Yes?
- I've just noticed something.
- Yes?
You're awfully pretty
when you argue with me.
- Thank you, sir.
- Oliver.
Oliver.
Do you really just love money
and power and capitalism?
They'll never love you back.
- Your teeth are crooked.
- I'll have them fixed.
- I like them crooked.
- I'll leave them.
Thank you.
I could have the papers
signed this morning.
- Grace.
- Oliver.
It means a great deal to you, doesn't it?
Yes, it means a great deal to me.
I'll do it myself.
Oh! I could just kiss you!
- Grace.
- Yes?
Get her a little gift.
That's a good idea.
Something from Tiffany's. A new locket.
Be careful at that orphanage.
That woman's got claws and fangs.
Annie.
We got Annie.
- We've got Annie?
- Yeah.
♪ She's like a shine on your shoes ♪
♪ Or hearing the blues
That's great ♪
♪ Makes you relax ♪
♪ Like a big tax rebate ♪
♪ We got Annie ♪
♪ And Benny Goodman's got swing ♪
♪ Bing is the king, by far ♪
♪ Mutt has got Jeff
And Eleanor, FDR ♪
- ♪ We got Annie ♪
♪ We've got Annie ♪
♪ We got Annie ♪
♪ Annie ♪
It's a hard-knock life for us.
No one cares for you a smidge
when you're in an orphanage.
What are you doing?
Why aren't you marching in line
with the rest of them?
Duffy, come here. Come on.
You're hiding something
from Miss Hannigan behind your back.
- No.
- Let me have it.
Get inside!
I've seen his picture in the paper
with President Roosevelt.
- Hannigan, I presume?
- Yes.
I want to talk to you about Annie.
You want to return her
and forget it, or trade up?
I want to adopt her.
Would you excuse me for a moment?
- Would you care to step into my office?
- Thank you.
Hi, sweetie.
- Ow!
- Ah, little cutie.
Up, up, up!
This way.
- Welcome.
- Miss Hannigan...
Mr. War bucks, you know, for a Republican,
you are sinfully handsome.
Thank you.
I go absolutely weak in the knees
over men like you.
- My God, is that thing real?
- Just sign the papers.
Wouldn't you like to see the bedroom,
my little billiard ball?
Sign.
- I make a very dry martini.
- Right here.
- I make a very wet soufflé.
- Just your name.
- Don't be so mean, you mean old meanie.
- Come, my dear.
♪ Let's you and me make
Why shouldn't we make hay? &
- I have an appointment at 1.
- This way.
- ♪ You ever been to Buenos Aires ♪
- Where?
- ♪ I hunger for the Argentine ♪
- Argentine.
- ♪ Let's me and you fill up our diaries ♪
- What? Stop!
- ♪ Buy me a ruby ♪
- No!
♪ Why shouldn't you be mine? ♪
- ♪ Come close, madame ♪
- ♪ I got your number, you like to rumba ♪
- ♪ While we pry through this ♪
- ♪ I'll call you Ollie, my hot tamale ♪
- ♪ And now I gotcha, my cucaracha ♪
- ♪ File from my private eye ♪
Aye-yi-yi.
- ♪ You spend evenings in the shanties ♪
- You had me followed?
- ♪ Imbibing quarts of bathtub gin ♪
- Bronchitis.
- ♪ You're dancing in your scanties ♪
- Great gams.
- With some old geezer, Little Caesar
-He's an uncle.
- ♪ You lock the orphans in the closet ♪
- They love it.
- ♪ You hock their Christmas souvenirs ♪
- Drink?
- ♪ You steal funds you should deposit ♪
- It's fresh.
♪ You make them grovel
While you buy lavalieres ♪
- ♪ You'll ♪
- ♪ Must you upset me ♪
- ♪ Sit out this century ♪
- ♪ Why don't you pet me? ♪
♪ It's you I crave now
Let's misbehave now ♪
♪ In some deep, dark ♪
♪ You wanna smoochie
My little poochie ♪
♪ Penitentiary ♪
- Jail?
- Sign!
- ♪ I guess I'll never know the feeling ♪
- ♪ You'll rot in jail ♪
♪ Of running fingers
Through your hair ♪
♪ In Sing Sing ♪
♪ I guess this means
No Buenos Aires ♪
- ♪ Will you sign? ♪
- ♪ Well, I don't need you ♪
- ♪ That's fine ♪
- ♪ So just forget me ♪
- ♪ The dotted line ♪
- ♪ Forget my sweetness ♪
- ♪ Don't whine, you can't decline ♪
- ♪ Forget you met me ♪
- ♪ Today is sorta... ♪
- ♪ Just sign ♪
♪ My bread and Waterloo ♪
♪ Sign ♪♪
Why didn't you say so
in the first place, swine?
Women! Does it take this long
to get to Tiffany's and back?
Where is she?
- I hear the car.
- It's probably not the right car.
It's the Duesenberg.
Miss Farrell took the Duesenberg.
What took you so long?
What's happening here?
Where's Annie?
She's taking her karate lesson
with the Asp.
- Don't be nervous.
- I'm not. You give it to her.
- It was your idea.
- She likes you better than me.
Oliver, will you pull yourself together?
Mr. War bucks, want to see
what the Asp taught me today?
Hi-yah!
Oh!
To the couch, Punjab, if you please.
- Oh, gee. I didn't think it would work.
- Now you know it does.
- Shall I call a doctor?
- Oh, it'll be fine.
Punjab.
Ah.
Thank you.
We'll leave you two alone.
Annie, I want to talk to you
about something very serious.
- You don't want me anymore, right?
- On the contrary, I do.
Good Lord.
Annie, can we have a man-to-man talk?
Sure.
What I'm proposing would
involve a long-term, um, agreement.
Actually,
maybe you ought to know more about me
before you make up your mind.
- Okay.
- Let's go for a walk.
Okay.
I was born in Liverpool
in a railroad switch house.
My brother died of pneumonia because
we didn't have money for medicine.
Well, I decided then and there
that one day I would be very rich.
Good idea.
In those days,
America was the land of opportunity.
I sighed on a ship as cabin boy
when I was 12.
By the time I was 21,
I'd made my first million.
In the next 10 years,
I turned that into 100 million.
-Wow.
In those days, that was a lot of money.
I was ruthless, hurt a lot of people.
Making money was all I ever
gave a damn about, up to now.
- Let's go inside.
- Okay.
It's occurred to me that
no matter how many houses I have,
how many Rembrandts,
how many Duesenbergs,
unless I have someone to share it with,
well, I might as well be broke.
Annie, do you understand
what I'm trying to say?
Sure.
Good.
Kind of.
- Kind of?
- I guess not.
Damn. Oh, excuse me.
- You've given me so much already.
- I got the papers signed. It's official.
What is?
It's so pretty, but...
- Let me put it on you.
- No.
It's a swell locket, but if it's
all the same, I'll keep my old one.
It isn't all the same.
Your old one's broken.
This one is engraved.
You didn't even look. "To Annie.
With love from Daddy War bucks."
Mr. War bucks, when my folks left me
at the orphanage 10 years ago,
they left a note saying they'd come back
to get me as soon as they could.
They kept the other half of this locket
so I'd know them when they came.
I'm going to find them someday
and have a regular mother and father
like a regular kid. I am.
I don't mean to hurt your feelings.
You've been nicer to me
than anybody in the whole world.
But I've been dreaming of my folks
for as long as I can remember.
And I've just got to find them.
And I'll help you.
Grace! Get me ♪. Edgar on the phone!
Drake, get me the chief of police!
Asp, get me Walter Winchell!
Punjab!
Get me William Randolph Hearst!
And, Saunders, get me a drink!
Six, seven, eight, you're on.
♪ I-O-D-E-N-T
lodent ♪
♪ Hey, hobo man
Hey, dapper Dan ♪
♪ You both got your style ♪
♪ But, brother ♪
♪ You're never fully dressed
Without a smile ♪
♪ Your clothes may be
Beau Brummelly ♪
♪ They stand out a mile
But, brother ♪
♪ You're never fully dressed
Without a smile ♪
Aha, the lovely Boylan Sisters.
♪ Doot, didoot, doot, doot
Doot, didoot, doot, doot ♪
♪ Who cares
What they're wearing ♪
♪ On Main Street or Savile Row ♪
- ♪ It's what you wear from ear to ear ♪
- ♪ Ear to ear ♪
♪ And not from head to toe ♪
♪ That matters ♪
♪ Doot, doot, didoot... ♪
Tonight, as a special treat
from yours truly, Bert Healy,
I'd like to introduce
a little orphan named Annie.
Hey. Who's that who just walked into
our Red Network studios?
Well, it's none other than the Wall Street
tycoon, Oliver War bucks!
"Thank you, Bert Healy.
It's swell..." Do I say swell?
"Swell to be on the lodent Hour."
I understand you're conducting
a search for Annie's parents.
Yeah, I told you that
before we went on the air. Oh, yes!
"Bert Healy, I am now conducting
a coast-to-coast, nationwide search
for Annie's parents.
Drop page. War bucks continues.
Furthermore, I am offering
a cash reward to Annie's parents
of $50,000 cash."
Oh, Mr. War bucks!
Oh, boy! Oh, boy, 50,000 smackers.
So, Annie's parents, if you're listening,
please contact Oliver War bucks...
"War bucks interrupts.
At my house, Bert Healy, 987 Fifth Avenue,
New York City. Ha, ha!
Thank you, Bert Healy,
and thank you, all-new lodent.
The toothpaste with miracle K-64
to fight hali... Hali..."
- Tosis.
- "And for letting me talk to you.
Good night, Bert Healy,
and for the Red Network. Drop page."
Did I just do a commercial?
Let's get out of here.
I've never endorsed a product
in all of my career.
♪ Doot, doot, didoot, doot
Doot, doot, didoot, doot ♪
For all of you, our smiles family,
this is Bert Healy saying...
♪ Hey, hobo man
Hey, dapper Dan ♪
♪ You both got your style ♪
♪ But, brother
You're never fully dressed ♪
♪ Without a smile ♪
♪ Your clothes may be
Beau Brummelly ♪
♪ They stand out a mile ♪
♪ But, brother
You're never fully dressed ♪
♪ Without a smile ♪
♪ Who cares what they're wearing ♪
♪ On Main Street or Savile Row ♪
♪ It's what you wear from ear to ear ♪
♪ And not from head to toe ♪
♪ That matters ♪
Ah, the lovely Boylan Sisters.
♪ I-O-D-E-N-T ♪
♪ Doot, doot, didoot, doot
Doot, doot, didoot, doot ♪
♪ So, senator
So, janitor ♪
♪ So long for a while ♪
♪ Remember you're never
Fully dressed ♪
♪ Without a smile ♪
♪ You're never fully dressed
Without a smile ♪
♪ Who cares what they're wearing ♪
♪ On Main Street or Savile Row ♪
- ♪ It's what you wear from ear to ear ♪
- ♪ Ear to ear ♪
♪ And not from head to toe ♪
♪ That matters ♪
♪ So, senator
So, janitor ♪
♪ So long for a while ♪
♪ Remember you're never
Fully dressed ♪
♪ Though you may wear the best ♪
♪ You're never fully dressed ♪
♪ Without a smile ♪
♪ You're never fully dressed
You're never fully dressed ♪
♪ Without a... ♪♪
Do I hear happiness in here?
They never miss.
Everybody's going to get their chance.
Annie, it's your mother.
We've got to get her out of here.
- We can't expose her to this.
- Get the autocopter ready.
Wow.
Annie, guess what. Mr. War bucks
is going to take you to see the president.
Oh, boy!
Marvelous!
Aren't Republicans ostentatious?
Franklin, behave.
It's astonishing he's here at all.
What do you call this thing, Oliver?
It looks like great fun.
An autocopter.
You don't need an airport,
just a backyard.
They say it can land on a dime.
Whatever that may be.
I appreciate you coming.
It means a great deal.
It means nothing. It means only
that Annie wanted to meet you.
It's nice to meet you,
Mr. President Roosevelt.
It's my pleasure, Annie.
And thank you for bringing the old goat.
Make a New Dealer of him yet.
- Inconceivable.
- Don't mind him, Oliver.
Come along, Annie.
My Uncle Theodore used to teach
his children to walk on stilts.
I can't teach you that, but I can
teach you to roll in a chair with wheels.
It's my own private roller coaster.
The New Deal is badly planned,
badly organized and administered.
You don't think your
programs through, Franklin.
Think what they're going to do
to the economy in the long run!
- People don't eat in the long run.
- People can't feed their children.
The lucky ones end up in orphanages.
The older ones
are abandoned to steal, starve.
This business of this country
is business. You have to...
Take them off the dole and
put them to work. That's what I'll do.
In the National Parks, clearing trails,
fighting fires, planting trees.
- Hold it.
- I want to feed them and house them
and pay them.
Enough to send home to their parents
so they can hold their heads up
and be proud to be Americans.
- That's a swell idea.
- It isn't a swell idea, Annie,
it's mistaken foolishness.
Big-hearted and empty-headed.
Which parks? Which children?
What will it cost?
Who's going to organize it?
Who's going to run it?
- I, uh, was hoping you would.
- Me?
And Annie.
Leaping lizards!
- Out of the question.
- How could I help?
Wait a minute.
- You could help us recruit young people.
- Hold everything!
Many of them think their government
doesn't care whether they live or die.
With your help, we could
convince them that with a little effort...
I want to say something.
There's this song I used to sing
in the orphanage when I'd get sad.
- It always cheered me up.
- Eleanor.
♪ Just thinking about tomorrow ♪
♪ Clears away the cobwebs
And the sorrow ♪
♪ Till there's none ♪
♪ When I'm stuck with a day ♪
♪ That's gray and lonely ♪
♪ I just stick out my chin ♪
♪ And grin and say ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ The sun'll come out tomorrow ♪
♪ So you gotta hang on till tomorrow ♪
♪ Come what may ♪
♪ Tomorrow, tomorrow ♪
♪ I love ya, tomorrow ♪
♪ You're only a day away ♪♪
Oh, Franklin.
- You'll help us too, won't you, Oliver?
- Bah.
Think of the children. Think of Annie.
♪ The sun'll come out
Tomorrow ♪
Sing, Oliver, that's an order
from your commander in chief.
- ♪ There'll be sun ♪
- Eleanor?
- I can't sing.
Sing.
♪ Tomorrow ♪
♪ Clears away the cobwebs
And the sorrow ♪
♪ Till there's none ♪
Solo for the president.
♪ When I'm stuck
With a day ♪
♪ That's gray and lonely ♪
♪ I just stick out my chin ♪
♪ And grin and say ♪
Everybody! Republicans too, Oliver.
Sing!
♪ The sun'll come out tomorrow ♪
♪ So you've got to hang on
Till tomorrow ♪
♪ Come what may ♪
Harmony!
♪ Tomorrow, tomorrow ♪
♪ I love ya, tomorrow ♪
♪ You're only a day away ♪
♪ Tomorrow, tomorrow ♪
♪ I love ya, tomorrow ♪
♪ You're only a day ♪
♪ Away ♪♪
All right, everybody, step up.
I've got fresh fish here.
- Yeah?
- Excuse me. Do you run this establishment?
Unfortunately.
Ten years ago, we left our
little baby girl on the front steps.
We were starving. There was a job managing
a hotel, but only if we had no children.
Wrap it up. I'm listening to Helen Trent.
We never meant to leave our little Annie.
Annie?
Now we have a hardware store
in New Jersey. We could take care of her.
We've always loved her.
You're Annie's parents?
Our place isn't fancy, but it's home.
We live over the store.
- There's a yard out back.
- We have chickens.
And a rooster.
Rooster?
My God! I never would have recognized you.
Hurry.
Sis, if we can fool you,
we can fool "Big Bucks."
- Fifty thousand smackers.
- You're gonna be the death of me.
Oh, come on, sis. This is going to be
the best bunco job ever.
- All we need is details.
- About Annie. Specifics.
I see.
- What's in it for me?
- A three-way split of the $50,000.
- I want half.
- Half?
- Half!
- All right, half!
- Rooster!
- All right!
Twenty-five grand for me and Lil,
25 grand for you.
Hey!
Why don't we wait
and see what she's got, huh?
See if it's worth 25 grand.
You want details? I got details.
I got specifics on every kid in this dump.
It's just a question
of finding the right box.
Ha!
Annie wears a locket around her neck.
It's a broken locket.
She says her parents saved the other half
to someday come and claim her with.
Well, years ago,
years and years ago,
her parents were killed in a fire.
And the cops brought me all their junk.
Well, my darling baby brother,
if Annie's parents can claim her
with that locket, so can we.
Fifty thousand smackers!
And the kid,
we'll drop in the river.
They're going to do
something bad to Annie! Pepper!
- Have you cleaned the can?
- Listen to me. I mean it.
Clean the can!
- Duffy, Tessie, somebody!
- Do you want a knuckle sandwich?
- We've gotta warn Annie!
- Scrub!
It's in a sealed envelope.
♪ It ain't fair how we scrounge
For three or four bucks ♪
♪ While she gets War bucks ♪
The little brat. Look in those!
♪ It ain't fair
This here life is driving me nuts ♪
Make yourself useful!
♪ When we get peanuts ♪
♪ She's living fat ♪
♪ Maybe she holds the key ♪
- ♪ That little lady ♪
- ♪ To getting more bucks ♪
- Right, instead of less.
- It'll have her name on it.
♪ Maybe we fix it again
With something shady ♪
♪ Where does that put us? ♪
♪ Give you one guess ♪
Open it. Open it.
Hurry.
♪ Easy Street ♪
- ♪ Annie is the key ♪
- ♪ Yes, sirree ♪
Bop!
- ♪ Easy Street ♪
- ♪ We'll live the plush life ♪
- ♪ The lazy, lush life ♪
♪ Better get there ♪
♪ The gravy's flowing there ♪
♪ We'll soon be going there ♪
♪ Where you sleep till noon ♪
- ♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
- ♪ Move them feet ♪
- ♪ Move them ever-loving feet ♪
- ♪ To Easy Street ♪
- ♪ Where living's sweet ♪
♪ That's where we're gonna be ♪
♪ Easy Street ♪
♪ Move them feet to Easy Street ♪
♪ That's where we're gonna ♪
Hit it, sis.
♪ Stay ♪
♪ Easy Street ♪♪
Now do the other one.
Ow!
Duffy, Tessie, somebody!
They're going to do
something bad to Annie!
- Who is?
- They are!
- Who's they?
- Miss Hannigan.
Oh, my goodness!
Beautiful.
- Where do you think you're going?
- Run, run, go tell Annie!
Stop them!
Get in that closet.
Stop it!
Whose rotten idea was this?
Are they here?
Did they bring me a brother and sister?
A man who counts his chickens
before they hatch gets a scrambled egg.
What?
Have my parents come for me?
We haven't found them, Annie.
I interviewed 865 couples.
None of them knew about the locket.
I never realized how many
dishonest people there are in New York.
I guess they're dead. I guess I've
known that deep down for a long time.
I'm not giving up. Don't you give up.
I didn't want to be just another orphan.
I wanted to believe I was special.
You are special.
Never stop believing that.
We're trapped.
Shh!
Oh, my goodness. Oh, my goodness.
Poor Annie.
- We'll never get out of here.
- I've got an idea.
That's a great idea.
- It's heavy.
- Don't drop it.
- All right. Shh!
- Now what do you want to do?
She'll be so mad
if she catches us.
I'm not so sure
if I want to do this.
We're gonna be in so much trouble.
- Duffy, hand me something.
- Here.
- There's space up here.
- Be careful.
Oh, my goodness. Oh, my goodness.
Help me get up.
Give me your hand.
It's a long way down.
Are you sure you want to do this?
- Wish me luck.
- Good luck.
We were starving. We needed the job.
That's why we left our little girl.
Wrapped in a newspaper.
On the steps
of the Hudson St. Orphanage.
What's this?
Mr. War bucks,
this is Ralph and Shirley Mudge
from Hoboken, New Jersey.
Annie!
Oh!
Oh, Ralph, look.
She still has the locket.
We finally found you.
I suppose you heard about the reward
on the radio.
- Reward?
- We don't have a radio.
- In the paper.
- Paper?
- What paper?
- How did you know Annie was here?
That kind lady at the orphanage told us.
I have her birth certificate right here.
I've kept it close to my heart
all these years.
"Ann Marie Mudge.
October 18, 1922."
I'll go pack.
Do you want me to help, baby?
No, thanks...
Mom.
Come on.
A certified check.
Oh, sir, we're just so thrilled
to have found Annie.
We don't need any money.
- I'll take it back.
- Of course, we are poor people.
It would help us a lot.
We could buy her milk, a warm blanket.
Put it in your pocket, Mrs. Mudge.
Come on, you guys.
Oh, my goodness!
We're never gonna make it.
- We've found Fifth Avenue.
- Number one, Fifth Avenue.
We gotta go to 987.
Molly, get on my back.
Come on, you guys, help.
- Will the stores take this back?
- All your new clothes?
Well, I guess so, Annie.
Don't you want to keep them?
My folks are poor. All these clothes
are going to make them feel bad.
Could you take them to the orphanage
and give them to my friends?
Certainly.
This will look so cute on Molly.
This will look good on Duffy.
♪ Betcha my life
Is gonna be swell ♪
♪ Looking at them ♪
♪ It's easy to tell I
♪ And maybe I'll forget ♪
♪ How nice he was to me ♪
♪ And how I was almost his baby ♪
♪ It'll be fine ♪
♪ Nothing to fear ♪
♪ She'll be as happy
As she was here ♪
♪ Things have worked out
Much better than planned ♪
♪ It makes you smile ♪
♪ When fate takes a hand ♪
♪ And I know I'll forget ♪
♪ How much she meant to me ♪
♪ And how she was almost my baby ♪
♪ Maybe ♪♪
- Did you get it?
- She has it.
Let me see it.
- You know, I think I'd better hold it.
- Over my dead body.
That's the brightest thing
I've ever heard you say.
Ladies! Ladies!
- Help, Mr. War bucks! Help!
- Get on the road!
We'll never find the house.
I wish I'd been
outside in New York City.
When do I get my half?
- I say we go back.
- We can't.
We've been walking for 100 years!
- We're never going to get there.
- But we have to.
- Let's take a vote.
- All in favor of calling it quits?
I'll get me one of those
little gold lamé numbers.
In Atlantic City.
We aren't stopping
till we hit Atlantic City.
Whoo.
- Help, Mr. War bucks! It's Miss Hannigan!
- Shut up, kid.
Look, there's Sandy!
Come here! Come here!
Come on, let's go!
- Hurry up.
- Hurry! Hurry!
I can't run anymore.
All right, quiet down, girls.
You want to see Mr. War bucks?
All right, come on.
Oh, my goodness!
- What now?
- Sir.
- I think he's a highness.
- Your Highness.
- We're friends of Annie's.
- Annie's gone.
Her parents came and took her away.
But they wasn't her real parents, mister.
- They was bad people.
- Leaping lizards!
You take the autocopter,
I'll take the car.
J. Edgar? War bucks here.
Orphan Annie has been kidnapped.
I want every G-man east of the Mississippi
on this in the next 20 minutes.
Where's the fire, fellas?
Sahib.
Sahib, the truck is on Canal Street,
heading east.
East on Canal.
Well done, Punjab. Don't lose them now.
Excuse me, mister.
Can we stop a second? I gotta go.
I really gotta, Miss Hannigan.
I mean it, lady. You're asking for it.
When you gotta go, you gotta go.
Make it fast.
Rooster, grab her! She's got the check!
Cut her off at the bridge.
Goddamn it!
Come back here,
you goddamn kid!
Mr. War bucks will eat your livers!
I'll kill you.
I'll kill you, you little brat!
- Wring her neck, Rooster!
- He's really gonna kill her.
Rooster!
Rooster, stop!
Rooster, she's a baby!
Come back here!
Rooster!
- I'm gonna Kill her!
- No! I'm not gonna let you!
She may be a mean, rotten little orphan,
but I'm not gonna let you kill her.
Let go of me, you old boozer!
Stop it! Just stop it!
Sahib.
- Sahib, they're at the B&O bridge.
- They're on the bridge. Turn right.
I know, I know.
We're pulling up over here!
Help, somebody! Help! Help!
Help, somebody!
Leave me alone! Please help!
Please help!
Let's go,
get the ladders in there!
Help! Help!
Somebody help me!
Come on, over here!
Hurry it up there!
Bring it up this way!
Help! Help!
Have we got two nets?
Hurry up! You're too slow! Let's go!
Please! Punjab, help me.
Help me, Punjab! Help!
Punjab, help!
You need both hands. We must hold on.
I can't!
Buddha says a child without courage
is like a night without stars. Come.
Let's back it in here.
Rooster, you reprobate!
Okay, let's clear the area over here!
- ♪ Together at last ♪
- Together forever
- ♪ We're tying a knot ♪
- ♪ They never can sever ♪
♪ I don't need sunshine now ♪
♪ To turn my skies to blue ♪
- ♪ I don't need anything but you ♪
♪ You've wrapped me around ♪
♪ That cute little finger ♪
♪ You've made life a song ♪
♪ You've made me the singer ♪
♪ And what's that bathtub tune
You always ba-ba-boo? ♪
♪ Ba-ba-ba, ba-ba-ba
But you ♪
♪ Yesterday was plain awful ♪
♪ You can say that again ♪
- ♪ But that's ♪
- ♪ Not now ♪
- ♪ That's then ♪
♪ I'm poor as a mouse ♪
Ha, ha!
♪ I'm richer than Midas ♪
- Oliver, marvelous!
- ♪ But nothing on earth ♪
- ♪ Could ever divide us ♪
- ♪ And if tomorrow ♪
- ♪ I'm an apple seller too ♪
- ♪ I don't need anything ♪
- ♪ Anything, anything ♪
- ♪ I don't need anything but ♪
♪ She's like the fizz in a Coke ♪
♪ A buck when you're broke
And more ♪
♪ When woes and worries take hold ♪
♪ Who gives them the old trap door ♪
- ♪ I do not mind repeating ♪
- ♪ We got Annie ♪
That 4th of July kid!
♪ We got Annie
I wish she were my kid ♪
♪ We've got Annie ♪
♪ And she's got it all ♪
Annie!
"To Annie, with love."
I love you, Daddy War bucks.
♪ Tomorrow, tomorrow ♪
♪ I love ya, tomorrow ♪
♪ You're only a day away ♪
♪ Tomorrow, tomorrow ♪
♪ I love ya, tomorrow ♪
♪ You're only a day ♪
♪ Away ♪♪
♪ The sun'll come out tomorrow ♪
♪ Bet your bottom dollar
That tomorrow ♪
♪ There'll be sun ♪
♪ Just thinking about tomorrow ♪
♪ Clears away the cobwebs
And the sorrow ♪
♪ Till there's none ♪
♪ When I'm stuck with a day
That's gray and lonely ♪
♪ I just stick out my chin ♪
♪ And grin and say ♪
♪ Oh, the sun'll come out tomorrow ♪
♪ So you gotta hang on till tomorrow ♪
♪ Come what may ♪
♪ Tomorrow, tomorrow ♪
♪ I love ya, tomorrow ♪
♪ You're only a day away ♪
♪ Tomorrow, tomorrow ♪
♪ I love ya, tomorrow ♪
♪ You're only a day ♪
♪ Away ♪♪