Captain wants you to keep 500ft.
Manoeuvring, Control.
Come in shallow to 500ft.
- Keep 500ft.
- Keep 500ft, sir.
What the hell's going on, Eddie?
Emergency stations. Emergency stations.
Captain to the control room.
- What the hell's going on?
- Control, Manoeuvring.
- Control.
- I'm losing electrical frequency.
- I'll have to break down the system
- Control, Sound Room.
Total loss of power on all sonar sets.
Surface. Blow forward, blow aft. Rise on
both planes. Raise the search periscope.
Oh, my God!
Put him through.
Good morning, sir.
No, First Sea Lord. No, there's been
no contact with Ranger yet, sir.
No. No sightings, no distress signals, sir.
It looks very much like it.
Yes. Yes, of course I will, sir.
We've lost one of our nuclear submarines.
What?
The submarine Potemkin
disappeared without trace?
But what a catastrophe,
Comrade Chairman.
Yes, of course.
I will assign our best agent immediately.
Rube/vitch, where is Agent Triple X?
On leave, General. At the People's
Rest and Recuperation Centre.
It's been a wonderful weekend.
- I shall never forget it.
- Nor will I.
When can we meet again?
As soon as my mission is accomplished.
I must go. I have to be in Austria tonight.
Five more minutes.
Agent Triple X
Calling Agent Triple X You will report
to headquarters immediately.
Agent Triple X, acknowledge and verify.
This is Triple X.
Message received and understood.
Yes, Mr Prime Minister.
I understand the gravity of the situation.
Yes, I'll put our best man on it at once.
Goodbye.
Moneypenny, where's 007?
He's on a mission, sir. In Austria.
Tell him to pull out. Immediately.
Oh, James.
I cannot find the words.
Let me try and enlarge your vocabulary.
- What happened? Where are you going?
- Sorry. Something came up.
But, James, I need you.
So does England.
He has just left.
He has just left- Over and out.
Message received.
We are waiting. Over and out.
Now.
Nobody does it better
Makes me feel sad for the rest
Nobody does it
Half as good as you
Baby, you're the best
I wasn't Iookin'
But somehow you found me
I tried to hide from your love light
But like heaven above me
The spy who loved me
ls keepin' all my secrets safe tonight
And nobody does it better
Though sometimes
I wish someone could
Nobody does it
Quite the way you do
Why'd you have to be so good?
The way that you hold me
Whenever you hold me
There's some kind of magic inside you
That keeps me from runnin'
But just keep it comin'
How'd you learn
to do the things you do?
And nobody does it better
Makes me feel sad for the rest
Nobody does it
Half as good as you
Baby, baby
Baby, you're the best
Send in Agent Triple X.
You sent for me, Comrade General.
Good morning. Major Amasova,
we are facing a most delicate situation.
Our nuclear submarine
Potemkin has disappeared.
- Sabotage?
- That is for you to find out.
We have one lead. A connection in Cairo.
You leave tonight.
Will that be all, Comrade General?
There is one more thing.
I regret to inform you, Major,
that Agent Sergei Barsov has been killed.
On a mission,
at Berngarten in the Austrian Alps.
- A tragic occurrence, Comrade General.
- It had not escaped our notice
that you had been more than friends
for some time. I'm very sorry.
- How did he die?
- We haven't all the details yet,
but it appears he'd become involved
in a British Secret Service operation.
Please keep me informed,
Comrade General.
I should very much like to meet
whoever was responsible for his death.
Sea King 05, finals to land. Over.
Sea King 05, this is Faslane.
Sea King 05. Roger. Out.
Good morning, sir.
- Morning, 007.
- Hello, Q.
- Mission successful?
- On and off.
Morning, Commander.
- Captain Forsyth.
- Commander.
Commander Bond, sir.
Mr Frederick Gray, Minister of Defence.
Morning, Commander.
Admiral Hargreaves,
Flag Officer Submarines.
- Ark Royal, wasn't it?
- Yes, sir.
- I believe M told you about this.
- Yes, Minister.
Over here, please, gentlemen.
This is Ranger's prearranged course
to her patrol area?
That's right.
- Who knew this course?
- Admiral Hargreaves, myself,
and Talbot, the captain of the submarine.
Good God!
- Where did this come from?
- For the moment that's top secret.
I see, sir.
This means the Russians can track our
submarines underwater and sink them.
- I believe it does.
- How could they? It's impossible.
No. It's quite simple, really.
Heat-signature recognition most likely.
- With your permission, Minister?
- Yes, of course.
We already know that satellites
with infrared heat sensors
can detect a nuclear missile in flight
by its tail fire.
- Well?
- Someone can now locate
a submerged nuclear submarine
in exactly the same way, by its wake.
But that means they can totally
undermine our Western defence strategy.
It looks like it, yes.
- Where did we get the tracing, Freddie?
- Cairo. Diplomatic bag.
Somebody got hold of the plans of that
tracking system and is trying to sell them.
They sent us that tracing
as proof that it's genuine.
If there is a deal to be made,
the price is going to be high.
High? Astronomical.
That missing submarine
had 16 Polaris missiles aboard.
- I take it we have a contact in Egypt?
- M will give you the details.
You leave tonight.
- Dr Bechmann and Professor Markovitz.
- Thank you.
Well, gentlemen, now that the moment
has come to bid you farewell,
I congratulate both you,
Doctor, and you, Professor,
on your brilliant work
in the development
of the submarine tracking system.
Thanks primarily to you, I'm happy to say
that the first phase of our operation
has met with considerable success.
I have instructed my assistant to have
paid into your Swiss bank account
the sum of ten million dollars each.
- Thank you, sir.
- Thank you indeed.
And that, I think, concludes our business.
Before you go, however,
I very much regret to inform you
that a dangerous development has
recently been brought to my notice.
Someone has been attempting to sell
the plans of our tracking project
to competing world powers.
Someone intimately associated
with the project.
My dear, it would perhaps be
more seemly if you were to leave us.
Thank you.
It was you who betrayed me.
You had access to all the information.
And now you will pay the penalty.
Once again, gentlemen,
my most profound thanks.
- Sandor.
- Yes, sir.
Jaws.
I'm assigning you the task
of recovering the microfilm copy
of the tracking system.
Sandor, you will go with him. Obey him.
Every person who even comes
into contact with that microfilm
is to be eliminated.
Stand by for helicopter takeoff.
A/I personnel clear
of the flight-deck platform.
Cancel transfer of 20 million dollars.
Inform next of kin that a tragic accident
has resulted in the deaths of
Professor Markovitz and Dr Bechmann.
The funeral was at sea.
- Fade! Kadeer.
- Garabna-
Sh ukran
- Shukran.
- Afwan.
- Assalaam alaykum.
- Ala ykum assalaam.
May the peace of Allah descend upon this
abode and allow a poor traveller to enter.
May the hospitality of these miserable
quarters be sufficient to your needs.
James Bond! What a delightful surprise
after all these years. Do sit down.
Thank you.
I wondered what you were going to do
when you went down from Cambridge.
I never had any problems knowing what
you were going to do, Hosein. Shukran.
We don't only have oil, you know.
What can I offer you?
Sheep's eyes, dates? Vodka martini?
Information. Who is putting the submarine
tracking system on the market?
What a pity it is you persist
in being so businesslike.
The gentleman you will eventually
be dealing with is a certain Max Kalba.
- Eventually?
- To reach Kalba,
you must first make contact
with a man called Fekkesh, Aziz Fekkesh.
I'll give you the address of his apartment
in Cairo, but it's too late to meet today.
Can I persuade you
to accept a bed for the night?
It's kind of you, Hosein, but
I really feel I...
Are you quite sure
I can't persuade you to stay the night?
When one is in Egypt, one should
delve deeply into its treasures.
Mr Bond.
Yes. I'm sorry. The door was open.
Mr Fekkesh is expecting me.
I phoned him.
He asked me to give you a message.
He will be a little late.
May I ask where he is?
Mr Fekkesh asked me to entertain you
while you are waiting.
Really?
Where is Fekkesh?
- You are very suspicious, Mr Bond.
- I find I live much longer that way.
Now, where is he?
If there's anything you would like...
Anything at all...
I had lunch, but...
I seem to have missed dessert.
As urgent as my appointment is,
I'd hate him to walk in and surprise us.
There is no danger of that.
- He's gonna be some time, then, is he?
- Mm-hm.
Is he meeting someone?
I'm sorry. I cannot answer that question.
I think you can.
No!
Where's Fekkesh?
- Where's Fekkesh?
- Pyramids.
Agh!
What a helpful chap.
You have come tonight
to the most fabulous
and celebrated place in the world.
Here on the plateau of Giza
stands for ever the mightiest
of human achievements.
No traveller, emperor, merchant or poet
has trodden on these sands
and not gasped in awe.
The curtain of night is about to rise
and disclose the stage on which
the drama of a civilisation took place.
Those involved have been present
since the dawn of history,
pitched stubbornly
against sand and wind.
And the voice of the desert
has crossed the centuries.
Excuse me, Major.
I'll be back in a moment.
With each new dawn, I see the sun god
rise on the far bank of the Nile.
I am the faithful warden
at the foot of his Lord,
so faithful, so vigilant,
so near him
that he gave me his face for my own.
I am a Pharaoh's companion,
and I am he, the Pharaoh.
This is the tomb of Cheops,
Pharaoh of the fourth dynasty
4,500 years ago.
Here is the great pyramid which he built
to defend himself against death.
Here in the depths of this tomb
a servant of the king awaits the call
to set out upon his journey into eternity.
Death lies waiting.
- Where is Fekkesh?
- With the Pharaohs.
- You killed him.
- No, he was dead when I found him.
Hope you enjoyed the show. Good night.
What an unexpected pleasure.
Welcome to the Mujaba Club.
Buy you a drink, Major Amasova?
Or may I call you Triple X?
So you know who I am.
You made quite an impression.
I'm sorry about Ivan and Boris.
- They exceeded their orders.
- Good staff is hard to find these days.
- Yes, sir?
- The lady'll have a Bacardi on the rocks.
For the gentleman,
vodka martini, shaken not stirred.
Touché.
Commander James Bond,
recruited to the British
Secret Service from the Royal Navy.
Licensed to kill,
and has done so on numerous occasions.
Many lady friends, but married only once.
- Wife killed...
- All right, you've made your point.
- You're sensitive, Mr Bond.
- About certain things, yes.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
tragically, I have a previous engagement.
Happily enough, so do I.
- Goodbye, Mr Bond.
- Let's say au revoir.
I have the oddest feeling
we'll be meeting again sometime.
- I'm looking for a Mr Kalba.
- Mr Max Kalba is the owner of the club.
Over there.
Mr Kalba,
my name is Bond, James Bond.
What of it?
You had an appointment
with a Mr Fekkesh.
Well?
He won't be joining you.
- You have something I might like to buy.
- Just a moment.
I would like to bid for it, too.
You forgot your drink, Mr Bond.
Thank you. Na zdoroviye.
It seems you have competition,
Mr Bond,
and from where I sit, I fancy you will find
the lady's figure hard to match.
Might the contestants at least be
permitted to view the article for sale?
Well, now, who will start the bidding?
Mr Kalba, sir.
The telephone. An urgent call.
Excuse me.
Pardon me.
This is Kalba.
AII6 ? A/I6?
Another?
We've really got to stop meeting like this.
Kalba was called to the phone.
What happened?
He was cutoff... Permanently.
The microfilm. Where is it?
Search me.
He must have it, or you wouldn't be here.
You don't know who he is.
He's on our records. A professional killer.
Called Jaws? Make no mistake, Mr Bond.
I want that microfilm
and I'm going to get it.
Unless I get it first.
Watch out!
Don't move.
The microfilm. Give it to me.
Egyptian builders.
Sorry.
You're just too late.
Give me the key.
The key!
Give it to me.
Try the big one.
Can you play any other tune?
Let's try reverse. That's backwards.
Would you like me to drive?
- Women drivers.
- Quiet! Watch this.
Shaken, but not stirred.
That gorilla must have
his teeth fixed by a riveter.
By the way,
thanks for deserting me back there.
Every woman for herself, remember?
Still, you... You did save my life.
We all make mistakes, Mr Bond.
The cylinder-head gasket.
Oh.
Hey! Stanna!
Stanna!
- Khuddnf Iii Kaa Hira
- Aywa, tfadal.
- What did he say?
- He thinks we're overdressed,
- but he'll take us to Cairo.
- Good.
It's getting cold.
Is there
anything I can do to warm you up?
You don't have to worry about me,
Mr Bond.
I went on a survival course in Siberia.
Yes, I believe a great number
of your countrymen do.
- What did they teach you?
- That it's very important
to have a positive mental attitude.
Nothing more practical than that?
Food is also very important.
What else?
When necessary, shared bodily warmth.
That's the part I like.
- Is this really what they do in Siberia?
- Yes, but not how they do it.
You're not trying to take advantage of me,
are you?
The thought never crossed my mind.
Just when it was getting interesting.
Where's the girl?
- Fein el bent?
- El bent, enta w'nayem rahet.
Morning, Moneypenny. Is he in?
Uh-huh.
My, it must have been quite a party.
Boring, Moneypenny.
As a matter of fact, I dropped off.
- Hello, James. We've been expecting you.
- Good morning, sir.
There's been a change of plan.
You probably recognise my opposite
number in the KGB. General Gogol.
And I believe you're familiar
with Major Amasova.
Enough to know
which cigarettes she smokes.
Our respective governments
have agreed to pool their resources
to find out what happened
to our submarines.
We have entered a new era
of Anglo-Soviet cooperation.
And as a sign of Russian good faith,
I'm prepared to make available the
microfilm recovered by Agent Triple X.
With considerable ease, I might add.
Don't bother with it. It's useless.
I examined it on the boat.
I assure you it is quite genuine.
Except that the vital technical information
has been taken out.
This was only intended
to whet our appetites.
Maybe Q can make something out of it.
I want that ready for Ahmed's tea party.
- After you, Alexis.
- No, no. After you, Miles.
Thank you.
That could bring tears to your eyes.
Everybody ready? Right.
Now, we're pretty certain that
this drawing was drafted in Italy.
The size corresponds
with a Venetian octavo,
and the typeface is an Italian one.
Now, note the slight upward stress
on the transversals.
Q, what's that mark there?
Probably something the drawing was
resting on when it was photographed.
Must have been done in a hurry.
- Can you enlarge it?
- Mm. Wait a minute.
Oratory. What is that?
- It's another word for chapel.
- Looks a bit like a bishop's mitre.
It is a fish. That is the symbol
of the Stromberg shipping line.
Karl Stromberg is one of
the richest men in the world.
One of the principal capitalist
exploiters of the West, sir.
It's not oratory, it's laboratory. Stromberg
has a marine research laboratory.
On Corsica, I believe.
Well done, James.
Actually, sir, it is in Sardegna.
That's brilliant. I'm certain
that two such perceptive talents
will enjoy working together in Sardinia,
and that it will help to make
Anglo-Soviet cooperation a reality.
Here we are.
That was a delicious meal. Thank you.
I didn't realise
you had such a healthy appetite.
Neither did I. It must be
travelling by train. I always enjoy it.
I remember when...
- What do you remember?
- I was going to talk about a mission.
Silly, isn't it? We can't talk
and yet we're in the same business.
- But with rival companies.
- We're not rivals at the moment.
No.
Then... How about a nightcap
on the company? My company.
I'm very sorry. I have an idea tomorrow's
going to be a busy day. I must sleep.
Yes. Well, then, sleep well.
And you.
- Good night.
What happened?
He just dropped in for a quick bite.
You're hurt.
Later.
Let's worry about you.
What was it they taught you
on that survival course?
A positive mental attitude.
And shared bodily warmth.
Nothing about keeping out of draughts.
Still enjoy travelling by train?
You saved my life.
Thank you, James.
I'm sorry.
Why don't you lie down
and let me look at it?
What can we use for a bandage?
How about this?
Grazie.
Wait a moment.
- Good morning, Major Boothroyd.
- Morning.
Look what Q's brought for us.
Isn't it nice?
Right, pay attention, O07. I want you
to take great care of this equipment.
- There are one or two accessories...
- Q, have I ever let you down?
Frequently.
- Buongiorno.
- Buongiorno, signore e signora.
You have a reservation for me. Sterling.
Ah, yes. Mr and Mrs Sterling.
Booked from Cairo.
- That's right.
- We have suite A5 for you.
A sitting room... And two bedrooms.
Moneypenny being a little over-efficient.
Do you have any messages for me?
Thank you.
Excellent.
We have been granted an audience.
- Mr Sterling?
- Yes.
I'm Naomi.
Mr Stromberg sent me to collect you.
How do you do? This is my wife,
who also happens to be my assistant.
- You are on holiday here?
- Where there's an ocean,
a marine biologist is never on holiday.
Can we offer you a drink before we go?
No, thank you. Mr Stromberg's
a very busy man. His time is precious.
What a handsome craft. Such lovely lines.
Thank you.
Very impressive.
I wonder if you'd show my wife around
while I'm with Mr Stromberg.
- Of course. This way.
- Thank you.
Now, don't be a bother to Naomi, darling.
I'll be back soon.
Oh, by the way,
Mr Stromberg prefers not to shake hands.
- It's the third button.
- Thank you.
Why do we seek to conquer space,
when seven-tenths of our universe
remains to be explored?
The world beneath the sea.
You seem to be well-equipped
to repair that oversight, Mr Stromberg.
My name is Sterling, Robert Sterling.
It's very kind of you to receive me.
Not at all. It's always a pleasure to
welcome someone with a mutual interest.
An extraordinary number of rare species.
You recognise that variety, of course.
Of course.
Pterois volitans. Other fish avoid it.
Those dorsal spines
are laden with venom.
Handsome but deadly.
I see you know your subject, Mr Sterling.
One tries. You have a remarkable
establishment here, Mr Stromberg.
I'm somewhat of a recluse.
I wish to conduct my life
on my own terms
and in surroundings
with which I can identify.
That is a privilege of wealth.
Don't you miss the outside world?
For me, this is all the world.
There is beauty,
there is ugliness,
and there is death.
I think you will find
this interesting, Mr Sterling.
- An underwater city.
- Fascinating, isn't it?
- The only hope for the future of mankind.
- We all have our dreams.
No dream, Mr Sterling. Soon a reality.
I'm afraid you must excuse me.
I have business to attend to.
Goodbye, Mr Sterling.
And if we don't meet again,
I wish you luck with your research.
Thank you. The brief glimpse
you've afforded me today
will only encourage me
to redouble my efforts.
Goodbye, Mr Stromberg.
- How interesting.
- There you are.
Darling, you should look at this model.
It's beautiful.
This is the Liparus, the latest
addition to the Stromberg fleet,
launched nine months ago.
Over a million tons,
it's the largest tanker in the world.
After the Karl Marx, of course.
Really, darling? It's amazing
the items of information you store away.
Were they the two on the train?
James Bond.
And the woman is Major Amasova,
a Russian agent.
Let them get ashore
and then kill them.
You're being secretive.
Where are we going?
I want another look
at that Stromberg laboratory.
Could he operate
the tracking system from there?
It's possible. All we know for sure is
that two nuclear submarines are missing.
What did you think of the model?
There was something strange about the
design of her bows. M's checking her out.
- James, that motorcycle...
- Has been following us for the last mile.
All those feathers and he still can't fly.
- James, there's...
- I know. Don't tell me.
Mamma mia! Che é successo?
Oddio, tutto distrutto!
Do you ever get the feeling
somebody doesn't like you?
Can you swim?
It's time we said goodbye
to an uninvited guest.
Alone at last.
That's what we've come to look at.
James!
Brace yourself.
Look!
How did you know about that?
I stole the blueprints of this car
two years ago.
Can we make it?
- Hello.
- I have a message for you.
- I think you just delivered it.
Thank you.
Sorry to interrupt you,
but I asked M for a list of all the ports
- the Stromberg tanker had called at.
- And what is the answer?
Since she was fitted out, there is no
record of her putting into port anywhere.
That's very odd
if it's true.
We don't make mistakes of that sort.
You sound just like a Russian.
I think we should take a closer look
at that tanker, don't you?
Yes, I do.
- Shall I contact Gogol?
- There's no need.
M has already offered to fix it.
- Very nice.
- It's Austrian. I bought it in Berngarten.
- Berngarten?
- Yes, I was doing some skiing.
- When was this?
- About three weeks ago. Why?
Do you recognise him?
No. Who is he?
The man I loved.
He was in Berngarten three weeks ago.
Did you kill him?
When someone's behind you on skis
trying to put a bullet in your back,
you don't always have time
to remember a face.
In our business, Anya, people get killed.
We both know that. So did he.
It was either him or me.
The answer to the question is yes.
I did kill him.
Then when this mission is over,
I will kill you.
Come in.
- Commander Carter?
- That's right. Welcome aboard. Major.
Have a seat.
- Can I get you something?
- Not for me. I don't know about the major.
Maj...
I'm sorry.
I hadn't expected you to be a woman.
Aboard this vessel, Commander,
I am Major Amasova of the Russian army.
- Yeah, sure.
- It's good of you to help us out.
- Got a couple of cabins at your disposal.
- Thank you.
Major, you're welcome
to use the shower in my quarters.
You do not have to show me
any special favours, Commander.
All the same,
I think it might be better if I did.
From COMSUB Atlantic, sir.
Right.
What's the matter, sailor? You never seen
a major taking a shower before?
Stand by for
second observation on target.
Up scope.
Check.
Target bearing. Mark.
Range. Mark.
Down scope.
- One division in high power.
- Range, 6,200 yards, sir.
- Angle on the bow, port 50.
- Torpedo Room. Boarding party ready.
Captain, sir. Our best solution
for the target is 120, speed three knots.
Officer of the deck, come right north. Tell
Manoeuvring to make turns for 11 knots.
Which bullet has my name on it,
the first or the last?
I have never failed on a mission,
Commander. Any mission.
In that case, Major,
one of us is bound to end up gravely
disappointed, because neither have I...
Control, Manoeuvring.
We're losing electrical frequency.
Control, Sonar.
Total power supplies failure.
Surface. Blow forward. Blow aft.
Up scope. Stand by.
Where the hell is she?
My God. She's right behind us.
Impossible.
Stand by at Number Two Dock.
Containment Crews, take up positions.
Dock Officer to Operations.
Mobilisation Crew entering dock area.
Number Two Dock to Operations.
25m to run.
I say again, 25m to run.
Activate Number Two Dock.
Operations Room, Number Two Dock.
Docking now complete.
Disembarkation Crew
moving into position.
S-ra y programme completed. Magnetic
field shut down. All systems normal.
Limpet speaker in position, sir.
Commander, you have precisely
two minutes to open your hatches
and surrender your ship.
The alternative is extermination
by cyanide gas.
Well?
There's no alternative.
Now, hear this. Your captain speaking.
Open all hatches
and proceed quietly onto the casing.
Hurry, Commander!
I'm not renowned for my patience!
OK, two ranks! Move it out!
Stay close to me. We'll try and hide you.
Our time is limited, Captain.
- Commence operations forthwith.
- Yes, sir.
Attention all personnel.
Stromberg Crews One and Two,
embark your submarines.
Put the Americans
in with the others, Captain.
Remove the prisoners.
Don't look up. You're on Candid Camera.
Complete nuclear missile loading.
Operations, Bridge. Altering course
number to 340, coming up to six knots.
Operations, Engine Room.
Revolutions 96 set.
Anya!
Operations, Radar.
No contacts within 25, 00om.
Bring those two prisoners here.
Operations Room, Sonar.
No contacts, no transmissions.
James Bond and Major Amasova.
You have certainly been persistent.
Very well.
Now your curiosity can be satisfied.
Both crews aboard, sir.
Missile onload completed.
They have already
been given their targets.
At 12 noon
they will have reached firing positions.
Within minutes, New York and Moscow
will cease to exist.
Global destruction will follow.
The new era will begin.
Submarines One and Two,
commence departure drill.
All right, Stromberg. You've made
your point. How much do you want?
How much?
Whatever do you mean, Mr Bond?
The price for not firing
those nuclear missiles.
You're deluded, Mr Bond.
I'm not interested in extortion.
I intend to change the face of history.
- By destroying the world?
- By creating a world.
A new and beautiful world
beneath the sea.
Today civilisation as we know it
is corrupt and decadent.
Inevitably, it will destroy itself.
I'm merely accelerating the process.
That does notjustify mass murder.
For that, Major,
I will accept the judgment of posterity.
Submarines ready for departure, sir.
Open bow doors, Captain.
Stromberg One,
you are clear to proceed to sea.
Stromberg Two,
you are also clear to proceed to sea.
Observe, Mr Bond.
The instruments of Armageddon.
Put this man
with the rest of the prisoners.
No, no, no, no. The lady will be
travelling to Atlantis with me.
Farewell, Mr Bond.
That word has, I must admit,
a welcome ring of permanency about it.
Au revoir, Anya.
Bring her.
Get that man at all costs!
Keep going.
Call him over.
Hey!
- Where's your captain?
- Here.
- Release the crews. Go to the armoury.
- Follow me, men.
Come on! Let's go!
Seal the operations room.
You! Stand by over there!
Help yourselves to firearms!
Grab a weapon! Come on, let's go!
We've taken both sides of the lower dock
area, but I'm afraid your captain's dead.
We're still no closer to that control room.
Leave it to me, sir.
Andrews, James, Marshall, Purvis!
Follow me!
That armour plating is inches thick.
We'll never get through it.
- Let's get to the armoury.
- What's there?
- A nuclear missile.
- A nuc...? Hey, wait!
This could take hours, sir.
- You got a date?
- No, sir.
Now you are beautiful.
I'm sorry if you feel less than comfortable.
But you have a tendency to violence
that has to be controlled.
- What is it?
- I, uh... Have to report, sir,
a break-out by some of the prisoners.
That is unfortunate, Captain.
However, we now have
the situation under control.
The operations room
is quite impregnable.
Then we must hope, Captain,
that you will suffer no further mishap.
OK.
All I need is the detonator.
Are you sure
you know what you're doing?
There has to be a first time for everything.
Blast!
What's the problem?
I mustn't touch
the impulse conductor circuit.
This ring houses
It's magnetic. I mustn't touch it
with any part of the detonator.
- What happens if you do?
- It'll go off.
- Give me a number six detonator.
- Aye aye, sir.
Number six, sir.
Thank you.
Did you fix that 20-second fuse?
Yes, sir. Here it is.
- Plastic explosive.
- Is it proceeding according to plan?
- Yes, sir.
Excellent.
- Sir!
- What is it?
The monitor's faded.
Change the circuit.
Cease fi re!
You're too late, Bond.
Our submarines are already on station.
In four minutes
the missiles will be launched.
- The transmission unit, can you work it?
- Sure. But we've only got three minutes!
If we find the position of the submarines,
maybe we can reprogramme them.
- To do what?
- To destroy each other.
James! The globe!
Take the position of the first submarine
and pass it on to the second as her target.
- And vice versa.
- Exactly.
Missile Control, this is the captain.
We have a change of target.
New coordinates are 034285219.
Missile Control. Captain.
We have a new target.
Everybody back on board the submarine!
Pass it on! Come on! Let's go!
Come on!
Foster, get those lines cleared! Come on!
Leaver, throw those guys a line!
Get those fenders cleared!
Fon/vard and aft!
- Get the submarine at diving stations!
- Diving stations!
Manoeuvring. Reactor into half-power
state. Ready to check telegraphs.
All personnel, take up positions fast!
Get Roberts to the gyro unit.
Come on! Move it!
- Stand by to revert to normal lighting.
- Come on. Get that hatch shut. Quick.
Torpedo Room, Control.
Load tube one with Mark 46 torpedo.
Open outer door on tube one.
- Select zero gyro angle.
- Outer door on tube one open.
- Match bearings and shoot.
- Set.
- Shoot.
Torpedo running.
- Rudder amidships. Ahead two thirds.
- Left seven degrees rudder.
How far would you say?
Mm. About 10,000 yards, sir.
Commander.
Close it.
I got this signal from the Pentagon.
"On instructions from the Security
Council, destroy Atlantis fast."
- What does fast mean?
- Battle stations five minutes.
With torpedoes?
Yes.
- He has Anya on there.
- I know, James. I'm sorry.
- I have to get her off.
- How?
The equipment Q sent for me.
Can I have it?
Sure.
Barton. That package for
Commander Bond, bring it in quick.
- I need an hour.
- That comes from the top!
40 minutes.
You're gonna get me court-martialled.
OK. One hour.
Come in.
Here, I'll give you a hand.
Good evening, Mr Bond.
I've been expecting you.
Stay where you are.
I'll send the elevator down for you.
Goodbye, Mr Bond.
You did want me to drop in.
- Where's Anya?
- Well, well, well.
A British agent in love with
a Russian agent. Détente indeed.
Sit down, Mr Bond.
Your time's running out, Stromberg.
Yours too, Mr Bond. Yours too.
And faster than you think.
You've shot your bolt, Stromberg.
Now it's my turn.
How does that grab you?
We're five minutes overdue, Captain.
James! Stromberg?
Dead. So are we
unless we get out of here fast.
Match bearings and shoot.
Ah. Maybe I misjudged Stromberg.
Any man who drinks Dom Pérignon '52
can't be all bad.
- The mission is over, Commander.
- Mm?
In my country the condemned man
is usually allowed a final request.
Granted.
Let's get out of these wet things.
But, James,
- what would our superiors say?
- They're never going to know.
Lower the stern gate.
- ls there a danger of the bends?
- We'll soon find out.
James!
-007!
' Triple x:
Bond, what do you think you're doing?
Keeping the British end up, sir.
Nobody does it better
Makes me feel sad for the rest
Nobody does it half as good as you
Baby, you're the best
I wasn't Iookin'
But somehow you found me
I tried to hide from your love light
But like heaven above me
The spy who loved me
ls keepin' all my secrets safe tonight
And nobody does it better
Makes me feel sad for the rest
Nobody does it
Half as good as you
Baby, baby
Darlin', you're the best
Baby, you're the best