Stand up and cheer for Ridgeville
As we rout the foe
Strong and fearless
Jack, you'd better hurry
if you want hot wheat cakes.
Coming, honey.
Stand up and cheer for Ridgeville
As we rout the foe
Strong and fearless
Proud and peerless
Go! Go! Go!
Stand up and shout for Ridgeville
Hail the red and blue
We are here for
Here to cheer for
Ridgeville U
- One, two, up and do it.
- Jack, will you hurry, please?
Be right down in a minute, hon.
Keep those wheat cakes hot.
One, two, up and do it.
Jack.
Are you hurrying, dear?
Another 35 and I'll be right down, hon.
One, two...
Young Junior gonna have breakfast
with us, Miss Jackson?
I think so, May.
I hope he gets back
from the doctor's in time.
Not sick again?
Nothing serious.
Just his old trouble, his eyes.
And what with this rainy weather,
his sinus has been none too good.
Oh, May,
we'll have to get rid of those flowers.
You know, Junior's hay fever.
Seems to me
like that boy's getting worse.
Not at all.
Junior's just had his share of bad luck.
After all, he's only a baby.
He'll outgrow it.
I don't know.
I've been in this house for 15 years.
He's sure taking his time.
We're not discussing
Junior's physical condition.
- Now let's check on those wheat cakes.
- Yes, ma'am.
Jack, will you please hurry?
Everything's getting cold.
Coming, honey!
Watch out below.
Jack!
Now, got a big kiss for your husband?
Just as soon as I catch my breath.
Breath? That's not the girl I married.
Since when does the former
Olympic women's swimming champ
- get out of breath?
- As of now.
You know, I'm ashamed of you, Ann.
I think you're getting old.
You're not the girl I married.
The girl you married wants you
to sit down and eat your breakfast.
The girl I married
was the greatest swimmer
to ever win in the Olympics,
and that was the day that I proposed.
Oh, you never change.
The perennial college boy.
Now sit down, and let's forget sports.
They belong in the scrapbooks,
and we sure have our share of them,
all neatly bound.
So, as we grow older,
we can sit before the fire and read them
and quietly disintegrate together.
I hate to grow old.
Well, I must say,
you're doing it rather gracefully.
I've never seen you
looking more attractive.
Pretty good shape for a man of 41.
Still could get out on that football field
at Ridgeville U,
and make those youngsters
watch their step.
Oh, no. Not Ridgeville U and football.
They just haven't had a team
up there in years, Ann.
The kids today just don't play
"guts" football.
Jack, Ridgeville is a small university.
You can't expect them to beat
a university like Southern California.
When you and I went to school
and I played quarterback,
we beat Southern California.
Oh, sit down, dear,
and eat your breakfast.
What a team we had that year. Oh, boy!
Bronco Clayton.
There was a fullback for you.
And Dusty Henrickson, an end.
Dynamite!
How do you want your eggs, dear?
Big Butch Gorky.
There never was a halfback like him.
How do you want your eggs,
Mr. Jackson?
And Pudgy Durkin, lightning fast.
We had a team that year, Ann.
I tell you, there'll never be football
like that again.
How do you want your eggs?
And in all due modesty, I must say
we'd have never beaten USC
without "Jarring" Jack Jackson.
You know, they don't make you
All-American on pull.
Didn't get that name
"Jarring" Jack for nothing.
None of this fancy-pantsy dodging
like the kids are doing today.
You hunched yourself,
and you hit the line hard,
and you didn't go down
because somebody grabbed you.
- You carried them with you, right?
- Right.
How do you want your eggs?
USC thought they had us.
You remember, hon?
The score was six to nothing,
one minute to go,
twenty yards,
and they thought we'd pass!
Jack, I asked you a question.
Let me explain it to you, hon,
so you'll see it for yourself.
Here was the play. Here.
You play Stubby Cochran's position,
center.
I don't want to play
Stubby Cochran's position!
He was a great center, Ann.
Almost made All-American.
- Now stay down there. May?
- Yes, sir.
You play end for USC.
Excuse me, Mr. Jackson.
I can't play end for USC.
The wheat cakes will get cold.
Well, maybe you're right. Play guard.
Play right off-center. That's it.
Stay down there, hon.
All right, now watch it, May.
I'm coming around your end.
But, Mr. Jackson,
what about the wheat cakes?
Jack, this is ridiculous.
Stay down, hon.
We only got a minute to go.
All right, 44, shift, 33, shift,
22, shift, 21, hike!
Hi, folks...
- Are you hurt, Son?
- No, sir.
Get up, boy.
Put your hands up over your head.
Take a few deep breaths.
Come on. That's it.
- You'll be all right. You'll be...
- Jack, stop that.
Here, dear. Let me help you.
- Where are your glasses?
- I don't know, Mother.
They must be around here someplace.
Well...
Oh, dear.
Are you all right, dear?
Here, let me help you.
There.
I'll be all right.
I'll just sit here at the piano for a while.
Thanks, Dad.
Dad, what were you doing?
- Oh, nothing. I was just...
- Your father was reliving his youth.
Well, dear, you'd better go upstairs
and freshen up for breakfast.
- All right, Mother. I'll be down in a jiffy.
- All right.
Oh, Mother, Dad,
do you notice anything different
about me?
- No. You look the same to me, Son.
- No. What is it?
Well, the lower half of the brace is off,
and the other half comes off next week.
- That's wonderful, Junior!
- I think so.
And I also have good news
from Dr. Hunter.
What?
He says that the liver shots
are working out better than he expected,
and it'll only be a question of time. Bye.
Ann,
you know that I love Junior
as well as any father ever loved a son.
In fact, I've named him Junior after me.
But how could this have happened
to the two of us?
How could what have happened?
Let's face facts, Ann.
Look at you, look at me
and then look at Junior.
Is there nothing to this
doggone heredity business?
- But, Jack, he's only a baby.
- A baby?
- He's graduating from high school.
- Yes, but he's just a child.
A child?
Is that any excuse
for him to have hay fever
in both winter and summer,
to wear glasses
since he was six years old,
to have sinus trouble whether
it's raining or whether it isn't raining?
For heaven's sakes, Ann, what's he
going to be when he grows up?
It's frightening.
Jack, there's nothing wrong with Junior,
physically.
Dr. Hunter says it's psychosomatic.
Psychosomatic? What's that?
Well, his ailments are brought on
by mental and emotional disturbances.
Well, who's disturbing him?
- You are.
- Me?
Don't be ridiculous.
You know there isn't a better father
than I am.
I've given that boy everything.
When he was six years old,
I built him a gym out in the garage.
When he was 10 years old,
I gave him the finest
professional football equipment.
Oh, no, don't put the blame on me.
He's half yours.
Please, Jack, he'll hear you.
Well, I don't care if he... If he does.
Let's eat our breakfast.
May. May!
Junior! Hurry, your father's waiting.
I'll be right down, Mother.
I just have one more nostril to go.
Come on, Junior. Everything's ready.
I'm sorry I'm late, Dad.
I used your razor. Do you mind?
Razor? What for?
Well, I'll be shaving soon.
In fact, it's starting to come in
on my upper lip now. See?
Well, that's encouraging.
Just be careful you don't
cut yourself with it, that's all.
Oh, I'll be careful,
but if anything did happen...
I always have my Boy Scout first-aid kit
with me at all times.
I'm not an Eagle Scout for nothing,
you know.
Have some strawberries, Son.
Help yourself.
- I'll have to pass it up, Dad.
- Why? Build you up.
Well, I...
Jack, you know Junior's allergic
to strawberries.
- He breaks out in a rash.
- Oh, yeah, I forgot.
That's all right, Dad,
but I'm taking shots for it.
Great. Well, what's next?
May!
Jack, you don't have to bellow.
Boy, those look good.
Pass your plate, honey.
Thank you.
That's it, Son. Now I want you to eat
every one of those.
Put some syrup on there.
Now, dig in, boy. Make a man of you.
- Dad, I...
- Oh, you want butter. Sure.
That-a-boy.
- Dad, I can't eat these.
- Why not, boy?
Jack, you just go on and eat
and let Junior alone.
What's the matter?
Why can't you eat it, Son?
Well, Dad, I have too much
sugar content in my system now,
which Dr. Hunter says could ultimately
lead to diabetes when I get older,
and I'm taking shots for it.
Shots!
Good night!
Say, these wheat cakes are pretty good.
By the way, where are the eggs?
May!
You want them
with the ham and the bacon?
Leave off the bacon, May.
I wanna lose some weight.
- Just the ham and eggs.
- Yes, sir.
What's the matter with you, boy?
I'm waiting for my egg, sir.
An egg!
What kind of a breakfast
do you call that, anyway?
You're graduating from high school.
You have to go on to college
and play football like any other boy.
How do you expect to do that
on one egg?
That's my diet, sir.
Jack, leave the boy alone.
You're only making him nervous.
He's making me nervous!
I can't eat a thing!
Now what are you doing?
I'm preparing to take my pill, Dad,
which will allow me to eat the egg.
You want me to gain weight, don't you?
Why don't you just swallow it down
with water?
I can't take a pill that way, sir. I gag.
Gag?
Look,
you just take the pill,
you put it on the back of your tongue,
flush it down with water and it's all over.
I've tried that, sir, but I gag.
That's ridiculous. You're not going
to grow up to be a sissy!
Jack, please.
Will you stay out of this, Ann?
After all, I'm not a villain.
I have a perfect right
to show my own son how to take a pill.
Now, Son, just relax,
and leave everything to me.
Have you got another pill there?
Give it to me.
Now you take your glass of water
in your right hand.
Come on. Take your pill in your left.
Stick out your tongue.
Way out.
Now put the pill
on the back of your tongue.
Way back. That's it. Now,
flush it down with water.
Oh, for heaven's sake.
Here. I'll help you. Give me another pill.
All right, now open up.
Flush it down.
Now you got it?
Good. Now, you see, Son,
it just takes a little guts
and a little doing.
Simple case of mind over matter, right?
Now, Junior,
I'm going upstairs to dress,
but before I go to work,
I want to have a little talk with you.
See you in the den.
My favorite room.
Nothing like the old den
for a heart-to-heart talk.
I'm more proud of you
every time I come in here, Dad.
I wanna be proud of you, Son.
That's why I wanna have this little talk.
Now just sit down and relax. Have one?
- Oh, no, thank you, sir.
- Go ahead. You're old enough.
Yes, sir.
I guess you're not ready yet.
And don't call me "sir."
It sounds like I'm training you
to be an English butler.
This is just man talk, you and me.
So relax, Son.
Now,
what are your plans for college?
Oh, well, Dad, I thought that I'd...
You'd like to go to Ridgeville.
That's natural.
Your grandfather went there,
built the stadium.
Your mother went there,
and I went there.
I was a nine-letter man myself.
So, naturally, you'll be there.
Yes, the name Ridgeville and Jackson
are one and the same thing.
- I know, Dad, but I thought I'd like to...
- You'd like to try for the team?
You're a lucky boy, Junior.
I can help you there.
As it happens, Coach Wheeler
is a very dear friend of mine.
Matter of fact,
I gave him a new gym last year,
so I guess we won't
have any trouble there.
But, Dad, I thought,
well, I'd like to join...
Join a fraternity. Naturally, you'll be
an ALK man, just like your dad.
I guess we won't have any trouble there.
I gave the boys a new house last year.
- But, Dad...
- Yes, you'll have four grand years
at Ridgeville, Junior,
before you come out to the plant
and take over in my place.
You've got a good life, Junior.
Why, I wish I were your age,
just starting out,
everything to look forward to.
Oh, to be young again.
You're a lucky boy, Junior.
- Dad, could I say something?
- Certainly, Son.
Well, sir, I don't want you to think
that I'm disrespectful,
or that I don't appreciate everything
you're trying to do for me.
Well, I have an idea.
- You have an idea?
- Yes, sir.
I want to go to college,
but I don't want to go to Ridgeville.
Not go to Ridgeville?
Well, there's nothing wrong
with Ridgeville, sir. It's just that
I became interested
in animal husbandry,
and there's
a very wonderful school upstate.
Northern California Aggie. It's a farm
college, and they're very progressive.
Northern California Aggie?
A farm college?
Yes, sir. It's an experimental school,
and they're doing wonders with animals.
For instance, the Dean of Men
crossed a pig with a hybrid,
- and it's very interesting what came out.
- What?
A very short pig.
But the experiments
aren't finished yet, Dad.
And I thought I might even become a vet
and work with animals,
'cause they're very different
than human beings.
They can't tell you when they're in pain.
They have no way of communicating
with you.
Therefore, one has to have
more feelings for them
than the ordinary doctor.
Am I making you understand, Dad?
You're making me ill.
Are you standing there telling me
that a son of mine,
a Jackson, wants to go
to some jerk agricultural college
and study to be a horse doctor?
You two boys ought to be ashamed
of yourselves,
in here chatting
when there's so much to do.
Jack, the car is waiting,
and Junior, it's your graduation day.
Now, come along, Jack.
- Jack.
- Yeah, what is it?
Remember, be home early.
Junior's graduating tonight,
and the ceremonies start at 7:30.
Don't worry, I'll be there with bells on.
Cowbells.
"Jarring" Jack Jackson's son,
a horse doctor.
Mother, what's wrong with Dad and me?
We don't get along.
Oh, you're just imagining things.
Every boy has certain disagreements
with his father. That's natural.
All the time? Is that natural?
But, Junior, your father's heart is set
on your going to Ridgeville.
I know, Mother,
but I can't follow in Dad's footsteps.
His shoes are too big,
and I feel uncomfortable in them.
- You understand.
- Yes, I understand.
Sometimes I think your father is the boy
and you're the man.
Now come along.
Everybody look this way!
Smile!
Attention!
Now, that was very good.
Quiet, everybody.
I would now like to get a picture
of the most popular boy,
president of the student body,
Washington High School
and the greatest athlete
who ever graduated,
Bill Baker.
All right, Bill. Steady.
Mr. Jackson, that's my son, Bill.
That strapping, good-looking,
healthy specimen belongs to you?
Wait a moment, sir.
I want you to have a picture taken
with Babs Hunter,
the most beautiful girl
in our graduating class.
Babs, will you come up?
Babs looks wonderful, Doc.
You must be very proud of her.
She's quite a girl. Quite a girl.
Junior Jackson,
will you come here a minute?
No, not in the picture.
I want you to hold the flashlight.
Now!
Thank you.
Hiya, Dad. How do you feel?
Fine, my boy. Fine.
Mr. Jackson,
I want you to meet my son, Bill.
- Glad to meet you, young man.
- Nice to know you, sir.
You've got quite a boy there, Henry.
He's got quite a handshake.
Quite a boy. Quite a boy.
Mr. Jackson,
I know this isn't the time or the place,
but I was wondering if you could see Bill
tomorrow, on a little personal matter.
Of course. I'd be glad to.
I'll see the two of you
at the plant tomorrow morning.
Good luck to you, my boy.
I wish you were.
That heredity business is all cockeyed.
Little Henry Baker.
Oh, come on, Jack.
Let's have some punch.
- Hello, Mother. Hello, Dad.
- Hello, Son.
- My, you look nice, Son.
- Thank you.
- Doesn't he, Jack?
- Sure does.
- Oh, take it easy, Dad.
- I forgot. I'm sorry.
Anyway, congratulations, Son.
Thank you, Dad.
And thank you for the watch.
See, Mother?
"To Junior. Love, Dad."
Oh, Jack, that's sweet.
- Congratulations, Junior.
- Oh, thank you, Dr. Hunter.
I say, sir, would it be all right with you
if I took Babs home tonight?
- Why, certainly, Junior, certainly.
- Thank you.
Dad, may I have the car?
You see, I'd like...
Of course, Son. You and Babs
have a good time. Here are the keys.
Don't stay out too late.
Cuts down on your wind.
I'll be home early, Dad.
- You sure you don't mind, sir?
- Why, not at all, Junior.
- Where is Babs?
- I don't know, sir, but I'll find her.
Little Henry Baker.
Take it easy, girls.
I'll get writer's cramp.
Well, Bill, you haven't signed mine yet.
And you promised to sign mine, too.
Don't forget I have the second dance
with you.
- And I have the third.
- And I have the fourth.
Bill.
- Thanks.
- Thanks, Bill.
You're welcome.
Could I have your autograph, too?
Babs, you can have anything you want.
You sure look pretty tonight.
Thanks. You look pretty good yourself.
- Want to dance?
- I'd love to.
- May I have this dance, Mrs. Johnson?
- Why, I'd love to, Junior.
Here's a new dance
we ought to show them how to do
Gives us a chance to really show them
Something new
Are you ready?
Ready and waiting, sir
Well, okay
First you put your two knees
Close up tight
Then you sway them to the left
And then you sway them to the right
Then?
Step around the floor
Kind of nice and light
Then you twist around and twist around
With all your might
Wow!
Stretch your loving arms
Straight out into space
Do the Eagle Rock with style and grace
Swing your foot way around
Then bring it back
Now that's what I call balling the jack
First you put your two knees
Close up tight
Then you sway them to the left
And then you sway them to the right
Then?
Step around the floor
Kind of nice and light
Then you twist around and twist around
With all your might
Wow!
Stretch your loving arms
Straight out into space
Do the Eagle Rock with style and grace
Swing your foot way around
Then bring it back
Now that's what I call balling the jack
- First
- Yes?
Your knees up tight
- Then sway them
- Done
To the left, to the right
Step around the floor
Kind of nice and light
Then twist
With all your might, boy
Your arms in space
You do the Eagle Rock
With style and grace
Swing your foot way around
Then bring it back
Now that's what we call balling the jack
- Knees
- Cuddle your knees, close up tight
- Hep, hep
- To the left
- Reverse
- To the right
Then you step around the floor
Kind of nice and light
Then twist, boy, with all your might
- Stretch
Out in space
Do the Eagle Rock with form and grace
Your foot way round
Bring it back
That's what we call balling the jack
Stretch your loving arms
With style and grace
Swing your foot way around
Bring it back
Boy, boy, boy, move along
That's what we call
Balling the jack
I can't understand it.
Henry Baker to have a son like that.
I hope Junior and Babs like each other.
She's such a sweet girl.
I think they'd be a nice couple.
Little man to have such a big son.
It just doesn't make sense.
Jack, what are you mumbling about?
Oh, nothing.
It's amazing.
Just doesn't seem fair.
I'm sorry we didn't get to dance
the last waltz together, Junior.
I guess we missed each other,
but I looked for you.
Well, anyways, you're taking me home,
and I'm with you.
You don't mind taking Bill home,
do you?
No, not at all.
Thanks, Junior.
This sure is a sweet car.
You're a lucky guy.
Put the radio on, will you, Junior?
Yeah, sure.
Drive slowly through the park,
huh, Junior?
I'm in the mood for love
Simply because you're near me
Funny, but when you're near me
I'm in the mood for love
Why stop to think of whether
This little dream might fade
We've put our hearts together
Now we are one
I'm not afraid
If there's a cloud above
If it should rain, we'll let it
But for tonight forget it
I'm in the mood for love
Boy, you sure are a lucky guy
to have a girlfriend like Babs.
Yep. Lucky guy.
- Yes?
- Coach Wheeler is here to see you, sir.
- Coach Wheeler! Yes, send him right in.
- Yes, sir.
"Jarring" Jack Jackson. Put it there!
Coach Wheeler, you old son of a gun.
Glad to see you.
- What's the beef?
- No beef. I've got good news.
Ridgeville's got a chance
for the Championship this year.
- On the level?
- Yep. Here's the layout.
There's a great athlete in this town,
Bill Baker.
Just graduated
from Washington High School.
His old man's a bookkeeper someplace.
Underpaid, hasn't got a cent,
works for some rich, miserable guy,
so this kid doesn't have the money
to go to college.
It's the old story, Jack.
Coach, I know this kid, Baker.
His father works for me.
He's my bookkeeper.
- Well, Jack, I didn't mean to...
- That's all right, Coach. Forget about it.
What do you want me to do?
Finance this kid through school.
All right. I'll do it on one condition.
When my son comes to Ridgeville,
you've got to see that
he makes the team and gets his letter.
But, Jack, be reasonable.
Your kid's never played football.
- Besides, he's too light.
- So what?
He could be another Sammy Baugh,
a great passer,
or Albie Booth, a great kicker.
- Well, it's possible, but...
- There's no buts to it, Coach.
I want my kid to earn his letter
at Ridgeville more than anything in life.
It's a package deal, Coach.
If you want to take Bill Baker,
you'll have to take my son. Yes or no?
I need this Baker boy
like I need my right arm,
and I need your son, Junior,
like I need a...
Okay, it's a deal.
- So long.
- So long, Coach.
My son's here.
- Could you see him now, Mr. Jackson?
- Yes, send him right in.
- Mr. Jackson.
- Hi, Bill.
Sit down.
- What's on your mind?
- Well, I was talking with my dad,
and he suggested I come on over here
and ask you for a job in your plant.
Well, aren't you planning
to go to college?
Well, I always wanted to,
but frankly, we don't have the money.
What would you do if someone
offered you a chance to go to Ridgeville,
all expenses paid?
- I'd faint.
- Well, don't faint,
because I'm going to make you
that offer.
But why?
Well, Bill,
you know my son, Junior?
I spent a few hours with him
last night, but I don't know him too well.
That's the point.
Well, I want you to know him better, Bill.
You see, he's a great kid,
but he didn't turn out
the way I wanted him to.
I wanted him to be more like you.
Well, maybe he's just a different type.
You're so right.
That's why I thought
that maybe if the two of you
were roommates at Ridgeville,
that you could sort of look after him.
Maybe you could inspire him
to be an athlete like yourself.
You know,
the strong looking after the weak?
What does he say about all this?
He doesn't know anything about it.
And he must never know.
Well, what do you say?
- Is it a deal?
- It's a deal, Mr. Jackson.
But, you know, with Junior,
it's not gonna be too easy.
I only hope I have enough time left
to play football.
You're getting closer to Ridgeville, Son.
Yes? Hello, dear.
Feeling fine, fine. Yes.
Delighted to have him
for dinner, certainly!
Good old Ben Green, my old classmate.
Phi Beta Kappa, smart as a whip.
Yes, I'll be home early for dinner.
All right, dear. Bye.
Let me get this straight, Ben.
Aren't you a doctor?
I'm a psychiatrist.
- You mean, dealing with crazy people?
- Oh, no, Dad.
A psychiatrist is a man who helps
people adjust to their environment
and overcome inhibitions.
Very good, son.
That, in essence, is what we do.
You'd be surprised how many people
need help and don't know it.
- Well, I think it's all the bunk.
- Jack, please.
Now, that's all right.
Jack hasn't offended me.
A lot of people share his viewpoint.
They don't know they need help.
I was on a very interesting case
in Chicago about a month ago.
Typical case of a dominating father
trying to run his son's life.
Result, typical son.
Shy, introverted, psychosomatic
symptoms,
clash of personalities, tragedy.
What happened?
Well, in this case,
the father committed suicide.
He jumped out
of a second-story window.
That's very interesting, Dr. Green.
Do you know of any similar cases?
Well, there was another case
of a father and son...
Yes, well, I don't approve of this kind
of conversation in front of children.
Junior, why don't you go upstairs now
and get a good night's rest?
- Kiss your mother good night.
- But, Dad...
You heard what I said, Son.
Kiss your mother good night.
Shake hands with Dr. Green here,
and upstairs you go, right, Son?
- Good night, Mother.
- Good night, Son.
- Good night, Dad. Good night, sir.
- Good night, good night.
Would you know where I could get
any books on this subject, Dr. Green?
- Son!
- Oh, good night.
An only child?
Yes, he's our only child.
Very interesting.
Well, if you'll excuse me,
I have some things to do.
Jack,
I don't want to get too personal,
but I think you have a problem
with your son. Let me help you.
You know, a lot of people pay me
fancy prices for this. You can get it free.
Thanks, Ben.
There is a problem,
and there shouldn't be.
Because no one could be a better father
than I am to that boy.
Ben, he's going to step right into
a big business. It's all set up for him.
I had it all planned for him
to go to Ridgeville.
I had it all arranged for him to have
the best room in the fraternity house.
I even had it fixed for him
to get his letter.
- What do I get for it?
- He resents it.
How did you know?
Say, Ben, what is happening
with this younger generation?
They're ungrateful.
Jack, you don't understand.
He's not the problem. You are.
Me?
Why, there isn't a better father
than I am, Ben.
- That boy's had the best.
- Well, let's not get into all that.
You've done nothing for that boy.
You've done it all for yourself.
- You're selfish, Jack.
- Selfish?
- I only want my son to be a leader.
- Maybe he's not a leader.
Well, he's got to be.
Jack, you're trying to run your son's life,
and it won't work.
He's not like you.
And if you keep it up, you're going
to run into a much worse problem
than whether or not
he wants to go to Ridgeville.
It can become much worse.
Well, what'll I do, Ben?
Why don't you go up and visit with Ann,
let me talk to Junior a few minutes?
Maybe I can help.
Junior, will you come down here
a minute?
I'm getting ready for bed.
Well, forget about it,
and come on down here.
- Son.
- All right, Dad.
Now, remember,
I want that boy to go to Ridgeville.
Dr. Green here would like to have
a little talk with you.
- You wanted to see me, sir?
- Yes, Junior.
- Just like to have a little chat with you.
- Well, is it all right with...
Oh, yes, yes. Let's go on in the den,
where we can be more comfortable.
If you don't mind, sir,
could we talk someplace else?
- You see...
- You don't have to explain. I understand.
Would the patio be better?
- I think so.
- Fine.
- You don't like the den, Junior. Why?
- Oh, it's a nice room.
It's my father's favorite.
But it's his room. You understand.
Very interesting. Of course.
Anyway, it's a nice night,
so let's just make ourselves comfortable
and have a pleasant chat.
Junior, I'd like to ask you
a few questions.
- You don't mind, do you?
- No, sir. I like talking to you, Dr. Green.
Good.
Well, now that you've graduated
from high school,
what would you like to do?
Well, will it be confidential?
Just between the two of us?
Confidential.
Well, sir, I'd like to go to Ridgeville,
and I'd like to play football,
but I never will.
- Why not?
- Because of my dad.
Don't get me wrong, sir.
I love him, and I respect him,
and I'd like to do everything he did,
but I never will,
because I couldn't do it as good.
I'm scared.
Well, how do you know
you couldn't do it as good?
No one is as good as my dad, sir.
Just ask him.
He does everything the best.
That's why I do everything the worst.
I got what you call complexes,
and I don't mean to be disrespectful,
sir, but I'm frustrated.
Have you ever told your dad
what you would like to do?
Oh, no, sir. You can't tell him anything.
He tells you.
Well, why don't you try
to meet your dad halfway?
Talk it out with him.
Try and show him your side of it.
You take the initiative.
You know, older people are more set
in their ways.
I think you owe it to your dad
and yourself
to try to become better acquainted
with him.
- I'll try, Dr. Green.
- Fine.
You can go to bed now, Junior,
if you like.
Thank you, sir.
- Good night, sir.
- Good night.
Ben,
what's wrong with him?
Nothing, Jack. He's a fine boy.
I think someday
you're going to be proud of him.
I would suggest, however,
that you try to see more of him alone,
get to know him better.
I'd like to, Ben, but it seems like
every time we're together, we fight.
I think the boy resents me.
It's unnatural.
On the contrary, Jack,
it's the most natural thing in the world
for children to resent their parents.
It's based on the fact
that from the time they're born,
parents represent authority,
interfere with their will.
So the average normal child
often resents his parents.
Some children wish
they had different parents.
Some children even hate their parents.
What about Junior? Think he hates me?
Hates you?
The only advice I can give is
never take your boy hunting.
- Who is it?
- It's me.
Just a minute, Dad.
Come in, Dad.
Son,
I think we ought to become
better acquainted, don't you?
I think so.
A father and a son ought to be,
well, close, more like buddies.
- Don't you think so?
- I think so.
Tomorrow's Sunday. Why don't we
spend the whole day together?
Just you and I, alone, you know, like...
Like pals.
- I'd like that, Dad.
- Good.
What would you like to do, Son?
Anything you'd like to do, Dad.
Well, no, no, it's your day.
Now, what would you like to do?
- Anything you'd like to do, Dad.
- Now, I'm asking you...
What would you like to do, Son?
Well, I have a splendid idea, Dad,
something I think we'll both enjoy.
Well, what is it?
Would you take me hunting?
If that's what you really want to do, Son.
- Careful with that gun. It may be loaded.
- No, it isn't, Dad. See.
Oh, will you be careful with that thing?
You know it's loaded!
- I know it, Dad.
- You know, an accident can happen.
Wouldn't it be a terrible thing
if you shot your own father?
Yeah.
What are you grinning about?
I'm so happy.
I'm having such a good time, Dad.
I think we'll find some game over there.
Now, Son,
why don't you go in front of me?
I want you to have the first shot.
No, Dad. You go in front of me.
No, Son. Now, you go in front of me.
I'll cover your rear.
No, Dad. I'll be in back of you. You first.
- It's a fine specimen, isn't it, Dad?
- Certainly is, Son.
Let's have a little nip to celebrate.
- Join me, Son?
- Oh, I've never had a drink, Dad.
You're a man now.
Anybody who can shoot like that,
can have a little nip.
I'd rather that you have it with me.
You've my permission.
Son, here's to you and Ridgeville.
He's a jolly good fellow
That nobody can deny
- Well.
- Good evening, madam.
Good evening, Mother.
What is this all about?
Just a little evening
between father and son.
- Perfectly normal.
- Perfectly normal!
- You've both been drinking!
- Drinking? That's ridiculous.
Just a little celebration
of Junior's deciding to go to Ridgeville.
Right, Son?
Right, Dad.
May! May!
Hi.
- This is Room 24, isn't it?
- Yeah.
What are you trying to do,
grow up to be a rabbit?
No, these are my Dr. Denton pajamas,
in case I get a chill.
Well, I guess you and I
are gonna be roommates.
Why?
I don't know why.
They just assigned me to Room 24.
What's the matter?
Did you expect to bunk alone?
No, no. I was just wondering why
the two of us are roommates, that's all.
Just wondering.
I don't know why.
They just put us together, I guess.
Okay?
Yeah. Okay.
Mind if I have a drawer?
Oh, no, no. I didn't know.
I'll get them out.
Would you like the top drawer
or the bottom drawer?
Makes no difference to me.
- Will one drawer be enough?
- One is plenty.
- More shirts?
- Oh, no, these are my medications.
Oh, you're planning
to become a doctor?
Oh, no.
You see, I haven't been too well.
Do you want the upper shelf or
the lower shelf of the medicine chest?
Either one. I haven't got too much.
- The lower one is easier to get to.
- Makes no difference.
Makes no difference to me.
If you ever have sinus,
this stuff'll clear it up in a minute.
Just two drops in each nostril,
and you'll breathe again.
Of course, a little will trickle
down your throat.
But I have a pill for that
which clears it up.
I wouldn't have any use for that.
I'm pretty healthy.
Oh, that's nice.
Do you want to sleep
in the upper or the lower?
- Makes no difference.
- Makes no difference to me.
You gonna make up your mind,
or are you gonna drive me nuts?
You don't have to get huffy.
I'll take the lower.
Fine.
I think I'd better take the upper.
Why?
It's drafty here in the lower.
My sinus, remember?
Okay.
I better go back to the lower.
Why?
I'm getting a nosebleed up here.
It's too high.
Okay. Anyway you want.
- Good night, Bill.
- Good night, Junior.
Aren't you gonna open a window?
Why, are you warm?
You got to sleep with the window open.
You want to be healthy, don't you?
I do? I mean, I do!
I'll get it.
I said open it.
Bill?
- What are you doing?
- Nothing.
- You closing the window?
- No. Don't you believe me?
I believe you, but open it.
Gee, I hope we'll become friends
and like rooming together.
You know, roommates and pals?
Bill, are you asleep?
Coach, that Baker kid's great.
Look at that punt, 70 yards.
Yeah, he's all right.
We've got a good chance, boys.
I've never seen a better football player
since "Jarring" Jack Jackson played
for Ridgeville.
We got a break when they changed
the freshman ruling.
All right, you guys, over on the dummy.
Come on, move! On the double!
- Coach Wheeler?
- Yes?
I'm ready to report, sir.
Who are you gonna report and for what?
- Me. I'm ready to play football.
- Look, I'll save you a broken neck.
The ping-pong team
needs an anchorman.
- But, sir...
- Look, you're too light for football.
- Sorry!
- Yeah, but you wrote me a letter,
and it said, "Junior Jackson to report."
- What did you say your name was?
- Junior Jackson.
Yes, Junior Jackson.
I didn't recognize you.
- Must you wear glasses?
- No, sir. Only when I wanna see.
Well, okay.
Get in with the rest of the boys.
- We're hitting the dummy.
- Yes, sir!
Nice one.
- Junior! You hurt?
- No, I'm all right. I must've stumbled.
- Here, let me help you up.
- I don't need any help. I'm all right!
Kid's like his old man. He's got guts.
But as far as being a football player,
there the resemblance ends.
Grass drill, running in place.
Ready? Begin!
Bring those knees up!
On your stomach! On your back!
On your stomach! On your feet!
On your right side, left side,
on your feet!
On your back, right side.
On your feet!
All right, bring those knees up! Move it!
All right,
all the backs on the chinning bar.
Linemen around the goalpost
and into the shower.
- You need any help?
- No, I can make it.
When? The football season will be over.
- Bill?
- Yeah?
- Is this good for me?
- Of course.
How come I'm getting nauseous?
Up on the table, son.
- I'll take these.
- I can't see without them.
You'll be better off.
It's all in the neck, son. All in the neck.
Got to straighten out that spine.
Now just relax, boy. Just relax.
Better?
Yeah, but what happened to the head?
Junior?
- Junior?
- I'm in here.
- What are you doing?
- Nothing. I'm just sitting here.
- Why?
- Why? Where can I go?
The whole body's broken.
So I'm just sitting here,
but I ain't got nerve enough
to put my head under the water.
- Where does it hurt?
Where doesn't it hurt? It's easier.
I know just the thing for you.
I'll go down to the drugstore,
get something
that'll fix you up in a minute.
- What is it?
- What you need is a good rubdown.
- I'll go get some alcohol.
- Oh, no.
Come in.
You're Bill Baker, first year at school,
wear shirt size 15-and-a-half,
40-regular in jacket.
Hate ties, like soft white shirts
and haven't much money.
What are you,
a walking department store?
No. Let me introduce myself. My card.
"Terry Howard, college representative
of nationally known brands.
"Buy at your convenience.
Don't come see me. I'll see you.
"Save half
by seeing Terry Howard first."
What are you selling?
I have here some of the finest cashmere
you've ever seen.
Just feel that material.
Crush it in your hands.
Once a girl gets a load of the cashmere
in a jacket like that,
she'll never let you alone.
Let me show you my whole line
of sports clothes.
Well, I have to go down...
You haven't seen the new argyles
that just came in.
Socks to match your eyes.
Every color, every description.
And the luscious maroon sweater I have
to go with those dark, wavy locks...
- A saleswoman with sex appeal, huh?
- Strictly business.
This is the way I work my way
through college.
Now what can I give you?
I don't think you have it
in that sample case.
Just a minute.
Let's stick to business, huh?
I know when I'm outmatched.
I can't afford any new clothes.
I'll see you around.
Bill? Bill?
"Junior Jackson.
Size-nine shoe, 10-and-a-half sock
"and 13-and-a-half shirt."
I'm dying. I'm dying.
- Are you Junior Jackson?
- Yeah.
- Are you decent?
- I've always tried to live a clean life.
- No, I mean, are you in the bathtub?
- Yeah, I'm taking a bubble bath.
I'm Terry Howard,
college representative
of some of the finest manufacturers
in the country.
For new customers,
we have an introductory offer.
These nylon swimming trunks,
absolutely no cost on your part.
Here, put them on.
Although I haven't seen you,
I know you're the type
that would like a dark cashmere suit,
very suitable for eveningwear
in place of a tuxedo.
- Can I come in?
- Yeah.
Gee, a girl saleslady.
What kind of college is this, Vassar?
A milk bath.
We have a much better product,
Pink Tonic.
It's cheaper,
and it makes the bubbles last longer.
Please, miss, if you don't mind...
Let me show you
these wonderful cashmere jackets.
As you can see,
this one has a belt in the back,
and it's very sporty.
And this dark blue
is very suitable for eveningwear
in place of a tuxedo.
Yes, of course,
this one is English-made.
You have the shoulders for it, I notice.
Please, lady, forget the clothes.
I just want to get my body back.
There's no obligation on your part,
so let me finish.
Of course, it's hard to tell
what you would wear.
- I haven't much to go on, you know.
- Look, miss...
You can call me Terry.
You're Junior Jackson.
How do you know?
I have a line on every new student
who comes here to school.
- Do you do this for a gag?
- Not at all.
You see, it's the only way
I can get my education.
Some girls are waitresses.
I'm a salesgirl. I prefer it.
Anyway, it helps me
in my psychology training.
- You see, I'm a psychology major.
- Gee, I wish I had your spirit.
I'm glad to meet a girl like you. Oh.
Oh, just happen to have
the thing for you.
This striped robe,
marked down from $45 to $22.
Well, it just so happens I need a robe,
but you'll have to leave the room.
Bill.
- See you at the house, Bill.
- Hi.
All right. Hi.
How come
I haven't seen you around lately?
Football season.
What's the matter?
Don't you ever relax?
- Sometimes.
- Well, why don't you try it some night?
Say, tonight, for instance.
I'm not doing anything.
Now, look, Terry,
I know you're about as good-looking
as they come on this campus,
but I also know there are three things
that'd stop a guy from playing football.
That's being with a dame,
going with a dame and liking a dame.
So I'll see you around.
Nine tennis sneakers, size 10.
One dozen silk ties.
- Nine tennis sneakers...
- Three socks, size eight-and-a-half.
One dozen argyles,
size nine-and-a-half.
One dozen V-neck sweaters,
formerly $8, on sale for $9.
Formerly $8, on sale for $9?
The price of living's gone up all over.
Junior, you've been a great help to me.
I can't thank you enough.
- Terry, will you tell me something?
- What?
- How does someone become like you?
- Don't try. I'd rather be rich like you.
No, I mean, you have
so much confidence in yourself.
It's all a matter of ego, Junior.
That's what psychology teaches you.
- Ego?
- Sure.
You see, Junior,
you've got to believe in yourself.
You've got to keep saying
over and over to yourself,
"I'm big! I'm big!" Now say it.
I'm big.
No, no, no, Junior. Believe it.
Out, out. Throw your chest out.
- It's difficult for me. I'm skinny.
- Well, spiritually, then.
Put your shoulders back.
Walk up and down. Be cocky.
Say, "I'm big! I'm big! You hear me?
I'm big."
I'm big. I'm big. You hear me?
I'm big?
Well, it's a start in the right direction.
And that's what you've got to believe.
And I'll help you.
You'll sort of be my guinea pig
in my psychology experiments.
Guinea pig?
Come in.
- Who is it?
- It's me, Junior.
- Well, come on in!
- I can't. Help me!
Well, why can't...
What is this?
Christmas is months away.
What are you doing?
- I just had a date with Terry.
- You'd better stop seeing that dame.
We won't have any room to sleep here.
Oh, no, Bill. She's wonderful
and so good for my ego.
The least I could do
was buy some things.
Look at this dressing jacket I bought.
It can also be used for grouse hunting.
You know, it's reversible.
Of course,
you have to live in England for it.
But it's practical.
Of course. Where's the monocle?
Oh, she didn't have any in stock,
but she's ordering it. It's due next week.
Grand.
- Bill.
- What?
I'll tell you a secret.
- Go ahead.
- I think I'm stuck on Terry.
I'd have never guessed it.
Yeah, she's the first girl I ever had
that took a personal interest in me.
She certainly took a personal interest
in you, all right.
- Would you do me a favor?
- Well, it all depends.
Did you ever hear
of Cyrano de Bergerac?
Cyrano de Bergerac?
Didn't he play end for Cornell?
No. He was a character
in a very famous play,
and he had a big nose,
and he was very ugly,
and he sent his best friend
to talk for him to the girl he loved,
because he was very self-conscious
about his nose.
- So?
- So I'm in worse shape than Cyrano.
I'm self-conscious about all of me.
So I thought if you could go over
and see Terry
and tell her how I feel about her...
Why me?
Well, because you have an easy way
with the women,
and you're a big football hero.
Would you do that for me, Bill?
You just got to.
Why must I just got to?
Look at all this stuff.
I'm running out of money!
Come in.
- Hi, Bill.
- Hi.
What can I do for you?
You need some shirts?
- Always selling, aren't you?
- Well, a gal's got to live.
Oh, you sure are living.
I just brought over a check
for the stuff you sold Junior.
When you gonna stop
selling him clothes?
Well, he needed clothes badly.
And I see you did all right
for yourself, too.
I always say a man
can't have too many clothes.
What do you always say?
I always say
I think the kid's stuck on you.
- You're kidding.
- Well, who else but a guy in love
would buy 15 pairs of shoes
in one week
and all of them tennis sneakers?
I'm interested in Junior
as a psychological study.
- He's sort of snooky, you know.
- Yeah, but he's a great guy.
You'd be lucky to get somebody
like him.
What do you mean?
Trouble with you dames is,
you have no vision.
Most of you go for a big, husky,
broad-shouldered,
good-looking, football-hero type.
So?
Some day, Junior's gonna be like that.
- Bill.
- Yes?
How long do you think it'll take him?
- Take him quite a while.
- To be like you?
- Yes.
- Well, why should I wait, then?
"Dear folks, it seems hard to realize
"that a month has gone by
since I left home.
"I like Ridgeville pretty much.
"I'm rooming with a swell fellow,
Bill Baker,
"who was in our graduating class.
- "He's been very nice to me. I..."
- He ought to be.
- What did you say, dear?
- Nothing. Go on.
"I also like a girl named Terry Howard.
"She's very unusual
and has a forceful personality.
"I think Dad will like her."
I thought he liked Doc Hunter's girl,
Babs.
Well, kids that age are fickle.
Besides, she's here,
and he's at college.
Let's forget about his love life.
Go on with the more important things.
"Tell Dad that much to my surprise
I'm still on the football squad.
"I can't understand it,
"because try as I might,
I'm not improving fast enough.
"The coach doesn't like me
or dislike me.
"He just seems nervous
when I'm around.
"But I hardly think
he'll let me in the first game,
"so there's no reason
for you and Dad to come up.
"I'm sorry. I'm doing the best I can.
"Love, Junior."
I miss the boy.
You'll get a chance
to see him this weekend
when we go up for the game.
Oh, but it says he doesn't think
he'll get in the game.
Yeah?
Well, "Jarring" Jack Jackson's son
will be in that first game,
I can promise you that!
May! Oh, May!
R-I, D-G,
E-V,
l-L,
L-E,
Ridgeville! Ridgeville!
Go, Ridgeville!
All right, men. Attention!
I want you to meet Ridgeville's
most distinguished alumnus.
He's gonna say a few words to you.
This is the famous
"Jarring" Jack Jackson!
Men, I'm going to be short
and to the point.
I just had three rules
when I played football.
You hit them fast, you hit them low,
you hit them hard.
And if they get up, you hit them again.
So let's get out on that field
and play "guts" football.
Remember,
you're playing for Ridgeville.
So, good luck to you all,
and let them have it!
Come on, let's go!
Wait a minute, Junior.
I want to talk to you.
- But, Dad, I better get out there.
- This'll only take a minute.
Junior, you can make this
the happiest day in my life
if you'll just get out there
and really play football.
I don't even know
if I'll get in the game, Dad.
Don't worry.
I have a feeling that you will.
- Well, I hope so. I better get out there.
- Wait a minute, Junior.
You know, you're not gonna
just run out on the field
like the rest of the players.
- You're gonna make an entrance.
- What do you mean, sir?
Well, you see this old number 66?
That's your dad's old jersey.
When I quit playing football
20 years ago,
they retired that number,
and nobody has worn it until now.
You're gonna put this on
and really make an entrance
in this jersey, Son.
Those people out on the field are gonna
see another Jackson coming out,
wearing old number 66
to play for good old Ridgeville.
- How do you feel, Son?
- Isn't it a little large, Dad?
Well, tuck it in.
And remember,
live up to old number 66.
Old "Jarring" Jack Jackson's number.
Now, go to it, boy!
Good afternoon, sports fans.
This is Tom Harmon speaking to you
from the stadium
where today we'll bring you the game
between Ridgeville
and Thornton University.
The ballgame today, of course,
is the opening of the season,
and it promises to be
a whale of a football game.
The captains return to their teams.
And they're now getting
their final instructions from the coach.
There they go to line up for the kickoff.
Jones will kick off for Thornton.
Yes, that's right.
And back in the receiving position
for Ridgeville is Tom Edwards
and Bill Baker,
Ridgeville's All-American candidate.
Jones signals. The ball clubs get ready.
He approaches the ball,
it's a long end-over-end kick
going way down field.
It's going to Baker.
He takes it on the seven-yard line.
He's at the 10, the 20,
picks up some nice blocks.
He's at the 35.
Straight arms two tacklers.
He's going to go all the way!
He's on the two-yard line
and rolls into the end zone
for a touchdown!
It certainly seems apparent
that if this Baker boy
continues to spark the Ridgeville team,
as he has done today, all season,
the playoff for the Rose Bowl
will be between Ridgeville
and that great
University of California team.
Did you see that run, Jack?
You couldn't have done it better.
Very good. Very good.
When you gonna send Junior in?
The teams are lining up
for the extra point now.
Smith will hold and Baker will kick.
Get set. One, two, three!
There's the pass from center,
and it's good!
Ridgeville leads seven to nothing.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I always like to be pretty conservative
when I talk about football,
but I certainly would like
to make a prediction here.
This Ridgeville club certainly looks
like the greatest team
that they've had in 20 years. And why?
Simply because of one man, Bill Baker.
That boy's an All-American
if I've ever seen one.
All right, Coach, how about Junior?
- Okay, Jackson, get in.
- Me?
Wait a minute. There's a substitution.
They're taking Baker
out of the ballgame,
and I certainly don't blame them.
There's no sense in risking an injury
with that boy at this time.
The substitute for Bill Baker is number
sixty-six.
Number 66?
Let's try K-97 on two.
That's a pleasant play.
We might enjoy ourselves with that one,
unless you'd rather have K-97 on four.
That's a little more strenuous,
but we might get through with it.
No, we'd better do K-97 on two.
On two. Break!
They're out of the huddle now.
Fellas, I have a better idea.
I'm sorry. Will you come back?
They're back in the huddle again.
Take it easy, Coach. Take it easy.
The boy will come through.
You'll have to excuse us,
but this is private.
Jackson's apparently having
a little trouble with his signal.
My heavens, you're nosey.
Come on.
Delaying the game!
Ridgeville penalized five yards
for delaying the game.
It's now third down, 20 yards to go.
Ridgeville's ball
on Thornton's 47-yard line.
Take it easy, Coach.
The boy will come through.
Spread flanker left, spread flanker right.
B.G. Opposite, two lead swing,
thirty-six A.O. On four.
On four. Break!
Ridgeville comes out of the huddle.
They go into an unusual
spread formation.
- No blockers.
- One, two, three, four, five.
The ball is snapped. Jackson has it.
He's smothered back
on his own 45-yard line!
He fumbles.
There's a big pile-up down on the field.
I believe, yes, they did,
Thornton recovered the fumble.
Ladies and gentlemen,
so far in this ballgame,
young Jackson has not been
anything like his father, believe me.
But then, too,
Thornton's had their troubles.
They're now going to have to go
into punt formation and kick.
It's Phillips back in punt formation.
There's the snap from center.
Gets off a long spiral kick
that comes down the field.
Jackson waits for it on the 20-yard line.
And he's caught it.
There he goes!
He's at the 25, the 30,
the 35. He's at midfield.
A Thornton man has grabbed him
with a necktie tackle,
but Jackson is still on his feet.
Wait a minute! Wait a minute!
Jackson is running the wrong way!
He's at the Thornton 40, the 30,
the 10, the five.
Hit by his own man
on the five-yard line and fumbles,
and Thornton recovers for a touchdown!
Listen to that crowd boo.
Get in there and take that...
That kid's place!
Well, folks, they're taking
Junior Jackson out of the ballgame
and putting Bill Baker back in.
Believe me, ladies and gentlemen,
Junior Jackson
is nothing like his father.
He'll win ballgames, perhaps,
but I'm afraid for the other team.
This has been the worst day of my life.
- How could my own son do this to me?
- It's not all Junior's fault.
Ann,
you see before you
the mere shell of a man.
A man who's devoted his entire life
to his child,
and look what happens.
He makes a touchdown
for the other team.
- Is there no justice?
- Oh, don't be so dramatic.
It's only a football game.
Only a football game?
Out there
in front of all of my old classmates,
in front of 20,000 students,
the son of "Jarring" Jack Jackson
disgraces himself.
- Is there anything worse?
- Yes, he could've been a criminal.
That wouldn't have been so bad.
Then at least we could've
sent him away and no one would know.
Jack, I'm not going to stand here
and have you berate Junior.
- He probably feels bad enough.
- Ann,
are you sure he's our son?
- Stop it, Jack. He was born at home.
- Oh, yeah, that's right.
I haven't even got the satisfaction
of thinking
they might have switched him on us
in the hospital.
Junior Jackson!
What are you doing
in this empty stadium at night
without your coat on?
You'll catch your death of cold.
I'm sorry, Mother.
Junior, I'm worried about you.
Do you still want to play football?
I like it,
but I guess I'll never get a chance now.
The coach will drop me from the squad.
Gee, today, I disgraced everybody.
Son, listen to me.
You were at a disadvantage.
It isn't the easiest thing in the world
to be the son of a great athlete.
A prominent father
is the biggest drawback a boy can have.
Don't I know!
So from now on,
your father will not dominate you.
You'll be left alone
to make your own decisions.
I'll see to that.
You're going to stop playing football,
take up your regular studies,
and you're going to shower
and have dinner immediately.
But I don't want to...
From now on,
you have nothing to worry about.
You can make up your own mind.
You're a man.
Come along, Son.
Yes, ma'am.
Bill, Mr. Jackson wants to talk to you.
Be seeing you, Jack, and thanks.
Sit down, Bill.
Played a great game
this afternoon, boy.
- You reminded me a little of me.
- Thank you.
Of course you can't pass like me,
or run like me.
You don't hit the line like I used to,
but you reminded me a little of me.
- Well, there'll never be another you, sir.
- Thank you, son.
Bill, you remember the proposition
I made you?
Coach Wheeler is dropping Junior
from the squad,
but our deal is still on.
But, Mr. Jackson, you don't understand.
I like living with Junior.
- We're getting to be great friends.
- You don't have to pretend.
- But I'm not pretending.
- I understand, Bill.
You're loyal, and you're just trying
to make it easier for me.
Your father should be a very happy man.
I know that I would be.
And, Bill,
you'll still get my check every month.
You've lived up to your part
of the bargain.
That's very generous of you, sir, but...
Well, thank you.
- Coach?
- Yes, Bill?
I was just talking to Mr. Jackson.
You can't drop Junior.
Why not? Didn't he say it was okay?
Well, it might be okay with him,
but it's not okay with me.
You got to give him another chance.
- Now wait a minute.
- Either Junior plays, or I don't play.
- But you don't...
- That's the way I want it.
Now what do you say?
It's getting tougher to be a coach
every day.
Okay, but you'd better be good
next Saturday.
Because with your methods,
you got to have a lot of talent.
Don't worry, I got it.
Terry, I tell you I'm through
double-crossing Junior.
Now take it easy, Bill.
Don't tell me to take it easy.
You talked me out of it once before.
I'm through being a heel.
I'm gonna tell him.
But it's so bad for his ego.
Never mind his ego.
It's more honest this way.
Okay, but I'll handle it.
I want to break it to him gently.
I don't want to shatter his confidence
in himself.
- When are you gonna tell him?
- The next time I see him.
Good. It's the only fair thing to do.
Terry, can I come in a minute?
Where am I gonna hide?
I don't want him to find me here.
- Quick. In the closet.
- You be sure you tell him.
Leave everything to me.
I just came over to say goodbye.
I'm leaving school.
Leaving school? Why?
I ran out of reasons.
Today on the football field,
I disgraced my father and the team.
Now I'm being dominated by my mother
and she's almost as bad as my father.
I shouldn't have come to Ridgeville
in the first place.
Sit down, Junior. Let's talk this out.
There's nothing to talk about.
I'm a failure.
Don't get excited, Junior.
Something will turn up to give you
your confidence back.
No, I'm a failure.
The only reason Bill lived with me
is because he felt sorry for me,
and you tried to help
because you're a nice person.
Besides, I'm a good customer.
No, I'm leaving school.
But, Junior, if you leave school,
I'll feel very bad.
- You will?
- Yes.
I like you for yourself.
- You do?
- Well, sure.
And I think if you stick it out,
you'll be able to prove to your father
and to everybody that you're a man.
Well, I could do it, Terry, if...
- lf...
- Yes?
If I had a girl like you behind me.
I mean, if I thought that you thought
I was somebody.
Well, I do think you are.
You know, Terry, I've been stuck on you
since the first day you sold me the robe
when I was in the bubble-bath.
Well, I liked you, too, Junior,
but I've got to tell you about Bill and me.
Oh, no, we can talk about Bill
some other time.
If you wear my fraternity pin,
I won't leave school.
- Well, how will that help?
- Well, it'll give me a reason to stay.
It'll be a little victory,
and it'll restore my confidence.
That's what you said I needed.
Just wear it a little while
and see if you like it.
Well, okay, but on one condition,
that you won't leave school.
Oh, no, I won't. I'm a new man.
I'm a tiger. I'm big.
You're wearing my fraternity pin. I'm big!
Well, you certainly told him.
What did you expect me to do
with everybody browbeating him?
He needed someone to turn to,
and this was no time
to sell him more shirts.
- What about you and me?
- We'll have to wait.
I'll have to be Junior's girl,
until he builds up his confidence
in himself.
- But you love me.
- Of course.
- This is just for Junior.
- Okay. Just for Junior.
- I can't go on with this.
- Sure you can, Junior. It's all for you.
Yeah, Junior, it's all for you.
Come on, once more.
I told you to crouch. Crouch.
I told you a million times,
use your body, your knees.
- I can't go on with this.
- Sure you can, Junior. It's all for you.
Yeah, Junior, it's all for you.
Come on, we'll try it once more.
Set! One, two, three, four, five!
Now?
Not now.
Sit down! Sit down!
Kick the ball.
Set! One, two, three, four!
Good kick, Junior.
You're developing into a great kicker.
Yeah, and I'm getting
more confidence, too.
Maybe I'll get in the homecoming game.
Sure you will. Now don't you feel better?
Oh, sure, and I owe it all to you two,
my best friends.
- I'll always be grateful to you for this.
- That's okay.
It's all for you, Junior.
Now?
Not now.
Sit down! Sit down!
Stand up and cheer for Ridgeville
As we rout the foe
Strong and fearless
Proud and peerless
Go! Go! Go!
Rah! Rah! Rah!
Stand up and shout for Ridgeville
Hail the red and blue
We are here for
Here to cheer for
Ridgeville U
Rah! Rah! Rah!
Stand up and cheer for
Sing!
As we rout the foe
Come on! Sit down!
Proud and peerless
Go! Go! Go!
Rah! Rah! Rah!
Stand up and cheer for Ridgeville
Hail the red and blue
We are here for
Here to cheer for
Ridgeville U
Sit down!
Stand up and shout for Ridgeville
Hail the red and blue
We are here for
Here to cheer for
Ridgeville U
Coach! Coach!
We want Coach Wheeler!
We've come a long way
since the beginning of the season.
I want to thank the student body
for being with us all the way.
We've got to break up now,
because I want the boys
to get a good night's sleep.
Yeah, team! Yeah, team! Yeah!
Hey, Bill, the coach told me
I might get in the game tomorrow
for a few seconds.
- That's great.
- And I owe it all to you.
I'll never be able to tell you
how grateful I am.
Forget it. We're pals.
Well, that's why I want you to be
the first to know.
Know what?
After the game tomorrow,
I'm throwing a little party.
I'm gonna introduce Terry to my folks,
and if they like one another,
you never can tell, Bill,
you might be my best man.
- You mean...
- Yeah, aren't you happy about the idea?
Yeah, I think it's real great.
I'm only sorry I can't be with you,
but I have a party of my own to go to.
Hey, Bill.
- Who is it?
- It's me. Your boyfriend.
Bill, what are you doing here?
It's after hours.
Just come up to congratulate the bride.
Hope you and Junior...
What are you talking about?
You've been drinking,
and it's the night before the game!
So what? Besides, drunk or sober,
I know when I'm being double-crossed.
What's come over you?
You ought to know.
You planned it that way.
Me, Bill Baker, big All-American.
Big All-American sucker!
- I don't understand.
- You wouldn't understand.
First I let his old man
buy me through college,
then I let my own girlfriend
talk me into playing second fiddle.
All for Junior.
I thought we agreed it was for his ego.
And what about my ego?
Everything for Junior's ego.
I'm getting tired of it,
and I've come up to tell you I'm tired.
- Someone will hear you.
- Don't shush me.
I'm tired of playing games.
What's going on with you two?
I'm glad you asked
that question, madam.
It's what I come up to find out.
Well, ladies and gentlemen,
this had been one of Ridgeville's
saddest homecoming games.
Without Bill Baker,
they've put up a good fight
but Wilton is winning, seven to nothing.
With only five minutes left to play,
Ridgeville has called time out.
Son, I never should have let you room
with a boy like that.
I'd rather not talk about him.
One chance in a million
for a championship,
and that kid's got to get loaded.
Why did he do it?
Why did he pick last night?
Coach, you gonna let Junior in?
- Please, Dad!
- Oh, yeah.
Son, maybe some of living with Baker
rubbed off on you.
Loosen up.
Junior, I've got to talk to you about Bill.
Forget it, Terry.
I thought he was my friend.
He is your friend.
That's why he's in this trouble.
He wanted to tell you long ago
about your father's money,
and that we loved each other,
but I wouldn't let him.
Because we were trying
to build up your ego.
In building you up,
he thought I double-crossed him.
That's why he came to my room drunk
to tell me off
and got himself expelled.
- And it's all your fault!
- Well, what can I do to make it up?
There's only one thing to do.
Stop being self-centered
and dependent on other people.
Get out there
and stand on your own two legs.
You have reason
to have confidence now.
Bill helped you.
Now get out there and help Bill.
Okay, Terry. I'll try.
All right, Jackson,
there's two minutes left.
- Get in there.
- Coach, I'd like to ask you something.
Did Bill keep me on the squad?
- I'd like to ask you a favor.
- What is it?
Could I wear Bill's jersey?
- Red, got 32's jersey?
- Yeah. Here it is.
Okay, hurry it up.
Junior Jackson is wearing
Bill Baker's number 32.
Junior Jackson is going
into the ballgame for Ridgeville.
- K-24 on three.
- On three. Break.
Ridgeville's ball
on Wilton's 20-yard line.
Set. One, two, three!
The ball is snapped.
He starts to circle his left end.
No, wait a minute! He's running back
towards his own goal!
Junior is running the wrong way!
No, wait a minute!
He's reversing his field!
He picks up his blockers.
He's back to the 40, the 30,
the 20, the 10, the five.
Junior Jackson scores a touchdown
for Ridgeville!
What a beautiful tactical maneuver!
That's my boy! That's my Junior!
The score is now seven to six,
with Wilton leading.
Jackson covered almost 90 yards
on that touchdown run.
Now it'll be Ridgeville's turn
to try for this all-important extra point.
It'll be Ryan who will attempt
the extra point for Ridgeville.
But, Coach,
I could've made the extra point.
Son, you've been seeing
too many college movies,
where the hero goes in
at the last minute and wins the game.
That touchdown you made
was a miracle.
Thanks. Sit down.
There's a snap from center.
He puts the ball down. There's the kick!
It's no good. It's wide.
Wilton leads by a score of seven to six,
with but one minute left to play.
That missed kick
may have been the ballgame.
Ridgeville lining up for the kickoff now.
They'll kick off to Wilton.
There's the kick,
a long end-over-end kick
coming down the field.
Barton takes it in the end zone.
He's ready to run it out.
He's back to the five,
the 10, the 15, the 23.
He's hit at the 23 and goes down,
and he fumbles!
And I believe Ridgeville recovers.
Yes, they did. It'll be first down
and 10 yards to go for Ridgeville.
Five seconds left to play
in the ballgame.
Now we'll see whether or not Ridgeville
can capitalize on this break.
Ridgeville has called for a time-out.
Coach, I tell you, you gotta put Junior in.
He's a great kicker.
I've been practicing with him
day after day.
He's a Jackson.
I tell you he'll come through.
Junior, it's a tough spot.
You'll be kicking from the 29-yard line.
- Stiff wind blowing. What do you say?
- I'll do the best I can, Coach.
Okay. It's crazy, but go in.
And good luck.
Coach Wheeler
is making a substitution.
He's taking Ryan out
and putting young Jackson in.
Ridgeville is going to try a field goal
from an almost impossible angle.
Break.
I wonder what's going through
young Jackson's mind now.
You can do it, Junior. You're big now.
Do it for Bill.
Remember all the hours we practiced?
Take your time. You can do it.
There's the kick. It's up, up, up,
and it's over for a field goal!
The gun goes off, and Ridgeville wins
by a score of nine to seven!
That's my boy! That's my Junior!
What a hero Junior Jackson will be
in this town tonight.
Entire Ridgeville team
is swarming off the bench...
Go, Junior!
They've got Jackson on their shoulders
and are carrying him off the field.
Well, what a football game
that boy has played today.
Well, Terry,
all misunderstandings cleared away?
- You happy?
- Very happy.
- I am, too.
- Oh, there's Bill.
Let's go tell him the news.
Bill, we've got some news for you.
Congratulations,
but it's not news, anymore.
Oh, you don't understand.
Will you dance with Terry?
She wants it that way.
- Right, Terry?
- Well, I don't...
- Please, Bill.
- And I want it that way.
She's for you. Okay, pal?
Okay, pal.
- Junior.
- Hiya, Babs.
I've been looking all over for you.
You know, I can't tell you
how thrilled I was this afternoon.
Why, you're just the best football player
there ever was in the whole wide world.
- No, I guess I was just lucky.
- Lucky? Why, you just thrilled me.
You know, I've always liked you
ever since high school.
- Yeah? You did?
- Of course. Couldn't you tell?
Well, I...
Well, you'll be able to tell
from now on, sugar.
What have you got for your little Babs?
Close your eyes.
Pucker up your lips.
Bye.
Dad. See? I won my letter.
That's nice, Son,
but where are your glasses?
Oh, my glasses, well,
since I won the game this afternoon,
and I'm a hero,
I don't need them anymore.
Doc Hunter was right.
It was psychosomatic.
But, Dad,
aren't you pleased about the letter?
Son, you've taught me
there are more important things in life
than football.
Will you please autograph my program?
- Mine, too!
- Certainly, youngsters. Happy to do it.
Who's talking to you? We mean him.
Yeah, who does that old geezer
think he is?
That old geezer is my dad,
"Jarring" Jack Jackson,
the greatest football player
ever turned out at Ridgeville.
So what? We saw you this afternoon,
and for our money, you're the greatest.
I'm going out for football
next season, Junior.
Could you give me some advice?
Well, there were three things
when I played football.
You hit them low, you hit them fast,
you hit them hard.
And if they get up, you hit them again.
Yes, sir, you got to play "guts" football.
- Thanks, Junior.
- Yeah, thanks a lot, Junior.
Okay.
- I'm sorry, Dad.
- That's all right, Son.
That's my boy.