The Ring of the Fisherman,
which bears the official papal seal,
must be destroyed immediately
following the Pope's death.
The Papal apartment is then
sealed for nine days of mourning,
a period known as "Sede Vacante",
the time of the empty throne.
Over the last several days,
Catholic leaders
from every corner of the world
have flocked to Rome,
shocked by the sudden death of
this progressive and beloved pope.
Today, in St. Peter's Square,
the faithful pray that there is
among them another leader
who can unite their church,
which has been so riven by change
and dissent in recent years.
As the body of the pontif passes by,
we see prayers are being
offered by the Preferiti,
favorites among those being considered
to succeed him as the Vicar of Christ.
At the end of the mourning period,
the College of Cardinals
will lock itself
behind the doors of the
Sistine Chapel for Conclave.
The process by which they
will choose a new leader
for the world's one billion Catholics
who now find their
church at a crossroads,
its ancient traditions
threatened by a modern world.
Attention: Control booth going online.
We are powering up.
Attention Category 1 personnel.
Interlock areas are now restricted.
You've blocked all access, Philippe.
You are terrified because
you gave it your all.
The accelerator should
never create antimatter.
It's only three cylinders under high
security. I only ask you to wait.
We can't wait any longer.
Antimatter is only the beginning.
We will have free access.
But listen, even with proper
calibration, we might not be prepared.
Just call the director. Stop this.
ATLAS underground is
now a restricted vault.
Vittoria, Vittoria...
Protons are being loaded.
This will not blast us to
the other side, so, please.
Powering on LHC magnets.
Ionic stage in 4, 3, 2...
Start the collision sequence.
Vittoria, what did Phillipe want?
He about shitted. We should
still wait. What do you think?
It's now or never.
Beam stability is good.
Take your places, people.
ATLAS and CMS checked.
Trigger is set. Collision is imminent.
Let's hope the heavy
ion guys didn't mess up.
Luminosity monitors operational.
B-line has no restrictions.
Enable beam capture.
Accelerating the beam.
Stage 1: Line up.
Magnets to full field.
Last P still too high.
We are moving up the
luminosity 10 to 34.
Eject particle beams.
Filling the LHC.
Fusion commenced.
We are back online.
The merger may be any time.
Particles in transition.
Collisions are fixed and running.
LHC injecting protons: Beam 1.
Lock the feedback systems.
Particles at 99% the speed of light.
Colliding stable beams.
Enact injection kicker.
We have a signal on
the luminosity monitors.
We have events.
Protons are moving.
We have created antimatter.
The unknown has been created.
Silvano, we have succeeded.
We are now in God's hands, Vittoria.
I am on my way.
Silvano?
Silvano!
Oh, God.
Help! Aiuto! Aiuto!
- A swim might help your jet lag.
- I beg your pardon?
The bags under your eyes.
It's five in the morning
and you're from the Vatican.
Crossed keys under the Triregnum.
It's a papal symbol.
Claudio Vicenze.
Corpo della Gendarmeria Vaticano.
Vatican Police?
I was expecting another letter.
My request for access to your archives.
Shouldn't you be in Rome?
Kind of a busy time for you guys, huh?
In fact, I was in New York.
A detail to the UN. I received a
phone call in the middle of the night.
"Find Professor Robert Langdon.
A matter of great urgency."
They said to show you this.
The Illuminati? They disappeared
hundreds of years ago.
Did they?
Look at that again. It's an ambigram.
It's the same image,
forward and backward.
Now, that's common for a
symbol like a Yin and Yang
or a swastika but... that's a word.
That Illuminati ambigramatic symbol has
been considered a myth for 400 years.
Supposedly, in the 16th century,
some artist created it as a tribute
to Galileo's love of symmetry.
It was only gonna be revealed when the
Illuminati had amassed enough power
to resurface and carry
out their final goal.
I wrote a book about it.
Which is why you're here.
"The Art of the Illuminati"
by Robert Langdon.
Part One.
I haven't been able to finish Part Two
because I'm not allowed
access to your archives.
It's remarkable. Similar.
Someone is trying to make you believe the
Illuminati themselves have returned to Rome.
Right after the death of a pope.
Four cardinals were kidnapped from
their quarter's inside the Vatican
sometime between 3
and 5 am this morning.
Shortly afterward, that document was
sent to the office of the Swiss Guard
along with the threat
the Cardinals will be
publicly executed
one per hour begining
at 8 pm tonight in Rome.
The conclave?
Was to begin today.
We have postponed the
start for a few hours
with the story of illness.
There are no suspicions... yet.
What do you want from me?
These criminals, who sent this ambigram,
meant it as a taunt, a provocation.
But Captain Olivetti think if you
can use it to learn their identity,
perhaps we can stop this abomination.
Why me?
Your expertise. Your erudition.
Your recent involvement
with certain church...
shall we say... mysteries.
I wasn't under the impression that
episode had endeared me to the Vatican.
Oh, it didn't.
But it did make you,
what is the word for...
"formidable"?
Formidable?
A Vatican jet is standing
by twenty minutes from here.
Will you come with me?
Professor Langdon.
You've spent your life searching for symbols
like the one you now hold in your hand.
How much longer are we going to pretend
you have not already decided to come?
If the Illuminati have
returned and are in Rome,
we will hunt them down and kill them.
The Illuminati did not become
violent until the 17th century.
Their name means
'The Enlightened Ones'.
They were physicists,
mathematicians, astronomers.
They were concerned with the
church's inaccurate teachings
and they were dedicated
to scientific truth.
But the Vatican didn't like that.
So, the church began
to, how did you say it?
Oh. Hunt them down and kill them.
Drove them underground
into a secret society.
- Professor Langdon.
- Yes?
Welcome to Vatican City.
Ernesto Olivetti, Inspector
General of the Vatican Police Force.
My pleasure.
This way please.
We'll meet in the headquarters
of the Swiss Guard.
- I thought you were Swiss Guard.
- No, uh, the Gendarmaria.
We are responsible for everything
inside the Vatican walls
with the exception of the
security of His Holiness...
- Yeah.
- ... and the Apostolic Palace.
That is Swiss Guard.
i}The Roman Carabinieri are here as
well in an advisory capacity.
So jurisdictionally this is...
A goddamn nightmare.
- Oh, yes. Pope Pius IX's great castration.
- I beg your pardon?
1857. Pope Pius IX felt the
male form would inspire lust.
So, he took a hammer and chisel and
'un-manned' hundreds of these statues.
The plaster fig leaves were added later.
Are you anti-Catholic,
Professor Langdon?
No. I'm anti-vandalism.
I urge you to guard your tone here.
The Swiss Guard is a
calling, not a profession,
and it encourages a certain civiltry.
Commander Richter, the head of the
Guard, is a deeply spiritual man.
He was close to the
late Pope. Understood?
Look, I dont study symbols because
I consider them unimportant.
Ceremony, traditions,
heavily mark our lives.
I just hope I can help.
- So do I.
You were my idea.
Wait here. Please.
Commander? Commander Richter?
Doctor Vetra?
I'm Commander Richter, principal of
the Swiss Guard. Thank you for coming.
Oh. Professor Langdon.
What a relief.
The symbologist is here.
This way, please, Miss Vetra.
The situation has changed.
We received another
threat from the kidnapper.
The canister was stolen from
my lab around noon yesterday.
The intruder killed my research
partner, Silvano Paintivolio
and mutilated him in
order to bypass security.
We use retinal scanners.
They cut out his eye.
Is that your stolen canister, Ms. Vetra?
- Where is that camera, number 86?
- It's wireless.
It, too, was stolen. It could be
anywhere inside the Vatican walls.
That canister contains an extremely
combustible substance called antimatter.
We need to locate it immediately.
We evacuate Vatican City.
I'm quite familiar with
incendiaries, Miss Vetra.
I've never heard of
antimatter being used as such.
Well, its never been generated
in significant quantities before.
It's a way of studying the
origins of the universe.
To try to isolate what some
people call "the God Particle".
But there are implications
for energy, research-
"God Particle"?
What you call it isn't important.
It's what gives all matter mass.
The thing without which we could not exist.
You're talking about the moment of creation.
- Yes, in a way, I am.
The antimatter is suspended there...
in an airtight nano-composite shell
with electromagnets on each end.
But if it were to
fall out of suspension,
and come into contact with matter,
say with the bottom of the canister,
then, the two opposing forces would
annihilate one another violently.
What might cause it to
fall out of suspension?
The battery going dead.
Which it will just before midnight.
What kind of annihilation? How violent?
A cataclysmic event.
A blinding explosion
equivalent to about 5 kilotons.
Vatican City will be consumed by light.
Those are the exact
words the kidnapper used.
We will destroy your four pillars.
We will brand your Preferiti and
sacrifice them on the altars of science.
Then bring your church down upon you.
Vatican City will be consumed by light.
A shining star at the end
of the Path of Illumination.
It's the ancient Illuminati threat.
Destruction of Vatican City through light.
Four pillars. There's
your kidnapped cardinals.
You didn't tell me they were the Preferiti,
the favorites to be named the next Pope.
Play it again.
We will destroy your four pillars.
We will brand your Preferiti...
Wait, stop it. Stop.
Brand them?
That's another Illuminati legend.
This one says that there
are a set of five 'Brands'.
Each one an ambigram.
The first four are the
fundamental elements of science:
earth, air, fire and water.
Th fifth is a mystery.
Maybe it's this.
You said they'd be killed publicly.
Yes. Revenge. For La Purga.
La Purga?
Geez, you guys don't even
read your own history, do you?
1668. The church kidnapped
four Illuminati scientists
and branded each one of them on the
chest with the symbol of the cross.
To 'purge' them of their
sins and they executed them,
threw their bodies out in the street
as a warning to others
to stop questioning
church rulings on scientific
matters. They radicalized them.
The Purga created a darker,
more violent Illuminati.
One bent on... on retribution.
And look how they intend to
finally get it. Using anti-matter.
Technology to destroy the church.
Science obliterates religion.
Is there any more?
...and sacrifice them
on the altars of science.
Then bring your church down upon you.
Vatican City will be consumed by light.
A shining star at the end
of the Path of Illumination.
Path of Illumination?
I need access to the Vatican archives.
Professor, I don't think this
is the appropriate moment-
Your petition has been
denied seven times.
No, no. This has-
This has nothing to do with my work.
The Path of Illumination
is a hidden trail through Rome itself
that leads to the
Church of the Illumination.
The place where the Illuminati
would meet in secret.
If I can find the "Segno", the sign,
that marks the beginning of that path,
the four churches along it.
It may be where he intends
to murder your Cardinals.
One every hour. At 8, 9, 10 and 11.
Then the device explodes at midnight.
If we could figure out the first
church and get there before he does,
maybe we could stop it.
But I can't find the start of the
path until I get into the archives.
Even if I wanted to help you,
access to the archives
is only by written decree
by the curator on the
Board of Vatican Librarians.
Or by papal mandate.
Yes, but, as you no doubt have
heard, the Holy Father is dead.
What about il Camerlengo?
The Camerlengo is just a priest
here. The former pope's chamberlain.
Doesn't the power of the Holy See rest
in him during "Tempo Sede Vacante"?
Fellas, you called me.
His Holiness once told me
the Pope is a man torn between
the real world and the divine.
It seems the real world
is upon us tonight.
I'm familiar with Illuminati lore
and the legend of the brandings.
The Purga is a dark stain
on this church's history.
I'm not surprised this ghost
has returned to haunt us.
Commandante, have you begun a
search for this explosive device?
Of course, but it could be anywhere.
My primary concern at the moment
is the safety of the cardinals.
The Sistine Chapel is a fortress.
As long as the cardinals
are in conclave,
your security concerns
are at a minimum.
Devote as many of your people-
Signore, if you are about to suggest
a naked eye search
of the entire Vatican City,
I will tell you...
- Commander.
- ... I do not have the people.
Although I am not His Holiness,
when you are addressing me,
you are addressing this office.
Do you understand?
- Yes, Father.
- Good.
Now, you said the image on the screen
was illuminated by artificial light.
Might I suggest methodically cutting
power to various sections of the city?
When the image on the
screen goes dark,
you'll have a more specific
idea of the camera's location.
Dr. Vetra, beside yourself
and your research partner,
who else knew about
this antimatter project?
No one but the research team.
This project was strictly confidential.
But Silvano kept detailed journals.
If he told anyone else
about what we were doing,
he would have made a note of it.
And do you have these journals?
I can have them flown here
from Geneva in an hour.
Please.
Professor Langdon.
Mr. Langdon.
You are correct that I may
grant you access to the archives.
Thank you, Padre.
I said that you are correct that I may,
not- not that I will.
Christianity's most sacred
codes are in that archive.
Given your recent
entanglement with the church,
there is a question I'd like to ask you
first, here, in the office of His Holiness.
Do you believe in God, Sir?
Father, I simply
believe that religion...
I did not ask you if you
believe what man says about God.
I asked if you believe in God.
I'm an academic.
My mind tells me I will
never understand God.
And your heart?
Tells me I'm not meant to.
Faith is a gift that
I have yet to receive.
Be delicate with our treasures.
- The archives are this way.
- Professor Langdon?
If this path really leads to
the Church of Illumination,
that may be where they've
hidden the antimatter.
The shining star at the end
of the path. I thought so, too.
Follow the path and we may find
the canister at the end of it.
Can you deactivate the device?
I can change the canister's batteries as long
as we have more than five minutes of life.
That would give us another 24
hours to get it safely back to CERN.
- Robert Langdon.
- Vittoria Vetra.
Are you really a symbologist
or was he mocking you?
No. Both. You're a physicist?
Bioentanglement Physics.
The interconnective life systems?
Okay.
Your project... it was to give
towards the energy research?
Eventually, yes.
One pack of antimatter could
power an entire city for a month.
Or tonight, I guess, destroy one.
What are we looking for in the archives?
- A banned volume written by Galileo.
- Galileo was Illuminati?
- Yeah, and an obedient Catholic.
Who didn't think the church
and science were enemies
but just a different language
telling the same story.
Anyone of like minds could find
the Church of Illumination.
But he couldn't exactly advertise its
location, so he created a coded path.
Richter has started to turn
off the power at various rates.
It will be back on in a minute.
Then some unknown Illuminati
master sculpted four statues.
Each one a tribute to one
of the fundamental elements:
earth, air, fire, water.
And placed the statues out in
public, in churches throughout Rome.
Each statue held a clue
pointing to the next.
At the end of the path was
the Church of Illumination.
If you could find that,
you were one of them.
What makes you think he's going to
murder the cardinals in the churches?
The Illuminati called those four churches
by the special name "L'altare de la Scienza".
Sacrifice them on the
altars of science, he said.
Exactly.
Oh, wow. Look at this.
Excuse me. Signori.
Cardinal Strauss, have you
been informed of the situation?
Yeah.
My belief is we should proceed
with the sealing of conclave.
At this late hour?
That would be highly unorthodox.
And, yet, was ensured to wrought
my power in great elective.
The cruelest honor in Christendom.
I have no personal ambitions, Patrick.
Only those I hold for my church.
St. Peter's church, which is someday
taken at its most vulnerable moment.
And this is not a coincidence.
The church will not fall in a
day. We must evacuate Vatican City.
That is exactly what they
want. Publicity and panic.
No. We must not give them
oxygen for the media fire.
But the people in St. Peter's Square?
Care deeply about
their church, as we do.
Their faith will sustain them.
Their faith will not protect
them from an explosion.
We are all bound for heaven
eventually, are we not?
Spoken like one who has enjoyed the
blessings of a long and full life.
Patrick, do not confuse the power
of the office you temporarily hold
with your true place
here at the Vatican.
You were a favorite of His Holiness.
But His Holiness is with his father now.
Mea culpa.
Seal the doors.
Everyone outside.
This way, please.
Oh. Beautiful.
The chambers are hermetic vaults.
Oxygen is kept at the lowest possible
level. It is a partial vacuum inside.
So, extended stays are not recommended.
So, don't panic if you
feel light headed at first.
I'll be just outside the door,
watching you, Mr. Langdon.
Conclave will go on without us.
It must. Now of all times.
May God forgive you
for what you have done.
Father, if God has issues,
they won't be with what I've done.
They will be with what I'm about to do.
It was confiscated from the Netherlands
by the Vatican just after Galileo died.
I've been petitioning to see it
for about ten years.
Ever since I realized what was in it.
What makes you so sure
that this thing is there?
The number 503.
I kept seeing it, over and over
again. In Illuminati letters.
Scribbled in the margins.
Sometimes just signed '503'.
It's a numeric clue, but, to what? Five?
Well, that's a medieval
number to the Illuminati.
There's the pentagram. Pythagoras.
Dozens of other examples in science.
But what about 3?
It didn't make sense, until I thought:
What if it's Roman numerals?
DIII.
- D3. Galileo's third text.
Dialogo. Discorso. Diagramma.
Just a few days with this and I
could've actually finished my book.
And sold dozens of copies
at the Harvard bookstore.
Il Diagramma Veritatis.
Diagram of Truth.
I know about the
Dialogo and the Discorsi.
Galileo laid out his theories about
the earth revolving around the sun.
Right. It said the earth was not
the center of some universe
with heaven above, hell below,
as the church had said it was.
So, they forced him to
recant his second book.
But what was this one?
This is how he got the word out.
This is the truth. Not what
the Vatican forced him to write.
Smuggled out of Rome, printed in
Holland on setched papyrus. See?
That way, any scientist
that was caught with a copy
could just throw it in water and
Galileo's heresy would disolve. Disappear.
Between that and Vatican burnings
it's possible this is the
only copy that remains.
And if I'm correct,
the segno is hidden on page number...
Five.
Yeah.
Do you need help with the Latin?
Sure.
Movement of the planets,
elliptical orbits, idiosyntricity...
Sorry. I don't think there's anything
that could be interpreted as a...
Wait, wait, wait.
Do that again.
What is that?
Wait. It's a watermark.
And there's a line of text.
Go back.
It's in English.
English?
Why English?
English wasn't used in the
Vatican. It was too polluted.
It's free thinking. It was the language
of radicals, like Shakespeare and Chaucer.
Here's another one.
"The path of light is laid a sacred test.
" Would you write this down as I dictate?
Sorry, Professor. No time.
Yeah, yeah.
Well, what the hell? Yeah.
Twenty minutes till eight.
Where are we headed?
Hold on. Hold on.
I'll tell you in a minute.
Here. Let me see that page again.
Where did you get that paper?
We borrowed it.
"From Santi's earthly tomb,
the demon's hole..."
Are you insane?
"...across Rome the mystic
elements unfold."
"The path of light is
laid in a sacred test."
"Let angels guide thee
on thy lofty quest."
You removed a document
from the Vatican archives?
She did.
"From Santi's earthly tomb..."
- The first marker is at Santi's tomb.
- Yeah.
- But who's Santi?
- Raphael.
- Raphael? The sculptor?
- Yeah. Santi was his last name.
- So, the path starts at Raphael's tomb?
- Raphael's buried at the Pantheon.
- Isn't the Pantheon a church?
- The oldest Catholic church in Rome.
I just pulled a dozen
of my best men for this.
You better be right.
This is one of the busiest
spot in all of Rome.
You can never get away
with it. It's impossible.
The poem implies-
The poem? Unbelievable.
I'm basing this operation on an American's
interpretation of a 400 year old poem.
Well, the information we have
clearly refers to Raphael's tomb
and Raphael's tomb is
inside that building.
And because the Vatican destroyed all
of the pagan statues in the late 1800s,
if this is the first marker,
whatever clues were here to lead
us to the next are sure gone by now.
The path is dead. So, this
is it. Your only chance.
Seperate approaches.
No closer than two blocks and
no uniforms. Three minutes.
I'll need a set of eyes inside.
Excuse me. Two men with symmetric black suits
and earpieces? They're hardly disguised.
That's what I have.
- Well, fine. I'll go in.
You don't have communication.
You can't carry a walkie talkie.
It's too conspicuous.
Tourists have cell phones, don't they?
No, no. You can't send
her in there alone.
All right. I won't.
Don't look so anxious.
We're supposed to be married.
Well, maybe we're not
getting along today, hmm?
Hold my hand.
- But don't crush it.
- Sorry.
Nervous newlywed.
Ooh. Look, honey. The oculus.
That could be the
demon's hole in the poem.
Why are the tombs at an angle?
They're facing east to
worship the rising sun.
But this is a Christian church.
New religions often adopt
the existing customs and holidays
to make conversion less of a shock.
Like the 25th of December.
It's the pagan celebration
of the unconquered sun.
It also makes a handy date
for the birth of Christ.
- Let's check the recesses.
- Okay.
I'll go to the right and
I'll meet you in 180 degrees.
Follow me, please.
Now, the Pantheon, which
means 'Temple of all Gods',
was originally built as a temple to
all the gods of ancient Rome in 27 BC.
Although the building is usually
credited to Agrippa of Damascus...
Robert!
It's Raphael's tomb,
but it's the wrong one.
What are you talking about?
It was moved here in 1759, a century
after Diagramma was published.
Where was he originally buried?
Urbino, I think.
Santi's earthly tomb. What could
posssibly be Santi's earthly tomb?
Damn it! Santi's tomb. It must
mean the chapel that he built.
He's not buried in it. He designed it.
The demon's hole. It's not that oculus.
It's an undercroft. It's a crypt.
Are there any questions?
Yes. Yes!
Did Raphael Santi ever design
a chapel with an ossuary anex
in an angel figure commissioned
by the Catholic church?
I'm sorry. I can only think of one.
One is good.
Wrong? What do you mean wrong?
It's the Chigi chapel in the
Church of Santa Maria del Popolo.
It was once called Capella della
Terra, the Chapel of the Earth.
Earth. The first element. That's it.
- You're certain about the Pantheon?
- We have four minutes.
Back to the Vatican.
Back to the Vatican?
You-You can't.
Commandante, if you care at all about
your church, you'll listen to me.
My church?
My church comforts the sick and dying.
My church feeds the hungry.
What does your church do, Mr. Langdon?
That's right. You don't have one.
Take him if you want. I'm done with him.
All right, this makes sense.
Look, look, look!
Right in front of the church.
An obelisk. A lofty pyramid.
The Egyptian symbol
adopted by the Illuminati.
If he's going to kill him,
he'll do it here.
Eight o'clock.
No. No. Here. It's an Annulus.
Which one is the Chigi Chapel?
Must be in one of these areas.
Pyramids in a Catholic church.
This is it. This is the Chigi Chapel.
The Demon's Hole.
Yeah, but it's askew. Come here.
Give me your flashlight.
What's that?
My Savior Christ will be my judge,
to testify that my voice is His.
For I believe that He should
be chosen for the sake of God.
I wish to Pontifex,
Dominicus Scolamiero.
I wish to Pontifex, Eduardo Rossi.
They are voting for themselves
to prevent a majority.
They're waiting for the
Preferiti to be rescued.
Perhaps we should, as well, yes?
Not until the smoke is white
will the College of Cardinals
have chosen a new Holy Father.
For now the Vatican seat of
ultimate power remains vacant.
Get the body out of there.
Search the rest of the building.
- Chartrand!
- Sir.
Outside a perimeter.
Secure, but invisible.
No lights, no guns.
Nobody knows. Understand?
Yes, sir.
Is it Raphael?
The chapel is Raphael.
But the sculptures are Bernini.
The unknown Illuminati master?
Bernini?
- He worked for the church.
- Almost exclusively.
But the Illuminati were infiltrators.
There wasn't a powerful organization
on earth they didn't penetrate,
including the Vatican,
by hiding in plain sight.
Habakkuk and the Angel.
He's the prophet that predicted
the annihilation of the earth.
"Let angels guide thee
on thy lofty quest."
This is the first marker.
The path is a line.
Southwest.
It was pointing southwest.
Earth, air, fire, water.
We're looking for a Bernini sculpture
having something to do with air.
The second church is
somewhere southwest of here.
You're sure this time?
I need a map showing
all the churches of Rome.
I could use it now.
The purple layers with these black
crosses represent the churches.
But nothing intersects the line until
it hits... until it hits St. Peter's.
Michelangelo designed
St. Peter's, not Bernini.
Michelangelo designed the Basilica.
Bernini designed St. Peter's Square.
The second marker must be a
statue in St. Peter's Square.
It's ten minutes to nine.
Can you go any faster?
Not unless you want the full
attention of the world press.
No majority in the first vote,
but Cardinal Baggia from
Italy is the clear favorite...
Still no new Pope, but Cardinal Guidera
from Spain has the best chance...
The more conceivable candidate could
be Cardinal Ebner from Germany...
Stem cell research is murder!
You condemn sick people to death.
Man is not God.
There. Another obelisk.
Check the crowd. It's almost
nine. He's got to be here already.
Must be a hundred statues up there.
None of them are angels.
Those are all saints.
How in God's name would anyone
create a sculpture about air?
Bas relief. Of course.
It's still a sculpture.
Check the ground.
Look at the carvings.
Look for another having
something to do with air.
Vento Ponente. West wind.
Vittoria.
Here it is.
West wind. An angel blowing
out five streaks of air.
This is it.
Call the police!
Call an ambulance!
He's still alive.
His chest.
They punctured his lungs.
"And you squeezed the life
out of a bishop of Rome."
And he's actually claiming responsibility
for the death of His Holiness.
That's ridiculous. He died of a stroke.
It impliess the Illuminati murdered
him with his own medication.
What?
It's on here.
"With man's solution
we stilled his heart."
"With his own needle
did we pierce his unholy vein."
Did the Holy Father take any
kind of medication by injection?
Tinzaparin.
He had thrombophlebitis.
He took an injection every
day, but no one knew that.
Someone knew it.
Well, he had health concerns
and seizures, as well.
But he took steps to make
sure he was watched for safety.
He didn't want it made public,
so we have no reason to discuss it.
Tinzaparin is lethal
in the wrong dosage.
An overdose could cause massive
internal bleeding and brain hemorrhages.
It might look like a stroke at first,
but in few days,
his body would show signs.
This could easily be examined.
Ms. Vetra, in case
you're not aware of it...
Papal autopsy is
prohibited by Vatican law.
We're not going to defile his Holiness body
just because of these claims.
But why would they
send this letter now?
In order to cause panic.
"The sun will blind at midnight..."
"and neither police nor
professors can stop it."
He knows I'm here.
Obviously, they were hoping
this letter would become public.
We might be wise to preempt
their next attempt
by making an announcement of our own.
- To refute this absurd claim.
- That's out of the question.
Cardinal Strauss has insisted this
entire matter be kept internal.
He shouldn't even be aware of it.
He's locked in conclave.
His final instructions, before
sealing the doors, were very clear.
Cardinal Strauss does not
dictate Vatican protocols.
And to say, yet, technically,
now that conclave has begun,
it is privilege and duty to
control public announcements.
I've drafted a press release
about the incident at the piazza,
but any other statements
are specifically prohibited.
For that, the cardinal has asked me
to remind you we have a chimney.
Commander Richter,
the search for the device?
Well, we've turned the power on and off
to about twenty percent of Vatican city
- but nothing on the video yet.
- We're running out of options.
How long would you need
to evacuate everyone?
If I pull all my men from the
search for the bomb, thirty minutes.
Mr. Langdon, you have been
right so far about the path.
It's now 9:15. How quickly
can you find the next church?
The lines of breath on the carving pointed
due east directly away from Vatican City.
But there were five of them,
so there's room for error.
About twenty churches intersect those lines.
None of them have names that invoke fire.
So, the Bernini sculpture must
be inside one of them that does.
I'm willing to get back
into the archives to find it.
- Would you escort Mr Langdon?
- Yes, Father.
Silvano's journals.
The killer's name could be in here.
- May I stay?
- Please. Fine. Of course.
Professor.
Would it surprise you to
find those clothes suit you?
It would surprise the hell out of me.
The Vatican expressed its sympathy
with the families of the victim.
A tourist from Dsseldorf,
whose death is confirmed.
Vatican police have
arrested a suspect...
The investigation is completed.
Vatican will permit access to St. Peter's
again, with strict security measures.
The Vatican did admit that, where there
are crowds, so often follows crime.
We're trying now to get the
name of the tourist who was...
But wait.
We're getting word now of smoke.
Smoke from the Sistine Chapel chimney.
Apparently, there's been another vote.
The smoke is black.
Once again, the Cardinals have
failed to reach consensus,
and the Catholic Church
remains without a leader.
What are you looking for now?
- Church assets.
- I beg your pardon?
Artwork. It's valuable.
Corporations tend to keep
track of their holdings.
The Catholic church is not
a corporation. It's a beacon.
A source of inspiration for one
billion lost and frightened souls.
Sure, I get that. It's also a bank.
Commander Olivetti said that I was
not to leave your side this time.
It wasn't me. It was her.
Power in zone 3 is disabled.
No response on the screen.
Power on zone 3 again
and continue with zone 4.
What sort of signs?
I'm sorry?
If the Holy Father was given
an overdose of Tinzaparin,
what signs would his body bear?
Bleeding of the oral mucosa.
His tongue.
Post-mortem, the blood congeals,
then turns the inside of the mouth black.
Even after fourteen days?
It wouldn't show up until at
least a week after his death.
He was very important to me.
Yeah, I understand.
Will you come with me, please?
Signore, would you
organize a security team
to escort Ms. Vetra and
myself down to the crypt?
Yes, sir. We'll leave immediately.
Do you smoke?
A little bit.
You better sit down
before you keel over.
What does this say in Italian?
Ecstasy of Saint Theresa. Right there.
Moved at suggestion of the artist.
Moved? To another church?
At the suggestion of Bernini?
I don't know.
Here. Translate all of this for me,
and I'll buy you a pack of smokes.
I'm looking for a reference of fire.
- Seraphim, meaning "the fiery one".
- Right.
His great golden spear. A point of fire.
Then "woman left completely afire."
The ecstasy of Saint Theresa.
Saint Theresa on fire.
So, this sculpture was
moved to this church?
Why are they shuting down the system?
They know we're down here.
If there's no power, there's no oxygen.
- Can we get out?
- The door is electronic.
Well, that's disappointing.
- Where are we going?
- To see my father.
I don't understand.
I was orphaned when I
was nine years of age.
A bombing in Ulster, the UVF protesting
the visit of a Catholic Archbishop.
The Archbishop felt responsible
and he adopted me the following day.
I was raised by him and by the Church.
He was the wisest man I ever met.
Even when I was young and stubborn,
I wanted to be ordained,
but I was brought up in Italy
so I also wanted to do my military service.
I wanted to fight.
He told me, "Learn to fly."
So, I joined the Aeronautica Militari.
Flew helicopters.
Bringing the wounded back to hospitals.
- He was a great man.
- Your father died.
Fourteen days ago.
Headquarters, you hear me?
The flow is completed.
Oxygen level is very low.
- Answer, please. Anybody hear me?
- Did you get anything?
No. The walls are lead lined.
There's no signal.
This way.
If the Holy Father was murdered,
the implications are profound.
Vatican security is impenetrable.
No one from the outside
could've got anywhere near him.
It was someone on the inside.
We can trust no one.
On my screen, no response in zone 7.
We rechon that the
battery will soon be empty
and the device will explode
shortly before midnight.
Holy Father...
when I was young, you've told me the
voice in my heart was God's voice.
You said I should follow
it no matter how painful.
Forgive me.
Please, give me strength.
What I do, I do in the name
of everything you believed.
God help us.
Santa Maria della Vittoria.
Do you know it?
- Yes, I do.
- It's the next church.
I think someone just tried to kill me.
Professor, I promise you,
we had no idea.
- He knows I'm here?
- Yes.
You heard me ask permission.
You gave me an escort.
Yes, but we had no idea
that portions of our white zones
were crosswired with that building.
Commander Richter was
extending the search.
If he had known the archives
were on that grid,
he never would have killed the power.
But there is the other possibility.
Is it conceivable the Illuminati...
have infiltrated the Swiss Guard?
Perhaps.
The journals. Where are they?
Who took the journals from this desk?
Signore, this is unacceptable.
For a Camerlengo to enter the
chapel once conclave has begun.
Forgive me.
There's been a development.
His Holiness Celestine was murdered!
Is it so inconceivable
that it will happen again?
Signori, please, a moment.
Please. Signori.
Our church is at war.
We are under attack from an old enemy.
The Illuminati.
They have struck us from within.
Murdering our Holy Father!
And threatening us all with destruction
at the hands of their new God 'Science'.
They call it retribution.
They think it justified...
because of the Church's attacks on men of
science in the distant past and it's true.
Since the days of Galileo, this church has
tried to slow the relentless march of progress.
Sometimes with misguided means.
But science and
religion are not enemies.
There are simply some things that
science is just too young to understand.
So the Church pleads, "Stop."
"Slow down."
"Think. Wait."
And, for this, they call us backwards.
But who is more ignorant?
The man who cannot define lightning...
or the man who does not respect
its natural awesome power?
The battle is well under way, signori.
We must defend ourselves.
But, what if this time, we fight
their stealth with openness?
Combat their wicked
scheme with simple truth.
And end this brutish
battle once and for all.
If the outside world could
see this church as I do,
looking beyond the
ritual of these walls,
they would see a modern miracle.
A brotherhood of
imperfect, simple souls...
who want nothing more than to be voices of compassion
in a world spinning out of control.
Signori, I ask..
I pray...
that you break this conclave.
Open the doors,
evacuate St. Peter's Square
and tell the world the truth.
Get him down.
There. There, that
chain. On that pulley.
This bench. Get this pew off
here and make it a ladder.
Vatican Police.
My son...
God answers all prayers, but...
sometimes His answer is no.
The College will not break conclave.
May I suggest...
you direct your energies
to helping the Swiss Guard
find this explosive device.
If it exists.
And leave Church leadership...
to its leaders.
Eminence.
There is a growing fear
that without the four Preferiti
it defers much authority
for any candidate.
It will not be possible,
- unless...
- Speak plainly.
It is the recommendation of many
that you asked to be removed...
from your post as Great Elector.
Thereby making yourself eligible
to wear the Ring of the Fisherman.
Well, if it is God's will.
May His will be done.
Here! I hear someone.
Remove the lid.
Come on.
Signore, are you okay?
I know he is there.
Madam, it is necessary
that you remain quiet.
Don't tell me that I should remain calm.
I want to know what he will do.
Commander, here's Ms. Vetra.
Those journals are private property.
I demand that you return them to me.
They're material evidence
in a Vatican investigation.
I am an Italian citizen.
My rights do not end just
because I crossed the other side.
This is not Italy.
It's not even Rome. It's the Vatican.
A country with its own laws.
And when those journals passed the
border, they became my property.
I will give them back to you
when I've decided they contain
nothing of value to the investigation.
Do you have something to
hide, Commandante Richter?
Do you, Dr. Vetra?
If it were up to me,
it wouldn't be this way.
It's a sin to kill with pain.
It's a sin to kill
without reason, Father.
They made me a sinner.
Saint Theresa on fire.
Professor Langdon?
- What direction is that?
- West, I think.
"Across Rome the mystic
elements unfold."
Piazza Barba Rini is here.
Saint Theresa is here.
Where is the Santa Maria del Popolo,
the first altar of science?
- Santa Maria del Popolo?
- Yes.
Thank you.
St. Peter's is here.
We are here.
A church with water.
Wait. Wait, wait.
Across Rome.
The poem must mean it's
literally across Rome.
Professor Langdon.
Commander Richter has ordered me to
escort you to the Vatican immediately.
Piazza Navona. Earth. Air. Fire. Water.
"A-Cross" Rome.
Bernini's Four Rivers.
Professor Langdon, the Vatican insists
that I have to take you back immediately.
The Vatican is about to see its
fourth cardinal murdered tonight.
Now, look.
You can do as they say and
force me back to the Vatican,
where we can all mourn
his death together.
Or you can show me how real cops act
and take me to Piazza Navona,
where we still might be able to stop it.
Oh. By all means, let's talk it over.
In fourteen minutes,
he's going to be dead.
Okay. This way, Professor.
Yes, Padre?
At 11:15, if the church
is still in peril,
give the order to
evacuate the cardinals.
But with dignity.
Let them walk out into St. Peter's
Square with their heads held high.
We don't want the last
image of this church to be
of frightened old men
sneaking out the back door.
"Where the angels guide thee..."
There it is. There it is.
Professor, I know this fountain.
There is no angel.
The dove. The angel of peace.
And it's looking in what direction?
Uh... east, I think.
Professor, just wait here. Stay put.
Good evening. Can you help me?
I need a doctor.
Come here.
Calm down. Don't shoot.
Hey!
Help! Somebody help!
Help! Somebody!
Cardinal Baja.
Si?
Where was he hiding you?
The Church of Illumination.
Where is it?
Castel Sant'Angelo.
Castle of the Angel.
Sir, there's news about Cardinal Baja.
The cardinal told Langdon he was
being held in Castel Sant'Angelo.
If Langdon's right,
that's where the bomb is.
- Send everyone we can spare.
- And you?
I'm staying here.
Vittoria.
- You're all right?
- I'm all right, yes. What about you?
I just heard about
Olivetti on the radio.
I'm all right. I'm okay.
Robert, we can't trust Richter.
He took Silvano's journals.
There must be something in
there he doesn't want us to see.
The head of the Swiss Guard.
From the Castel Sant'Angelo.
It's close enough so the wireless signal
from that camera
could still reach the Vatican.
The Church of Illumination
is somewhere here
and your canister is inside it.
Come with me.
For 400 years, the Illuminati
met right under the Church's nose.
The Vatican used this as a hideout
and as a prison for their enemies.
If the explosion happens here, would
the blast radius take out the Vatican?
And part of Rome along with it.
They're pointing to it. The angels.
The container must be down there.
Come on!
- Where are they going?
- Back to search the other castle.
No, no. It has to be here!
Robert, it's a dead end.
No, it's not.
See if you can find a flashlight.
All of these stones
are rectangular granite.
Except right here. What is this?
It's a pentagram.
An eye...
that leads to...
Nowhere.
Robert?
These walls overlap and
there's a passageway in here.
Here. Let me have the flashlight.
It's a passageway that
leads to the Vatican.
An ancient escape route.
Oh, God.
Here.
Look.
Get on the radio.
Get the word out.
Conclave remains sealed.
The Camerlengo gave the
order for evacuation at-
I'm counter-manning it.
This is it. This is their church.
The canister should be
lit by artificial light.
It's not here, Robert.
"The shining star at the end of the path."
It has to be.
It's not here.
What's the poem say?
- Nothing.
Nothing. It's all over.
There was just four lines,
each one describing...
There's a fifth brand.
It's not an ambigram.
It's just two crossed keys.
- The symbol for the Vatican.
- No.
No, the papacy.
They intend to kill him.
Before they destroy the Vatican,
they're going to brand
and kill the pope himself.
There is no pope.
"Tempo Sede Vacante."
The Camerlengo.
- We have to warn him.
- Take a step back, please.
Take your cell phone from your pocket.
Throw it in the fire.
Murderer.
You know, when they call me,
and they all call me,
it is so important to them
that I know that what they
ask is the Lord's will.
Or Allah's. Or Yahweh's.
And I suppose they're right.
Because if he was not vengeful,
I would not exist, now, would I?
I've had several chances
to eliminate you tonight.
You're still alive
because you have no weapon.
And they didn't ask me to kill you.
But if you pursue me,
it is another matter.
Be careful.
These are men of God.
The Camerlengo.
Have you come to make me a martyr?
Here. Here.
- I need to see the Camerlengo.
- He is not available.
- I demand to see the Camerlengo!
We'll see about that.
Oh. It's a chiusa chiave.
It's a one way portal.
The only entrance is on the other side.
No. Hey! Help!
This is Robert Langdon and
Dr. Vetra. Open the door.
The Camerlengo is in danger.
He's the one. He's got a gun.
- Illuminatus!
- You bastard.
Illuminatus!
You bastard!
Padre?
Order the evacuation.
We only have nineteen minutes.
Here. He's...
And get the helicopter for
the older cardinals, right?
Yes, sir.
Robert?
The brand, the symbol.
Could it have another meaning?
Crossed keys,
but those were upside down.
St. Peter.
The first pope...
...was crucified upside down.
- On Vatican Hill.
- A few hundred feet below us.
- Necropolis. City of the dead.
"Upon this rock, I
will build my church."
"Or bring it down upon itself."
The bomb. It's in St. Peter's tomb.
The grid is still cycling.
The power to this section must be down.
It must be here. It must be.
Don't touch it.
We have seven minutes.
Robert, hold this.
It's cold down here, isn't it?
What's wrong?
Cold decreases battery life.
- We may have less than five minutes.
- So?
If I pull the power with
less than five minutes...
the residual charge
won't hold suspension.
We should leave it here
and get clear if we can.
At least down here the damage-
No!
- No. Wait!
- Father!
We are live here at
St. Peter's Square...
where, despite a bomb threat,
and an orderly evacuation,
the crowd is actually growing in size.
As we await an official announcement
from the Vatican spokesman
as to the exact nature of the threat
and whether or not they are
treating it as a credible danger...
This way!
He's got a bomb with him.
A bomb?
Roberto, this is an emergency.
I'll take her up alone.
He's got clearance.
Oh, my God.
Get down!
Cardinal Strauss?
It was the Camerlengo.
He has saved us all.
He has saved the Church
and he's still alive.
Praise God. Praise God.
He is alive.
He sacrificed himself for all of us.
You know the worst thing
we thought would happen
was that our work would fall into
the hands of the energy companies.
We thought we could change the world.
- So naive.
- No, not naive.
Innocent, maybe.
But it's not a crime.
I'm not so sure.
Go back to work.
Change the world.
A gift, uh, you understand?
Let's say for Catholics everywhere.
The Carmelengo's age
shouldn't influence the decision.
Signori, you are no doubt
aware that by Holy Law
the man is inelligible
for election to the papacy.
He's not a cardinal.
He's a priest.
He's of insufficient age.
Or maybe there's a way we
could consider the possibility.
I am sorry. The protocols of conclave
are not subject to modification.
I will not call a ballot on this matter.
But, signore, you
would not hold a ballot.
Surely, you remember? You gave
up your post as Great Elector.
They are singing at St. Peter's Square.
Now, what happened here
tonight transcends our laws.
Has it? Is it God's will that
we give ourselves over to frenzy?
Discard the rules of the Church?
Perhaps we need not discard them.
Signori, I am thinking now of Romano
Pontifici Eligendo numero 60...
- Acclamation by Adoration.
- Exactly, signore. Exactly.
Yes. If the Holy Spirit
speaks through us,
and we call a man's name out loud...
That is election by adoration.
- Yes.
- He's God's choice.
Yes. And the candidate need only be
an ordained member of the clergy,
present in the Sistine Chapel
at the moment of his election.
- Signor Camerlengo?
- Yes?
The cardinals ask you to join them
in conclave as soon as possible.
- Me?
- Yes, Padre.
What are you doing?
Silvano's journals. I want them back.
Richter said...
His Holiness suffered from seizures
and steps were taken...
for safety.
He made sure he was watched, he said.
What if he were trying
to give me this key?
That's the Papal office.
If the Pope was worried about seizures,
he must've had Richter install
cameras without telling anyone.
To keep an eye on him for his safety.
Maybe it records.
- I read the journals, Patrick.
- The scientist kept journals. So?
- You figure prominently in them.
- Really?
The Devoli wasn't just a physicist.
He was also a Catholic priest.
As such, he was deeply conflicted
about the implications of his work
and in need of spiritual guidance.
Like Galileo.
About a month ago,
he requested an
audience with the Pope.
But you know that,
cause you granted the audience and
you were also present during it.
The 'God Particle'. To actually
claim an act of creation.
- The blasphemy. The arrogance.
- The Holy Father didn't see it like that.
He urged him to go public.
His Holiness thought that
the discovery could actually
scientifically prove the
existence of a divine power.
And begin to bridge the gap
between science and religion.
His work was not religious.
It was sacrilegious.
But you...
You saw the pope's position
as a softening of church law.
As an old man's weakness.
Your father's weakness.
You murdered the Vicar of Christ.
He raised me to
protect this Church,
even from within.
Then you conjured up an old enemy
from the past. The Illuminati.
You found the ancient brands
in the papal vaults
and put them to use
to spread fear!
The Cardinals are men of belief.
Right now, their belief
in evil is uniting them.
The entire Catholic world
will be united by this attack.
There is no attack.
You're trying to convince the
Cardinals they're in a war,
so they will choose a
warrior to lead them.
We are at war.
We're weak when we should be strong.
If science is allowed to
claim the power of creation,
what is left for God?
It didn't work, Patrick.
- It isn't finished.
- Oh yes, it's finished.
It's finished.
I've shown the journals
to Father Simeon.
The moment the doors
to the Conclave open,
he will tell the Cardinals
what you've done.
I was planning on doing this alone.
Put it down.
But, perhaps,
it's better that you're here.
Put it down.
Put it away.
Help. He's the one.
He's got a gun.
- Illuminatus!
- You bastard.
Illuminatus!
You bastard!
Padre.
And get the helicopter for
the older cardinals, right?
I've been summoned by
the College of Cardinals.
Gently.
But within our walls.
He's on your side.
Father, into thy hands
I commend my spirit.
Church sources now confirm that
Carmelengo, Father Patrick McKenna,
has died of internal injuries
sustained in his heroic fall...
The Catholic church thanks
Camerlengo for his selfless act
and demands his
immediate canonization.
The Vatican has also confirmed
the deaths of three Cardinals
and the fire in the
Santa Maria della Vittoria.
As we await the appearance of the new
Holy Father Cardinal Baggia of Italy,
one of the four original Preferiti,
who, despite terrorist
attempts at disruption
seems to have been selected
in one of the swiftest and smoothest
conclaves in modern church history.
Professor Langdon? Please.
A token of thanks from His Holiness
and from his new Camerlengo.
We are grateful you saved his life.
And it's our understanding
that you require this text
to complete your scholary work.
We ask only that in your
last grand testament
you ensure it finds its way home.
Of course.
And when you write of us,
and you will write of us,
may I ask one thing?
Do so gently.
I'll try.
Religion is flawed,
but only because man is flawed.
All men, including this one.
He chose the name Luke.
There's been many Marks and Johns.
Never a Luke.
It said he was a doctor.
It's quite a message.
Science and faith, all in one.
The world is in need of both.
You'll counsel him wisely.
I'm an old man.
I'll counsel him briefly.
Mr. Langdon.
Thanks be to God for sending
someone to protect this church.
I don't believe He sent me, Father.
Oh, my son.
Of course He did.
subtitle made by rakib00, atheeshkr, lockjaw
and rogard. Nice teamwork, guys.