Cinderella
You're as lovely as your name
You're a sunset in a frame
Though you're dressed in rags
You wear an air of queenly grace
Anyone can see
A throne would be your proper place
Cinderella
If you'll give your heart a chance
It will lead you
To the kingdom of romance
There you'll see your dreams unfold
Cinderella
In the sweetest story ever told
Once upon a time... in a faraway land,
there was a tiny kingdom...
peaceful, prosperous,
and rich in romance and tradition.
Here, in a stately chateau,
there lived a widowed gentleman...
and his little daughter, Cinderella.
Although he was a kind and devoted father,
and gave his beloved child
every luxury and comfort,
still he felt she needed a mother's care.
And so he married again,
choosing for his second wife
a woman of good family...
with two daughters just Cinderella's age.
By name... Anastasia and Drizella.
It was upon the untimely death
of this good man, however,
that the stepmother's
true nature was revealed.
Cold, cruel, and bitterly jealous...
of Cinderella's charm and beauty,
she was grimly determined
to forward the interests...
of her own two awkward daughters.
Thus, as time went by,
the chateau fell into disrepair,
for the family fortunes were squandered...
upon the vain and selfish stepsisters,
while Cinderella was abused, humiliated,
and finally forced to become
a servant in her own house.
And yet, through it all,
Cinderella remained ever gentle and kind,
for with each dawn she found
new hope that someday...
her dreams of happiness would come true.
Well, serves you right...
spoiling people's best dreams.
Yes, I know it's a lovely morning, but...
it was a lovely dream too.
What kind of a dream?
Uh-uh. Can't tell.
'Cause if you tell a wish,
it won't come true.
And after all...
A dream is a wish
Your heart makes
When you're fast asleep
In dreams, you will lose
your heartaches
Whatever you wish for
You keep
Have faith in your dreams
And someday
Your rainbow will
come smiling through
No matter how your heart is grieving
If you keep on believing
The dream that you wish
Will come true
Oh, that clock! Old killjoy!
I hear you. "Come on, get up!" you say.
"Time to start another day."
Even he orders me around.
Well, there's one thing.
They can't order me to stop dreaming.
And perhaps someday...
The dreams that I wish
Will come true
Shoo! Shoo! Hurry!
Come on, Jaq. Shoo!
la.la...ha.ha...la.la...
No matter how your heart is grieving
If you keep on believing
The dream that you wish
Will come true
Look what I found!
Wait a minute! Wait a minute!
One at a time, please!
Now, Jaq, what's all the fuss about?
New mouse in the house.
Brand-new. Never saw before.
- Visitor, visitor!
- Oh, a visitor.
Well, she'll need a dress.
- No, no, no.
- She's a he. He, he!
Oh, that does make a difference.
- He'll need a jacket, shoes...
- Gotta get out! Gotta get out!
- In a trap-trap!
- Trap-trap!
Where? In a trap?
Well, why didn't you say so?
Now, now, now... Calm down, everybody.
Oh...
The poor little thing’s scared to death.
Jaq, maybe you'd better
explain things to him.
Zuk-zuk, Cinderelly. Zuk-zuk.
Now, now, now...
Look-a, little guy.
Take it r-easy. Nothin' to worry 'bout.
We like-a you.
Cinderelly like you too. She's nice.
Very nice. That's-a better.
Come on, now. Zuk-zuk-zuk!
Za... za... zuk-zuk.
Well, that's better.
Well, let's just slip it on for size.
It is a little snug,
but it'll have to do.
Now, for a name.
I've got one... Octavious!
But for short, we'll call you Gus.
Like it, Gus-Gus? Like it? Like it?
Uh... Gus-Gus.
Now I've got to hurry.
See that he keeps out of trouble, Jaq,
and don't forget to warn him about the cat.
Zuk-zuk. Look-a... uh, uh...
ever seen a cat-cat?
Duh... cat-cat?
Hup! Cat-cat! R-ucifee, that's-a him.
Mean...sneaky... Jump at you!
Jump at you! Ha! Big, Big! Big as a house!
Zuk-zuk... R-ucifee?
Duh... R-ucifee. Zuk-zuk.
Here kitty, kitty, kitty, kitty.
Come, kitty. Come on.
Lucifer! Come here!
I'm sorry if Your Highness
objects to an early breakfast.
It's certainly not my idea to feed you first.
It's orders. Come on.
Duh... R-ucifee. Is that a R-ucifee?
Zuk... R-ucifee. That's-a him!
Gus-Gus take-a R-ucifee and...
Look-it.
Wait! No, Gus-Gus, no!
Now, listen here. R-ucifee not-a funny.
R-ucifee mean.
Bruno...
Bruno!
Dreaming again.
Chasing Lucifer?
Catch him this time?
That's bad!
Suppose they heard you upstairs?
You know the orders.
So if you don’t want to lose a nice warm bed,
you'd better get rid of those dreams.
You know how?
Just learn to like cats.
No, I mean it.
Lucifer has his good points too.
For one thing, he...
Well...Sometimes he...
Hmm...
There must be something good about him.
Bruno!
Oh, Bruno.
Come on now, outside.
I know it isn't easy,
but at least we should
try to get along together.
And that includes you, Your Majesty!
Breakfast time! Everybody up!
Hurry, hurry!
Come on, everybody. Breakfast, breakfast!
- Come on, everybody, breakfee!- Breakfast!
Breakfast?
Ooh, breakfast!
Oh-oh!
R-ucifee! How we gonna get out?
Hup-hup... carefee!
Listen, everybody! Got an idea.
Now, somebody gotta sneak out.
Let R-ucifee chase him.
Run over to a corner and beat R-ucifee there.
Then we all run out. Zuk?
Zuk-zuk, out!
Now we choose the one that do it.
Everybody, hup!
- Hup!
- Uh, hup.
- R-ails up!
- Hup!
Now...
Hup, hup, hup!
Uh, duh... uh, hup!
Oh, there you are.
I was wondering.
All right, breakfast is served.
Uh... take it r-easy. Zuk-zuk.
Uh, duh... let go! Let go now!
Let... go...
Stop that. Shoo, shoo, shoo.
Go on! Shoo, shoo, shoo!
Poor little Gus.
Here.
Help yourself.
Hmm... No Gus-gus.
Well, guess he got away.
Cinderella!
I'm coming. Oh, my goodness.
Morning, noon, and night.
- Cinderella!
- Coming!
Coming!
Cinderella!
I'm coming.
- Cinderella!
- In a minute.
Cinderella!
Good morning, Drizella. Sleep well?
As if you cared.
Take that ironing and
have it back in an hour.
One hour!
- You hear?
- Yes, Drizella.
Good morning, Anastasia.
Well, it's about time!
Don't forget the mending.
And don't be all day getting it done, either!
Yes, Anastasia.
- A-a-ahem.
- Well, come in, child.
- Come in.
- Good morning, Stepmother.
Pick up the laundry
and get on with your duties.
Yes, Stepmother.
Mother! Oh, Mother, Mother!
Mother! You did it!
You did it on purpose! Mother!
Oh, Mother, Mother, Mother!
- Now what did you do?
- Oh!
She put it there!
A big ugly mouse...
under my teacup!
All right, Lucifer.
What did you do with him?
Oh, you're not fooling anybody.
We'll just see about this.
Come on! Let him go.
Now the other one. Come on! Oh...
poor little Gus.
Oh, Lucifer, won't you ever learn?
Cinderella!
Yes, Stepmother.
- Are you gonna get it!
- Close the door, Cinderella.
Come here.
Oh, please, you don't think--
Hold your tongue!
Now...
It seems we have time on our hands.
- But I was only trying to--
- Silence!
Time for vicious practical jokes.
Perhaps we can put it to better use.
Now... let me see.
There’s the large carpet in the main hall.
Clean it!
And the windows, upstairs and down.
Wash them!
Oh, yes...
and the tapestries, and the draperies.
- But I just fin--
- Do them again!
And don't forget...
the garden... then scrub
the terrace... sweep the halls...
and the stairs... clean the chimneys.
And of course, there's the mending,
and the sewing, and the laundry.
Oh, yes, and one more thing.
See that Lucifer gets his bath.
- But, but, but--
- No "buts" about it!
My son has been avoiding
his responsibilities long enough!
It's high time he married and settled down.
Of course, Your Majesty.
- But we must be patient.
- I am patient!
But I’m not getting any younger, you know.
I want to see my grandchildren before I go.
I understand, Sire.
No, no, you don't know
what it means to see...
your only child grow farther...
farther... and farther away from you.
I'm lonely in this desolate old palace.
I...
I want to hear the pitter-patter
of little feet again.
Now, now, Your Majesty.
Perhaps if we just let him alone.
Let him alone?
W-w-with his silly romantic ideas?
But, but, Sire, in matters of love--
Love... Ha!
Just a boy meeting a girl
under the right conditions.
So, we're arranging the conditions.
But, but, Your Majesty,
if the Prince should suspect--
Suspect?
Ha! Look...
the boy's coming home today, isn't he?
Yes, Sire.
Well, what could be
more natural than a ball...
- to celebrate his return?
- N-n-nothing, Sire.
If all the eligible maidens
in my kingdom just...
happened to be there,
why he's bound to show
interest in one of them, isn't he?
Isn't he?
Y-y-yes, Sire.
The moment he does...
soft lights, romantic music,
all the trimmings.
It can't possibly fail.
Can it?
Y-y-yes, Sire. N-n-no, Sire.
Very well, Sire. I shall
arrange the ball for--
Tonight!
- Tonight? Oh, but, Sire--
- Tonight!
And see that every eligible maid is there!
Understand?
Yes, Your Majesty.
The pear-shaped tones.
Oh, sing sweet nightingale
Sing sweet nightingale
High...
Above me
Oh, sing sweet nightingale
Sing sweet nightingale
High...
Above...
Oh, sing sweet nightingale
Sing sweet nightingale
High...
Oh, sing sweet nightingale
Sing sweet nightingale
Sing...sweet...
Oh, sing sweet nightingale
Sing...
Oh, sing sweet...
Oh...
Sing...
Oh! Oh, Lucifer!
You mean old thing!
I'm just going to have to...
teach you a lesson.
Open in the name of the King!
An urgent message from His Imperial Majesty.
- Thank you.
- From the King!
What's it say, Cinderelly?
Duh... uh... uh... What's it say, huh?
I don’t know.
He said it’s urgent.
Maybe I should interrupt the... uh...
music lesson.
Oh, sing sweet nightingale
Sing sweet nightingale
High...
You clumsy! You did it on purpose.
- Be still, you!
- You're always--
- Girls, girls!- It's her fault, Mother.
Above all...
self-control.
Yes!
Cinderella!
I've warned you
never to interrupt while--
But this just arrived from the palace.
From the palace!
- Give it here!- Let me have it!
- No, it's mine!
- No--
I'll read it.
Well...
- There's to be a ball.- A ball!
In honour of His Highness, the Prince!
Oh, the Prince!
And by royal command,
every eligible maiden is to attend.
- Why, that's us!
- And I'm so eligible!
Why, that means I can go too!
Ha! Her, dancing with the Prince!
I'd be honoured, Your Highness.
Would you mind holding my broom?
Well, why not?
After all, I'm still a member of the family.
And it says, "By royal command...
every eligible maiden is to attend."
Yes... So it does.
Well, I see no reason why you can't go...
if you get all your work done.
Oh, I will! I promise.
And if you can find something...
suitable to wear.
I'm sure I can!
Oh, thank you, Stepmother.
Mother! Do you realize what you just said?
Of course.
I said, "If..."
Oh, "If..."
Isn't it lovely? It was my mother's.
It's pretty-pretty, but it’s old.
Well, maybe it is a little
old-fashioned, but...
oh, I'll fix that.
H-H-How you do that, huh?
Wait a minute.
There ought to be...
some good ideas in here.
Uh-huh.
This one.
- Oh, very nice-nice.
- Like it!
- We can do it.- It'll be R-easy.
I'll have to shorten
the sleeves... I'll need a sash...
a ruffle... and something for a collar.
- And then I'll--
- Cinderella!
Oh, now what do they want?
Oh, well, guess my dress
will just have to wait.
- Cinderella!
All right, all right! I'm coming.
Poor Cinderelly.
Every time she find a minute,
that's the time when they begin it!
- Cinderelly, Cinderelly--
- Cinderella!
Cinderelly, Cinderelly
Night and day it's Cinderelly
Make the fire, fix the breakfast
Wash the dishes, do the mopping
And the sweeping and the dusting
They always keep her hoppin'
She go around in circles
'Til she's very, very dizzy
Still they holler
Keep-a busy, Cinderelly
Yeah...Keep-a busy.
You know what?
Cinderelly's not go to the ball.
What?
- Not go?
- What did you say?
You'll see. They fix her.
Work, work, work.
She'll never get her dress done.
P-p-poor Cinderelly.
Hey! We can do it!
We can do it we can do it
We can help our Cinderelly
We can make the dress so pretty
There’s nothing to it, really
We'll tie a sash around it
Put a ribbon through it
When dancing at the ball
She'll be more beautiful than all
In the lovely dress we'll make for Cinderelly
Hurry, hurry hurry, hurry
Gonna help our Cinderelly
Got no time to dillydally
We got to get a-goin'
I'll cut it with the scissors
And I can do the sewing
Leave the sewing to the women
You go get some trimmin'
And we'll make a lovely dress for Cinderelly
We'll make a lovely dress for Cinderelly
Follow me, Gus-Gus. I know where to go.
Find a pretty-pretty if we can.
Ho-ho-ho. Cinderelly needs help.
Surprise, surprise! Pretty
surprise for Cinderelly!
- And this too, Cinderella,
my slippers. Now don't forget-
- Cinderella, take my dress!
- Here, mend the buttonholes.
Press my skirt too, and mind
the ruffle. You're always--
- And, Cinderella...
- Yes?
When you're through, and before
you begin your regular chores,
I have a few little things.
- Very well.
- Mother I don't see why...
everybody else seems to have
such nice things to wear...
and I always end up in these old rags.
This sash!
Why, I wouldn’t be seen dead in it!
You should talk! These beads!
I'm sick of looking at them!
- Trash! Oh, I hate--
- I don't see why I can't have-
Come on! Now, be carefee.
Duh... uh... yes-yes-yes, real carefee.
Oh-ho-ho! We can use that, Gus-Gus!
Uh... pretty-pretty
pretty-pretty--
Shhh! Look-it!
R-ucifee!
Uh... duh... duh... look.
Oh, beads! Oh-ho-ho-ho!
Very pretty beads! Oh-ho-ho!
Shhh!
A dream is a wish your heart makes
When you're fast asleep
In dreams you will lose your heartaches
Whatever you wish for you keep
Have faith in your dreams and someday
No matter how your heart is grieving
If you keep on believing
The dream that you wish will come true
Okay. 1-2-3-4-5-6-7-8.
Whatever you wish for you keep.
All right.
Heave-ho, heave-ho!
Heave-ho.
Mmmm mm mm believing
The dream that you wish will come...
Will come true...
Yes?
- The carriage is here.
- Oh.
Why, Cinderella, you're not ready, child.
I'm not going.
Not going? Oh, what a shame.
But of course, there will be...
- other times, and--
- Yes. Good night.
Oh, well. What's a royal ball?
After all, I suppose it would be...
frightfully dull... and... and boring...
and... and completely...
completely wonderful.
Oh, why... it’s my...
Surprise!
Surprise! Surprise!
- Surprise!
- Duh... duh... Happy birthday!
- No, no, no, no!
- Why, I never dreamed...
It's such a surprise!
Oh!
How can I ever...why...
Oh, thank you so much!
Now remember, when you're
presented to His Highness,
- be sure--
- Wait!
Please... wait for me!
Isn't it lovely?
Do you like it?
Do you think it will do?
- Cinderella!
- Mother, she can't!
- You wouldn't--
- Oh, no! You...
- can't let her!
- Girls, please!
After all, we did make a bargain.
Didn't we, Cinderella?
And I never go back on my word.
How very clever,
these beads.
They give it just the right touch.
Don't you think so, Drizella?
No, I don't! I think she's--
Why you little thief!
They’re my beads! Give them here!
Oh, no!
Oh... and look, that's my sash!
Wearing my sash! She can't!
Oh, don't! Please, stop!
- My ribbon!
- Why, you thief!
- Kitchen wench!
- You ungrateful little--
Girls, girls.
That's quite enough.
Hurry along now, both of you.
I won’t have you upsetting yourselves.
Good night.
In dreams you will lose your heartaches
Whatever you wish for you keep
Oh, no. No, it isn't true.
Have faith in your dreams and someday
It's just no use.
Your rainbow will come smiling through
No use at all.
No matter how your heart is grieving
If you keep on believing
- I can't believe, not anymore.
- The dreams that you wish...
There’s nothing left to believe in.
Nothing.
Nothing, my dear?
Oh, now you don't really mean that.
- Oh, but I do!- Nonsense, child!
If you'd lost all your faith,
I couldn’t be here,
and here I am!
Oh, come now. Dry those tears.
You can't go to the ball looking like that.
The ball? Oh, but I'm not--
- Of course you are.
But we'll have to hurry,
because even miracles take a little time.
- Miracles?
- Uh-hmm. Watch.
What in the world did I do
with that magic wand?
- I was sure I--
- Magic wand?
That's strange... I... I always--
Why then, you must be--
Your Fairy Godmother? Of course.
Where is that wand? I--
Oh! I forgot.
I put it away.
- Look-a what she did!
- Duh... duh... How'd she do it
Now... let's see. Hmm...
I'd say the first thing
you need is, um... a pumpkin.
- But... a pumpkin?
- Uh-huh. Now, um...
Now... the magic words.
Uh... Oh...
Ahem!
Salaga doola menchicka boola
Bibbidi-bobbidi-boo
Put them together and what have you got
Salaga doola menchicka boola
Bibbidi-bobbidi-boo
It'll do magic believe it or not
Now salaga doola means
Menchicka boola roo
But the thing-a-ma-bob that does the job
Is bibbidi-bobbidi-boo
Oh, salaga doola menchicka boola
Bibbidi-bobbidi-boo
Put them together and what have you got
Bibbidi-bobbidi
Bibbidi-bobbidi Bibbidi-bobbidi-boo
- Oh, looky, looky.
- Isn't it wonderfee?
Isn't it, huh?
Oh, it's beautiful!
Yes, isn't it?
Now, with an elegant
coach like that, of course,
we'll simply have to have... uh...mice!
Uh... uh... mice?
Oh, this really is nice.
Why, we'll have a coach-and-fou
when we're through.
Just a wave of my stick,
and to finish the trick,
Bibbidi.. bobbidi...
boo!
Gracious, what did I do?
I was sure there were four there.
There should be one more.
Oh, ha-ha. There you are.
Bibbidi... bobbidi...
boo!
- Shoo!- Oh, poor Lucifer.
Serves him right, I'd say.
Now... um... where were we?
Oh, goodness, yes.
You can't go to the ball without... um...
a horse!
A-a-another one?
But tonight, for a change,
you'll handle the reins...
and sit in the driver's seat too.
For instead of a horse,
why the coachman, of course.
Bibbidi-bobbidi-boo!
Well, that does it, I guess.
Except for-- oh, yes,
the finishing touch...
and that's you. Yes, Bruno, that's right!
You'll be footman tonight.
Bibbidi-bobbidi-boo
Well, well, hop in, my dear.
We can't waste time.
- But... uh--
- Now, now, now...
don't try to thank me.
Oh, I wasn't-- I mean... I do, but...
- but don't you think my dress-
- Yes, it's lovely, dear.
Lov-- Good heavens, child!
You can't go in that.
Now, uh.. let’s see, dear.
Your size... and the shade
of your eyes... Uh-hmm.
Something simple, but daring too.
Oh, just leave it to me!
What a gown this will be.
Bibbidi-bobbidi bibbidi-bobbidi...
Bibbidi-bobbidi-boo
Oh, it's a beautiful dress!
Did you ever see such a beautiful dress?
And look, glass slippers.
Why, it's like a dream,
a wonderful dream come true.
Yes, my child, but like all dreams,
well, I'm afraid this can't last forever.
You'll have only
'til midnight and then--
- Midnight? Oh, thank you.
- Oh, now, now just a minute.
You must understand, my dear.
On the stroke of twelve,
the spell will be broken,
and everything will be as it was before.
Oh, I understand, but...
it's more than I ever hoped for.
Bless you, my child.
I-- Goodness me! It's getting late!
Hurry up, dear. The ball can't wait.
Have a good time, dance, be gay!
Now, off you go. You're on your way.
With a bibbidi-bobbidi, bibbidi-bobbidi...
Bibbidi-bobbidi-boo
The Princess Fredrica
Eugenie de la Fontaine.
M'amselle Augustina Dubois,
the daughter of General Pierre Dubois.
Ah... the boy isn't cooperating.
M'amselle Leanora Mercedes de la Torre,
daughter of Colonel and Madam de la Torre.
I can't understand it!
There must be at least one
who'd make a suitable mother.
Shhh! Sire!
Uh... a suitable wife.
The Mademoiselles Drizella
and Anastasia Tremain,
daughters of Lady Tremain.
I give up!
Even I couldn’t expect the boy to--
Well, if I may say so, Your Majesty.
I did try to warn you, but you,
Sire, are incurably romantic.
No doubt you saw the whole
pretty picture in detail.
The young Prince...
bowing to the assembly.
Suddenly, he stops.
He looks up, for lo,
there she stands, the girl of his dreams.
Who she is, or whence she came...
he knows not, nor does he care.
But his heart tells him that here...
here is the maid predestined to be his bride.
A pretty plot for fairytales, Sire,
but in real Life... oh, no... no.
It was foredoomed to failure.
Failure, eh?
Take a look at that, you pompous windbag!
Who is she? You know her?
No, Sire.
I've never seen her before.
That's one thing in her favour.
The waltz. Quick, the waltz!
Soft lights.
The lights!
Aha! Failure, eh!
Well...now for a good night's sleep.
Quite so, Sire. I believe I too--
You will stay right here.
See they're not disturbed.
And when the boy proposes...
notify me immediately!
- Notify me immed--
- And remember...
if anything goes wrong...
la...ha...
- But who is she, Mother?
- Do we know her?
certainly seems to.
But I know I've never seen her.
Nor I.
But she certainly is-- Wait...
there is something familiar about her.
Ahem.
So this is love
So this is what makes life
Worthwhile
I'm all aglow
And now I know
The key to our heaven is mine
My heart has wings
And I can fly
I'll touch every star
In the sky
So this is the miracle
That I've been dreaming of
So this is love
Oh! Oh, my goodness!
What's the matter?
It's midnight.
- Yes, so it is, but--
- Goodbye.
No, no, wait. You can't go now. It's only--
Oh, I must, please. Please, I must.
- But why?
- Well, I...I...
Oh, the Prince. I haven't met the Prince.
The Prince? But didn't you know--
- Goodbye!
- No, wait. Come back.
Please come back!
I don't even know your name.
How will I find you?
Wait! Please wait!
Goodbye.
I say, young lady!
- Who is she?
- Wait!
- Isn't she lovely?
Mademoiselle!
See rita!
Just a moment!
Stop! Stop!
Stop that coach! Close those gates!
Follow that coach!
Open the gates!
I'm sorry.
I... I guess I forgot about everything,
even the time, but...
but it was so wonderful.
And he was so handsome,
and when we danced--
Oh, I’m sure that even the Prince himself...
couldn't have been more... more--
Oh, well. It's over and--
Cinderelly! Look, look!
- A slipper, a slipper!
- Yeah, a slipper.
- Your slipper, Cinderelly.
- Yeah, your slipper.
Oh!
Thank you.
Thank you so much, for everything.
Your Majesty, I see no point
in beating about the bush.
I regret to inform you, Sire,
that the young lady has disappeared...
leaving behind only this glass slipper.
Yes, I'll do it.
No, I just can't.
Well? Come in.
Come in!
- Your Majesty--
- So... he's proposed already!
- Tell me all about it.- Well, Sire--
Who is she?
Where does she live?
- Well, I didn't get a chance--- No matter.
We've more important things to discuss.
Arrangements for the wedding,
invitations, a national holiday.
- All that sort of thing.
- But, but, Sire--
Here, here, have a cigar. Take a few more.
ha...
But, but, but--
Better practice passing these out, eh?
But, but, but, if you'd... only listen!
And for you, my friend...
Your, Your Majesty, p-p-please.
a knighthood!
I hereby dub you Sir...
Uh... um...
By the way, what title would you like?
- Sire, she got away, sir.
- She got away?
A peculiar title, but if that’s what you--
She what?
Why you, you... you traitor!
Now, Sire, remember your...
your blood pressure.
Traitor!
No, Sire, no!
Sabotage!
You were in league with the Prince all along!
I tried to stop her...
but she vanished into thin air!
- A likely story!
- But it’s true, Sire!
All we could find was this glass slipper.
The whole thing was a plot!
But, Sire, he loves her.
He won't rest 'til he finds her.
He's determined to marry her.
What? What did you say?
The Prince, Sire, swears
he'll marry none but the girl...
- who fits this slipper.
- He said that, did he?
Ha-ha! We've got him!
Yahoo-o-o!
But, Sire, this slipper
may fit any number of girls.
That's his problem. He's given his word.
- We'll hold him to it.
- No, no, Your Highness.
I'll have nothing to do with it.
You'll try this on every maid in my kingdom,
and if the shoe fits...
bring her in!
Y-y-yes, Your Majesty.
Cinderella! Cinderella?
Cinderella!
- Oh, where is that--
- Yes? Here I am.
Oh... my daughters, where are they?
I... I think they're still in bed.
Oh... Well, don't just stand there.
Bring up the breakfast
trays at once, and hurry!
Uh-oh! Wonder what's the matter.
Duh... duh... What's the matter with her?
I don’t know. Let's find out.
Come on!
Drizella! Drizella!
What?
Get up! Quick! This instant!
We haven't a moment to lose.
Anastasia? Anastasia.
Get up, Anastasia!
What for? Why?
Oh, everyone's talking about it
the whole kingdom. Hurry now!
- He'll be here any minute.
- Who will?
The Grand Duke. He's been hunting all night.
- Hunting?
- For that girl.
The one who lost her slipper
at the ball last night.
They say he's madly in love with her.
- The Duke is?
- No, no, no! The Prince!
The Prince!
You clumsy little fool!
Clean that up, and then
help my daughters dress.
What for?
If he’s in love with that girl,
why should we even bother?
Now, you two, listen to me!
There is still a chance
that one of you can get him.
What? One of us?
Why, Mother, what do you mean?
Just this. No one, not even the Prince,
knows who that girl is.
We do! We do! Cinderelly, Cinder--
The glass slipper is their only clue.
The Duke has been ordered to try it
on every girl in the kingdom,
and if one can be found
whom the slipper fits, then...
by the King's command, that girl
shall be the Prince's bride.
Bride... Bride!
Cinderella, get my things together.
Never mind her, mend these right away!
Not until she irons my dress!
- Mend these.
- After she's brushed my shoes.
But first get my new--
W-w-what's the matter with her?
- Wake up, stupid!
- We've gotta get dressed!
Dressed... Oh, yes...
We must get dressed. It would never do...
for the Duke to see me looking like this.
Mother, did you see what she did?
- Are you just going to let--
- Quiet!
So this is love
- What she gonna do?
- Shhh! I don't know.
Gotta watch her. Come on!
la, la...
- Cinderelly, Cinderelly!
- Cinderelly!
- Look out, look out!
- So this is the miracle
That I've been dreaming of
- Cinderelly, look out!
- Behind you, behind you!
- Look behind you, Cinderelly!
- What?
Oh! Oh, no!
No, please!
Oh, you can’t! You just can't!
Let me out! You must let me out!
oh... ho...
You can't keep me in here!
Please...
No, no! She can't do it!
She can't lock up Cinderelly! I'm gonna--
Oh, please, please.
We gotta get that key, Gus-Gus.
We just gotta get that key.
Whoa!
He's-a here, he's-a here! A Duke-Duke!
- Duh... duh... a who?
- A Grand Duke with the slipper.
- Gotta get that key quick!
- Zuk-zuk key-key quick-quick.
Oh, Mother, Mother. He's here!
- He's here!
- The Grand Duke!
Do I look all right? I'm so excited, I just--
Girls, now remember...
this is your last chance. Don't fail me.
Announcing His Imperial
Grace, the Grand Duke.
You honour our humble home, m'Lord.
Ahem. Quite so.
May I present my daughters,
Drizella and Anastasia.
Your Grace.
Ladies, charmed I'm sure.
His Grace will read a royal proclamation.
All loyal subjects of His
Imperial Majesty are hereby...
notified by royal proclamation
in regard to a certain...
glass... slipper.
It is upon this day decreed--
Why, that's my slipper!
Well, I like that! It... it's my slipper!
No, No! Cinderelly's
slipper! Cinderelly's slip--
- How can she--- Girls, girls, girls!
Your manners.
A thousand pardons, Your Grace.
Please continue.
Yes, quite so.
It is upon this day decreed
that a quest be instituted...
throughout the length
and breadth of our domain...
the sole and express purpose
of said quest to be as follows:
That every single maiden
in our beloved kingdom,
without prearranged exception,
shall try upon her foot...
this aforementioned slipper of glass.
And should one be found upon whose foot said
slipper...
shall properly fit...
such maiden shall be acclaimed
the object of this search...
and immediately forthwith
shall be looked upon...
as the one and only true love
of His Royal Highness,
our beloved son and heir,
the Noble Prince.
Said Noble Prince will humbly
and upon bended knee...
beg, request, or if need be, implore...
said maiden, that they
grant her hand in marriage.
Well...Whereupon,
should the aforementioned maide
look with favour upon his suit,
then shall the happy couple
pledge their troth...
on... uh...
And in due course,
upon the inevitable demise...
of His Most Gracious
and August Majesty, the King,
succeed to the throne,
there to rule over all the land...
as Kingsland Queen of our beloved kingdom.
Oh... So be it.
You must be quite fatigued, Your Grace.
May we offer you some tea?
What? Tea?
Thank you, madam, no.
We must proceed with the... the fitting.
Of course. Anastasia, dear.
There! I knew it was my slipper.
Exactly my size.
I always wear the same size.
As soon as I saw it, I said--
Oh! Well... it... it may be
a trifle snug today.
You know how it is... dancing all night.
I can't understand why.
It's always fit perfectly before.
I don’t think you're half trying!
- Mother, can you--
- Shhh. Be quiet, my dear.
We mustn't disturb His Grace.
Young man, are you sure you're
trying it on the right foot?
Oh, it's the right foot, but
it must have shrunk or something.
A glass shoe isn't always reliable.
Come on, Gus-Gus. Hurry! Up the stairs!
Up the stairs!
Why can't you hold still a minute?
Oh, my word!
Enough of this!
The next young lady, please.
Hear that, Gus? Hear that?
- Yup.
- Quick. Gotta hurry!
Come on, come on! Hurry!
. Gus-Gus, Gus-Gus. Aw, come on.
Look, Look. It's just up there
Come on!
Us a-comin', Cinderelly.
Us a-comin'! Us'll get you out.
You've got the key.
How did you ever manage it?
Lucifer! Let him go, Lucifer!
Please, let him go!
- Let him go.
- Let him go! Let him out!
Let him out! Here! Here, R-ucifee!
Bruno!
Yes! Bruno!
Quick! Get Bruno! Get Bruno!
Oh, of all the stupid little idiots!
I'll do it myself!
Get away from me!
I'll make it fit!
There!
- It fit!
- It fits?
Oh, Your Grace, I'm dreadfully sorry.
It shan't happen again.
Precisely, madam.
Come on, come on! Get up, Gus-Gus!
Get up, get up!
Don't, don't, don't, don't, don't.
Let go, let go!
You are the only ladies
of the household, I hope-- I presume.
There’s no one else, Your Grace.
Quite so. Good day.
- Good day!
- Your Grace!
Your Grace!
Please! Wait! May I try it on?
Oh, pay no attention to her.
- It's only Cinderella.- Our scullery maid.
- From the kitchen.
- It's ridiculous.
- Impossible.
- She’s out of her mind.
Yes, yes. Just an imaginative child.
Madam, my orders were every maiden!
Come, my child.
Oh, no! Oh, no, no, no!
Oh, no! This is terrible. The King!
What will he say?
What will he do?
But perhaps, if it would help--
No, no. Nothing can help now, nothing.
But, you see, I have the other slipper.
Have faith in dreams and someday
Your rainbow will come smiling through
No matter how your heart is grieving
If you keep on believing
The dreams that you wish
will come true.