Hold on.
You've got yours.
What are they doing?
They're trying to lift him up
and carry him off.
Gallant fools.
I missed mine.
You wounded yours. It took off.
We'll go after it later.
We have to get rid
of these others. Look out.
You stay here.
Come on.
I'll bet the big fellow
of mine breaks a record.
What do you think, Quatermain?
Well, they're all right.
You don't seem to have much zest
for hunting yourself.
My job is to take you out,
find you the game,
and let you do the shooting.
Don't tell me
your respect for animals
has turned into sentiment.
There are times when
I prefer them to humans.
Very sorry Qually died.
Bad hunters?
No worse than usual.
It's bad luck, that's all.
Speak to his wife.
I'll see her in the morning.
Hello, Lulu.
How's my girl, huh?
- Hello, Allan.
- Oh, hello, Eric.
Come on. Sit down.
- Bad trip?
- No. I was paid.
I hear you lost Qually.
He was a good man.
Yes, the best. I'll miss him.
He was with me eight years.
Want to take on another party?
Had an inquiry today.
No, not this time, Eric.
These people seem
pretty decent.
And willing to pay
almost anything.
No, not anymore.
I've had enough.
I think I'm through.
Perhaps I'll do this house up,
send for my son.
Bring the boy out here?
It's no life for a child.
How old is he now?
He's almost 7.
I can understand
your wanting to see him.
But isn't he better off
where he is?
English schools, all that.
Or perhaps I'll go back
to England for good.
I've thought of that, too.
What would you do there?
Become a shopkeeper?
This is a mood, Allan.
I've seen it growing on you
the past few months.
You've been alone too much.
England's no place for you.
You've built a career here.
Don't toss it away.
The happiest, finest fate
a man can have in this world
is to be the best at something.
You may not realize it,
but your reputation's
spread to England, too.
- Have another drink.
- I mean it.
Today, that pair from London
who were looking for a guide,
they knew your name.
Ever meet a man called
Curtis? Henry Curtis?
No.
Curtis?
Yes, there was a fellow about
18 months ago, an Englishman.
Tried to get me to go west
into unexplored country.
Had some crazy sort of notion
about a lost diamond mine.
That's the man.
Yeah, well,
I turned him down.
It sounded like romantic
foolishness.
Is he the fellow wants
to go hunting now?
- No.
- Had a letter from him about
seven or eight months ago.
No, it was asking about him.
It didn't make any sense.
It was his wife, Mrs. Curtis,
who tried to engage you today.
A woman? A woman on safari?
No, thank you.
- She seemed very --
- Listen, any woman who wants
to go traipsing through jungle
must have something
the matter with her.
Besides, I really
am fed up, Eric.
I'll tell her so.
If you're serious about England,
stop in at the office tomorrow.
Perhaps I can be of service.
Hmm.
Get some sleep.
- Oh, I'm sorry. I didn't --
- Come in, Allan. Come in.
- I dropped in for a talk.
- John Goode, Allan Quatermain.
- Hello.
- How do you do?
Mr. Goode insisted on
waiting to see you.
I told him it was useless.
I refuse to give up.
I've come all the way
from England.
I thought at the very least
you might be able to give me
some information.
I see. I thought you said
it was a woman.
There are two of us.
My sister and I.
Two years ago, her husband,
Henry Curtis, left England.
His last letter
came from here.
He was headed west
into unknown territory.
We never heard from him again.
We want to find him.
I'm afraid I can't give you
any information other than
he asked me to go with him,
and I declined.
He was tracking down
some queer legend about
a fabulous diamond mine
far into the interior.
Such stories are constantly
cropping up in Africa.
No, Henry Curtis' project
was a bit too thick for me.
- I advised him against it.
- Why?
Because nobody's ever been
in that region before.
At least, nobody's
ever been there
and lived to tell about it.
You mean, returned
to tell about it.
You must admit, as far as you
or anyone else can say,
Henry Curtis
may still be alive.
Well, perhaps as a captive,
but the chances are very slim.
My sister feels as long
as there's a chance at all,
she must pursue it.
She's had a bad time lately.
Can't sleep nights.
Wakes up screaming.
Dreams about him wandering in
the jungle, that sort of thing.
Surely you must have made
other inquiries.
I was able to establish
that he headed north
and west toward the Kaluana
country in the dark area.
The Kaluana country?
Well, there you have it.
How would you proceed?
The Kaluana country lies there.
We'd have great difficulty
getting even that far.
Then where would you go?
Thousands and thousands
of square miles
where no white man has ever been
and even the natives
are afraid to go.
In which direction
would you begin?
- We have a map.
- A map?
Henry's last letter was
addressed to me.
In it, he enclosed a copy of
the map he intended to follow.
There are no maps.
There isn't a native village
or a river recorded beyond
the Kaluana region.
This sort of thing is constantly
being peddled to greenhorns
from Timbuktu to Johannesburg.
You may be right.
Henry said he bought
the original of the map
to King Solomon's Mines
from an Arab trader
who claimed
it was 400 years old.
Kaluana village, desert,
water, White Twins...
King Solomon's Mines.
The Flying Dutchman.
Captain Kidd's treasure.
Alright. Perhaps
there is no diamond mine.
But at least this map tells us
where to look for Henry
because he followed it.
So we'll follow it.
With your help.
This safari is not child's play,
Mr. Goode, especially with a...
well, shall we say
an overwrought woman?
Elizabeth knows that.
So do I.
I assure you, you have
absolutely no idea
of the dangers of such a trip.
Neither have I.
But I at least can guess.
Allan knows the country better
than anyone else, you see.
But that's exactly why
we want him.
That, and because I can see
you'd be fair and honest
with us.
Well, thank you, but I'm sorry,
I can't undertake it.
My advice is to take
your sister back to England
and both of you pray that
eventually her husband turns up.
It was nice to have met you.
- Bye, Eric.
- Bye, Allan.
Sorry, I couldn't have been
more help to you.
Mrs. Curtis, I believe.
Won't you come in?
Oh, excuse me.
Now, this is Lulu.
Lulu, this is Mrs. Curtis.
Oh, she's enchanting.
She's a charmer.
She knows it.
And she makes use of it.
Lulu and I enjoy having
visitors, Mrs. Curtis,
but I think I ought to warn you
you've come on
a hopeless errand.
My brother told me
your reasons.
There was one argument
he neglected to use.
Oh, what was that?
Money.
That's a very good argument.
I'm willing to pay anything.
Beyond reason, of course.
Why are you so determined
to go on with this?
I can understand your planning
it before you knew its dangers,
but now, your brother
must've told you.
Are you sure you aren't
exaggerating the dangers?
With proper equipment
and your services,
we should be able to manage.
I'm not afraid.
Your courage does you
no credit, Mrs. Curtis.
It's the result
of ignorance.
What is your usual fee
for a safari, Mr. Quatermain?
200 pounds and all expenses.
I wouldn't undertake
this one for 500.
Would you for 5,000?
- That's a great deal of money.
- I mean it.
That's more than I could save
in a lifetime.
- Would you pay it, win or lose?
- Of course.
Even though you backed out
before we'd gone
a tenth of the way?
Yes. You expect me
to back out, don't you?
Frankly, yes.
I'll pay the 5,000 in advance
and a bonus of 500 at the end
whether I back out or not.
You're weakening, aren't you?
You've half decided to go.
Oh, I've fully decided to go.
My reasons are
entirely mercenary.
Nobody's been in the region
beyond the Kaluanas before,
but I'm willing to try it
for cold, hard cash.
Apparently, you're not so
certain after all
that we'd never return.
I'm just as certain as ever.
And yet you'd go?
Mrs. Curtis, the average life
of a man in my profession
is approximately eight years.
Now, I've been at it for 15.
So, you see, I'm living
on borrowed time.
My wife died here
six years ago.
Sooner or later, an animal
or an unfriendly native
or a tropical disease
will get me.
I have a son in England.
There will be very little money
for him if anything should
happen to me in the ordinary
course of events.
But the money you're offering
would provide very nicely
for the boy until he's old
enough to take care of himself.
- I see.
- So, I'll take on your safari.
But before we leave, I'd like to
send the 5,000 pounds
to London for my son.
You can pay me the bonus
when we return.
You mean, if we return.
From now on, we'll say
when we return.
What I privately think
mustn't color the mood
of this fine safari.
It isn't just the danger
of the undertaking
that's making you
so antagonistic.
There's something else.
What is it, Mr. Quatermain?
I don't understand
your motives.
I think you mean
you don't believe them.
- Frankly, I don't.
- Why?
Well, it's wiser if we don't
discuss this, Mrs. Curtis.
Why?
Well, because on a safari,
it's better to travel
with people one likes.
In that case, you better tell me
now and give me time to recover.
What about my motives?
Very well.
It occurred to me that since
your husband's body was never
found, you can't
inherit his money until
you prove that he's dead.
That could be the reason
for this visit.
One of the reasons my husband
went looking for that
diamond mine was the possibly
foolish hope of finding
a fortune of his own.
You see, I hold all the wealth
there is in the family.
Well, then I still
don't understand.
What? That I'd be willing to
risk my life for my husband?
That you're proposing to throw
it away. That's not normal.
It has a smell of sickness
about it.
I happen to love my husband.
Perhaps that's an emotion you
are incapable of understanding.
Perhaps.
Perhaps you've never known
a woman truly in love.
Perhaps, but I have known people
who make elaborate sacrifices
for reasons they themselves
don't quite understand.
Sometimes it's to expiate
a feeling of guilt. Sometimes --
If I were you, I'd examine my
own motives, Mr. Quatermain.
A man who doesn't care
whether he lives or dies
is not exactly
a wholesome specimen.
I'm risking my life
for a man I love.
You're doing it for money.
- Mrs. --
- No, no, no, not your son.
There are things
you can do for him
other than toss your life away.
What's your sickness,
Mr. Quatermain?
Nothing to live for?
I'll meet you in Eric Masters'
office in the morning.
I haven't thanked you
for taking on this safari.
I'm wondering what made you
change your mind?
I didn't know Elizabeth
could be all that persuasive.
There's something very
persuasive about 5,000 pounds.
She's quite a nice girl, really.
Oh, she does have definite ideas
of her own about certain things.
Those clothes, for example.
I gather from the way you
looked at them this morning,
you don't quite approve.
- I don't.
- Why didn't you tell her so?
No need.
She'll find out.
- What's wrong?
- Mrs. Curtis is sick.
What's the matter?
Oh, I think I'd like
to walk for a while.
You all right, Beth?
This old wagon, it's not
very comfortable. It rocks.
-  She's seasick.
-  I'm perfectly all right.
Let's go on.
Now, just a moment.
What are you doing?
Mrs. Curtis, out here,
perspiration has got to be given
time to evaporate,
or you won't last two hours,
and you're sealed up
like a tin of pears.
Khiva, get that box!
Now, this may be the just
the costume for
shooting pheasant in Sussex,
but it won't do out here.
Now, go behind those bushes
and change.
And take off those corsets.
Impertinent, wretched man.
To think I would...
Terrible.
Unbearable behavior. Really.
That's a very becoming
outfit, Beth.
I hate it!
If you'll keep
absolutely still...
Oh.
Don't shoot. Stand still.
That was a close call.
No, not really.
They're not dangerous
unless they're hungry.
Well, how do you know
when they're hungry?
Well, if they eat you,
they're hungry.
Seriously, Allan,
how did you know?
Look.
Why didn't you shoot?
Why, do you want a trophy
to take home?
No, but it might have
killed us!
Well, if it had tried,
I'd have shot it.
Otherwise, there's not
much point, is there?
I didn't tell you to run!
A man's heart can stand
still, so can you.
How far have we gone,
Mr. Quartermain?
Well, we started here,
and now we're somewhere
about here.
That took us seven days?
We have to head for the
Kaluana village, which is there.
Now, Curtis' map starts
where the large map ends --
at the Kaluana village,
and that in itself is
quite a long trip.
We know where the Kaluana tribe
is, but know very little
else about them except
that they're said
to be pretty dangerous.
You've never been among them?
No, I'm a hunter,
not an explorer.
In fact, to my knowledge,
no white man has been near
the Kaluanas for five years.
Nowadays, they're feared
as much by the natives
as they are by the whites.
We're gonna have trouble getting
our own boys to get that far.
We can't be sure that
Henry got that far.
No. We'll inquire of other
tribes on the way, of course,
but we've got to go
to the Kaluana.
This is the only place we know
that Curtis was trying to reach.
How long will it take us
to get there?
Weeks. Months, perhaps.
I don't know.
I've never taken a woman
on a safari with me before.
Have I been a handicap?
Why, no, Mrs. Curtis,
but the fun hasn't started yet.
When it does, I'm sure
we'll all enjoy it.
What do they sing about?
Oh, about all sorts of things.
About their work.
About all the money they're
gonna earn on this job.
About their wives
and sweethearts.
Everything they're gonna do
when they get home.
What are they singing
about now?
Now, they're singing about
Mrs. Curtis.
They call her the...
That means "the lady
with the flaming hair."
Oh.
What else?
Well, they say you're very
fortunate because Bwana Allani
will protect you from lions,
leopards, elephants,
and all the terrors
of the jungle.
What are they saying now?
Well, they say that
I'm very fortunate, too.
I'm sorry. I couldn't help it.
It was one of those...
It was a dream again.
I'm sorry, truly I am.
Oh!
- Where are they going?
- They're going back.
This is as far as it goes.
I wondered how we were
going to get over that.
From now on, we've got to do
without a few luxuries.
Oh, by the way, did you hear
anything last night?
I thought I heard a scream.
A human scream,
as a matter of fact.
I didn't hear anything.
You must have been dreaming.
Come on, let's get going.
Beth.
You sure you don't
want to go with them?
Lovely, isn't it?
It has a sort of majesty,
a feeling of forever.
Forever's quite correct.
- Looks completely peaceful.
- It isn't.
It's been tearing its own throat
for a million years.
In this one small area here,
there are 1,000 creatures,
living, reproducing,
killing, being killed,
eating, being eaten.
There's not a square inch
that doesn't have war
if you look for it.
Look.
Ooh!
And look there.
I don't see anything.
Now wait a minute.
It will move.
Ooh!
That's a mamba. One nip
from that, and you stay here.
Much of the forest
lives up there.
The vines keep reaching
up to the sun.
They make that layer up there
thicker and thicker
until in some places, they shut
out the sun so completely
nothing green will
ever grow down here.
Look. There's a sight.
Oh, look!
Yeah, a scavenger.
Everybody knows about vultures,
but there are others,
all sorts of others in the great
forest that keep it clean.
Hey, careful!
Safari ants.
They attack in thousands.
Give them half the chance,
they'll eat you, too.
Anteater.
Eating and being eaten.
There isn't a creature
in the forest that isn't
hunted by something else,
except the elephant.
They're all afraid of him.
He's king.
The elephant, not the lion?
No, no, not the lion.
Not in Africa.
He's not brave enough
or clever enough.
Elephant's the king.
And man?
He's just meat
like everything else.
There are no souls
in the jungle,
very little justice,
and no ethics.
In the end, you begin
to accept it all.
You watch things hunting
and being hunted,
reproducing, killing, and dying.
It's all endless and pointless.
Except, in the end, one small
pattern emerges from it all.
The only certainty.
One is born, one lives for
a time, and then one dies.
That's all.
All the rest is yuet saba.
What's that?
Yuet saba?
Oh, it's a game
the natives play.
It doesn't make sense.
It's quite pointless.
A chases B,
B chases C, C chases A.
Then they turn around
and go the other way,
and make a great fuss about
trying to get things
away from each other.
Bits of nothing.
Twigs and leaves.
It's quite senseless.
Except that the fellow
who is here has satisfied
his desire to be over there.
Everybody's had the fun
of running after something.
Everybody's grabbed a handful
of stuff that they wanted
because everybody else
wanted them.
And, well, it's endless.
It's quite pointless.
It's a silly game,
yuet saba.
- I'm sorry.
- Sorry?
You are sick of life,
aren't you?
What are you talking about,
Elizabeth?
Motives.
You're being confoundedly
enigmatic.
No, she's not.
She's making very good sense.
Look.
Meat for the Zavonbardes.
I saw a face over there
in the bushes watching us.
That's right.
Look, there's another.
What do they want?
Are they surrounding us?
No.
They're so quiet.
Why don't they say something?
There's nothing to say.
They know who I am.
They're just checking.
Did you see those fellows
peeping at us?
They're acquaintances
of Mr. Quatermain's
with nothing to say,
just checking.
Where are they?
What happened to them?
Get the meat and the salt.
I have a feeling
they're about somewhere.
They're about, all right.
Go ahead.
I thought it was always beads.
If you had to live here,
you'd find a bag of salt
is worth 100 times
its weight in beads.
They're not stupid, you know.
What happens next?
Well, I'll drive a bargain with
them for the use of their boats.
The Zavonbarde River
lies beyond this village.
We've got to cross it.
How can you make a bargain
with people you can't see?
I can see them.
Khiva.
How long will this take?
Not long.
Maybe two hours,
six hours. Not know.
Do they seem friendly to you?
I've got the oddest feeling
we're going to get
cooked in that pot.
They don't seem
to be getting on.
Khiva, what are they saying?
Seven boat go over river.
Is that all?
Yes. Only got seven boats.
He says he's seen dozens
of hunters since he's been here
in the last two years,
but he claims that he
remembers Henry Curtis.
Says he had an odd looking
bearer with him.
Chap with one eye and a soar
on his cheek. I hope so.
Why?
Because I know that fellow
with the one eye.
He's a first-class bearer,
tough, knows the country.
Curtis was in good hands.
I wonder what that is?
I don't care.
I'm famished.
Better get her out of the sun
if we're gonna stop here.
We're not going to stop.
Oh. Ow.
- Beth?
- Yes, Jack?
Hmm.
Beth, I've been thinking.
What would you sa --
If there's one thing that
bothers me more than
anything else,
it's those centipedes.
I've counted 40 varieties.
Have you noticed the one
that leaves a slimy trail?
It's that long.
I think I'll have one
stuffed and mounted.
It'll make a far more
interesting trophy
than the usual lions
and panthers.
Yes, I've seen them.
I'll take a panther any day.
Or Allan Quatermain.
He's not a bad sort, Beth.
What's wrong between you two?
- Something seem wrong?
- You keep watching each other.
Each of you seems to be hoping
the other will fall on his face.
Beth, I've made a decision.
I think we should turn back.
I've discussed it
with Quatermain.
He's willing if you are.
Mr. Quatermain would like
nothing better
than to see me give up.
Today I'm sure he took us
through that swamp
intentionally.
That's not true, Beth.
He had asked me this morning
if I thought you were up to it.
You're being unfair.
Nevertheless,
we made a poor choice
in our selection of a guide.
His heart's not in it.
I wonder.
Oh, I've lost all my hairpins,
and my hair seems to be a trap
for every fly, every mosquito,
every ant in the forest
and they -- and they bite.
Why don't you try pigtails?
I remember when you wore them,
and very attractive they were.
I'm a grown woman, Jack.
Sometimes I wonder
about that, too.
I think you owe
that man an apology.
And some gesture
of friendliness.
What happened?
There was an animal,
a large animal!
- Where? In here?
- No, there. Outside!
What is it?
Nothing, she's been
dreaming again.
It was not a dream. The animal
tried to get into my tent.
I asked you not to shoot unless
it was absolutely necessary.
Do you mean I'm lying?
It dug its claws
right through the tent.
Look at it.
Well, I don't think you hit it.
The bullet holes are too high.
Oh, so there was an animal.
You turn in. I'll keep watch
the rest of the night.
Next time, call me.
I did call you.
You go to bed.
Good night, Beth.
Oh, he's a dreadful man.
- Quick, get her behind there.
- What is it?
Go on! Never mind.
Get behind there!
What are they running for?
Bush fire. They're stampeding.
Look.
That's what started it.
Alright, now, fire.
Keep on firing. Scatter them.
Hey, come back!
No!
What a waste of time
and equipment and lives.
This ridiculous safari.
I hope the lady enjoyed it.
Wait here. Come on.
- Calecapesa.
- Calecapesa?
Curtis...
He apparently said
the Kaluanas are that way.
- Far that way.
- What does Calecapesa mean?
It means "unpleasant."
Come on.
What have you done
to your hair?
What?
What have you done
to your hair?
Oh, I cut it.
What?
I cut it.
Ah, good idea.
What?
Good idea.
Lunch is ready.
Lunch.
Oh.
Oh, look. There's our lunch.
Is it an ostrich egg?
Well, not exactly.
Look.
Watch. It's hatching.
See?
It's a crocodile.
Good heavens,
what a strange-looking man.
Who the devil is that?
I don't know. He says
he wants to talk to me.
He must be 7 feet tall.
That face and hair.
Never seen a native
who looked like that.
Neither have I, not in all
my years in Africa.
What's he saying?
He wants to join our safari.
Says he's willing to
act as bearer or
without pay
if we'll take him along.
- How'd he get this far alone?
- I don't know.
But he needs the help of our
guns to get through
the dark country.
He can't make it alone.
Why would he want to go
into the dark country?
- I don't like him.
- Why?
His form of dress.
He's too elegant by half.
He says he didn't
ask us our reasons.
Perhaps you've grown too
accustomed to subservience.
I like him.
Going to turn him down?
No. It's better to have him
with us than tracking us.
Are you sure he said he wanted
to go into the dark region?
Perhaps, he meant
he was willing.
He said he wanted to go.
I don't know why.
- What was all that about?
- Oh, it was nothing.
Look, I've given Umbopa to you
as your gun bearer.
You look after the rear and keep
your eye out for deserters.
Right.
- You're coming with me.
- Why were they so frightened?
Oh, they claim that that's
a Kaluana rattle.
They decided
it's time to go home.
What about you?
They're singing as usual.
They don't seem to be
frightened.
They're singing to keep
their spirits up.
They're scared to death really.
Four of them have left already.
Cleared off without pay.
Took some of our supplies.
It doesn't matter.
With fewer boys, we couldn't
carry it all anyway.
I'd like to know
what's on that fellow's mind.
He often stands
alone, brooding like that.
He never joins the others.
Well, they seem to like him,
and he likes them.
Have you found out any more
about him? Where's he from?
He grew up
in the Karabda village.
That's miles from
where we found him.
Doesn't say
he was born there.
Just that he lived there
with his mother,
and when she died, he left.
I've had several talks with him
in the last two weeks,
but all I have been able
to get out of him
is a vague connection between
the death of his mother
and his determination to visit
the dark area.
He made her a promise
or something of that sort.
Have you ever noticed
the shape of his eyes?
Hmm, they're strange,
aren't they?
The only other place I ever saw
eyes like that was in a museum.
He's like the ghost
of an ancient Egyptian king.
What's up?
Check the supplies.
See what they've taken.
Check the ammunition.
Well, the boys have gone,
cleared off.
All except Umbopa and Khiva.
That means we can take only
the medicine chest,
the rifle, and ammunition,
and the bare essentials.
All the rest must remain here.
Well, we have a decision
to make. Shall we go on?
I don't know.
What do you think?
Well, I'm being paid.
I haven't finished my job yet.
Well, that's scarcely
the right answer.
Beth, this is no time
for an emotional outburst.
We've got to weigh our chances.
Well, from now on,
the conditions of travel
will be the same whether we go
on or whether we turn back.
- Won't they?
- To begin with, yes.
But if we turn back now,
we may be able to pick up
some bearers from
the friendly tribe.
And if we go ahead?
Well, we may be able to pick
them up from the Kaluanas.
- I don't know.
- We're close to
- them now, aren't we?
- Yes.
Well, we've come all this way
just to get to the Kaluanas.
You said yourself
that among the Kaluanas,
we might get the first
believable news
of Henry, good or bad.
How about you?
We haven't done so badly
so far.
No one likes to give up
before he's beaten.
Alright. We'll have
to remake the packs, Khiva.
Take that, and that
and the medicine chest.
Come on. Umbopa?
I pray that we're doing
the right thing.
We none of us want
to turn back now, Beth.
Not even Allan,
though he hasn't said so.
Thank you, Jack.
Did you ever dream
that you were crying out?
That you were in dreadful
trouble and crying for help
and people were going by
and nobody heard
and nobody cared.
That's how I think
about Henry.
Alive somewhere,
hoping help will come,
but forsaken.
That last year in London,
before he left for Africa,
I used to feel very sorry
for him sometimes.
Sorry for him? Whatever for?
Someday I'll tell you.
Or perhaps,
someday you'll tell me.
I'd better help Allan.
Oh.
Oh!
Stay here. Keep quiet.
She says the Kaluana village
is straight ahead.
Well, this is it.
She says a white man's living
in the Kaluana village.
- Speak English?
- I speak English.
My name's Allan Quatermain.
This is Mrs. Curtis,
and this is John Goode.
- This is your entire party?
- Yeah, for the moment, yes.
Lost your bearers, huh?
Come in.
Khiva.
I haven't seen a white face
for five years.
You've been here
five years, Mr...
Smith.
Yes, for five years and more.
I like it here.
What are you doing
in these parts?
Just looking for trouble?
No. We're looking
for a man called Curtis.
Henry Curtis.
He was here?
About a year ago,
with only one bearer.
A fellow with one eye
and a scarred face.
Where is Curtis now?
I haven't anything better
to offer you.
This is poka.
It's a vile drink.
Do you know where he is?
Please tell us.
You don't happen
to have anything better
than this with you, do you?
We have. Got a bottle
of brandy outside.
Brandy! I haven't
tasted brandy in years.
Give me the brandy.
That fellow Quatermain.
I've heard of him. He's...
Where is Curtis?
He stayed with me
for a day and left.
Had a notion there was
a desert in the northwest.
His bones are probably moldering
in the jungle by now.
Is there a desert
to the northwest?
I don't know. Nobody ever
goes as far as that.
Why?
Taboo. Legends.
About what?
Monsters, gods,
and terrible animals.
- Not about desert?
- No.
Not even about diamond mines.
I know. That's what that Curtis
fellow was after. The fool.
I knew he couldn't last long
in there, so I let him go.
Are you saying you let Curtis go
because you were sure
he would die?
It wasn't my business!
That's not what you said.
You say you've been here
five years.
You must know
these fellows pretty well.
Are the stories
of murder true?
They are naturally warlike.
Have you heard any rumors
about Curtis after he left
- from the natives?
- Nothing.
Unless you believe what One-Eye
said when he came back.
- Came back?
- Yes.
Alone, after about three weeks.
What did he say?
Tell us about One-Eye.
He came back here.
Staggered back.
He was dying, lasted about
four hours. Died right here.
And we buried him.
I think we buried him.
I won't guarantee
that my people didn't...
They're very short of meat here.
There's not much game
in this region.
What there is, we can't get
without ammunition.
What did One-Eye say
before he died?
He was out of his head.
Rambled about burning sun and
burning earth again and again.
Did he say anything
about Curtis?
I gather he deserted him
and came back.
- Have another drink.
- Oh.
Now, you're gonna get us
out of here.
What do you think
you're doing?
You had no intention of letting
us leave this place alive.
Your name's Van Brun.
I've had your description
for years.
He's wanted for murder
in Nairobi.
He can't afford for anyone
to get away
with an account
of his whereabouts.
Yes, he said he let Henry go
because he was sure to die.
Yes, but you're not so sure
about us, are you?
Get out. Go away.
You're gonna get us
out of here before those
fellows outside start warming up
and carrying out your orders.
I'm not sure
I can control them now.
We will soon find out.
Stay close behind me. Alright.
Go on.
Stop. Keep up here with me.
I can't keep up.
I just can't.
Khiva. Keep him covered.
Come on, you must try.
Khiva.
Goode, give me a hand
here, will you?
Let's get out of here.
Is he coming?
Oh, God.
I told him to leave
a false trail.
Alright, we're going up here.
Goode, get up that tree.
Keep a lookout for us.
Come on. You're coming with me.
- Oh, no, I can't.
- Yes, you can.
Now, wait here.
Give me your hand.
Alright, come on.
- Hold on to there.
- Yes. Alright.
Oh!
I got you.
I got you. Alright.
Oh!
Ahh!
Well, there's the desert.
The map was right.
Well, we'll stay here until dark
and go on by night.
It'll be too hot
to travel by day.
There may be a diamond mine
out there.
The map was right
about the desert.
It may be right
about the mine.
I'll be happier if it's right
about the water hole.
That fellow's probably heard
about the mines.
That would explain him.
But he's got a long way to go
to get to them.
There's the problem
of getting back.
Well, we could always sprout
wings and fly back to England.
You're awfully
cheerful about it.
Well, I for one don't care.
I want to see what's out there.
Everything on the map
is correct so far.
And I have a feeling that
when the mists clear,
we're gonna see the mountains
marked on that map.
One-Eye babbled to Smith
about burning earth
and burning sun.
That means that Curtis
reached this desert.
And if the water is where
it's marked on the map,
he may have reached that, too.
There they are, the mountains.
The White Twins. You see them,
those two peaks?
Now, if we head
straight for them,
we should see the water
indicated on the map.
I'll take a bearing while
I can still see them.
What does a water hole
look like?
Well, it can look
like an oasis,
or it can look like that.
I should think it would
take us about five days to get
to the mountains.
Now, two swallows, no more.
We'll rest here until
the sun goes down.
Get some sleep.
Oh!
Good heavens, it's like
English countryside.
Temperate country
in the heart of Africa.
That's because
it's a plateau.
Must be thousands of feet higher
than the jungle or the desert.
Some natives bury
their dead that way.
It's Curtis'.
Got a message on it.
"Ammunition gone,
heading northwest.
Inform Elizabeth Curtis,
73 Grosvenor Square, London.
Henry Curtis."
He's alive.
Out there somewhere.
You said someday
you'd tell me.
You send you'd tell me.
You weren't in love with Henry,
and you treated him badly.
That's why he ran off
to Africa.
That's about it.
Hasn't this trip been
penance enough?
More than enough.
In more ways than you
can guess, Jack.
I'm not blind.
The human heart's
a strange thing.
When I started on this trip,
I was very confused.
I thought my motives
were so noble but...
Allan guessed the truth,
the first time I met him.
It was guilt.
I know it now, and I'm better
for knowing it.
The nightmares are over.
But another sort of nightmare
seems to be beginning.
What are we to do?
Can't we face that
when we come to it?
Alright, let's go.
Come on.
Look.
That's the first game
we've seen in weeks.
Dare we invest a bullet
in some fresh meat?
I have exactly
three shots left.
- Let's vote on it.
- I'm awfully hungry.
Alright.
Don't miss.
Allan!
What are they saying?
I don't understand
a word of it.
It's a dialect
I've never heard before.
This explains Umbopa.
He's come home.
These are his people.
He says there was
a white man here.
Could've been Curtis. In fact,
it's almost a certainty.
Why?
Because they've never
seen a gun before.
Curtis had no gun.
I think your magic
frightened that one.
My guess is he's gone ahead
to warn the others.
It appears we've been
traveling with a king.
A what?
A king in rags, returning
home to claim a kingdom
that was stolen from him.
He says it's
the mark of a king.
Every time a king is born,
they carve that snake on him.
Says they belong to a tribe
called the Watussi.
They've offered
to lead us there.
The present king's Umbopa's
cousin, called Twala.
They say he's not a very nice
fellow. Bad king, cruel.
King Twala is not going to be
happy at the sight
of that snake.
We do seem to be traveling
with a cargo of dynamite.
It promises to be exciting.
Exciting?
I'm sorry.
He says there's a lot of
discontent here already.
Kafa, that's the old boy,
and some of the others
are fed up with
the present king.
There's a civil war brewing.
With Umbopa returning,
it may come to a head.
Incredible!
- I've seen them before.
- Where?
On the walls of Egyptian tombs,
exactly such cattle.
The old man said the Watussi
came here from the north.
The north could be Egypt.
Umbopa's gone.
It's unlike him
to have deserted us.
Do you suppose those two
were in league with the king?
Our reception committee.
So, Blue-Stripes
did announce our arrival.
Jack, you better shove
your half of the ammunition
up the spout.
How do we behave?
Friendly but aloof
and dignified.
They've heard about the magic of
our weapons, so show your guns.
Don't know what you're
talking about, old chap,
but lead on.
That's either
a speech of welcome
or an announcement
of our imminent death.
That wasn't very successful.
They don't understand
the usual dialects.
Have you seen white man?
White man? Curtis?
Wait a minute,
this is the place. This is it.
Look. Look on
the king's forehead.
You know what that is?
That's an uncut diamond.
Look. The old witch doctor's
wearing one, too.
If we're ever gonna find Henry
Curtis, this is the place.
Oh!
- Good shot.
- Now, we know their intentions.
They also know
the power of our gun.
But they don't know we've only
got one bullet left.
Curtis.
- Curtis?
- Curtis.
I hope that means he's gonna
take us to Curtis.
That's a chance
we'll have to take.
We've no other choice.
King Solomon's Mines.
Come on, get back!
Uh, it's hopeless.
We'll never dig
our way out of here.
The only end to this
is suffocation.
Torches.
We've been in here for ages.
The torches should be dying
for lack of air.
There's some air
coming in here somewhere.
It's here. Hold this.
Come on, pull.
Take a deep breath, all right?
- The drums of the Watussi.
- Celebrating our death.
Look, Elizabeth, can you go on?
The sooner we get out of here,
the better.
- Quick. Come on.
- Poor Umbopa.
He was very nearly a king.
Quick.
It's Umbopa.
The insurrection has started.
These are the rebels.
Well, we were expecting
a civil war, weren't we?
Umbopa says that according
to the customs of his people,
two claimants to the throne
must settle it by
hand-to-hand combat.
They discovered it saves
war and bloodshed.
- Do we go along?
- It'll be safer with them.
Here, take this. It's not
loaded, but nobody will know.
Come on.
This is where
the fun begins.
Look out!
It's all right now.
It's all over.
It seems we're gonna live.