No, son... never.
The blood stays on the blade.
One day you'll understand.
Some of it
I half remember.
And the rest...
the rest, I took from dreams.
St. Michael, the Archangel,
defend us in battle.
Be our protector...
against the snares...
and the wickedness
of the devil.
Now, son... who's that?
St. Michael.
Who is it?
- St. Michael!
- And what did he do?
He cast Satan out of Paradise.
Good boy.
May God put the steel of
the Holy Spirit in your spine
and the love of the
Blessed Virgin in your heart.
Hey, boyo.
Johnny.
What's the battle?
Natives against
the Dead Rabbits.
Which are you?
What do you think?
Dead Rabbits.
Aaah!
Aaah! Aaah!
Well, well, Monk...
Are you with us or not?
For the last time, Vallon, I'm
with you if the money is right.
I'll give you ten per notch.
Ten?
You have my word.
Ten per notch?
Per new notch.
Then I'm your man.
Is this it, Priest?
The pope's new army?
A few crusty bitches
and a handful of ragtags?
Now, Bill, you swore this was
a battle between warriors,
not a bunch of Miss Nancys.
So warriors is what I brought.
The O'Connell Guards!
The Plug Uglies!
The Shirt Tails!
The Chichesters!
The Forty Thieves!
Bene.
On my challenge...
by the ancient laws
of combat...
we have met
at this chosen ground
to settle, for good and all,
who holds sway
over the Five Points...
us Natives, born rightwise
to this fine land...
or the foreign hordes
defiling it!
Yeah!
By the ancient laws of combat,
I accept the challenge
of the so-called Natives.
You plague our people
at every turn.
But from this day out,
you shall plague us no more.
For let it be known
that the hand
that tries to strike us
from this land
shall be swiftly cut down!
Yeah!
Then may the Christian Lord
guide my hand
against your Roman popery!
Prepare to receive
the true Lord!
Yeah!
Aaah!
Aaaaahhhh!
Priest!
Look to me!
Who is this under my knife?!
Father, get up! Get up!
Where are you?
Oh, my son...
Don't never look away.
Soon be over, Priest.
Finish it.
Ugh!
You may need this
across the river.
Ears and noses will be
the trophies of the day.
But no hand shall touch him!
No hand shall touch him!
He'll cross over whole...
in honor.
Not before I get what's owed.
No!
It's fair...
a touch indelicate, but fair.
My sympathies.
What'll we do
with the boy?
Look at me.
Give him to the law.
See he gets a good education.
Okay, boy,
say goodbye to your father.
- Hey.
Hey!
Get him!
Don't let him get away!
Hurry! Come in here!
Aaah!
- Aaah!
- He's going downstairs.
Come here, boy!
You're going to
Hellgate, son!
There he is.
Let's get him.
Priest Vallon died
a noble death.
But his Dead Rabbits is done
and outlawed!
Let no one even speak their name
from this time on!
In this place,
you have grown
from a boy into a man...
put to death
the earthly things in you...
immorality, impurity...
passion, vengeance.
The Lord has forgiven you.
You also must forgive.
You go forth
to a country torn apart
by civil strife.
Thank you, Reverend.
Lend your hand to the work
that yet remains,
that this war may end,
and the plague of slavery
that brought this conflagration
down upon us
vanish forever...
from the Earth.
In the second year
of the great Civil War,
when the Irish Brigade
marched through the streets,
New York was a city
full of tribes...
war chiefs...
rich and poor.
Down with Lincoln!
Lincoln will make
all white men slaves!
It wasn't a city, really.
It was more a furnace
where a city, someday,
might be forged.
That's the spirit, boys.
Go off and die
for your blackie friends.
Down with
the abolitionists!
We should have run
a better man against Lincoln
when we had the chance.
New York should secede
from the Union!
He trying to say we're
no different than niggers?!
You ain't.
- Good evening, brother.
God save the Union!
There's the Union.
Go back to Africa, niggers!
Go back to Africa!
Leave him alone!
- We're free.
The angriest talk
was of the
new Conscription Act...
the first draft
in Union history.
No nig noggery here!
None!
Yeah!
"New York Tribune"!
Buy your "Tribune" here!
Join the Army, lads!
Three square meals a day
and good pay!
When the Irish came,
the city was in a fever.
Since the time
of the great famine,
they'd come streaming
off the boats.
And they got
a right warm welcome.
Go back to Ireland,
you dumb Micks!
You remember that,
you bog-Irish gyps!
Get back on the boat, Paddy!
I only came two hours
downriver from Hellgate.
But they all took me
for an immigrant. Why not?
There were a thousand different
accents in New York,
and to the Natives, you see...
It was all the same.
Seven curses of God on you,
you bastard!
Tammany's here to take
the chill off your soul
and the weight off your heart.
Welcome to America, son.
Your long,
arduous journey is over.
Go back
to your own country!
Vote Tammany!
America for Americans!
New York loved
William Tweed...
and hated him.
And those of us
trying to be thieves...
well, we couldn't help
but admire him.
Mr. Cutting, gentlemen,
thank you for coming.
- It's an honor.
Mr. Tweed.
Sir, please.
Excuse me!
I think
you're frightening them.
So?
Don't mind him.
He used to be an Irishman.
Ah, the Five Points...
Murderers' Alley...
Brickbat Mansion...
the Gates of Hell.
It was here
in this vile place.
Look upon the face
of this poor child.
She lives in squalor
in this godforsaken den
of vice and misery behind me.
Every year, the reformers came.
Every year,
the Points got worse...
as if it liked being dirty.
...degraded men and women.
Where am I going to go?!
Move! The Reverend
wants you out of here!
You can't do this!
Come on,
you filthy grubworm!
A glorious resurrection
will spring
from the filthy depths...
to which these miserable
creatures have fallen.
In God, they will find
their true home.
You may
or may not know, Bill,
that every day,
I go down to the waterfront
with hot soup for the Irish
as they come ashore.
It's part of building
a political base.
I've noticed you there.
You may have noticed me.
Indeed I have...
throwing torrents of pavers
and withering abuse
on every single person
who steps off those boats.
If only I had the guns,
I'd shoot every one of them
before they set foot
on American soil.
Mulberry Street...
and Worth...
Cross and Orange...
And Little Water.
Each of the Five Points
is a finger.
When I close my hand,
it becomes a fist.
And anytime that I wish,
I can turn it against you.
I understand, but we're talking
about different things.
I'm talking
about civic duty...
responsibilities
we owe to the people...
schools and hospitals,
sewers and utilities,
street construction,
repairs, and sweeping,
business licenses,
saloon licenses,
carting licenses...
St. Michael, the Archangel...
defend us in battle.
Be our protector against
the snares and the wickedness
of the devil.
Streetcars, ferries,
rubbish disposal...
There's a power of money
to be made in this city, Bill.
With your help...
the people must be made
to understand
that all these things
are best kept within,
what I like to call,
the Tammany family,
which is why I'm talking
about an alliance
between our two
great organizations.
You're talking
about muscle work.
That too.
Muscle to match our spirit!
You own the crushers.
Get them to do it.
The police? Oh, no.
Jesus, no.
The appearance of the law
must be upheld...
especially while
it's being broken.
Give me the strength
for what I must do.
Who are you?
- Ah!
Hey!
No.
I said, "Who are you?"
What are you doing here?
I just like it down here,
is all.
See what's
in his pockets, Jimmy.
Now, look, boys,
I really don't want a fight.
Don't want a fight?
Don't worry, son,
ain't gonna be much a fight.
Don't kill me.
Where'd you get that?
I told you
I didn't want to fight!
Why not?
Look how good you done.
You're the Priest's son,
aren't you?
You, get away from me,
understand?!
You don't remember me, do you?
I's the one tried to help you.
What?
I's the one
tried to help you...
when the Natives took you.
Oh, that was you?
Yeah.
I thought you was killed.
They just locked me up,
you know that?
This long?
But I kept trying to escape,
you know.
They add on time for that.
So what are
you doing back here?
I guess I missed the place.
Bowery Boys.
That's enough now.
Hey! Get back here!
The Five Points...
Paradise Square...
the streets here
are always lively of an evening.
Who are the gangs around now?
You got the Daybreak Boys
and the Swamp Angels.
They work the river,
looting ships.
The Frog Hollows
Shanghai Sailors
down around the Bloody Angle.
Shirt Tails was rough
for a while,
but they've become a bunch
of jackrolling dandies,
lolling around Murderers' Alley,
looking like Chinamen.
Hell-Cat Maggie... she tried
to open her own grog shop,
but she drunk up
all her own liquor
and got throwed out
on the street.
Beautiful.
Now she's on the lay
for anything.
There's the Plug Uglies.
They're from somewhere
deep in the old country.
Got their own language.
No one understands
what they're saying.
They love to fight the cops.
And the Night Walkers
of Ragpickers' Row...
they work on their backs
and kill with their hands.
They're so scurvy, only the
Plug Uglies will talk to them.
But who knows
what they're saying?
The Slaughter Housers
and the Broadway Twisters...
they're a fine bunch
of bingo-boys.
And the little
Forty Thieves...
I used to run with them
for a while
till they got took over
by Bendrick the Cockroach
and his Red-Eyed Buggers.
Bendrick carries a germ.
If you try to leave the gang,
he hacks up blood on you.
The lime-juicers
are nothing but a bunch
of rapacious grab-ups.
The True Blue Americans
call themselves a gang,
but all they do is stand around
on corners damning England.
If you believe one word
that the British say,
you're a fool.
Do any of them got the sand
of the Dead Rabbits?
You don't say that name.
That name died with your...
They've been outlawed.
When I was in the blockhouse,
the Chinks told me
that the Natives celebrate
their victory every year.
Is that true?
Aye, that they do.
It's quite the affair.
The Butcher himself's got to
invite you, or you don't go.
Oh! Aah!
Look where you're going,
Johnny.
You look stunned
and poorly, sir.
Quite a pair
of conversationists, aren't you?
Maybe not...
but we're deep thinkers.
Well...
Gentlemen, I leave you in the
grace and favor of the Lord.
Jenny... the finest
bludget in all the Points.
She is
a prim-looking stargazer.
Hmm.
But I'd check my pockets
if I was you...
'cause I do believe
she lifted your timepiece.
Whoo!
Well, I let her take it.
I let her take things
all the time.
Is that right?
We always liked
a good fire in the Points.
Fire!
You could generally
pick up a little swag,
and if the cops came along,
then you really got a show.
Vote Tammany!
The Municipal Police
fought the
Metropolitan Police.
The Metropolitan Police...
they fought the street gangs.
Hurry up, men, before
the Black Joke get there!
There were
37 amateur fire brigades,
and they all fought each other.
The Black Joke
are on their way, Tweed!
And they'll beat
the shite out of you.
Okay, boys!
Get the hose out!
It's the Black Joke!
Go get them, boys!
Give those Bowery Boys hell!
Quick, before
there's nothing left.
Go back to
the Bowery, you bums!
Stop them! For God's
sake, they're taking everything!
In your next time of trouble,
ma'am, call on Tammany first.
But it's not too late!
You can still save my house!
Whoo!
Let's go.
I thought you said
you was hungry!
Grab what you can!
Let's get out of here!
May I point out that this
building is burning to ashes?
And may I point out
that this area
is the province of my own
Americus Fire Brigade
and that you lot
belong only in the Bowery?
May I point out that you're
outmanned, outmaneuvered...
...and, in a moment, outfought.
Am I?
There's the Black Joke!
Let's take them on the cobbles!
Go spill some claret, boys!
Go on, Shorty,
have a nice muss!
Clear the way
for Bill the Butcher.
Okay, boys, to work!
What's the point?
The fire's near burned
anything of value inside.
Boys, forget that one!
Next building over!
Mustn't let it spread!
Take what you want
from that one!
What are you doing?
There's nothing wrong with
this one. This is my house!
Aah!
Johnny!
- Help!
Help!
Aah.
Come on!
Come on, Johnny! Get up!
Leave that!
You two,
out of the way!
His name's Amsterdam.
How's the beak?
Ain't so bad.
You, you got anything,
you give it up,
or you get out.
Is that it?
That's it.
Right, here's the rake...
everything comes here.
We fence it.
Johnny takes our tribute
to the Natives,
and we chop up
the winnings...
each to his equal portion
amongst the gang.
Does that meet
with your approval, Hellgate?
My approval?
What's the matter, Jack Sprat...
can't you think for yourself?
I'll slit your fucking throat!
Hey, come on!
You boys will settle with me
before settling with each other.
I come for my due and proper.
Oh...
Well, this ain't a bad haul.
You know when folks
start in to saying
to where the country's
going to hell?
I always tell them...
"You just look
at all the hard work
our fine young lads is doing
down in the Five Points. "
Oh, yeah...
Now, this is just the thing
for Mrs. Mulraney.
All right, there, Happy Jack,
leave us with something to
quarter to Bill the Butcher, eh?
Would you?
Not my favorite tune.
Thank you, boys.
You keep out of trouble, now.
Every year,
the Natives celebrated
the killing of my father
all over again...
...at Sparrow's Chinese Pagoda
in Mott Street.
The Chinks hated the Natives
worse than we did.
The drum rolls, and the Butcher
drinks a glass of fire.
When you kill a king...
you don't stab him in the dark.
You kill him where the
whole court can watch him die.
Hey, got any timber?
# As I walked down
To Chatham Street #
# A fair maid I did meet #
# She asked me
To see her home #
# She lived
In Bleecker Street #
# To me a-weigh, you Santee #
# My dear Annie #
# Oh, you New York girls #
# Can't you dance the polka? #
# To me a-weigh, you Santee #
# My dear Annie #
# Oh, you New York girls #
# Can't you dance the polka? #
# And when we got
To Bleecker Street #
# We stopped at 44 #
# Her mother and her sister #
# Dared to meet us
At the door #
# To me a-weigh, you Santee #
# My dear Annie #
# Oh, you New York girls #
# Can't you dance the polka? #
# To me a-weigh, you Santee #
Hey, Maggie.
Right ear or left ear?
Ah, give us a drink,
you eejit.
Help yourself.
To health.
# The liquor was
So awfully strong #
Two minutes!
Place your bets!
Gentlemen!
The match is due to commence.
The count to beat
is 25 rodents in 3 minutes.
Towser against the vermin!
Are the enumerators
satisfied?!
- 50!
- Yes!
Let them go!
# My dear Annie #
# Oh, you New York girls #
# Can't you dance the polka? #
# To me a-weigh, you Santee #
# My dear Annie #
# Oh, you New York girls #
Where are you going, boyo?
I'm here to pay tribute
to Bill.
Are you, now? Give it to me.
I'll give it to him.
No, thanks,
I'll give it to him myself.
Come on.
What do you want to keep,
the money or your teeth, boyo?
John...
Welcome.
# To me a-weigh, you Santee #
# My dear Annie #
# Oh, you New York girls #
# Can't you dance the polka? #
For me and me lads, sir.
Mate of yours...
where's he from?
Oh, he's not from here, sir.
You!
# To me a-weigh, you Santee #
# My dear Annie #
# Oh, you New York girls #
# Can't you dance the polka? #
# To me a-weigh, you Santee #
# My dear Annie #
# Oh, you New York girls #
# Can't you dance the polka? #
That's close enough.
# To me a-weigh, you Santee #
# My dear Annie #
# Oh, you New York girls #
Your friend can't look me
in the eye.
That's not an admirable
characteristic.
No one can look you
in the eye, Bill...
not when you're playing cards.
# To me a-weigh, you Santee #
# Oh, you New York girls #
This is whist.
This is a gentleman's game.
Make a gentleman's bet.
I'm betting large, Bill.
That ain't large.
Aaaah!
# Oh, you New York girls #
Shh... please, don't make
that noise again, Harvey.
# My dear Annie #
# Oh, you New York girls #
I like a man who's willing
to burn for his swag.
Aah!
How do you fare on water?
Come closer.
Close, John,
I ain't gonna bite. Close.
# My dear Annie #
# Oh, you New York girls #
There's a "Portageezy" ship
lying low in the harbor...
quarantined three weeks.
Get there before
the Daybreak Boys strip her,
maybe you and me
will talk some more.
- Consider it done, sir.
- Good boy.
And, you, whatever your name
is... what is your name?
Amsterdam, sir.
Amsterdam.
I'm New York.
Don't you never come in here
empty-handed again.
You gotta pay for the pleasure
of my company.
Take him for a boat ride,
John.
Who knows, but he might
save your life again.
Daybreak Boys
catch us on this river,
they'll slit our throats.
I'll do it myself
if you don't keep quiet.
I never liked
the harbor after dark.
And now each night,
they brung ashore the bodies
of the soldiers.
So many mothers
have not even the solace
of knowing where
their sons have fallen.
I lost my own eldest
at Antietam,
and his mother and I were unable
to recover his remains.
It was
a mournful sight...
The war can't last forever.
But we had
business of our own.
Ooh!
The Daybreak Boys
have already been here.
And there's nothing left.
Let's go back, eh?
What in the hell...
Jimmy, get down!
Jesus! That'll bring
the harbor cops for sure!
Look out!
Let's take a look.
Jesus, they killed everybody.
There's nothing here but
a bunch of dead sea-crabs.
Come on, let's go.
Shove off!
No, wait for Amsterdam!
Where's Amsterdam?
- Aah!
No, you damn fool, take him!
What in the hell for?!
Look at my glims...
I said no less than $15.
Is this fresh?
Four hours, most.
Much obliged, gents.
What's that word?
Uh... it means body snatchers.
I didn't ask the meaning.
I asked the word.
Ghoul.
Ghoul?
That's a good word.
"Ghoul Gang Slaughters.
A fresh out... outrage
in the Five Points. "
That's a notice
you can be proud of.
Thank you.
Low thing... to do that
to a body. Low.
Why? They could have left
that ship with nothing.
Instead, they made
the "Police Gazette,"
a periodical of note.
A body's supposed to stay
beneath the Earth...
wearing a wooden coat
until the resurrection.
These two are just a pair
of bug-eating sons of
Irish bitches same as you are.
Don't seem
to bother them none.
But then maybe they don't share
your religious scruples.
Maybe they're just
a couple of Fidlam Bens.
I've been called
a lot of things, mister,
but I ain't never been
called a...
Fidlam Bens.
Fidlam Bens, right.
Well... if I knew
what in the hell that meant,
might be inclined
to take offense.
Fidlam Bens is a fellow steals
anything, dead or alive,
'cause he's too low to work up
a decent lay for himself.
Count that careful, Butcher.
Count that careful.
I'm telling you...
that's all they give us.
Now, chiseler...
if you had said chiseler...
now, there's a word
I understand, you know?
Now, is that what
you're calling us?
Oh, I could think of a number
of things to call you, boyo.
Right, but I asked if
you was calling us chiselers.
Supposing I am?
Well, then, we got business.
That we do.
Two bucks on McGloin!
Four bits on the kid!
Five bits on the kid!
I got five on Amsterdam!
Come on, McGloin,
he's just a kid!
Four bits to back Amsterdam!
One!
Watch his left, McGloin.
Watch his left.
Aaah!
Aah! Aah!
Aah! Aaaaah!
All right, that'll do.
That'll do.
Have you got anything
to say now?! Huh?!
That'll do, for Christ's sake.
Drag him off.
That's enough, kid.
You got him.
Come on, kid. You won.
Don't make a fool of yourself.
You can't do it anymore.
You're getting too old
for it, McGloin.
McGloin,
how would that head look
without the ears
and the nose on it?
You had better leave
that head alone, Bill.
I think I'm gonna trim
the ears and the beak
off of that head.
Make a nice pot of soup
of that head.
We could find a tastier head
than that, Bill.
I ain't got the stomach
for no Irish stew.
The mighty McGloin...
almost fishhooked by a sprat.
On the seventh day,
the Lord rested.
But before that he did,
he squatted over
the side of England,
and what came out of him...
was Ireland.
No offense, son.
None taken, sir.
I grew up here.
All I ever knew of Ireland
was in the talk of the others
at the orphan asylum.
And which part of that
excrementitious isle
were your forebears spawned?
I've been told Kerry,
but I lost proof of it
in my language at the asylum.
I was raised in a very similar
establishment myself.
Now everything you see belongs
to me, to one degree or another.
The beggars and newsboys and
quick thieves here in Paradise,
the sailor dives
and gin mills
and blind tigers
on the waterfront,
the anglers and amusers,
the she-hes and the Chinks...
everybody owes,
everybody pays,
because that's
how you stand up
against the rising
of the tide.
Is that right, boys?
Yeah, Bill, that's right.
Enlist! Join up!
Serve your country!
Come on in
out of the draft, boys!
Volunteer
and get your $50 bonus!
We need 30,000 volunteers,
and we're prepared to pay
$677 per volunteer.
Please read this.
Thank you.
Would you like to take one of
these, please, to fill out?
Three square meals a day.
Young man, enlist
and serve your country.
Three square meals a day,
gentlemen.
If you're interested,
I suggest you read this
and consider joining up.
Everywhere you went,
people talked about
the draft.
Now, you could buy
your way out for $300,
but who had $300?
For us, it might as well
have been $3 millions.
The recruiters...
they was too scared of
the gangs to come after us.
Besides, we never dreamt the war
would ever touch New York.
Good morning, sir.
You!
Don't you run into me.
Fair enough.
Oh! Oh!
I said, "Don't run into me. "
Well, sorry.
Everything in place?
It seems so.
Well, then, I leave you in the
grace and favor of the Lord.
- That's right.
- Thank you.
Oh, the dirty mab!
- Oh, no.
- Ah.
- I'm sorry.
- Ah, allow me.
Thank you kindly, sir.
Oh, it's my pleasure.
I hope you won't think me
rude if I speak.
I wouldn't want to
appear forward.
Well, sir, that depends
on what you say.
Ahh...
Would you call me reckless
if I said you were the
prettiest girl in New York?
Only New York?
This is my stop.
Ho!
Ah! May I walk with you
a little, then?
That, sir, would be too bold.
Ho!
For every lay,
we had a different name.
An angler put a hook
on the end of a stick
to drop behind store windows
and doors.
An autumn diver picked
your pocket in church.
A badger gets a fellow
into bed with a girl,
then robs his pockets
while they're on the go.
Jenny was a bludget...
a girl pickpocket...
and... a turtledove.
A turtledove goes uptown
dressed like a housemaid,
picks out a fine house,
and goes right through
the back door...
robs you blind.
It takes a lot of sand
to be a turtledove.
I'll have my medal back.
Oh, Jesus!
Unh!
Don't do that again.
Aah! Listen, I said
don't do that...
Go back to the Points
and leave me to my business,
or I will open your throat,
so help me God.
All right.
Go on, then.
I would.
Now... give me back my medal.
Make it quick!
I don't know
which one's yours.
Suppose I help myself
to everything?
Huh?
Suppose you do.
May I walk with you
a little, then?
What do you suppose a fellow
could earn up here in a day?
Maybe we could pal in
together.
Oh, I think you're a bit rough
for this sort of game.
Besides, I work alone.
Alone?
Well, what do you quarter
to the Butcher?
Me... nothing.
Nothing?!
The Butcher and me
have a special arrangement.
I don't want to see you again.
Well, I don't blame you.
Pennies in their pockets
and hope in their eyes,
they peer to the west,
searching the horizon for a
glimpse of land and salvation...
Ah... a glimpse of America.
Seeing all this poverty
must be most unsettling,
Miss Schermerhorn.
Some days, of course,
the uptown gangs
come down to us.
The Schermerhorns was one
of the oldest families
in New York.
They didn't run the city,
but they was listened to quite
carefully by them that did.
Commissioner Brunt said
you wished to view the Points
in all its splendor
and squalor.
"Spare nothing concerning
the conditions," said he.
Yeah, nothing except
our safety, Constable.
I'm sure we can be
in no danger
while we're in the constable's
company, my dear.
Quite so, madam. Witness.
Shall we continue on?
What, you dare
to leave it there?
Safe as a bank, Mr. Greeley,
since all know it's mine.
Is that man drunk?
Oh, dead as Good Friday, miss.
Good day to you, Mulraney.
Boys.
- Jack.
Slum sociable?
Fact-finding, reforms-studying.
May I present Mr. And...
The Schermerhorns
of 5th Avenue
scarcely require
an introduction from you, Jack.
Schermerhorn, indeed,
and their daughter.
This gentleman,
of course, is...
Mr. Horace Greeley,
the famous publisher.
A pleasure and an honor,
sir.
...of the "Tribune. "
I'm William Cutting.
How do you do, Mr. Cutting?
As of this moment,
extremely well, thank you.
How do you do?
Mmm, orange blossom...
delicious.
Mr. Cutting is, uh...
What a peach. She could have
a fine career on the stage.
...one of Five Points'
local...
Pleasure to meet you, sir.
...leaders.
- Mr. Greeley...
Pleased to meet you,
Mr. Cutting.
Five Points welcomes you.
You are welcome to these streets
and will pass in safety.
Oh, I'll see to their safety.
Thank you, Bill.
Here we are.
Good day, lads.
Criminal's braggadocio,
you see.
- He knows who I am.
- Oh, indeed, sir.
You're well-known
in these parts.
I must say that I find that
strangely flattering.
I never did like crushers.
Well, draw it mild, son...
Happy Jack don't fill his lungs
without I tell him
he may do so.
# He'll spend at
The Odd Fellows' club #
# At the office or store,
He was kept #
# He'll pretend,
And so he was, too #
# Drinking rum with a friend #
You think my watch would be safe
up on that lamppost, Bill?
# At the office or store,
He was kept #
Why don't you hang it
up there and see?
# He'll pretend,
And so he was, too #
- Someday.
- # Drinking rum with a friend #
Someday is right.
# Fortune's a false
And a fickle young jade #
This a new lad?
Just another
bastard son of Erin
I folded in the warmth
of my embrace.
# And the best
Of all blessings #
Hey!
Just want to see
your face, son.
- # Is a kind, loving husband #
- No harm intended.
# And a good-tempered wife #
# And the best
Of all blessings #
# We can meet in this life #
# Is a kind, loving husband #
# And a good-tempered wife #
You get to know a lot
butchering meat.
We're made up
of the same things...
flesh and blood,
tissue, organs.
I love to work with pigs.
The nearest thing in nature
to the flesh of a man
is the flesh of a pig.
Pig, huh?
That's right.
This is for you, Mother.
Here you go.
- God bless you, Mr. Cutting.
- God bless you.
She ain't really my mother.
I knew that, Bill.
This is the liver...
the kidneys...
the heart.
This is a wound.
The stomach
will bleed and bleed.
This is a kill.
Main artery...
this is a kill.
You try.
Go ahead.
The lung. Good.
Don't foul the blade
on the rib.
Very good... main artery.
Bleed him slow.
Let him think about it
for a while... slow death.
Good.
You will each bill
the city $5,000 a month
for supplies and services,
of which you'll receive 10%.
Bill!
Mr. Killoran will work out the
details. Thank you, gentlemen!
That's how we do things
around Tammany, gentlemen.
Who's this, then?
Thank you, boys.
Good day, sir.
You got something
on your mind?
Bill's taken
quite a liking to you.
Now, if you're
up to something...
bene.
Only I don't want
no part in it.
I was in Hellgate
for 16 years.
I'm just trying
to make my way, is all...
just like you.
Unless, of course,
you got a better notion.
No.
Bill, I can't get
a day's work done
for all the good citizens
coming in here
to harass me
about crime in the Points.
Some even go so far as to
accuse Tammany of connivance
in this so-called
rampant criminality.
What am I to do?
I can't have this.
Something has to be done.
What do you have in mind?
I don't know.
I think maybe
we should hang someone.
Who?
No one important, necessarily.
Average men will do...
back-alley amusers
with no affiliations.
How many?
Three or four.
Which?
Four.
You stand here convicted
varyingly
of lewdness, jackrolling,
sneak-thievery,
chloral-hydrating, sodomy,
strangulation,
and enthusiastic corruption
of the public good.
We all go someday.
Chin up.
Handsome bunch
of gallows fruit.
There's my old friend.
How are you feeling, Arthur?
I'm okay, I'm okay,
you know?
Oh, say hello to Amsterdam.
Nearly fishhooked McGloin
the other day.
- Nearly.
- How do you do?
I see you dressed
for the occasion, Arthur.
You know me, Bill...
always like to look me best.
That's the spirit.
That's a nice locket.
I'll give you a dollar for it.
It's me mother's.
Dollar and a half?
Done.
We'll miss you, Arthur.
See you in the hot country,
Seamus.
Hot corn!
Ears of early white corn!
Hot corn! Hot corn!
Is my son present here?
Where's my little fella?
Look at your da.
Farewell, dear boy.
I never struck a foul blow,
nor turned a card!
May God greet me as a friend!
# ... heart to fear #
# And grace my fears relieved #
# How precious
did that grace appear #
That night,
the reformers held a dance.
That was the Five Points,
all right...
hangings of a morning,
dancings of an evening.
Ow!
...sure meself, but it's not
a matter of words.
I can tell by the way
she smiles at me.
Well, she smiles
at a lot of people, Johnny.
- Sir...
- You don't know her.
A penny of gratitude for
a fighting Irishman, young sir.
You're from Kerry?
I am, sir. I am.
Look, it ain't much.
Thank you, sir.
Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we are delighted to see
so many young faces
in our first annual
Mission dance.
This'll be
a real ballum rancum, eh?
The Mission welcomes Christians
of every stamp,
and we are
particularly happy
to greet
our Roman-Catholic friends
who join us here tonight.
Ladies, come with me.
Come with me.
Sit with us.
We're going to start
the dancing in just a moment.
Good evening, Reverend.
Good evening, Your Holiness.
Looks as though
you should have shaved closer.
Oh.
Good evening, Reverend.
I do beg your pardon.
Miss...?
Uh...
Everdeane.
Miss Everdeane.
Now, gentlemen, over here,
if you don't mind.
Thank you.
Open it.
Hold it up.
Into the mirror.
Hmm...
Mmm...
All right.
That one.
Our queen has chosen.
Sir...
your lady.
Right.
Regular services are held
at the church at 6:00 and 8:00.
Go to hell.
What do you think
you're doing?
I'm dancing.
I said why'd you pick me?
That's none of your business.
Would you mind telling me?
Ohh!
I'm sorry.
God damn it.
- Ow!
- Sorry.
I'm not much of a dancer.
Just try to keep calm.
I've never been
to a stepping-ken before.
It's best not to look down.
You can hold me tighter
if you like.
All right.
So, why didn't you dance
with Johnny?
Because...
...I didn't want him.
I'm not wanting this.
Mmm...
Wait.
What?
How does this open?
It takes too long
to lace back up.
We'll be here all night.
Sure, all right.
I'll take it off.
There was a baby.
They cut it out.
I'm sorry.
No, it's fine.
Have you got any scars?
One or two.
What's that, then?
That... is a gift
from Mr. Cutting.
A gift?
A gift.
Was it your birthday?
No.
What'd you give him, then?
The answer to that
has nothing to do with you.
Don't tell me
you're angry with me.
No.
I'm through with you.
Well... you're quicker
than most fellows.
Generally,
they wait till afterwards.
Well, I ain't interested
in the Butcher's leavings.
Hey! Bill says
keep clear of the pikers.
15 to 1, Bug-Eye Moran.
Amsterdam!
Everyone was
working for the Butcher.
We ran his errands,
made his money,
took a piece
and said, "Thank you, sir. "
Gentlemen, it's a raid.
Even Tweed.
The fight's over!
Even me...
...my father's son.
- What the hell is this?
- Sorry, Bill.
The city ordinance against
boxiana's a blight, I grant...
I'm losing revenue
while you speechify.
Get out there
and collect those bets!
Sir, how do I collect
if no one won the fight?
This counts as a no-decision.
You got that covered, right?
Didn't anybody pay off
the goddamn police?
We paid the Municipal Police.
This is the Metropolitan Police.
You are gonna repay me
every cent.
- Mister Tweed...
- Who asked for your opinion?!
Let him speak!
He don't answer to you!
The law says that there's
no boxing in the city.
That's right...
in the city.
Well, where's the city end?
The winner
in the 75th round...
Allow me
to acknowledge the man
whose vision and enterprise
made possible
the staging
of this noble combat
in these awe-inspiring and
entirely legal surroundings,
Mr. William Cutting!
And...
and his young associate!
Good.
You done very good.
Well, we done good.
We done all right.
And while I have
your kind attention...
It was a good show.
...may I remind you
of the further wonders
that await you at my museum,
located on Broadway...
P.T. Barnum's
Gallery of Wonders!
- Watch who you're shoving!
- Keep your hands to yourself!
That's my money!
Get your hands
out of me pocket!
Stop it! Stop it!
It's a funny feeling
being took under the wing
of a dragon.
It's warmer than you think.
That's the building
of our country
right there, Mr. Cutting...
Americans aborning.
I don't see no Americans.
I see trespassers...
Irish harps.
Do a job for a nickel
what a nigger does for a dime
and a white man
used to get a quarter for.
What have they done? Name
one thing they've contributed.
Votes.
Votes, you say?
They vote how the archbishop
tells them,
and who tells the archbishop?
Their king in the pointy hat
what sits on his throne in Rome.
Bill's got mixed feelings
as regards the Irish.
Bill... deliver
these good and fervent folk
to the polls
on a regular basis,
and there'll be
a handsome price
for each vote
that goes Tammany's way.
My father gave his life
making this country
what it is...
murdered by the British
with all of his men
on the 25th of July,
anno Domini 1814.
You think I'm gonna help you
befoul his legacy
by giving this country
over to them
what's had no hand
in the fighting for it?
Why? Because they come off
a boat,
crawling with lice
and begging you for soup?
Tsk, tsk.
You're a great one for
the fighting, Bill, I know.
But you can't fight forever.
- I can go down doing it.
- And you will.
What did you say?
I said you're turning
your back on the future.
Not our future.
That document makes you
a citizen.
This one makes you a private
in the Union Army.
Now go fight for your country.
Next!
# Well, meself
And a hundred more #
Sign here, son.
Or make your mark.
# To America sailed o'er #
# Our fortunes to be made,
We were thinkin' #
# When we got to Yankee land #
# They shoved a gun
Into our hands #
# Saying, "Paddy, you must go
And fight for Lincoln" #
There's your musket. Make sure
you keep it dry on the boat.
Same for the cartridge case.
Where are we going?
I heard Tennessee.
Where's that?
# There is nothing here
But war #
# Where the murderin'
Cannons roar #
# And I wish I was at home
In dear old Dublin #
Do they feed us now,
do you think?
My children!
My children...
we must heal
the divisions between us.
This war must cease.
North and South
must stand united!
You're a liar!
Rubbish!
What happens
at the finish, then?
Then we have ourselves
a rowdy-dow.
Ain't you never been
to the theater before?
Nah.
Mr. Legree,
lay down your whip.
Miss Eliza,
join hands with Mr. Shelby.
And, Topsy,
dear little Topsy,
cradle Uncle Tom's head.
Aw, leave the nigger dead!
Get me down!
Down with the Union!
For the blood of the Irish!
Bill, get down!
Somebody's popped the Butcher!
Get back!
Uhh!
Aaaaaaaaaaaah!
Stifle that rat bastard down!
God, forgive me.
Ohhh!
Aaaaaaah!
Whose man are you?
Speak smart and speak up.
What's he saying, boy?
I think he's making
his peace with God.
The hell with that.
He makes his peace with me.
I'm hearing confession tonight,
you mother-whoring Irish nigger!
Whose man are you?
We speak English in this
country! Whose man are you?
You see this knife?
I'm gonna teach you to speak
English with this fucking knife!
Whose man are you?!
Well, that didn't tell us
very much.
Fine waistcoat.
Shame about it.
I don't think it can be mended.
Will I keep it
as a souvenir?
Yeah!
Where's Legree?
Where's Mopsy?
Tragedians, let's continue.
Intermission is over!
Yeah!
Now, that was
bloody Shakespearean.
What?
Do you know
who Shakespeare was, sonny?
He was the fellow who wrote
the King James Bible.
Mister, I don't know what in
the hell you're talking about.
That's because you're a thick,
ignorant, barbarous Irish whelp,
just like your father.
That's it! That's it!
Tear my head off
and destruct the world,
just like the rest of the stupid
Irish in this country.
That's why I never ran
with your dad.
Get off me,
you crazy bastard!
It means,
"If you're not strong,
you'd better be smart. "
Now, I don't know if you're
being too clever or too dumb,
but whichever it is,
just remember this much...
for all his faults,
your father was a man
who loved his people.
Amsterdam! Amsterdam!
New York is calling you!
Look at that.
What in Christ's name is that?
Rhythms of the Dark Continent
thrown into the kettle
with an Irish shindig.
Stir it around a few times,
pull it out,
it's a fine American mess.
A jig doing a jig.
Little keepsake.
Good on you, sir.
Come upstairs with me, Bill.
Have I ever had you before?
So you don't call me
by my Christian name.
Bill! Thank God
you're all right!
I heard the news and came over
as quick as I could.
You're as timely
as the Angel of Death.
Bill, you're not suggesting
that I would stoop to...
what you're suggesting?
Stop slabbering.
If I thought it was you,
you'd be in a wooden coat.
But I got a hole in
my shoulder, and it hurts,
so have a drink and shut up,
or shut up and get out.
I believe I'll have a drink.
Careful, Tweedy.
The mort's frenchified.
No! I'm clean.
Come on.
Let's go to the bar.
Jenny.
Bill.
I best wrap you up.
Ohhhhh!
It's got to be tight.
She loves to make me cry.
You can take it.
There's my boy.
Mmm...
It's all right.
To the Butcher.
We're all much obliged.
Forever.
- To the Butcher.
Why don't you
get out of here, Johnny.
Go on. Go.
Is there anyone in the
Five Points you haven't fucked?!
Yes! You!
Why, you little...
Aaaah!
Calm down!
Try it and I'll bite you!
If you were gonna bite me...
I don't think
you'd warn me, huh?
Find out!