Morning in Paris
The city awakes
To the bells of Notre Dame
The fisherman fishes
The baker man bakes
To the bells of Notre Dame
To the big bells
as loud as the thunder
To the little bells
soft as a psalm
And some say the soul
of the city's the toll
Of the bells
The bells of Notre Dame
Listen. They're beautiful, no?
So many colours of sound,
so many changing moods.
Because, you know, they
do not ring all by themselves.
- They don't?
- No, you silly boy.
Up there, high,
high in the dark bell tower...
Lives the mysterious
bell ringer.
- Who is this creature?
- Who?
- What is he?
- What?
- How did he come to be there?
- How?
- Hush.
- Ow.
Clopping will tell you.
It is a tale...
a tale of a man
and a monster.
Dark was the night
when our tale was begun
- On the docks near Notre Dame
- Shut it up, will you?
- We'll be spotted!
- Hush, little one.
Four frightened Gypsies
slid silently under
The docks near Notre Dame
Four guilders
for safe passage into Paris.
A trap had been laid
for the Gypsies
And they gazed up
in fear and alarm
At a figure whose clutches
were iron as much as the bells
Judge Claude Frollo!
The bells
Of Notre Dame
Judge Claude Frollo longed
to purge the world of vice and sin
And he saw corruption
everywhere except within
Bring these Gypsy vermin
to the Palace of Justice.
- You, there! What are you hiding?
- Stolen goods, no doubt.
Take them from her.
She ran!
Sanctuary!
Please, give us sanctuary!
A baby?
A monster!
- Stop!
- Cried the archdeacon.
This is an unholy demon. I'm sending it
back to hell, where it belongs.
See, there, the innocent blood
you have spilt
On the steps Of Notre Dame
I am guiltless.
She ran. I pursued.
Now you would add this child's blood
to your guilt
- On the steps Of Notre Dame
- My conscience is clear.
You can lie to yourself
and your minions
You can claim
that you haven't a qualm
But you never can run from
Nor hide what you've done
from the eyes
The very eyes
Of Notre Dame
And for one time in his life
of power and control
Frollo felt a twinge of fear
for his immortal soul
- What must I do?
- Care for the child,
and raise it as your own.
What? I am to be saddled
with this misshapen--
Very well, but let him live
with you in your church.
- Live here? Where?
- Anywhere.
Just so he's kept locked away
where no one else can see
The bell tower, perhaps.
And who knows? Our Lord
works in mysterious ways.
Even this foul creature
may yet prove one day to be
Of use to me
And Frollo gave the child
a cruel name...
a name that means
"half-formed."
Quasimodo.
Nowhere is a riddle
to guess if you can
Sing the bells Of Notre Dame
Who is the monster
and who is the man
Sing the bells, bells
bells, bells
Bells, bells
Bells Of Notre Dame
Good morning.
Will today be the day?
Are you ready to fly?
You sure?
Good day to try.
Why, if-if I picked a day to fly,
oh, this would be it.
The Festival of Fools.
It will be fun, with jugglers
and-and-and music and dancing.
Go on. Nobody wants to be
cooped up here for ever.
Man! I thought he'd never leave.
I'll be spittin' feathers for a week.
Well, that's what you get
for sleeping with your mouth open.
Go scare a nun. Hey, Quasi,
what's goin' on out there?
- A fight? A flogging?
- A festival.
- You mean the Feast of Fools?
- Uh-huh.
- All right, all right!
Pour the wine
and cut the cheese.
It is a treat to watch the colourful
pageantry of the simple peasant folk.
Boy, nothin' like balcony seats
for watching the ol' F.O.F.
- Yeah, watchin'.
- Oh, look. A mime.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
What gives?
Aren't you going to watch
the festival with us?
- I don't get it.
- Perhaps he's sick.
Impossible. If 20 years
of listenin' to you two...
hasn't made him sick by now,
nothin' will.
But watching
the Festival of Fools...
has always been the highlight
of the year for Quasimodo.
What good is watchin' a party
if you never get to go?
Here, get away from me!
Go on, ya bunch of buzzards.
He's not made of stone,
like us.
Quasi, what's wrong? You wanna tell
ol' Laverne all about it?
I-- I just don't feel like
watching the festival, that's all.
Well, did ya ever think
of goin' there instead?
Sure, but I'd never
fit in out there.
I'm not normal.
Oh, Quasi, Quasi, Quasi.
Do ya mind? I would like
to have a moment...
with the boy,
if it's all right with you!
Hey, quit beatin' around the bell tower.
What do we gotta do?
- Paint ya a fresco?
- As your friends and guardians...
we insist
you attend the festival.
- Me?
- No, the pope. Of course, you!
It would be a veritable potpourri
of educational experience.
- Wine, women and song.
- You can learn...
to identify
various regional cheeses.
- Bobbin' for snails.
- Study indigenous folk music.
- Playin' Dunk the Monk!
- Quasi, take it from an old spectator.
Life's not a spectator sport.
If watchin'
is all you're gonna do...
then you're gonna watch
your life go by without ya.
Yeah, you're human, with the flesh
and the hair and the navel lint.
We're just part
of the architecture, right, Victor?
Yet, if you kick us, will we not flake?
If you moisten us, do we not grow moss?
Quasi, just grab a fresh tunic
and a clean pair of hose, and--
Thanks for the encouragement,
but you're all forgetting one big thing.
- What?
- My master Frollo.
- Oh.
- Oh, yeah.
- Oh, dear, yes.
W-Well, when he says you're forbidden
from ever leaving the bell tower...
d-does he mean "ever" eve r?
Never eve r. And he hates
the Feast of Fools.
- He'd be furious if I asked to go.
- Who says ya gotta ask?
- Oh, no.
- Ya sneak out--
- It's just one afternoon.
- I-l couldn't.
- And ya sneak back in.
- He'll never know you were gone.
- And if I got caught.
- Better to beg forgiveness
than ask permission.
- He might see me.
- You could wear a disguise.
Just this once. What Frollo
doesn't know can't hurt ya.
- Ignorance is bliss.
- Look who's talkin'.
Nobody wants to stay
cooped up here for ever.
- You're right. I'll go.
- Oh, boy !
- Oh, hurrah!
- I'll get cleaned up.
- Yea!
- Yes, sir!
- I'll stroll down those stairs.
- There ya go!
I'll march through the doors and--
Good morning, Quasimodo.
Oh, good m-morning, Master.
Dear boy,
whomever are you talking to?
My...
friends.
I see. And what are your
friends made of, Quasimodo?
Stone.
Can stone talk?
- No, it can't.
- That's right.
You're a smart lad.
Now, lunch.
Shall we review
your alphabet today?
Oh, yes, Master.
I would like that very much.
- Very well. "A"?
- Abomination.
- " B"?
- Blasphemy?
- "C"?
- C-C-Contrition.
- " D"?
- Damnation?
- " E "?
- Eternal damnation.
- Good. " F"?
- Festival.
- Excuse me?
- F-F-Forgiveness.
- You said "festival."
- No!
You are thinking
about going to the festival.
I-It's just that
you go every year.
I am a public official.
I must go.
But I don't enjoy a moment.
Thieves and cut purses,
the dregs of humankind...
all mixed together
in a shallow, drunken stupor.
I didn't mean
to upset you, Master.
Quasimodo,
can't you understand?
When your heartless mother
abandoned you as a child...
anyone else
would have drowned you.
And this is my thanks for taking you in
and raising you as my son?
I'm sorry, sir.
Oh, my dear Quasimodo.
You don't know
what it's like out there.
I do. I do.
The world is cruel
The world is wicked
It's I alone whom you can trust
in this whole city
I am your only friend
I who keep you, teach you
feed you, dress you
I who look upon you
without fear
How can l protect you, boy
unless you always stay in here
A way in here
Remember what
I've taught you, Quasimodo.
- You are deformed
- I am deformed
-And you are ugly
-And l am ugly
And these are crimes
for which the world shows little pity
- You do not comprehend
- You are my one defender
Out there they'll
revile you as a monster
I am a monster
Out there they will hate
and scorn and jeer
Only a monster
Why invite their calumny
and consternation
Stay in here
- Be faithful to me
- I'm faithful
- Grateful to me
- I'm grateful
Do as l say
Obey
-And stay in here
- I'll stay in here
You are good to me, Master.
I'm sorry.
You are forgiven.
But remember, Quasimodo,
this is your sanctuary.
My sanctuary.
Safe behind these windows
and these parapets of stone
Gazing at the people
down below me
All my life I watch them
as l hide up here alone
Hungry for the histories
they show me
All my life
l memorise their faces
Knowing them
as they will never know me
All my life I wonder
how it feels to pass a day
Not above them
But part of them
And out there
Living in the sun
Give me one day
out there
A Ill ask is one
To hold for ever
Out there
Where they all live unaware
What I'd give
What I'd dare
Just to live
one day
Out there
Out there among the millers
and the weavers and their wives
Through the roofs and gables
I can see them
Every day they shout and scold
and go about their lives
Heedless of the gift it is
to be them
If l was in their skin
I'd treasure every instant
Out there
Strolling by the Seine
Taste the morning
Out there
Like ordinary men
Who freely walk about there
Just one day and then
I swear I'll be content
With my share
Won't resent
Won't despair
Old and bent
I won't care
I'll have spent
One day
Out there
Hmm. Uh-uh. You leave town
for a couple of decades...
and they change everything.
Excuse me, gentlemen, I'm looking
for the Palace of Justice.
Would you--
Mmm. I guess not.
What are you trying to say to me?
That the pants do not--
They fit.
- Ahh!
- Stay away, child.
They're Gypsies.
They'll steal us blind.
All right, Gypsy.
Where'd ya get the money?
- For your information, I earned it.
- Gypsies don't earn money.
- They steal it.
- You'd know a lot about stealing.
Troublemaker, huh?
Maybe a day in the stocks
will cool ya down.
Come back here, Gypsy !
- Achilles, sit.
- Hey-- Whoa!
Oh, dear, I'm sorry.
Naughty horse! Naughty !
He's just impossible.
Really, I can't take him anywhere.
Get this thing off me!
I'll teach you a lesson,
peasant!
You were saying,
Lieutenant?
Oh, uh-uh.
C-C-Captain!
Ow! At your service, sir.
I know you have a lot on your mind
right now, but the Palace of Justice?
- Make way for the Captain.
- Go on, make way !
Make way.
Everybody out of the way.
You, make way for the Captain!
- Make way.
- Make way now.
Come on, boy.
Achilles, heel!
- Stop.
- Sir?
Ease up.
Wait between lashes.
Otherwise the old sting
will dull him to the new.
Yes, sir.
Ah, so this is the gallant
Captain Phoebus, home from the wars.
Reporting for duty
as ordered, sir.
Your service record
precedes you, Phoebus.
I expect nothing but the best
from a war hero of your calibre.
And you shall have it, sir.
I guarantee it.
Yes. You know, my last
Captain of the Guard was, um...
a bit of a disappointment to me.
Well, no matter. I'm sure
you'll whip my men into shape.
Uh, thank you. It's a grea-- uh, tre--
uh, tremendous honour, sir.
You've come to Paris
in her darkest hour, Captain.
It will take a firm hand to save the
weak-minded from being so easily misled.
- Misled, sir?
- Look, Captain.
Gypsies. The Gypsies live
outside the normal order.
Their heathen ways inflame
the people's lowest instincts.
And they must be stopped.
I was summoned from the wars to capture
fortune-tellers and palm readers?
Eh, the real war, Captain,
is what you see before you.
For 20 years, I have been
taking care of the Gypsies...
one by one.
And yet, for all my success,
they have thrived.
I believe they have a safe have n
within the walls of this very city.
A-A nest, if you will.
They call it the Court of Miracles.
What are we going to do
about it, sir?
You make your point
quite vividly, sir.
You know, I like you, Captain.
Shall we?
Oh, duty calls. Have you ever attended
a peasant festival, Captain?
Not recently, sir.
Then this should be quite
an education for you. Come along.
Come, one
Come, all
Leave your looms
and milking stools
Coop the hens
and pen the mules
Come, one
Come, all
Close the churches
and the schools
It's the day
for breaking rules
Come and join the Feast
Of
Fools
Once a year we throw a party
here in town
Once a year we turn all Paris
upside-down
Every man's a king
and every king's a clown
Once again
it's Topsy-turvy Day
It's the day the devil in us
gets released
It's the day we mock the prig
and shock the priest
Everything is topsy-turvy
at the Feast of Fools
Topsy-turvy
Everything is upsy-daisy
Everybody's acting crazy
Dross is gold
and weeds are a bouquet
That's the way
on Topsy-turvy Day
Whoa!
Hey! Are you all right?
I-l didn't mean to.
I-l'm sorry.
Oh, you're not hurt, are you?
Here, here, let's see.
- No, no! N-No!
- There.
See? No harm done.
-Just try to be a little more careful.
- I-l-- I-l will.
By the way, great mask.
Topsy-turvy
Beat the drums
and blow the trumpets
Topsy-turvy
Join the bums
and thieves and strumpets
Streaming in
from Chartres to Calais
Scurvy knaves are extra scurvy
on the Sixth of Janu-ervy
All because
it's Topsy-turvy Day
Come, one
Come, all
Hurry, hurry
Here's your chance
See the mystery
and romance
Come, one
Come, all
See the finest girl
in France
Make an entrance
to entrance
Dance
La Esmeralda
- Look at that disgusting display.
- Yes, sir.
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
the pièce de résistance!
Here it is
The moment you've been waiting for
You know exactly what's in store
Now's the time we laugh
until our sides get sore
Now's the time
we crown the King of Fools
You all remember
last year's king
So make a face
that's horrible and frightening
- Make a face that's gruesome
as a gargoyle's wing
- Hey !
For the face that's ugliest
will be the King of Fools
- Why?
- Topsy-turvy
- Ugly folks, forget your shyness
You could soon be called
Your Highness
Put your foulest features
on display
Be the King
of Topsy-turvy Day
Boo!
- Bleah!
- Boo!
- That's no mask.
- It's his face!
- He's hideous!
- It's the bell ringer from Notre Dame!
Oh! Oh! Oh!
Ladies and gentlemen,
don't panic.
We asked for the ugliest face
in Paris, and here it is!
Quasimodo,
the hunchback of Notre Dame!
Everybody
Once a year
- We throw a party here in town
- Whoa!
- Where fools are king
- Once a year
- We turn all Paris upside-down
- Oh, what a king
Once a year
the ugliest will wear a crown
- Girls, give a kiss
- Right here on Topsy-turvy Day
We've never had a king like this
And it's the day we do the things
that we deplore
On the other
three hundred and sixty-four
Once a year we love to drop in
where the beer is never stoppin'
- For the chance
to pop some popinjay
- Oh!
And pick a king
who'll put the "top" in
Topsy-turvy
Mad-and-crazy
Upsy-daisy
Topsy-turvy Day
Quasimodo! Quasimodo! Quasimodo!
- You think he's ugly now? Watch this.
- Quasimodo! Quasimodo! Quasimodo!
Oh!
Now that's ugly!
- Hail to the King!
- Oh!
- Bon appétit!
Whoa!
Where are you goin',
hunchback?
The fun's just beginning.
Master!
Master, please.
Help me!
Sir, request permission
to stop this cruelty.
In a moment, Captain.
A lesson needs to be learned here.
Don't be afraid.
I'm sorry.
This wasn't supposed
to happen.
You! Gypsy girl!
Get down at once!
Yes, Your Honour. Just as soon
as I free this poor creature.
I forbid it!
How dare you defy me!
You mistreat this poor boy
the same way you mistreat my people.
You speak of justice, yet you are cruel
to those most in need of your help.
- Silence!
-Justice!
Mark my words, Gypsy.
You will pay for this insolence.
Then it appears
we've crowned the wrong fool.
The only fool I see
is you!
Captain Phoebus,
arrest her.
Now, let's see. One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight, nine.
So there's ten of you and one of me.
What's a poor girl to do?
- Witch craft !
- Oh, boys. Over here.
- There she is!
- Get her!
I'm free. I'm free.
Dang it.
Whoa!
What a woman!
Find her, Captain.
I want her alive.
Yes, sir.
Seal off the area, men.
Find the Gypsy girl,
and do not harm her.
I am sorry, Master.
I will never disobey you again.
- Oh!
- Stand back. Stand back.
Stand back.
He's coming.
Oh, he's hideous. I--
- Maybe over there.
- You, there. Get away.
- Move on, peasant!
- Hmm.
Uh. Oh, you!
Easy, easy.
I-l-l just shaved this morning.
- Oh, really? You missed a spot.
- All right, all right.
J-Just c-calm down.
Just give me a chance to apologise.
For what?
- That, for example.
- You sneaky son of a--
Ah, ah, ah. Watch it.
You're in a church.
Are you always this charming,
or am I just lucky?
Whoa!
Candlelight,
privacy, music.
Can't think of a better place
for hand-to-hand combat.
Ooh! You fight
almost as well as a man.
Funny, I was going to say
the same thing about you.
That's hitting a little below
the belt, don't you think?
No, this is.
Touché. Ohh!
I didn't know
you had a kid.
Well, he doesn't
take kindly to soldiers.
Eh, I noticed.
Ah, permit me.
I'm Phoebus.
It means "sun god."
- And you are?
- Is this an interrogation?
I believe it's called
an introduction.
-You're not arresting me?
-Not as long as you're in here. I can't.
- Huh. You're not at all
like the other soldiers.
- Thank you.
So, if you're not going
to arrest me, what do you want?
I'd settle for your name.
- Esmeralda.
- Beautiful.
And much better than
Phoebus, anyway.
Good work, Captain.
Now, arrest her.
Claim "sanctuary."
- Say it!
- You tricked me.
I'm waiting, Captain.
I'm sorry, sir. She claimed "sanctuary."
There's nothing I can do.
Then drag her
outside and--
Frollo, you will not
touch her!
Don't worry.
Minister Frollo learned years ago...
to respect the sanctity
of the Church.
All right, all right.
I'm going.
You think you've outwitted me...
but I'm a patient man...
and Gypsies don't do well
inside stone walls.
What are you doing?
I was just imagining a rope
around that beautiful neck.
I know what you were imagining.
Such a clever witch.
So typical of your kind
to twist the truth...
to cloud the mind
with unholy thoughts.
Well, no matter.
You've chosen a magnificent prison.
But it is a prison, nonetheless.
Set one foot outside...
and you're mine.
Frollo's orders.
Post a guard at every door.
Don't worry, Djali. If Frollo thinks
he can keep us here, he's wrong.
Don't act rashly, my child.
You created quite a stir
at the festival.
It would be unwise to arouse
Frollo's anger further.
You saw what he did out there,
letting the crowd torture that poor boy.
I thought if just one person
could stand up to him, then w--
Huh. What do they have against people
who are different, anyway?
You can't right all the wrongs
of this world by yourself.
Well, no one out there
is going to help, that's for sure.
Well, perhaps there's someone
in here who can.
I don't know
if you can hear me
Or if you're even there
I don't know
if you would listen
To a Gypsy's prayer
Yes, l know
I'm just an outcast
I shouldn't speak to you
Still, l see your face
and wonder
Were you once
An outcast too
God, help the outcasts
Hungry from birth
Show them the mercy
They don't find on earth
God, help my people
We look to you still
God, help the outcasts
Or nobody will
I ask for wealth
I ask for fame
I ask for glory
To shine on my name
I ask for love
I can possess
I ask for God and His angels
To bless me
I ask for nothing
I can get by
But l know so many
Less lucky than I
Please help my people
The poor and down trod
I thought we all were
The children of God
God, help the outcast
Children of
God
You! Bell ringer!
What are you doing down here?
Oh!
Haven't you caused
enough trouble already?
Wait.
I-l want
to talk to you.
Look, h-he's got
a friend with him.
Yeah. Maybe today wasn't
a total loss after all.
- A vision of loveliness.
- The one in the dress ain't bad either.
- Hurray !
- Way to go, Quasi!
- Congratulations!
- We knew you had it in ya.
- Got the girls chasin' ya already.
- A-A-Actually, l--
You mustn't run too fast,
or she'll get away.
Yes, l-l-l-l know.
That's what l--
Give her some slack,
then reel her in.
Then give her some slack,
- Then give her some slack--
- Knock it off, Hugo.
She's a girl,
not a mackerel.
Here you are.
- I was afraid I'd lost you.
- Yes.
Well, l, uh--
I have chores to do.
I-l-l-lt was nice
seeing you again.
- Oh!
- N-No, wait!
I'm really sorry about this afternoon.
I had no idea who you were.
I-l would never in my life
have pulled you...
up on the...
stage.
- What is this place?
- This is where I live.
Did you make
all these things yourself?
- Most of them.
- This is beautiful.
Oh, if I could do this,
you wouldn't find me dancing
in the streets for coins.
- But you're a wonderful dancer.
- Well, it keeps bread on the table,
anyway.
- What's this?
- Oh! No, please! l-l-l--
I-l'm not finished.
I-l-l still have to paint them.
It's the blacksmith.
And the baker!
You're a surprising person,
Quasimodo.
Not to mention lucky.
All this room to yourself.
Well, it's not just me.
There's the gargoyles...
and, of course, the bells.
- Would you like to see them?
- Yes, of course. Wouldn't we, Djali?
Follow me.
I'll introduce you.
I never knew
there were so many.
That's Little Sophia. And Jeane-Marie,
Anne-Marie, Louise-Marie.
- Triplets, you know.
- And who's this?
- Big Marie.
- Hello!
She likes you.
Would you like to see more?
How about it, Djali?
- We'd love to.
- Good. I've saved the best for last.
Oh!
I bet the king himself
doesn't have a view like this.
I could stay
up here forever.
- Y-You could, you know.
- No, I couldn't.
- Oh, yes, you have sanctuary.
- But not freedom.
Gypsies don't do well
inside stone walls.
But y-y-you're not like other Gypsies.
They are evil.
- Who told you that?
- My master Frollo. He raised me.
How can such a cruel man
have raised someone like you?
Cruel? Oh, no.
He saved my life.
He took me in when no one else would.
I am a monster, you know.
- He told you that?
- Look at me.
- Give me your hand.
- Why?
-Just let me see it.
Hmm. A long life line.
Oh, and this one
means you're shy.
Hmm. Hmm, mmm, mmm.
- Well, that's funny.
- What?
- I don't see any--
- Any what?
Monster lines.
Not a single one.
Now, you look at me.
Do you think I'm evil?
No! No-No. You-You are kind
and good and-and--
And a Gypsy. And maybe Frollo's wrong
about the both of us.
- What did she say?
- Frollo's nose is long,
and he wears a truss.
Ha! Told ya.
Pay up.
- Oh, dear.
- Chump.
You helped me.
Now I will help you.
But there's no way out.
There're soldiers at every door.
- We won't use a door.
- You mean, climb down?
- Sure. You carry him, I carry you.
- Okay.
Come on, Djali.
- Ready?
- Yes.
- Don't be afraid.
I'm not afraid.
- Now I'm afraid.
- The trick is not to look down.
- You've done this before?
- No.
- Wow, you're quite an acrobat.
- Thank you.
- Whoa!
- Check the alley !
- This way.
- I hope I didn't scare you.
- Not for an instant.
I'll never forget you, Esmeralda.
- Come with me.
- What?
- To the Court of Miracles.
- Leave this place.
- Oh, no.
I'm never going back out there again.
You saw what happened today.
No. This is where I belong.
- All right, then I'll come to see you.
- Here? But the soldiers and Frollo!
- I'll come after sunset.
- But at-at-at sunset...
I ring the evening mass, a-and after
that I clean the cloisters...
a-and then I ring the vespers, and--
- Whatever's good for you.
- If you ever need sanctuary,
this will show you the way.
- But how?
-Just remember...
when you wear this woven band,
you hold the city in your hand.
- Keep your eyes open.
- Hurry. You must go.
- Check the alley.
- Yes, sir.
- No one's here, sir.
- No one here, sir.
Check the street.
Hi, there. I'm looking
for the Gypsy girl. Have you seen her?
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Easy !
No soldiers !
Sanctuary! Get out!
- Wait! All I want is to--
- Go!
- I mean her no harm.
You tell her for me,
I didn't mean to trap her here...
but it was the only way
I could save her life.
Will you tell her that?
- Will you?
- If you go. Now !
I'll go. Now, will you
put me down, please?
Oh, and one more thing.
Tell Esmeralda she's very lucky.
- Why?
- To have a friend like you.
Hey, hey! There he is!
- Yeah!
- Ooh, wonderful! Bravo! Fantissimo!
- Ooh-hoo!
You ejected that tin-plated
buffoon with great panache.
The nerve of him, snoopin' around here,
tryin' to steal your girl.
- My girl?
- Esmeralda. Dark hair,
works with a goat, remember?
Boy, I do.
Way to go, lover boy !
" Lover boy"?
Oh, no, no, no, no.
Oh, don't be so modest.
Look, I appreciate
what you're all trying to do.
But let's not fool ourselves.
" Ugliest face in all Paris,"
remember?
I don't think
I'm her type.
So many times out there
I've watched a happy pair
Of lovers
walking in the night
They had a kind of glow
around them
It almost looked like
heaven's light
I knew I'd never know
That warm and loving glow
Though l might wish
with all my might
No face as hideous
as my face
Was ever meant
for heaven's light
But suddenly an angel
has smiled at me
And kissed my cheek
without a trace off right
I dare to dream that she
Might even care for me
-And as l ring
these bells tonight
- Eh?
My cold, dark tower
seems so bright
I swear
it must be heaven's light
You know l am
a righteous man
Of my virtue
l am justly proud
You know
I'm so much purer than
The common, vulgar
weak, licentious crowd
Then tell me, Maria
Why l see her
dancing there
Why her smouldering eyes
still scorch my soul
I feel her
l see her
The sun caught
in her raven hair
Is blazing in me
out of all control
Like fire
Hellfire
This fire in my skin
This burning desire
Is turning me
to sin
It's not my fault
I'm not to blame
It is the Gypsy girl
The witch who set this flame
It's not my fault
if in God's plan
He made the devil
so much stronger than a man
Protect me, Maria
Don't let this siren
cast her spell
Don't let her fire
sear my flesh and bone
Destroy Esmeralda
And let her taste
the fires of hell
Or else let her be mine
and mine alone
Minister Frollo,
the Gypsy has escaped.
- What?
- She's nowhere in the cathedral.
- She's gone.
- But how?
I--
Never mind.
Get out, you idiot.
I'll find her.
I'll find her if I have
to burn down all of Paris.
Hellfire
Dark fire
No w, Gypsy
It's your turn
Choose me
or your pyre
Be mine
or you will burn
God have mercy on her
God have mercy on me
But she will be mine
Or she
Will
Burn
'Tention!
Good morning, sir.
Are you feeling all right?
I had a little trouble
with the fire place.
- I see. Your orders, sir?
- Find the Gypsy girl.
Ten pieces of silver
for the Gypsy, Esmeralda.
Lock them up.
Twenty pieces of silver
for the Gypsy, Esmeralda.
Take them away.
Poor miller.
He's never harmed anyone.
Frollo's gone mad.
We found this Gypsy talisman
on your property.
Have you been harbouring Gypsies?
Our home is always open
to the weary traveller.
- Have mercy, my lord .
- I am placing you and your family...
under house arrest until
I get to the bottom of this.
If what you say is true and you are
innocent, then you have nothing to fear.
But we are innocent. I assure you.
We know nothing of these Gypsies.
- Burn it.
- What?
Until it smoulders. These people are
traitors and must be made examples of.
With all due respect, sir, I was
not trained to murder the innocent.
But you were trained
to follow orders.
Insolent coward .
The sentence
for insubordination is death.
Such a pity. You threw away
a promising career.
Consider it
my highest honour, sir.
Get him!
And don't hit my horse.
Don't waste your arrows.
Let the traitor rot in his watery grave.
Find the girl. If you have to burn
the city to the ground, so be it.
Sir, we have looked every where
and still no sign of the Gypsy girl.
I had the entire cathedral surrounded.
Guards at every door.
There was no way she could have escaped.
Unless--
- Oh, it doesn't look good.
- It's hopeless. Absolutely hopeless.
You're tellin' me.
I'm losin' to a bird !
Oh, but that poor Gypsy girl.
- I'm beginning the fear the worst.
- I know.
But now don't you say anything
to upset Quasimodo.
- He's worried enough already.
- Yeah, you're right.
- We better lighten up.
- Shh. Shh. Shh. Here he comes.
- Now, just stay calm.
- Not a word .
- Easy does it.
- Stone-faced.
Any sign of her?
Oh, it's a lost cause!
She could be anywhere! ln the stocks,
in the dungeon, on the rack! Oh!
- Nice work, Victor.
- No, he's right.
- What are we gonna do?
- What are you guys talkin' about?
If I know Esmeralda,
she's three steps ahead of Frollo...
- and well out of harm's way.
- Do you really think so?
Hey, when things cool off,
she'll be back. You'll see.
- What makes you so sure?
- Because she likes ya.
- We always said you were the cute one.
- I thought I was the cute one.
No, you're the fat, stupid one
with the big mouth!
What are you saying, exactly?
Take it from us, Quasi.
You got nothin' to worry about.
Yeah. You're irresistible.
Knights in shining armour
certainly aren't her type.
And those guys
are a dime a dozen.
But you,
you're one of a kind. Look.
Paris, the city of lovers
is glowing this evening
True, that's because it's on fire
But still there's I'amour
Somewhere out there
in the night
Her heart is also alight
And l know the guy
She just might be burning for
A guy like you
She's never known, kid
a girl does not meet every day
You've got a look
that's all your own, kid
Could there be two like you
No way
Those other guys
That she could dangle
All look the same
from every boring point of view
You're a surprise
From every angle
Mon dieu above
She's gotta love a guy like you
A guy like you
Gets extra credit
Because it's true you've got
-A certain something more
- You're aces, kid.
You see that face
Ya don't forget it
- Want something new
- That's you.
For sure
We all have gaped
at some Adonis
But then we crave a meal
more nourishing to chew
And since you're shaped
like a croissant is
No question of
She's gotta love a guy like you
Call me a hopeless romantic
But Quasi, l feel it
She wants you so
Any moment
she'll walk through that door
For
A guy so swell
A guy like you
With all you bring her
A fool could tell
it's why she fell
- For you-know- who
- We notice every string there
You'll ring the bell
You're the bell ringer
When she wants ooh-la-la
And she wants you-la-la
She will disco ver, guy
You're one heck of a guy
Who wouldn't love a guy like you
You got a lot
The rest have not
Gotta love a guy like you
Quasi? Quasimodo?
Esmeralda?
Esmeralda, you're all right!
I knew you'd come back!
You've done so much for me
already, my friend...
but I must ask your help
one more time.
Yes. Anything.
This is Phoebus. He's wounded
and a fugitive like me.
He can't go on much longer.
I knew he'd be safe here.
Please, can you hide him?
This way.
- Esmeralda.
- Shh. Shh. Shh.
You'll hide here
until you're strong enough to move.
Great. I could use a drink.
Yes!
Feels like a 1 470 Burgundy.
Not a good year.
That family owes you
their lives.
You're either the single bravest soldier
I've ever seen or the craziest.
Ex-soldier, remember?
Why is it, whenever we meet,
I end up bleeding?
You're lucky. That arrow
almost pierced your heart.
I'm not so sure it didn't.
I knew I'd never know
That warm and loving glow
Though l might wish
with all my might
No face as hideous
as my face
Was ever meant
for heaven's light
Frollo's coming.
You must leave.
Quick, follow me.
Go down the south tower steps.
Be careful, my friend.
Promise you won't let
anything happen to him.
- I promise.
- Thank you.
Quick! We gotta
stash the stiff.
Oh. Oh, Master. I-l-l-l
didn't think you'd be coming.
I am never too busy
to share a meal with you, dear boy.
I brought a little... treat.
Oh!
Is there something
troubling you, Quasimodo?
- Oh. No!
- Oh, but there is.
I know there is.
I think...
you're hiding something.
Oh, no, Master.
I-- There's no--
You're not eating, boy.
It's very good.
Thank you.
Seeds.
What's different in here?
Nothing, sir.
Isn't this one new?
It's awfully good.
Looks very much
like the Gypsy girl.
I know you helped her escape!
- But l--
- And now all Paris is burning...
because of you!
She was kind to me, Master.
You idiot! That wasn't kindness!
It was cunning!
She's a Gypsy !
Gypsies are not capable of real love !
Think, boy.
Think of your mother.
But what chance could a poor,
misshapen child like you have...
against her heathen treachery?
Well, never you mind,
Quasimodo.
She'll be
out of our lives soon enough.
I will free you
from her evil spell.
She will torment you
no longer.
What do you mean?
I know where her hideout is,
and tomorrow at dawn...
I attack with a thousand men.
We have to find
the Court of Miracles before daybreak.
If Frollo gets there first--
Are you coming with me?
- I can't.
- I thought you were Esmeralda's friend.
Frollo's my master.
I can't disobey him again.
She stood up for you. You've got
a funny way of showing gratitude.
Well, l'm not going to sit by and watch
Frollo massacre innocent people.
You do what you think is right.
What? What am l supposed to do?
Go out there and rescue the girl
from the-- from the jaws of death...
and the whole town will cheer
like l'm some kind of a hero?
She already has her knight
in shining armour and it's not me.
Frollo was right.
Frollo was right about everything.
I'm tired of trying to be
something that l'm not.
I must be out of my mind.
Phoebus! Shh.
I'm coming with you.
- Glad you changed your mind.
- I'm not doing it for you.
- I'm doing it for her.
- You know where she is?
No, but she said that this
will help us find her.
Good, good, good.
Ah, great. What is it?
- I'm not sure.
- Must be some sort of code.
Maybe it's Arabic. No, no. It's not
Arabic. Maybe it's ancient Greek.
"When you wear this woven band,
you hold the city in your hand."
- What?
- It's the city.
-What are you talking about?
-It's a map.
See. Here's the cathedral
and the rive r...
-and-and-and this little stone must be--
-l've never seen a map that looks like--
Look, l've lived up in the bell tower
for 20 years and l think l know...
- I've been in battles
on four continents.
- what the city looks like from above...
- I've got a very good idea what
a map looks like and this is not it.
- and this is it!
All right. Okay. If you say
it's a map, fine. It's a map.
But if we're going to find Esmeralda,
we have to work together.
- Truce?
- Well, okay.
Sorry.
No, you're not.
- This looks like the symbol on the map.
- But what does it mean?
I'm not sure.
I can make out an inscription...
but it's going to take
a few minutes to translate it.
Yes, well. Or-Or we could just,
uh, go down those stairs.
Is this the Court of Miracles?
Offhand, l'd say it's
the Court of Ankle-deep Sewage.
Must be the old catacombs.
Cheerful place.
Kind of makes ya wish ya got out
more often, eh, Quasi?
Not me. I just want
to warn Esmeralda...
and get back to the bell tower
before l get in any more trouble.
And speaking of trouble,
we should have run into some by now.
- What do you mean?
- You know. A guard. A booby trap.
Or an ambush.
Well, well, well.
What have we here?
- Trespassers !
- Spies!
- We're not spies!
- You've got to listen--
Don't interrupt me.
You're very clever
to have found our hideaway.
Unfortunately, you won't live
to tell the tale.
Maybe you've heard
of a terrible place
Where the scoundrels of Paris
collect in a lair
Maybe you've heard of that mythical
place called the Court of Miracles
- Hello, you're there.
- Where the lame can walk
And the blind can see
But the dead don't talk
So you won't be around
to reveal what you found
We have a method
for spies and intruders
Rather like hornets
protecting their hive
Here in the Court of Miracles
Where it's a miracle
if you get out alive
Gather 'round, everybody.
There's "good noose" tonight.
It's a double header.
A couple of Frollo's spies.
And not just any spies.
His Captain of the Guard
and his loyal, bell-ringing henchman.
The justice is swift
in the Court of Miracles
I am the lawyers and judge
all in one
We like to get the trial
over with quickly
Because it's the sentence
that's really the fun
Any last words?
That's what they all say.
- Now that we've seen all the evidence
- Wait! I object.
- Overruled!
- I object!
- Quiet!
- Dang.
We find you totally innocent
Which is the worst crime of all
So you're going to hang
Stop!
These men aren't spies.
They're our friends.
- Why didn't they say so?
- We did say so.
This is the soldier
who saved the miller's family...
and Quasimodo helped me
escape the cathedral.
We came to warn you. Frollo's coming!
He says he knows where you're hiding...
and he's attacking at dawn
with a thousand men.
Then let's waste no time.
We must leave immediately.
You took a terrible risk
coming here.
It may not exactly show,
but we're grateful.
Don't thank me.
Thank Quasimodo.
Without his help, l would never
have found my way here.
Nor would l.
After 20 years of searching...
the Court of Miracles
is mine at last.
Dear Quasimodo.
I always knew you would
someday be of use to me.
- No.
- What are you talking about?
- Why, he led me right to you, my dear.
- You're a liar.
And look what else
l've caught in my net.
Captain Phoebus,
back from the dead.
Another "miracle," no doubt.
I shall remedy that.
There'll be a little bonfire
in the square tomorrow...
and you're all invited to attend.
- Lock them up.
- No. Please, Master.
No, no.
Take him back to the bell tower.
And make sure he stays there.
The prisoner, Esmeralda, has been found
guilty of the crime of witch craft.
The sentence: death!
She is innocent!
The time has come, Gypsy.
You stand upon the brink of the abyss.
Yet even now
it is not too late.
I can save you from the flames
of this world and the next.
Choose me... or the fire.
The Gypsy, Esmeralda,
has refused to recant.
This evil witch has put the soul
of every citizen in Paris...
in mortal jeopardy.
- Come on, Quasi. Snap out of it!
- Your friends are down there.
- It's all my fault.
- Ya gotta break these chains.
I can't. I tried.
What difference would it make?
- But you can't let Frollo win!
- He already has.
So, you're givin' up? That's it?
These chains aren't
what's holding you back, Quasimodo.
Leave me alone.
Okay. Okay, Quasi.
We'll leave you alone.
After all,
we're only made out of stone.
We just thought maybe
you were made of something stronger.
For justice, for Paris...
and for her own salvation,
it is my sacred duty...
to send this unholy demon...
back where she belongs.
No!
Quasimodo!
Sanctuary!
- Captain.
- Sir?
Seize the cathedral.
Don't worry.
You'll be safe here.
Charge!
Come back, you cowards!
You men, pick up that beam.
Break down the door.
Alone at last.
Citizens of Paris!
Frollo has persecuted our people,
ransacked our city.
And now he has declared war
on Notre Dame herself!
Will we allow it?
I think the cavalry's here.
Hey, isn't that... Feeble?
- Doofus.
- Phoebus!
Sorry. Sorry.
Harder!
I'm-l'm free! I'm free!
Dang it!
Ready, aim, fire !
Are you sure
that's how it works?
Works for me.
Achilles, sit.
Get off me!
Fly, my pretties! Fly, Fly!
Put your backs into it!
Frollo, have you gone mad?
I will not tolerate
this assault on the house of God!
Silence, you old fool!
The hunchback and l
have unfinished business to attend to.
And this time
you will not interfere.
We've done it, Esmeralda!
We've beaten them back!
Come and see.
Esmeralda, wake up.
You're safe now.
Esmeralda?
Oh, no.
- You killed her.
- It was my duty, horrible as it was.
I hope you can forgive me.
There, there, Quasimodo.
I know it hurts,
but now the time has come...
to end your suffering forever.
Now, now. L--
- Listen to me, Quasimodo.
- No! You listen!
All my life, you have told me
that the world is a dark, cruel place.
But now l see that the only thing dark
and cruel about it is people like you.
- Quasimodo?
- Esmeralda!
- She lives.
- No!
Leaving so soon?
Look! Up there.
Hang on!
I should have known you'd risk your life
to save that Gypsy witch...
just as your own mother died
trying to save you.
- What?
- Now l'm going to do...
what l should have done
20 years ago!
- Whoa!
- Whoa! Oh!
Hold on. Hold on.
And He shall
smite the wicked...
and plunge them
into the fiery pit!
Quasimodo! Quasi!
No!
Three cheers...
for Quasimodo!
So here is a riddle
to guess if you can
Sing the bells Of Notre Dame
What makes a monster
and what makes a man
Sing the bells, bells
bells, bells
Whatever their pitch
you can feel them bewitch you
The rich and the ritual knells
Of the bells
Of Notre
Dame
Don't you ever migrate?
Someday
When we are wiser
When the world's older
When we have learned
I pray
Someday we may yet live
To live
And let live
Someday
Life will be fairer
Need will be rarer
And greed will not pay
Godspeed
This fine millennium
On its way
Let it come someday
Someday
Our fight will be won then
We'll stand in the sun then
That bright afternoon
Till then
On days when the sun is gone
We'll hang on
And we'll wish
Upon the moon
Whoa-oh
-And some days are dark and dreary
- Dark and dreary
- Seems we haven't got a prayer
- Haven't we got but a prayer
But a prayer for something better
Is the one thing we all share
- Someday
- When we are wiser
- When the world's older
- When the world is older
- When we have learned
- I pray someday we may yet
- l pray
- Let live
- Live
Let live
- To live
- To live, to live, to live, to live
-And let live
Someday
- Life will be fairer
- Need will be rarer
- Greed will not pay
- No, no, no
- Godspeed
This fine millennium
Let it come
Wish upon
A moon
One day
Someday
Soon
- One day
- Someday
Someday
Soon
Good night, everybody!
Subtitle by Snitch Company®