Now remember keep
your shoulders back.
Okay put your arm
around your brother. That's it.
That's it.
Right and breathe in.
Okay one more.
Now just to review
you're going to follow
along the procession...
until you get
to the headmaster.
At that point
he will indicate to you...
to light the candles
of the boys.
All right boys
let's settle down.
Banners up!
Ladies and gentlemen
boys...
the Light of Knowledge.
One hundred years ago
in 1859
41 boys sat in this room...
and were asked
the same question...
that now greets you
at the start of each semester.
Gentlemen
what are the Four Pillars?
Tradition. Honour.
Discipline. Excellence.
In her first year
Welton Academy graduated
five students.
Last year
we graduated 51.
And more than 75 percent
of those...
went on to the Ivy League.
This- This kind
of accomplishment...
is the result...
of fervent dedication
to the principles taught here.
This is why you parents
have been sending us your sons.
This is why
we are the best...
preparatory school
in the United States.
As you know
our beloved Mr Portius of the
English Department retired last term.
You will have the opportunity later to
meet his replacement Mr John Keating
himself an honours graduate
of this school.
And who for the past several years
has been teaching...
at the highly regarded
Chester School in London.
Richard you forgot your bag!
Hi Johnny!
Hey how you doin'?
Don't worry.
I got your room assignment.
They haven't moved
the dining area.
Glad you could come by.
- Thrilling ceremony
as usual Dr Nolan.
- You've been away too long.
- Hello Dr Nolan.
- Good to have you back.
- This is our youngest Todd.
- Mr Anderson.
You have some big shoes to fill.
Your brother was one of our finest.
Thank you.
- Lovely ceremony.
- Thank you. Glad you liked it.
- Gale.
- Tom.
- Good to see you again.
- Hello Mr Nolan.
- We expect great things
from you this year.
- Thank you sir.
Well he won't disappoint us.
Right Neil?
I'll do my best sir.
Hey come on son.
- Chin up.
- Okay.
- No tears now.
- Chin up.
- I don't want to go here.
- Honey I love you.
- I'll walk you over.
- You be a good boy. Do your lessons.
Hey! I hear
we're gonna be roommates.
- I'm Neil Perry.
- I'm Todd Anderson.
Why'd you leave Balincrest?
My brother went here.
Oh so you're
that Anderson.
- This is for his sinuses.
- Yes. I see.
Oh and if he can't swallow
you give him one of these.
And if he has trouble breathing
you can give him some of those.
- Did you remember your vaporizer?
- Yes I put it in my room.
- Hey how's it going Neil?
- Hey Knox.
Neil study group tonight?
- Yeah sure.
- Business as usual huh?
Hey I heard you got the new kid.
Looks like a stiff!
Oops.
Listen don't mind Cameron.
He was born with his foot in his mouth.
You know what I mean?
Rumour has it...
you did summer school.
Yep. Chemistry. My father
thought I should get ahead.
How was your summer slick?
Keen.
Meeks. Door. Closed.
Yes sir.
Gentlemen what are
the Four Pillars?
Travesty. Horror.
Decadence. Excrement.
Okay. Study group.
Meeks aced Latin.
I didn't quite flunk English.
- If you want we got our study group.
- Sure.
Cameron asked me too.
Anyone mind including him?
Hmm what's his specialty?
Bootlicking?
- Come on he's your roommate.
- That's not my fault.
I'm sorry. My name is Stephen Meeks.
Oh!
This is Todd Anderson.
- Nice to meet you.
Charlie Dalton.
Knox Overstreet.
Todd's brother was
Jeffrey Anderson.
- Oh yeah sure.
- What do you know?
- Valedictorian. National Merit Scholar.
- Oh well...
welcome to Hell- ton.
It's every bit as tough as they say
unless you're a genius like Meeks.
He flatters me.
That's why I help him with Latin.
And English. And trig.
It's open.
Father I thought you'd gone.
- Mr Perry.
- Keep your seats fellows.
Neil I've just spoken
to Mr Nolan.
You're taking too many extracurricular
activities this semester
and I've decided that
you should drop the school annual.
But I'm the assistant editor
this year.
- Well I'm sorry Neil.
- But Father I can't.
- It wouldn't be fair.
- Would you excuse us for a moment?
Don't you ever dispute me in public.
Do you understand?
- Father I wasn't disputing- -
- After you've finished medical school...
and you're on your own
then you can do as you damn well please.
But until then you do as I tell you.
Is that clear?
Yes sir.
I'm sorry.
You know how much this means
to your mother don't you?
Yes sir.
You know me:
always taking on too much.
Well that's my boy.
- You need anything you let us know.
- Yes sir.
Why doesn't he
let you do what you want?
Yeah Neil. Tell him off.
Couldn't get any worse.
Oh that's rich.
Like you guys tell your parents off?
Mr Future Lawyer
and Mr Future Banker?
Okay so I don't like it
any more than you do.
Well just don't tell me
how to talk to my father.
- You guys are the same way.
- All right all right.Jesus.
- So what are you gonna do then?
- What I have to do.
- Drop the annual.
- I wouldn't lose much sleep over it.
It's just a bunch of jerks
trying to impress Nolan.
I don't care. I don't
give a damn about any of it.
- Well uh... Latin 8:00 in my room?
- Yes.
- That sounds okay.
- Todd you're welcome to join us.
- Yeah come along pal.
- Thanks.
Slow down boys!
Slow down you horrible
phalanx of pubescence!
Pick three laboratory experiments
from the project list...
and report on them
every five weeks.
The first 20 questions at the end
of chapter one are due tomorrow.
- Agricolam.
- Agricola.
- Agricolae.
- Agricolarum.
- Agricolis.
- Agricolas.
- Again please. Agricola.
- Agricola.
Your study of trigonometry
requires absolute precision.
Anyone failing to turn in
any homework assignment...
will be penalized one point
off their final grade.
Let me urge you now not
to test me on this point.
Hey Spaz. Spaz.
Brain damage!
- Shh!
Well come on.
- Let's go.
- Let's go guys.
Let's go.
"O Captain my Captain."
Who knows
where that comes from?
Anybody?
Not a clue?
It's from a poem by Walt Whitman
about Mr Abraham Lincoln.
Now in this class you can
either call me Mr Keating...
or if you're slightly more daring
"O Captain my Captain."
Now let me dispel a few rumours
so they don't fester into facts.
Yes I too attended Hell- ton
and survived.
And no at that time I was not
the mental giant you see before you.
I was the intellectual equivalent
of a 98- pound weakling.
I would go to the beach and people
would kick copies of Byron in my face.
Now... Mr Pitts?
That's a rather
unfortunate name.
Mr Pitts where are you?
Mr Pitts would you open
your hymnal to page 542.
Read the first stanza
of the poem you find there.
"To the Virgins
to Make Much of Time"?
Yes that's the one.
Somewhat appropriate isn't it?
"Gather ye rosebuds while ye may.
"Old Time is still a- flying.
And this same flower that smiles today
tomorrow will be dying."
Thank you Mr Pitts.
"Gather ye rosebuds while ye may."
The Latin term for that sentiment
is "Carpe diem. "
Now who knows what that means?
Carpe diem.
That's "Seize the day."
- Very good Mister- -
- Meeks.
Meeks.
Another unusual name.
Seize the day.
"Gather ye rosebuds while ye may."
Why does the writer
use these lines?
- Because he's in a hurry.
- No! Ding!
Thank you
for playing anyway.
Because we are food
for worms lads.
Because believe it or not
each and every one of us in this room...
is one day going to stop breathing
turn cold and die.
I would like you
to step forward over here...
and peruse some of the faces
from the past.
You've walked past them
many times. I don't think
you've really looked at them.
They're not that different
from you are they?
Same haircuts.
Full of hormones
just like you.
Invincible just like you feel.
The world is their oyster.
They believe they're destined for
great things just like many of you.
Their eyes are full of hope
just like you.
Did they wait
until it was too late...
to make from their lives even one iota
of what they were capable?
Because you see gentlemen these
boys are now fertilizing daffodils.
But if you listen
real close...
you can hear them whisper
their legacy to you.
Go on lean in.
Listen.
Do you hear it?
Carpe.
Hear it?
Carpe diem.
Seize the day boys.
Make your lives
extraordinary.
- That was weird.
- But different.
Spooky if you ask me.
Think he'll test us
on that stuff?
Oh come on Cameron.
Don't you get anything?
What? What?
Let's go boys. Hustle up in here.
That means you Dalton!
Who's up for a quick
study group tonight guys?
- Me.
- What?
I can't make it guys. I have to have
dinner at the Danburrys' house tonight.
The Danburrys?
Who are the Danburrys?
Big alums.
How'd you swing that?
Friends of my dad's. They're probably
in their nineties or something.
Ooh!
Anything's better
than Hell- ton hash Knox.
- I'll second that.
- Yeah we'll see.
You coming to the study group tonight?
Uh... no. No I- -
Uh I've got some history I wanna do.
Suit yourself.
Ready Overstreet?
Ready to go sir.
Chet can you get that?
- I can't Mom.
- I'll get it!
Can I help you?
Hi. Knox Overstreet.
- Uh Dr Hager.
- Hi.
This is the Danburrys'
right?
- Are you here to see Chet?
- Mrs Danburry?
- No.
- Sorry. Thank you. I'm Mrs Danburry.
- You must be Knox.
- Yes.
Back by 9:00?
Please come on in.
- Chris come on!
- Chet I'm coming.
Knox. How are you?
Joe Danburry.
- Nice to meet you sir.
- He's the spitting image of his father.
- How is he? Come on in.
- Chris!
- Great. He just did a big case for G.M.
- I know where you're headed.
- I'm coming.
- Like father like son huh?
Ooh! Psycho!
- Yes!
- To Queen- Six.
- Another game?
- What do you mean?
- Duh!
just replace these numbers here
with 'x "for 'x"and 'y. "
- Of course.
- Of course. So what's the problem?
You think I can get in there?
You've been hogging it all day.
- Wait. No.
- How was dinner?
Huh?
- Terrible.
- Awful.
- Why? What happened?
Tonight I met
the most beautiful girl...
I have ever seen
in my entire life.
Are you crazy?
What's wrong with that?
She's practically engaged
to Chet Danburry.
That guy could eat a football.
- Too bad.
- "Too bad"?
It's worse than "too bad"
Pittsie. It's a tragedy.
A girl this beautiful
in love with such a jerk.
All the good ones go for jerks.
You know that.
Yeah forget her. Open your trig book
and try and figure out problem five.
I can't just forget her Cameron.
And I certainly
can't think about trig.
We got it!
All right gentlemen.
Five minutes.
Let's go.
- Did you see her naked?
- Very funny Dalton.
That wouldn't be a radio in your lap
- would it Mr Pitts?
- No sir. Science experiment.
Radar.
Gentlemen open your text
to page 21 of the introduction.
Mr Perry will you read
the opening paragraph of the preface
entitled
"Understanding Poetry."
"'Understand Poetry'
by Dr J. Evans Pritchard Ph.D.
"To fully understand poetry
we must first be fluent...
"with its metre rhyme
and figures of speech.
"Then ask two questions.
"One.: How artfully has the objective
of the poem been rendered?
'And two.: How important
is that objective?
"Question one rates
the poem's perfection.
"Question two rates
its importance.
'And once these questions
have been answered...
"determining a poem's greatness
becomes a relatively simple matter.
"If the poem's score
for perfection is plotted...
"on the horizontal
of a graph...
"and its importance
is plotted on the vertical
"then calculating
the total area of the poem...
"yields the measure
of its greatness.
"A sonnet by Byron might
score high on the vertical
"but only average
on the horizontal.
'A Shakespearean sonnet
on the other hand
"would score high both
horizontally and vertically
'yielding
a massive total area;:
"thereby revealing
the poem to be truly great.
'As you proceed through the poetry in
this book practise this rating method.
'As your ability to evaluate
poems in this manner grows
so will- - so will your enjoyment
and understanding of poetry."
Excrement.
That's what I think
of Mr J. Evans Pritchard.
We're not laying pipe.
We're talking about poetry.
I mean how can you describe poetry
like American Bandstand?
"I like Byron. I give him a 42.
But I can't dance to it."
Now I want you
to rip out that page.
Go on.
Rip out the entire page.
You heard me.
Rip it out.
Rip it out!
Go on.
Rip it out.
Thank you Mr Dalton.
Gentlemen tell you what.
Don't just tear out that page.
Tear out the entire introduction.
I want it gone history. Leave nothing.
Rip it out! Rip! Be gone
J. Evans Pritchard Ph.D.!
Rip! Shred! Tear!
Rip it out! I want to hear nothing
but ripping of Mr Pritchard!
We'll perforate it put it on a roll!
It's not the Bible.
You're not gonna go to hell for this.
Go on. Make a clean tear.
I want nothing left of it.
We shouldn't be doing this.
Rip! Rip! Rip!
Rip it out! Rip!
Rip it! Yeah! Rip it out!
- Rip it!
- What the hell is going on here?
- I don't hear enough rips.
- Mr Keating.
Mr McAllister.
I'm sorry I- -
I didn't know you were here.
- I am.
- Ah. So you are.
Excuse me.
Keep ripping gentlemen.
This is a battle a war.
And the casualties could be
your hearts and souls.
Thank you Mr Dalton.
Armies of academics
going forward measuring poetry.
No! We will not
have that here.
No more
of MrJ. Evans Pritchard.
Now my class you will learn
to think for yourselves again.
You will learn
to savour words and language.
No matter what
anybody tells you
words and ideas
can change the world.
I see that look
in Mr Pitts' eye...
like 19th century literature
has nothing to do...
with going to business school
or medical school.
Right? Maybe.
Mr Hopkins you may agree
with him thinking
"Yes we should simply study
our Mr Pritchard...
"and learn our rhyme and metre
and go quietly about the business...
of achieving other ambitions."
I have a little secret for you.
Huddle up.
Huddle up!
We don't read and write
poetry because it's cute.
We read and write poetry because
we are members of the human race.
And the human race
is filled with passion.
Medicine law
business engineering:
these are noble pursuits
and necessary to sustain life.
But poetry
beauty romance love- -
these are what
we stay alive for.
To quote from Whitman.:
"O me O life of the questions
of these recurring.
"Of the endless trains
of the faithless.
"Of cities filled
with the foolish.
"What good amid these
O me O life?
"Answer:
That you are here.
"That life exists
and identity.
"That the powerful play
goes on
and you may contribute
a verse."
"That the powerful play
goes on
and you may contribute
a verse. "
What will your verse be?
For what we are
about to receive
may the Lord make us
truly grateful.
Amen.
Quite an interesting class
you gave today Mr Keating.
- Sorry if I shocked you Mr McAllister.
- There's no need to apologise.
It was very fascinating
misguided though it was.
You think so?
You take a big risk by encouraging them
to become artistsJohn.
When they realize that they're
not Rembrandts Shakespeares or Mozarts
they'll hate you for it.
We're not talking artists George.
We're talking freethinkers.
Freethinkers at 17?
Funny I never pegged you
as a cynic.
Not a cynic.
A realist.
"Show me the heart unfettered
by foolish dreams
and I'll show you
a happy man."
"But only in their dreams
can men be truly free.
'Twas always thus
and always thus will be."
Tennyson?
No. Keating.
Hey I found his senior
annual in the library.
Listen to this.
Captain of the soccer team.
Editor of the school annual.
Cambridge bound.
Thigh man
and the Dead Poets Society.
"Man Most Likely
To Do Anything."
Thigh man?
Mr "K" was a hell- raiser.
What's the Dead Poets Society?
- I don't know.
- Is there a picture in the annual?
- Nothing. No other mention of it.
- That boy there
see me after lunch.
Mr Keating?
Sir?
- Say something.
- O Captain my Captain?
Gentlemen.
We were just looking
in your old annual.
Oh my God.
No that's not me.
Stanley "The Tool" Wilson.
- God.
- What was the Dead Poets Society?
I doubt the present administration
would look too favourably upon that.
Why?
What was it?
- Gentlemen can you keep a secret?
- Sure.
The Dead Poets were dedicated
to sucking the marrow out of life.
That's a phrase from Thoreau we'd invoke
at the beginning of every meeting.
You see we would gather
at the old Indian cave...
and take turns reading from Thoreau
Whitman Shelley- - the biggies.
Even some of our own verse.
And in the enchantment of the moment
we'd let poetry work its magic.
You mean it was a bunch of guys
sitting around reading poetry?
No Mr Overstreet.
It wasn't just guys.
We weren't a Greek organization.
We were romantics.
We didn't just read poetry we let it
drip from our tongues like honey.
Spirits soared women swooned
and gods were created gentlemen.
Not a bad way
to spend an evening eh?
Hmm.
Thank you Mr Perry
for this stroll down amnesia lane.
Burn that.
Especially my picture.
Dead Poets Society.
What?
- I say we go tonight.
- Tonight?
- Wait a minute.
- Everybody in?
- Where's this cave he's talking about?
- It's beyond the stream.
- I know where it is.
- That's miles.
- Sounds boring to me.
- Don't go.
- You know how many
demerits we're talking?
- So don't come. Please.
Look all I'm saying
is that we have to be careful.
- We can't get caught.
- No shit Sherlock.
You boys there!
Hurry up!
- All right who's in?
- Aw come on Neil. Hager's- -
Forget Hager! No!
Who's in?
I'm in.
I'm warning you! Move!
Me too.
- I don't know Neil.
- What? Pitts!
- Pittsie come on.
- His grades are hurting.
- You can help him Meeks.
- What is this a midnight study group?
Forget it Pitts. You're coming.
Meeks your grades hurting too?
- I'll try anything once.
- Except sex.
- Ha ha ha.
- I'm in as long as we're careful.
- What about you Knox?
- I don't know Charlie.
Come on Knox.
It'll help you get Chris.
Yeah? How?
- Women swoon.
- But why do they swoon?
Charlie tell me why they swoon!
Charlie!
Okay
follow the stream to the waterfall.
It's right there.
It's got to be on the banks.
I don't know.
This is starting to sound dangerous.
- Oh well why don't you stay home?
- Hey you're crazy.
For God's sake
stop chattering and sit down.
- Todd are you coming tonight?
- No.
Why not? God you were there.
You heard Keating.
- Don't you want
to do something about that?
- Yes.
- But- -
- But? But what?
Keating said that everybody
took turns reading
and I don't want to do that.
Gosh you really have
a problem with that don't you?
N- No I don't have a problem.
Neil I just- -
I don't want to do it okay?
All right.
What if you didn't have to read?
What if you just came and listened?
- That's not how it works.
- Well forget how it works.
What if- -
What if they said it was okay?
What- - What are you gonna
go up and ask them?
No.
No Neil.
- I'll be right back.
- Neil. Neil!
Oh shut up will you?
That's for my asthma okay?
Could you give that back please?
What's the matter?
Don't you like snakes?
- You're in.
- Get away from me okay?
- Why don't you check your pocket huh?
- Come on. I have to brush my teeth.
- Get a- - Get off.
- Cut out that racket in there!
Go. Go.
- I'm a dead poet!
- Aw shit Charlie.
- Guys! Over here!
- Funny. You're real funny.
It's too wet.
God are you trying
to smoke us out of here?
No no. The smoke's
going right up this opening.
You okay?
Oh God. Clowns.
All right forget the fire.
Let's go gentlemen.
- I hereby reconvene
the Dead Poets Society
Welton Chapter.
The meetings will be
conducted by myself...
and the other
new initiates now present.
Todd Anderson because
he prefers not to read
will keep minutes
of the meetings.
I'll now read
the traditional opening message...
by Society member
Henry David Thoreau.
"I went to the woods because
I wanted to live deliberately.
I wanted to live deep and suck
out all the marrow of life."
I'll second that.
"To put to rout
all that was not life.
"And not
when I had come to die
discover
that I had not lived."
- Keating's marked
a bunch of other pages.
- All right intermission!
Dig deep. Right here.
Right here lay it down.
On the mud? We're gonna
put our food on the mud?
Meeks put your coat down.
Picnic blanket.
Use Meeks' coat.
Don't keep anything back either.
- You guys are always bumming my smokes.
- Raisins?
- Yuck.
- Wait a minute!
- Who gave us half a roll?
- I'm eating the other half.
- Come on!
- What you want me to put it back?
It was a dark and rainy night
and this old lady
who had a passion
for jigsaw puzzles
sat by herself in her house at her table
to complete a new jigsaw puzzle.
But as she pieced
the puzzle together
she realized
to her astonishment
that the image that was formed
was her very own room.
And the figure
in the centre of the puzzle
as she completed it
was herself.
And with trembling hands
she placed the last four pieces...
and stared in horror at the face
of a demented madman at the window.
The last thing that
this old lady ever heard...
- was the sound of breaking glass.
- No she didn't.
Yes this is true. This is true.
I've got one that's better than that.
I do. There's a young
married couple
and they're driving through the forest
at night on a long trip.
And they run out of gas
and there's a madman on the- -
The thing with the hand?
I love that story!
- I told you that one.
- You did not.
- I got that in camp in sixth grade.
- Last year?
"In a mean abode
in the Shanking Road
"lived a man named
William Bloat.
"Now he had a wife
the plague of his life
"who continually
got his goat.
"And one day at dawn
with her nightshift on
he slit
her bloody throat."
Oh and it gets worse.
You want to hear
a real poem?
- You want this?
- No I don't need- - Get this outta here.
- What did you bring one?
- You memorized a poem?
You memorized a poem?
- An original piece by Charlie Dalton.
- An original piece.
- Take centre stage.
- You know this is history right?
Wow. Whoa.
Where did you get that?
Where did you- -
- Whoa.
- "Teach me to love?
"Go teach thyself more wit.
"I chief professor am of it.
"The god of love
if such a thing there be
may learn to love from me."
Wow. Did you write that?
Abraham Cowley.
Okay.
Who's next?
Alfred Lord Tennyson.
"Come my friends.
"'Tis not too late
to seek a newer world.
"For my purpose holds
to sail beyond the sunset.
"And though we are not
now that strength...
"which in old days
moved Earth and heaven.
"That which we are we are:
"one equal temper
of heroic hearts...
"made weak by time and fate
but strong in will...
"to strive to seek to find
and not to yield."
"Then I had religion
then I had a vision.
"I could not turn from
their revel in derision.
"Then I saw the Congo
creeping through the black
cutting through the forest
with a golden track."
- Then I saw the Congo
creeping through the black
- Meeks. Meeks.
cutting through the forest
with a golden track.
Then I saw the Congo
creeping through the black
- cutting through the forest
with a golden track.
Then I saw the Congo
creeping through the black
- cutting through the forest
with a golden track!
Then I saw the Congo
creeping through the black
cutting through the forest
with a golden track!
Then I saw the Congo
creeping through the black
cutting through the forest
with a golden track!
Then I saw the Congo
creeping through the black
- cutting through the forest
with a golden track!
Then I saw the Congo
creeping through the black
cutting through the forest
with a golden track!
Cutting through the forest
Then I saw the Congo
creeping through the black- -
A man is not "very tired. "
He is "exhausted. "
And don't use "very sad."
Use- -
Come on Mr Overstreet
you twerp.
- "Morose"?
- Exactly! Morose!
Language was developed for one
endeavour and that is- - Mr Anderson?
Come on
are you a man or an amoeba?
Mr Perry?
Uh... to communicate.
No! To woo women.
Today we're going to be talking...
- about William Shakespeare.
- Oh God.
I know. A lot of you
look forward to this...
about as much as you look forward
to root canal work.
We're gonna talk
about Shakespeare...
as someone who writes
something very interesting.
Now many of you have seen Shakespeare
done very much like this:
"O Titus bring your friend hither."
But if any of you have seen
Mr Marlon Brando
you know
that Shakespeare can be different.
"Friends Romans countrymen
lend me your ears."
You can also imagine maybe
John Wayne as Macbeth going...
"Well
is this a dagger I see before me?"
"Dogs sir?
Oh not just now.
"I do enjoy a good dog
once in a while sir.
"You can have yourself
a three- course meal from one dog.
"Start with a canine croquette.
"Go to your Fido Flambe
for main course.
'And for dessert
a Pekingese parfait.
And you can pick your teeth
with the little paw. "
Why do I stand up here?
- Anybody?
- To feel taller.
No! Thank you for playing.
I stand upon my desk...
to remind myself that we must constantly
look at things in a different way.
See the world looks
very different from up here.
You don't believe me?
Come see for yourselves.
Come on.
Come on. Just when you
think you know something
you have to look at it
in another way.
Even though it may seem
silly or wrong
you must try.
Now when you read don't just
consider what the author thinks.
Consider what you think.
Boys you must strive
to find your own voice.
Because the longer
you wait to begin
the less likely you are
to find it at all.
Thoreau said "Most men lead
lives of quiet desperation."
Don't be resigned to that.
Break out.
Don't just walk off the edge
like lemmings. Look around you.
There you go Mr Priske. Thank you!
Yes!
Dare to strike out
and find new ground.
Now in addition to your essays
I would like you to compose
a poem of your own an original work.
Ooh!
That's right.
You have to deliver it aloud
in front of the class on Monday.
Bon chance gentlemen.
Mr Anderson.
Don't think I don't know this assignment
scares the hell out of you you mole.
Take a power train in two!
- Three keep your eyes in the boat!
- Stroke! Stroke!
Stroke! Stroke!
- We got it Pittsie.
Radio Free America!
Some people like to rock
Some people like to roll
But movin'and a- groovin'
is gonna satisfy my soul
Let's have a party
Oooh
Let's spin it to the soul
Let's rock and roll
Let's have a party tonight
I never kissed a bear
I never kissed a goose
But I can shake a chicken
in the middle of the room
- Let's have a party
- I found it.
- You found what?
What I want to do right now.
What's really really inside of me.
- "A Midsummer Night's Dream."
- This is it.
- What is that?
- It's a play dummy.
I know that.
Wh- What does it have to do with you?
All right they're
putting it on at Henley Hall.
Open tryouts.
Open tryouts!
- Yeah so?
- So!
I'm gonna act.
Yes! Yes!
I'm gonna be an actor!
Ever since I can remember
I've wanted to try this!
I even tried to go
to summer stock auditions last year
but of course
my father wouldn't let me.
For the first time in my whole life
I know what I want to do.
And for
the first time I'm gonna do it...
whether my father
wants me to or not!
- Carpe diem!
- Neil Neil hold it.
How are you gonna be in a play
if your father won't let you?
First I gotta get the part
then I can worry about that.
But won't he kill you if he finds out
you went to an audition
and didn't tell him?
No no no. As far as I'm concerned
he won't have to know about any of this.
- Well that's impossible.
- Bullshit. Nothing's impossible.
Well why don't you just call him
and ask him and m- maybe he'll say yes.
That's a laugh.
If I don't ask him
at least I won't be disobeying him.
- Yeah but if he said no before- -
- Jesus Todd whose side are you on?
I mean I haven't even
gotten the part yet.
Can't I even enjoy the idea
for a little while?
- You're coming to the meeting?
- I don't know. Maybe.
Nothing Mr Keating has to say
means shit to you does it Todd?
- Wh- What is that supposed to mean?
- You're in the club!
Being in the club means
being stirred up by things.
You look about
as stirred up as a cesspool.
- So you want me out?
- No I want you in!
But being in means you gotta do
something not just say you're in.
Listen Neil I mean
I appreciate this concern
but I'm not like you
all right?
You- - You- You say things
and people listen.
I- - I- I'm not like that.
- Don't you think you could be?
- No.
I- - I- I don't know
but that's not the point.
The point is there's nothing you can
do about it so you can just butt out.
I can take care
of myself just fine.
All right?
No.
What do you mean "no"?
Give me that!
Neil!
- Neil give that back!
- "We are dreaming of a tomorrow- - "
- It's poetry!
- Neil!
I'm being chased by Walt Whitman!
Okay! Okay!
What are you guys doing?
I'm trying- - You see this chemistry- -
Hey. Give me- - Neil give me- -
Don't be immature. Come on!
- I need my- -
- Give it to me!
Charlie!
Let me have my book. I need my- -
Okay everybody on the bus.
Let's go boys.
Come on. Let's go. On the bus boys.
Now!
Now devotees may argue...
that one sport or game
is inherently better than another.
For me sport
is actually a chance...
for us to have other human beings
push us to excel.
I want you all to come over here
and take a slip of paper...
and line up single file.
Mr Meeks
time to inherit the Earth.
Mr Pitts...
rise above your name.
I want you to hand these out
to the boys one apiece.
You know what to do Pitts!
"Oh to struggle against great odds
to meet enemies undaunted."
Sounds like you're daunted.
Say it again like you're undaunted.
"Oh to struggle against great odds
to meet enemies undaunted"!
Now go on!
Yes!
Next!
"To be a sailor of the world
bound for all ports."
Next.
Louder!
"Oh I live to be the ruler of life
not a slave."
"To mount the scaffolds.
To advance to the muzzles of guns
with perfect nonchalance. "
Come on Meeks!
Listen to the music!
"To dance clap hands
exalt shout skip
- roll on float on!"
- Yes!
"Oh to have life henceforth
the poem of new joys."
Boo!
Come on Charlie
let it fill your soul.
"To indeed be a god!"
Charlie I got the part!
I'm gonna play Puck!
- I'm gonna play Puck!
- What did he say?
- Puck you!
- The main part!
- Great Neil!
- Charlie I got it!
- Congratulations.
- Good for you! Good for you!
Okay okay okay okay.
Neil how are you gonna do this?
They need a letter of permission
from my father and Mr Nolan.
- You're not gonna write it.
- Oh yes I am.
Oh Neil- - Neil you're crazy.
Okay.
I am writing to you...
on behalf of...
my son...
Neil Perry.
This is great!
"To Chris."
Who's Chris? Mmm Chris.
"I see a sweetness
in her smile.
"Bright light shines
from her eyes.
"But life is complete
contentment is mine...
"just knowing that- -
"Just knowing that...
she's alive."
- I'm sorry Captain. It's stupid.
- No. No it's not stupid.
It's a good effort. It touched on
one of the major themes: love.
A major theme
not only in poetry but life.
Mr Hopkins you were laughing.
You're up.
"The cat sat on the mat."
Congratulations Mr Hopkins.
Yours is the first poem to ever have
a negative score on the Pritchard scale.
We're not laughing at you
we're laughing near you.
I don't mind that your poem
had a simple theme.
Sometimes the most beautiful poetry
can be about simple things
like a cat or a flower or rain.
You see poetry can come from anything
with the stuff of revelation in it.
Just don't let your poems
be ordinary.
Now who's next?
Mr Anderson I see you
sitting there in agony.
Come on Todd step up.
Let's put you out of your misery.
I- I didn't do it.
I didn't write a poem.
Mr Anderson thinks everything inside
of him is worthless and embarrassing.
Isn't that right Todd?
Isn't that your worst fear?
Well I think you're wrong. I think
you have something inside of you...
that is worth a great deal.
"I sound...
"my barbaric...
"yawp...
"over the rooftops...
of the world. "
W.W.
Uncle Walt again.
Now for those of you who don't know
a yawp is a loud cry or yell.
Now Todd I would like you to give us
a demonstration of a barbaric yawp.
Come on you can't yawp sitting down.
Let's go.
Come on up.
Got to get in yawping stance.
- A- Ayawp?
- Not just a yawp. A barbaric yawp.
- Right. Yawp.
- Come on. Louder.
- Yawp.
- That's a mouse. Come on louder!
- Oh good God boy yell like a man!
- Yawp!
- There it is.
You see you have a barbarian
in you after all.
You don't get away that easy. There's
a picture of Uncle Walt up there.
What does he remind you of?
Don't think answer. Go on.
- A m- m- m- madman.
- What kind of madman?
- Don't think about it just answer.
- A cr- crazy madman.
No you can do better than that.
Free up your mind. Use your imagination.
Say the first thing that pops into
your head even if it's total gibberish.
A- A- A sweaty- toothed madman.
Good God boy there's
a poet in you after all!
There. Close your eyes.
Close your eyes. Close them.
Now describe what you see.
- Uh I- I close my eyes...
- Yes?
- uh and his image floats beside me.
- A sweaty- toothed madman.
A sweaty- toothed madman with
a stare that pounds my brain.
Oh that's excellent!
Now give him action
make him do something.
- H- His hands reach out and choke me.
- That's it. Wonderful. Wonderful.
- And all the time he's mumbling.
- What's he mumbling?
- Mumbling truth.
- Yes.
- Truth is like a blanket that
always leaves your feet cold.
Forget them. Forget them. Stay with
the blanket. Tell me about that blanket.
Y- Y- You push it stretch it
it'll never be enough.
You kick at it beat it
it'll never cover any of us.
From the moment we enter crying
to the moment we leave dying
it'll just cover your face
as you wail and cry and scream.
Don't you forget this.
That a boy Pittsie.
- Inhale deeply.
- My dad collects pipes.
- Really?
- He must have 30.
Your parents collect pipes?
Oh that's interesting.
- Come on Knox. Join in.
- Yeah Knox we're from the government.
We're here to help.
What's wrong?
- It's Chris!
- Here's a picture of Chris for you!
- Put that in your pipe and smoke it.
- It's not funny.
Knock it off.
Smoke your pipes.
- Neil.
- Friends scholars Welton men.
What is that Neil?
- Duh it's a lamp Meeks.
- No this is the god of the cave.
The god of the cave.
- Charlie what are you doing?
- What do you say we start this meeting?
- I need a light. Who's got a light?
- Anybody bring earplugs?
Gentlemen.
"Poetrusic" by Charles Dalton.
Oh man.
Laughing crying
tumbling mumbling.
Gotta do more
gotta be more.
Pitts.
Chaos screaming chaos dreaming.
Gotta do more gotta be more!
- Wow. Nice.
- That was great.
Where did you learn
to play like that?
My parents made me take
the clarinet for years!
- I love the clarinet.
- I hated it.
The saxophone.
The saxophone is more... sonorous.
Ooh more sonorous.
Vocabulary.
I can't take
it any more. If I don't have Chris
- I'm gonna kill myself.
- Knoxious calm down.
No Charlie!
That's just my problem.
I've been calm all my life.
I'm gonna do something about that.
Where are you going?
What are you gonna do?
I'm gonna call her.
- He's gonna call her!
- Wait for me!
Hello?
She's gonna hate me.
The Danburrys will hate me.
My parents will kill me.
All right goddam it.
You're right.
Carpe diem.
Even if it kills me.
- Hello?
- Hello Chris?
- Yes.
- Hi. This is Knox Overstreet.
Oh yes. Knox.
- I'm glad you called.
- She's glad I called.
Listen Chet's parents
are going out of town this weekend
and he's having a party.
- Would you like to come?
- Would I like to come to a party?
- Yes. Say yes.
- It's Friday.
- Well sure.
- About 7.:00.
- Great. I'll be there Chris.
- Okay.
- Friday night at the Danburrys'. Okay.
- Okay. Bye.
- Thank you. I'll see you. Bye.
Yawp!
Can you believe it?
She was gonna call me.
She invited me
to a party with her.
- At Chet Danburry's house.
- Yeah.
- Well?
- So?
So you don't really think
she means you're going with her?
Well of course not Charlie.
But that's not the point.
- That's not the point at all.
- What is the point?
- The point Charlie...
- Uh- huh?
- is...
- Yeah?
that she was
thinking about me.
I've only met her once
and already...
she's thinking about me.
Damn it it's gonna happen guys.
I feel it.
She is going to be mine.
Carpe! Carpe!
No grades at stake gentlemen.
Just take a stroll.
There it is.
- I don't know but I've been told.
Doing poetry is cold.
- Doing poetry is cold.
- Left. Left. Left right left.
Left. Left.
Left right left.
Left. Halt!
Thank you gentlemen.
If you noticed everyone started off
with their own stride their own pace.
Mr Pitts taking his time.
He knew he'll get there one day.
Mr Cameron. You could see him thinking
"Is this right? It might be right.
It might be right. I know that- -
Maybe not. I don't know."
Mr Overstreet
driven by a deeper force. Yes.
We know that. All right. Now I didn't
bring them up here to ridicule them.
I brought them up here to
illustrate the point of conformity.
The difficulty in maintaining your
own beliefs in the face of others.
Now I see the look in your eyes like
"I would have walked differently."
Well ask yourselves
why you were clapping.
Now we all have a great need
for acceptance.
But you must trust that
your beliefs are unique your own.
Even though others may think
them odd or unpopular.
Even though the herd may go
"That's ba- a- a- a- ad."
Robert Frost said
"Two roads diverged in the wood and I
I took the one less traveled by.
And that has made
all the difference."
I want you to find
your own walk right now
your own way of striding
pacing any direction.
Anything you want whether it's proud
whether it's silly anything.
Gentlemen the courtyard is yours.
You don't have to perform
just make it for yourself.
Mr Dalton
will you be joining us?
Exercising the right
not to walk.
Thank you Mr Dalton.
Just illustrated the point.
Swim against the stream.
Todd?
- Hey.
- What's going on?
- Nothing.
- Today's my birthday.
- Is today your birthday?
- Happy birthday.
- Thanks.
- What did you get?
- My parents just gave me this.
Isn't this the same desk set- -
Yeah yeah they gave me
the same thing as last year.
- Oh.
Maybe they thought you needed
another one.
Maybe they weren't
thinking about anything at all.
The funny thing is about this
is I didn't even like it the first time.
Todd I think you're underestimating
the value of this desk set.
I mean who would want
a football or a baseball- -
- Or a car.
- Mm- hmm or a car- -
if they could have a desk set
as wonderful as this one.
I mean if I were ever going
to buy a desk set... twice
I would probably
buy this one... both times.
In fact its... shape is- -
It's rather aerodynamic
isn't it?
You can feel it.
This desk set wants to fly.
Todd...
the world's first
unmanned flying desk set.
Oh my!
Well I wouldn't worry.
You'll get another one next year.
"To live deep and suck out
all the marrow of life.
- To put to rout all that was not life- - "
My God.
- Is this it?
- Yeah this is it.
Go ahead. Go on in.
It's my cave. Watch your step.
Uh- oh.
Hi.
- Hello.
- Hi.
Hi guys. Meet uh Gloria and- -
- Tina.
- This is the pledge class
of the Dead Poets Society.
- Hello.
- How do you do?
- Hi.
Guys move. Move!
Come on folks it's Friday night.
Let's get on with the meeting.
Guys I have an announcement to make.
In keeping with the spirit of passionate
experimentation of the Dead Poets
I'm giving up the name
Charles Dalton.
From now on
call me Nuwanda.
Nuwanda?
Hello? Hello Chris?
I crashed in thejungle
while trying to keep a date
With my little girl
who was back in the States
- I was stranded in thejungle-
- Knox!
- Hi.
- You made it! Great.
- Did you bring anybody?
- No.
No? Ginny Danburry's here.
Look I have to go find Chet.
- Why don't you go downstairs?
That's where everybody is.
- Yeah but Chris I've- -
- Make yourself at home.
- But I've- -
Baby baby
let's make romance
You know your old- time lover
hasn't got a chance
- Hi guys.
Hey you Mutt Sanders'
brother?
Bubba this guy look like
Mutt Sanders to you or what?
- You're his brother?
- No relation.
- Never heard of him. Sorry guys.
- Where's our manners Steve?
Here's Mutt Sanders' brother
and we don't even offer him a drink.
- Here you go. Have some whisky pal.
- Yeah.
I uh I don't really drink whisky.
- To Mutt.
To Mutt.
- How the hell is old Mutt anyway?
- Yeah what's old Mutter been up to?
I don't really know Mutt.
To the Mighty Mutt.
- To Mighty Mutt.
Listen I gotta go find Patsy.
- Say hello to Mutt for me okay?
- Will do.
Hell of a guy your brother Mutt.
We gonna have a meeting
or what?
Yeah if you guys
don't have a meeting
how do we know
if we want to join?
"Join"?
"Shall I compare thee
to a summer's day?
Thou art more lovely
and more temperate."
That's so sweet.
- I made that up just for you.
- You did?
I'll write one
for you too Gloria.
"She walks in beauty
like the night.
like the night...
"of cloudless climes
and starry skies.
"All that's best
dark and bright
- meet in her aspect and her eyes."
- That's beautiful.
There's plenty more
where that came from.
She sure looks fine to me
What's her name
Look out
Let me call her one time
Hey little girl
Gee you sure look fine
God help me.
Ooh baby
you're not mine
Hey little girl
How's about a date
- Carpe diem.
- Hey little girl
How's about a date
You know I'll come get you
early baby
Won't keep you out
too late
Say little girl
Now how's about a kiss
Yeah say little girl
How's about a kiss
- You don't remember?
- Well if you don't kiss me baby
- Chet. Chet. Look.
- What?
- It's Mutt Sanders' brother.
- Huh?
- Knox what- -
- And he's feeling up your girl!
What are you doing?
- What the hell are you doing?
- Chet. Chet don't!
- Now Chet I know this looks bad- -
- Leave him alone.
Chet no!
You'll hurt him!
- Chet stop it! Leave him alone!
- Damn!
- Chet stop it!
- Bastard!
Knox are you all right?
Chris get the hell away from him!
- Chet you hurt him!
- Good!
- I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
- It's okay. It's- It's okay.
Next time I see you
you die.
Go ahead.
Pass it around.
Me and Pitts are working
on a hi- fi system.
It shouldn't be that hard to
uh to put together.
Yeah. Uh I might
be going to Yale.
Uh but I- I might not.
Don't you guys miss
having girls around here?
- Yeah.
That's part of what this club is about.
In fact
I'd like to announce...
I published an article in the school
paper in the name of the Dead Poets
- What?
- demanding girls
be admitted to Welton...
- You didn't.
- so we can all stop beating off.
- How did you do that?
- I'm one of the proofers.
- I slipped the article in.
- It's- It's over now.
Why?
Nobody knows who we are.
Well don't you think
they're gonna figure out who wrote it?
They're gonna come to you and ask
to know what the Dead Poets Society is.
Charlie you had no right
to do something like that.
It's Nuwanda Cameron.
That's right. It's Nuwanda.
Are we just playing around out here
or do we mean what we say?
If all we do is come together
and read a bunch of poems to each other
- what the hell are we doing?
- All right.
But you still shouldn't
have done it Charlie.
This could mean trouble.
You don't speak for the club.
Hey would you not worry about
your precious little neck?
If they catch me
I'll tell them I made it up.
Fine.
Sit.
In this week's issue
of Welton Honor
there appeared a profane
and unauthorized article.
Rather than spend my valuable time
ferreting out the guilty persons- -
and let me assure you
I will find them- -
I'm asking any and all students
who know anything about this article...
to make themselves known
here and now.
Whoever the guilty persons are
this is your only chance to avoid
expulsion from this school.
Welton Academy.
Hello.
Yes he is.
just a moment.
Mr Nolan it's for you.
It's God!
He says we should have girls
at Welton.
Wipe that smirk off your face.
If you think Mr Dalton
that you're the first to try to get
thrown out of this school think again.
Others have had similar notions and have
failed just as surely as you will fail.
Assume the position.
Count aloud Mr Dalton.
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Five.
What is this Dead Poets Society?
I want names.
- You kicked out?
- No.
So what happened?
I'm to turn everybody in
apologise to the school
and all will be forgiven.
So what are you gonna do?
- Charlie- -
- Damn it Neil
the name is Nuwanda.
Excuse me.
May we have a word Mr Keating?
Certainly.
This was my first classroomJohn.
Did you know that?
My first desk.
I didn't know you taught
Mr Nolan.
English.
Long before your time.
It was hard giving it up
I can tell you.
I'm hearing rumours
about some unorthodox
teaching methods in your classroom.
I'm not saying they've had anything
to do with the Dalton boy's outburst
but I don't think I have to warn you
boys his age are very impressionable.
Well your reprimand made
quite an impression I'm sure.
- What was going on
in the courtyard the other day?
- Courtyard?
- Boys marching clapping in unison.
- Oh that.
That was an exercise to prove a point:
dangers of conformity.
WellJohn the curriculum here is set.
It's proven. It works.
If you question it what's to
prevent them from doing the same?
I always thought the idea of education
was to learn to think for yourself.
At these boys' age?
Not on your life!
TraditionJohn. Discipline.
Prepare them for college
and the rest will take care of itself.
Creak.
He starts walking around
towards my left.
Creak. Creak.
'Assume the position Mr Dalton "
which means- -
All right gentlemen.
- Mr Keating.
- Mr Dalton.
That was a pretty lame stunt
you pulled today.
You're siding with Mr Nolan?
What about carpe diem
and sucking all the marrow...
- out of life and all that?
- Sucking the marrow out of life...
doesn't mean
choking on the bone.
There is a time for daring
and there is a time for caution.
And a wise man understands
which is called for.
But I thought you'd like that.
No.
You being expelled from school
is not daring to me. It's stupid.
'Cause you'll miss some
golden opportunities.
Yeah? Like what?
Like if nothing else
the opportunity to attend my classes.
Got it ace?
Aye aye Captain.
Keep your head about you.
That goes
for the lot of you.
- Yes Captain.
Phone call from God.
If it'd been collect
it would have been daring.
- All right. Go on boy.
- No.
- We're trying to rehearse okay? Go.
A good persuasion
therefore hear me Hermia.
Wait wait. The excitement. I don't
hear any excitement about this play.
Now take her hand
bring her downstage...
and stop
and "Fair gentle Hermia."
Okay? Try again.
What's for dinner?
- Spaghetti and meatballs!
- Food!
Save some for me.
"But room fairy!
Here comes Oberon."
- Father.
- Neil.
Wait a minute.
Before you say anything
- please let me ex- -
- Don't you dare talk back to me.
It's bad enough that
you've wasted your time...
with this this
absurd acting business
but you deliberately
deceived me.
How- How- How did you expect
to get away with this?
Answer me.
Who put you up to it?
- Was it this new man? Keating?
- No.
Nobody p- - I thought I'd surprise you.
I've gotten all A's in every class.
Did you really think
I wasn't going to find out?
"Oh my niece is in a play
with your son" says Mrs Marks.
"No no no" I say. "You must be
mistaken. My son's not in a play."
You made a liar
out of me Neil!
Now tomorrow you go to them
and you tell them that you're quitting.
No I can't.
I have the main part.
The performance is tomorrow night!
I don't care if the world
comes to an end tomorrow night
you are through with that play!
Is that clear?
Yes sir.
I made a great many sacrifices
to get you here Neil
and you will not let me down.
No sir.
It's open.
Neil what's up?
- Can I speak to you a minute?
- Certainly. Sit down.
Oh.
- I'm sorry. Here.
- Excuse me.
- Get you some tea?
- Tea? Sure.
- Want some milk or sugar in that?
- No thanks.
Gosh they don't give you
much room around here.
It's part of the monastic oath.
They don't want worldly things
distracting me from my teaching.
- She's pretty.
- She's also in London.
Makes it a little difficult.
- How do you stand it?
- Stand what?
You can go anywhere. You can do
anything. How can you stand being here?
Because I love teaching.
I don't want to be anywhere else.
- What's up?
- I just talked to my father.
He's making me quit the play
at Henley Hall.
But acting is everything to me.
I mean- -
But he doesn't know. He- -
I can see his point. We're not
a rich family like Charlie's. I mean- -
But he's planning the rest
of my life for me.
And he- he's never asked me
what I want.
Have you ever told your father
what you just told me?
About your passion for acting?
Have you showed him that?
- I can't.
- Why not?
I can't talk to him this way.
Then you're acting for him too.
You're playing the part
of the dutiful son.
I know this sounds impossible
but you have to talk to him.
You have to show him
who you are what your heart is.
I know what he'll say.
He'll tell me that acting's a whim
and I should forget it.
They're counting on me.
He'll just tell me to put it
out of my mind for my own good.
You are not
an indentured servant.
It's not a whim for you. You prove it to
him by your conviction and your passion.
You show him that
and if he still doesn't believe you- -
Well by then you'll be out of school
and you can do anything you want.
No.
What about the play?
The show's tomorrow night.
Then you have to talk
to him before tomorrow night.
I- -
- Isn't there an easier way?
- No.
I'm trapped.
No you're not.
Chris!
Chris! Chris Noel.
Do you know where she is?
- Um I think she's in Room 111.
- Thanks.
I know.
Excuse me. Chris- -
Knox what are you doing here?
I came to apologize for the other night.
I brought you these
and a poem I wrote for you.
Knox don't you know that
if Chet finds you here he'll kill you?
- I don't care. I love you Chris.
- Knox you're crazy.
Look I acted like a jerk
and I know it.
- Please accept these. Please.
- No. No I- I can't.
Just forget it.
- Knox I don't believe this.
- All I'm asking you to do is listen.
"The heavens made a girl named Chris...
"with hair and skin of gold.
"To touch her...
would be paradise. "
Get out of here. Cameron you fool.
Hey how'd it go?
Did you read it to her?
- Yeah.
- Wow. What'd she say?
- Nothing.
- What do you mean nothing?
Nothing.
But I did it.
Well what did she say?
She had to say something!
- Hey Knox!
- Seize the day!
- Did you talk to your father?
- Uh yeah.
He didn't like it one bit but at least
he's letting me stay in the play.
He won't be able to m- make it.
He's in Chicago.
But uh I think he's gonna
let me stay with acting.
Really? You told him
what you told me?
Yeah.
He wasn't happy.
But he'll be gone
at least four days.
I don't think he'll make
the show but...
I think he'll let me
stay with it.
"Keep up the schoolwork."
Thanks.
- Oh baby.
- Beautiful baby.
- I am- -
- Excuse me.
- Just a moment. Yes. You're so good.
Come on Todd.
I'm trying to fix this.
Come on Nuwanda
we're going to miss Neil's entrance.
He said something about
getting red before we left.
- "Getting red"? What does that mean?
- I- - You know Charlie.
So Charlie
what's this 'getting red"bit?
- Ooh.
W- What is that?
It's an Indian warrior
symbol for virility.
Makes me feel potent
like I can drive girls crazy.
Oh come on Charlie.
The girls are waiting.
Whoa.
Chris.
What are you doing here?
- Gentlemen let's go!
- Go ahead guys. I'll catch up.
Yeah. Come on guys.
Chris you can't be in here.
- If they catch you we're both
gonna be in big trouble.
- Come on.
- Oh but it's fine if- -
- Shh shh. Chris.
It's fine for you to come barging into
my school and make a fool out of me?
I didn't mean
to make a fool out of you.
Well you did.
Chet found out.
It took everything I could do to keep
him from coming here and killing you.
- Knox you have got to stop this stuff.
- I can't Chris. I love you.
Knox you say that over and over.
You don't- -
You don't even know me.
Will you bejoining us Mr Overstreet?
Go ahead Captain. I'll walk.
Knox. Knox
i- it just so happens...
that I could care less
about you.
Then you wouldn't be here
warning me about Chet.
I have to go.
I'm gonna be late for the play.
- Are you going with him?
- Chet? To a play?
- Are you kidding?
- Then come with me.
Knox you are so infuriating!
Come on Chris
just give me one chance.
If you don't like me after tonight
I'll stay away forever.
- Uh- huh.
- I promise. Dead Poets honour.
You come with me tonight
and then if you don't want to see me
again I swear I'll bow out.
- What would happen if Chet found out?
- He won't know anything.
We'll sit in the back
and sneak away as soon as it's over.
And I suppose you would promise
that this would be the end of it?
- Dead Poets honour.
- What is that?
- My word.
- Hmm.
You are so infuriating.
Hey there he is!
Hey hey hey hey!
Shh boys.
Either I mistake your shape
and making quite...
or else you are that shrewd and
knavish sprite called Robin Goodfellow!
Thou speak'st aright.
I am that merry wanderer
of the night.
I jest to Oberon
and make him smile...
when I a fat and bean- fed
horse beguile.
Neighing in the likeness
of a filly foal.
Sometime lurk I
in a gossip's bowl...
in very likeness
of a roasted crab.
And when she drink
against her lips I bob...
and on her withered dewlap
pour the ale.
- The wisest aunt
telling the saddest tale.
- He's good. He's really good.
Sometime for three- foot stool
mistaketh me.
Then slip I from her bum
down topples she and "Tailor" cries...
and falls into a cough.
And then the whole quire
hold their hips and laugh...
and waxen in their mirth
nee- e- e- eze...
and swear.
A merrier hour
was never wasted there.
But room fairy.
- Here comes Oberon.
- And here my mistress.
Would that he were gone.
Then by your side
no bed- room me deny.
For lying so Hermia
I do not lie.
Lysander riddles very
prettily. Much beshrew my manners...
and my pride if Hermia
meant to say Lysander lied.
But gentle friend
for love and courtesy...
lie further off
in human modesty
such separation as may well be said
becomes a virtuous bachelor and maid.
Good night sweet friend. Thy love
ne'er alter 'til thy sweet life end.
Amen.
Amen to that fair prayer say I.
- And then end life when I end loyalty.
- Neil. That's your cue Neil.
Come on Neil.
Here's your crown. Let's go.
If we shadows have offended...
think but this
and all is mended.
That you have but slumber'd here
while these visions did appear.
And this weak and idle theme
no more yielding but a dream.
Gentles do not reprehend.
If you pardon we will mend.
And as I am an honest Puck
if we have unearned luck
now to 'scape
the serpent's tongue
we will make amends ere long;
else the Puck a liar call.
So good night
unto you all.
Give me your hands
if we be friends
and Robin shall
restore amends.
Yawp! Carpe diem!
That was great!
Excuse me. I'm Neil's father.
I'd like to see him please.
Neil your father.
- What did you think?
- You were all just wonderful!
Excuse me please.
- Excuse me. Excuse me.
- Neil! Back here! Neil!
Neil Neil you were great!
Come back Neil.
- I can't guys.
- Neil.
Excuse me.
Neil. Neil.
You have the gift.
What a performance.
You left even me speechless.
- You have to stay with- -
- Get in the car.
Keating
you stay away from my son.
Neil! Neil!
Mr Perry come on!
Don't make it
any worse than it is.
Do you want to take the other car?
Is it okay
if we walk back?
Captain?
- Knox?
- What?
We'll be home about 11:30.
We're trying very hard...
to understand why it is
that you insist on defying us.
But whatever the reason
we're not gonna let you ruin your life.
I'm withdrawing you from Welton and
enrolling you in Braden Military School.
You're going to Harvard
and you're gonna be a doctor.
But that's ten more years.
- Father that's a lifetime!
- Oh stop it!
Don't be so dramatic.
You make it sound like a prison term.
You don't understand Neil.
You have opportunities
that I never even dreamt of!
- I am not going to let you waste them!
- I've got to tell you what I feel.
- We've been so worried about- -
- What? What? Tell me what you feel!
What is it?
Is it more of this- this
acting business?
Because you can forget that.
What?
Nothing.
Nothing?
Well then
let's go to bed.
I was good.
I was really good.
Go on get some sleep.
It's going to be all right.
What was that?
What?
- That sound.
- What sound?
Tom?
What is it?
What's wrong?
Neil?
Tom what is it?
What's wrong?
Neil?
- Neil?
- I'll look outside.
Neil?
No!
- Oh Neil! Oh my God!
- Oh my God. Oh no no.
- Oh my son! My son! My poor son!
- He's all right.
He's all right!
- Stop it. Stop it. Stop it.
Stop it! Stop it.
Todd. Todd.
Oh Charlie.
What is it?
Neil's dead.
It's so beautiful.
Todd!
- It's okay Todd.
- Calm down.
It's all right Todd.
- Todd it's okay.
- It's okay Todd.
It's all right. It's all right.
- He wouldn't have done it.
- You can't explain it Todd.
- It was his father!
- No!
He wouldn't have left us.
It's because he- -
He wouldn't have.
- His dad was- -
- Todd.
His- His father did it.
His father killed him.
He made him do it.
Todd!
Leave him be.
...All my life
Shall surely
Follow me
And in God's house
Forevermore
My dwelling place
Shall be
Amen
The death of Neil Perry is a tragedy.
He was a fine student
one of Welton's best.
And he will be missed.
We've contacted each of your parents
to explain the situation.
Naturally they're all
quite concerned.
At the request
of Neil's family
I intend to conduct a thorough
inquiry into this matter.
Your complete cooperation
is expected.
- You told him about this meeting?
- Twice.
That's it guys.
We're all fried.
- How do you mean?
- Cameron's a fink.
- He's in Nolan's office now finking.
- About what?
The club Pittsie.
Think about it.
The board of directors
the trustees and Mr Nolan.
Do you think for one moment they're
gonna let this thing just blow over?
Schools go down because of things
like this. They need a scapegoat.
What's going on guys?
You finked
didn't you Cameron?
"Finked"? I don't know
what the hell you're talking about.
You told Nolan everything about
the club is what I'm talking about.
Look in case you hadn't heard
Dalton there's something...
called an honour code
at this school all right?
If a teacher asks you a question
you tell the truth or you're expelled.
- You- -
- Charlie!
He's a rat! He's in it up to his eyes
so he ratted to save himself!
- Don't touch him Charlie.
You do and you're out.
- I'm out anyway!
- You don't know that. Not yet!
- He's right there Charlie.
And if you guys are smart you will do
exactly what I did and cooperate.
They're not after us.
We're the victims.
Us and Neil.
What's that mean?
Who are they after?
Why Mr Keating of course.
The "Captain" himself!
You guys didn't really think he could
avoid responsibility did you?
Mr Keating responsible for Neil?
Is that what they're saying?
Well who else do you think dumb ass?
The administration? Mr Perry?
Mr Keating put us up
to all this crap didn't he?
If it wasn't for Mr Keating
Neil would be...
cozied up in his room right now
studying his chemistry...
- and dreaming of being called "Doctor"!
- That is not true Cameron!
You know that!
He didn't put us up to anything.
- Neil loved acting.
- Believe what you want
but I say let Keating fry.
I mean
why ruin our lives?
You just signed
your expulsion papers Nuwanda.
And if the rest of you are smart
you'll do exactly what I did!
They know everything anyway.
You can't save Keating
but you can save yourselves.
Knox Overstreet.
- Meeks.
- Go away. I have to study.
What happened to Nuwanda?
Expelled.
What'd you tell 'em?
Nothing they didn't
already know.
Todd Anderson.
- Hello son.
- Hello darling.
Mom.
Have a seat Mr Anderson.
Mr Anderson I think we've pretty well
put together what's happened here.
You do admit to being a part
of this Dead Poets Society?
Answer him Todd.
Yes sir.
I have here
a detailed description...
of what occurred at your meetings.
It describes how your teacher
Mr Keating
encouraged you boys
to organize this club...
and to use it as a source
of inspiration...
for reckless
and self- indulgent behaviour.
It describes how Mr Keating
both in and out of the classroom
encouraged Neil Perry to follow
his obsession with acting...
when he knew all along it was
against the explicit orders...
of Neil's parents.
It was Mr Keating's blatant abuse
of his position as teacher...
that led directly
to Neil Perry's death.
Read that document carefully
Todd.
Very carefully.
If you've nothing
to add or amend sign it.
What's gonna happen
to Mr Keating?
I've had enough. Sign the paper Todd!
Grass is gramen or herba.
Lapis is stone.
The entire building
is aedificium.
Sit.
I'll be teaching this
class through exams.
We'll find a permanent English teacher
during the break.
Who will tell me where you are
in the Pritchard textbook?
Mr Anderson?
- Uh in the in the Prit- -
- I can't hear you Mr Anderson.
In the in the in the Pritchard- -
Kindly inform me
Mr Cameron.
We skipped around a lot sir.
We covered the romantics and some of the
chapters on post- Civil War literature.
- What about the realists?
- We skipped most of that sir.
All right then
we'll start over.
What is poetry?
Come!
Excuse me.
I came for my personals.
Should I come back
after class?
Get them now
Mr Keating.
Gentlemen turn to page 21
of the introduction.
Mr Cameron
read aloud the excellent essay
by Dr Pritchard...
on "Understanding Poetry. "
That page has been
ripped out sir.
Well borrow
somebody else's book.
They're all ripped out sir.
What do you mean
"They're all ripped out"?
- Sir we- - Ac- -
- Never mind.
Read.
"'Understanding Poetry'
by DrJ. Evans Pritchard Ph.D.
"To fully understand poetry
we must first be fluent...
"with its metre rhyme
and figures of speech.
"Then ask two questions.
One:
"How artfully has the objective
of the poem been rendered?
"And two:
"How important
is that objective?
"Question one
rates the poem's perfection.
"Question two rates its importance.
'And once these questions
have been answered
"determining a poem's greatness
becomes a relatively simple matter.
If the poem's score for perfection is
plotted on the horizontal of a graph- - "
- Mr Keating!
They made everybody sign it.
- Quiet Mr Anderson!
- You've got to believe me. It's true.
- I do believe you Todd.
- Leave Mr Keating.
- But it wasn't his fault!
Sit down Mr Anderson! One more
outburst from you or anyone else
and you're out
of this school!
Leave Mr Keating.
I said "Leave Mr Keating."
- O Captain my Captain.
- Sit down Mr Anderson.
Do you hear me?
Sit down!
This is your final warning
Anderson.
How dare you.
Do you hear me?
O Captain my Captain.
Mr Overstreet I warn you!
Sit down!
Sit down! All of you!
I want you seated!
Sit down!
Leave Mr Keating.
All of you down!
I want you seated!
Do you hear me?
Sit down!
Thank you boys.