♪ They're writing
songs of love
[ALARM CLOCK RINGING]
♪ But not for
me
♪ A lucky star's
above
♪ But not for
me
[RINGING]
♪ With love to
lead the way
♪ I've found
more clouds are grey
♪ Than any Russian
play could guarantee
♪ I was a fool to
fall
♪ And get that
way
♪ Heigh-ho, alas,
and also lack-a-day
♪ Although I
can't dismiss
♪ The memory of
her kiss
♪ I guess she's
not for me
Good morning, Mrs. Statons.
Good morning, madam.
Thank you.
Late! Late!
At last.
Hello!
♪ It all began so
well, but what an end
Sorry we're late.
Good morning, darling.
Put it in the back.
♪ This is the
time
♪ A fellow needs
a friend
♪ When every
happy plot
♪ Ends with a
marriage knot
♪ And there's no
knot
♪ For me
♪
Oh, fuck! Fuck!
[GROANS]
Fuck!
Oh, fuck!
[ENGINE STALLING]
Fuck. Right.
We'll take yours.
It only goes 40 miles an hour.
[ENGINE REVVING]
What turnoff?
Um...
Better not be the B359.
It's the B359.
CHARLES: Fuck it!
[TIRES SCREECHING]
Fuck!
[TRUCK HORN BLARING]
CHARLES: Fuck.
[BELLS TOLLING]
[TIRES SCREECH]
Come on.
Fuck!
Oh, fuck!
Fuck. Fuck.
Fuckity-fuck.
Bugger.
[LAUGHING]
You look so beautiful in white.
Is it twisted?
Hello! You look lovely.
Hello, Charles!
ANGUS & LAURA
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
There's a sort of greatness
to your lateness.
Thanks. It's not achieved
without real suffering.
Look, I am so, so sorry, Angus.
Inexcusable.
I mean, I'll be killing
myself after the service,
if that's any consolation.
Doesn't matter.
Tom was standing by.
Thanks, Tom.
You're a saint.
In a disastrous haircut.
Sorry.
As long as you haven't
forgotten the rings.
No.
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
Hate people being late.
[EXCLAIMS DISAPPROVINGLY]
[HERE COMES THE BRIDE
PLAYING ON ORGAN]
Here we go.
Oh, isn't she lovely?
Scarlett, you're blind. She
looks like a big meringue.
Dear friends,
what a joy it is to
welcome you to our church
on this wonderful day
for Angus and Laura.
Before we start the service, let us
all join together in the first hymn.
[ORGAN PLAYING]
ALL: ♪ And did those feet
in ancient time
♪ Walk upon England's
mountains green
♪ And was the holy
Lamb of God
♪ On England's
pleasant pastures seen
♪ And did the
countenance divine
♪ Shine forth upon
our clouded hills
♪ And was Jerusalem
builded here
♪ Among those
dark satanic mills ♪
[WHISPERS] Scarlett.
[INAUDIBLE]
Dearly beloved, we are
gathered together here
in the sight of God and in
the face of this congregation
to join together this man and
this woman in holy matrimony.
Which is an honorable estate instituted
in the time of man's innocency.
Back in a sec.
Therefore, if any man can show
any just cause or impediment
why they may not be
lawfully joined together,
let him speak now
or forever hold his peace.
Do you promise to love her,
comfort her,
honor and keep her
in sickness and in health,
and, forsaking all others,
keep thee only unto her for
as long as ye both shall live?
I do.
LAURA: To love
and to cherish.
VICAR: Till death
us do part.
Till death us do part.
And thereto,
I pledge thee my troth.
Do you have the ring?
[CLINKING]
With this ring, I thee wed.
ANGUS: With this ring,
I thee wed.
VICAR: With my body,
I thee worship.
With my body, I thee worship.
And with all my worldly
goods, I do thee endow.
goods, I thee endow.
Hmm.
"If I speak with the tongues
of men and of angels,
"but have not love,
"I am become a sounding brass
or a clanging cymbal."
Good point.
BOTH: ♪ You know I can't
smile without you
♪ I can't smile without you
♪ I can't laugh
and I can't sing
♪ I'm findin' it hard
to do anything
♪ You see, I feel sad
when you're sad
♪ I feel sad
♪ I feel glad when you're glad
♪ If you only knew
what I'm going through ♪
[ORGAN PLAYING]
[CHUCKLING]
[BABY WAILING]
[BELLS TOLLING]
Great hat.
Thanks.
I bought it specially.
Thank you, uh...
There.
Get in your position, please.
Thank you. Smile.
Splendid, I thought.
What did you think?
I thought, splendid.
Splendid. I thought.
Scarlett, what a fabulous dress!
Ecclesiastical purple
and the pagan orange
symbolizing the magical
symbiosis in marriage
between the heathen
and Christian traditions?
That's right.
Lovely. And again.
[CAMERA CLICKS]
Any idea who the girl
in the black hat is?
FIONA: Name's Carrie.
CHARLES: Pretty.
American.
Interesting.
Slut.
Really?
Used to work at <font face= "sansSerif" Vogue. Lives in America now.
Only goes out with
very glamorous people.
Quite out of your league.
Well, that's a relief.
Thanks.
[PEOPLE CHEERING]
See you there.
Bye. Off you go.
Off you go.
Right. Reception.
MAN: Bye!
WOMAN: Bye! Bye!
[SHEEP BLEATING]
Oh!
Anyone else tread in a cow pat?
No. Thought not.
See you in a mo.
Do you think I'd hate him as
much if he wasn't my brother?
[LAUGHS]
They're only blowing
my chances for a mount
by smelling of dung all the
way through the reception.
[COWS MOOING]
FIONA: Oh, God. I never know what
to say in these wretched lineups.
It's a cinch. Just give
a big, warm hug
and say the bride
looks pregnant.
Or you could stick with tradition
and go for, "You must be very proud."
Heaven preserve us.
You must be very proud.
[CHUCKLING] Thank you.
Hello.
[WOMEN LAUGHING]
Hi, we met at the Rotary.
It's Richard. Richard Maples.
Oh, yes.
Bastard.
Hello, Paul.
Hello, Chuck.
Two, please. JOHN: It's
so nice to see you.
You have fun, now.
Take care.
Oh, hello.
Hi.
Uh, you want one of these?
Oh, thank you.
Um, I...
Hello, Charles.
Hello, dear John.
How are you?
Good, good. This is, uh...
Carrie.
Delighted. I'm John.
Hi, John.
[CHUCKLING]
So, John, how's that
gorgeous girlfriend of yours?
Uh, she's no longer
my girlfriend.
Oh, dear.
Still, I wouldn't get
too gloomy about it.
Rumor has it she never stopped
bonking old Toby de Lisle,
just in case
you didn't work out.
She's now my wife.
Excellent. Excellent.
Congratulations.
Excuse me.
[STAMMERING]
Any kids or anything, John?
Do we hear the patter
of tiny feet?
No.
Well, there's plenty of
time for that, isn't there?
No hurry.
[GRUNTS]
Hi. How are you?
My name's Fiona.
Uh, I'm Gerald.
What do you do?
I'm training to be a priest.
Good Lord!
Do you do weddings?
No. No, not yet. I
will, though, of course.
Jolly nerve-racking.
Yes, rather like
the first time one has sex.
Well, I suppose so.
They're rather less messy, of course,
and far less call for condoms.
[GIGGLES]
[HEAVES]
[INAUDIBLE]
How're you doing?
Remember the time you
started Dad's boat
and the propeller cut my
leg to shreds?
This is worse.
Who's that boy
over there in the gray?
Uh, his name's David.
Something of a dish, isn't he?
Well, I've always thought so.
Why are they, uh...
Oh, the dish can't hear.
Oh!
Gosh.
Yeah, silent,
but deadly attractive.
[GONG CLANGING]
Bang, bang, bang.
That's it.
Into the marquee, please,
ladies and gentlemen.
Dinner is served.
How do you do?
Hello. Tom.
Splendid to meet you.
Very exciting.
Hi.
My name's Scarlett.
Don't let me drink too much,
because I'll get really flirty.
How do you do?
My name is Charles.
Don't be ridiculous.
Charles died 20 years ago.
[STAMMERING] Must be a
different Charles, I think.
Are you telling me
I don't know my own brother?
No, no.
[GLASS CLINKING]
Ladies and gentlemen, I'm sorry to
drag you from your delicious desserts.
Uh, there are just
one or two little things
I feel I should say as best man.
[STAMMERING] This is only the second
time I've ever been a best man.
I hope I did the job
all right that time.
The couple in question are
at least still talking to me.
[PEOPLE LAUGHING]
Unfortunately, they're not
actually talking to each other.
[STUTTERING] The divorce came
through a couple of months ago.
[ALL LAUGHING]
But I'm assured it had
absolutely nothing to do with me.
Apparently, Paula knew that Pierce
had slept with her younger sister
before I mentioned it
in the speech.
[ALL LAUGHING]
[PEOPLE APPLAUDING]
The fact that he slept with
her mother came as a surprise
but I think was incidental
to the nightmare
of recrimination
and violence that became
their two-day marriage.
Anyway, enough of that. My job
today is to talk about Angus.
And there are no skeletons in
his cupboard, or so I thought.
[PEOPLE EXCLAIMING]
I'll come on to that
in a minute.
I would just like to say this.
Um...
I am, as ever,
in bewildered awe
of anyone who makes
this kind of commitment
that Angus and Laura
have made today.
I know I couldn't do it,
and I think it's wonderful
they can.
So, anyway, back to
Angus and those sheep.
[PEOPLE EXCLAIMING]
[MAN BLEATING]
[ALL APPLAUDING]
So, ladies and gentlemen, if you'd raise
your glasses, uh, the adorable couple.
MAN: Yes.
ALL: The adorable couple.
The adorable couple.
[PEOPLE CHEERING]
MAN: Give her one
for me, Angus.
[CROCODILE ROCK
PLAYING]
MAN: ♪ I remember
when rock was young
♪ Me and Suzie
had so much fun
♪ Holding hands
and skimming stones
♪ Had an old gold Chevy
and a place of my own
♪ But the biggest
kick I ever got
♪ Was doing a thing
called the Crocodile Rock
♪ While the other kids were
rockin' round the clock
♪ We were hoppin' and boppin'
to the Crocodile Rock ♪
[I WILL SURVIVE
PLAYING]
♪ I just walked in
to find you here
♪ With that sad
look upon your face
♪ I should have
changed my stupid lock
♪ I should have made
you leave the key
♪ I should've known
for just one second
♪ You'd be back
to bother me ♪
I remember the first time I
saw Gareth on the dance floor,
I feared lives would be lost.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
She's a pretty girl.
When you can't take your eyes
off, is that love at first sight?
Oh, good Lord, no,
no, it's the...
Just the bloke
she's dancing with,
I used to play rugby
with him at school.
I'm just trying to remember what
position he played in, that's all.
Though, let's say one...
For the sake of argument, one did
take a fancy to someone at a wedding.
I mean, do you think there really are
people who can just go up and say,
"Hi, babe, name's Charles.
This is your lucky night."
Well, if there are,
they're not English.
Not quite.
Three weeks is about my
question-popping minimum.
You know I love you,
Jean, don't you?
I love you.
And, Mike, I've never met you
before but I love you very much.
I really do.
Ignore her, she's drunk.
At least, I hope she is.
Otherwise I'm in real trouble.
How's it going, Lyds?
Bloody awful.
Oh, dear, what's the problem?
I was promised sex.
Everybody said, "If you'll be
a bridesmaid, you'll get sex.
"You'll be
fighting them off."
But not so much
as a tongue in sight.
Well, I mean,
if you fancy anything
I could always...
Oh, don't be ridiculous,
Bernard.
I'm not that desperate.
No. Right. Of course.
Fair enough.
It's a good point.
[PEOPLE CHEERING]
[WHOOPING]
LAURA: Bye!
Bye! Have a lovely,
lovely time!
Bye!
MAN: ♪ I feel it
in my fingers
♪ I feel it in my toes
♪ The love that's
all around me
♪ And so the feeling grows
♪ It's written on the wind
♪ It's everywhere I go
Where are you staying
tonight, Charles?
Oh, Scarlett and I
are at some pub.
The Lucky Boat, something like that.
Aren't we all?
Ah, no.
Slight change of plan.
The others are, in fact, coming back
to my place. Nansy's in residence.
Might knock us up a quick plate of eggs
and bac over a late-night Scrabble.
Wondered if you'd like to join.
Oh, yeah, that'd be great.
Thanks very much.
Is there room for Scarlett?
Oh, absolutely.
137 rooms, actually.
Tommy, are you the
richest man in England?
Oh, no, no!
I believe we're about seventh.
Mmm-hmm.
The Queen, obviously.
I know. Right.
And that Branson bloke's
doing terribly well.
Well, excellent news.
I'll go tell Scarlett.
Yeah.
That's, uh, unless
you get lucky first.
MAN: Forget about it!
Get out of it!
Get out. Go on!
Hi.
Hi. Hi!
I thought you'd gone.
No, not yet. I was just wondering
where you were staying tonight.
Uh, well...
I was staying at some pub
called the Lucky...
The Boat, or something like that.
Boatman.
Right. But, uh...
But now I'm gonna stay at some
friend's house with some friends.
[STAMMERING]
Well, I say "house."
I think "enormous castle" is
a more accurate description.
Oh, that's too bad,
'cause I'm at The Boatman.
Oh.
Well, it was nice
not quite meeting you.
It was a great speech.
Thanks.
Well, I'm going now.
No! No, no, no, no, no,
don't go. We can...
We can meet now.
The evening's
just getting going.
Oh, I think we both know
that's a big lie.
Fuck.
[GRUNTS]
♪ Sometimes it's hard
to be a woman
♪ Giving all your love
to just one man
The castle beckons, I think, Tom.
Are you sober?
Absolutely.
Orange juice all night.
Come on.
♪ 'Cause, after all,
he's just a man
Bye, everybody.
MAN: All together, now.
♪ Stand by your man
♪ Give him two arms
to cling to
Bernard!
♪ And something warm
to come to
♪ When nights are
cold and lonely ♪
[WOMEN SINGING]
CHARLES: Tom, Tom,
can you stop the car?
Stop the car!
Sorry. Sorry.
I just think I might stay
in that pub after all.
Why on earth?
[MEN MOCKING]
No, no, no, no, seriously.
[STAMMERING] I'm doing some research to
pubs with the word "boat" in the title.
I hope to produce
the definitive work.
Oh, well. Please yourself.
It's a...
It's a silly thing, you know?
Right.
Odd decision.
Hello.
Hi.
In the end, it turned out there
wasn't room for all of us.
You said it was a castle.
Yes, it is...
No, it is a castle. It's...
It's just a very,
very small one.
[STAMMERING] Tiny, in fact. Just
one up, one down, which is rare.
A drink, sir?
Yeah. I'd like a glass of
whiskey, please. Thanks.
Do you want?
Yeah, sounds good.
Make another one for the lady.
Doubles, sir?
Hmm. Thanks.
[WHISTLING]
Ah. You here, too?
How are you?
Hello. I'm fine.
Haven't seen Carrie, have you?
Who?
Carrie.
American girl. Lovely legs.
Wedding guest. Nice smell.
No. Sorry.
Damn. Blast.
I think I was in there.
Look, if you do see her, could you
tell her I've gone up to my room?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Your whiskey, sir.
Thank you.
And one for the...
Road. Lovely.
I sure think I might have one of those.
Do you mind if I join you?
No. It'd be lovely.
Another glass of whiskey,
and a cigar.
Hold on. Make that
a bottle of whiskey.
We might as well settle in, eh?
Let's see if we can push on
through till dawn, shall we?
Lovely wedding.
CHARLES: Yes, yes, yes.
I was at school with his brother Bufty.
Tremendous bloke.
He was head of my house.
Buggered me senseless,
still, taught me
a thing or two about life.
Hmm.
Where you know him from?
University.
Hmm. Splendid. Splendid. Yep.
I didn't go myself. Oh,
I couldn't see the point, you see.
I mean, when you're
working the money markets
what use are the novels
of Wordsworth gonna be, eh?
WAITER: Excuse me, sir.
Your wife says, could you
come upstairs at once?
Room 12, in case you're
so drunk you can't remember.
My wife?
Yes, sir.
[CHUCKLING]
Oh, my wife! My wife!
Oh, God! You are drunk. You can't
even remember you got a wife.
Yeah, yeah.
[SLURRING]
Do you mind if I... No, no, no.
Off you go. Off you go.
Best of luck.
Thanks, yeah.
Lucky bachelor me,
I'll think I'll have another
search for that Katie creature.
Carrie.
That's the one.
Damn fine filly.
I think I'm in there.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Hi.
Hello.
Sorry about that.
No, that's fine.
He was hard to get rid of.
Yeah.
So, um...
Maybe we could just skulk around
here for a bit and then go back down.
Now that's a thought.
I don't usually skulk a lot,
but I suppose I could skulk
if skulking were required.
Do you skulk regularly?
No. No,
I don't normally
think of myself
as a skulker, but...
Well, why don't you come in
and skulk for a while
and we'll see.
So I noticed the bride and
groom didn't kiss in the church,
which is kind of strange.
Where I come from,
kissing is very big.
Is it? Yes, well,
I think you're right.
I think we are probably
more reserved, you know.
"You may now kiss the bride," isn't
actually in the book of common prayers.
I always worry I'll go too far, you
know, in the heat of the moment.
Uh-huh?
How far do you think
too far would be, then?
Oh, I don't know.
Maybe
that would be all right.
Yes, I think that would be fine.
In fact, it might be
a bit dismissive.
Maybe this
would be better.
Yeah, I think it would be
dangerous to take it any further.
I mean...
You know.
That might be
taking it a little far.
Hmm.
CARRIE: What about this?
Do you think
the vicar would think
things had slipped just a
little bit out of his control?
CHARLES: I think he might.
You know, this kind of thing
is really better suited
to the honeymoon
than to the service itself.
Why do you think
it's called a honeymoon?
Um, I don't know.
I suppose it's "honey"
'cause it's sweet as honey.
And "moon" because
it was the first time
a husband got to see
his wife's bottom.
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
What's happening?
I have to go.
Where?
America.
That is a tragedy.
Just before I go,
when were you thinking
of announcing the engagement?
Hmm?
Sorry. Whose engagement?
Ours.
I assumed since we slept together and
everything we'd be getting married.
What did you think?
What?
I...
Gosh, you know, that's, uh...
Takes a lot of thinking
about, that kind of thing.
Uh, obviously, I'm...
You're joking.
God! For a moment there, I thought I was
in<font face= "sansSerif" Fatal Attraction.
I thought you were Glenn Close and I'd get
home and find my pet rabbit on the stove.
[SIGHS] No.
But I think we've both missed
a great opportunity here.
Bye.
[DOOR OPENS]
[RINGING]
BERNARD & LYDIA
Three months later
CHARLES: Oh, fuck!
Fuck.
Fuck. Fuckity-fuck.
Fuck!
Car or taxi?
Taxi. We could
never park.
Car seems a good idea.
Fuck.
Leave it.
No one will notice.
[ORGAN PLAYING]
Well.
Sorry I'm late.
Traffic.
Is it?
Yeah.
Who is it today?
One more, please.
They're ready to go.
In the name of the Father and of
the Son and of the Holy Spirit.
Amen.
ALL: Amen.
Let us pray.
Father, you have made the bond
of marriage a holy mystery,
a symbol of Christ's love
for His church.
Hear our prayers
for Bernard and Lydia
through your son,
Jesus Christ, our Lord,
who lives and reigns
with you and the Holy goat.
[STAMMERING] Ghost.
One God, forever and ever.
Amen.
It's his first time.
He's a friend of the family.
Ah, excellent.
Bernard and Lydia,
I shall now ask if you freely
undertake the obligations of marriage.
Bernard, repeat after me.
I do solemnly declare...
that I know not of
any lawful impediment...
why I, Lydia...
BERNARD: why I, Bernard...
Sorry.
[PEOPLE SNICKERING]
Why I, Bernard Godfrey
Saint John Delaney...
why I, Bernard Geoffrey
"St. John" Delaney...
may not be joined
in matrimony
to Lydia John Hibbott.
May not be joined
in matrimony
to Lydia Jane Hibbott.
Lydia, repeat after me.
I do solemnly declare...
that I know not of
any lawful impediment...
why I,
Lydia Jane Hibbott...
may not be johned
in matrimony...
may not be joined
to Bernard Geoffrey
"St. John" Delaney.
LYDIA: to Bernard Geoffrey
I call upon those persons
here present to witness...
that I, Bernard...
Delaney...
[SIGHS]
That I, Bernard Delaney...
do take thee,
Lydia Jane Hibbott...
to be my awful wedded wife.
To be my lawful
wedded wife.
That's... That's right.
May almighty God bless you all.
The Father, the Son and
the Holy Spigot... Spirit.
ALL: Amen.
Bravo!
[ORGAN PLAYING]
Thanks.
We're coming, Bernie.
Up here!
Sorry.
Sorry. Sorry. Sorry.
That way?
Yes, of course.
Sorry. Could you two...
Hey, sorry.
Tom, don't go away.
Sorry.
I've got a new theory
about marriage.
Two people are in love,
they live together,
and suddenly one day they
run out of conversation.
Uh-huh.
Totally.
I mean, they can't think of a
single thing to say to each other.
That's it. Panic.
Then suddenly, it occurs
to that chap that there is
a way out of the deadlock.
Which is?
He'll ask her to marry him.
CHARLES: Brilliant.
Brilliant.
GARETH: Suddenly they got something
to talk about for rest of their lives.
Basically, you're saying
marriage is just a way
of getting out of an embarrassing,
pause in conversation.
Yep. The definitive
icebreaker.
Tom, how's the speech
coming along?
It's pretty good, I think.
Something for everyone.
Tears, laughter.
Excellent.
Well, I think it's a
very good theory, Gareth.
Well, there is another
argument, of course,
that it does have something
to do with true love.
Hmm, that's a thought.
Can I help you, sir?
Can I have three glasses
of brandy, please?
Certainly, sir.
Hi.
Hello.
How are you?
Fine. Fine.
[LAUGHING] Yeah. Sorry,
I'm overwhelmed to see you.
Um, look, don't go back
to America. Please.
Be back in two secs, okay?
Okay.
Hi, Fi.
That's yours, that's yours.
See you in five hours.
Something happened?
Yeah, has a bit. This is a
bloody great wedding, you know.
Hi.
Well, you look perfect.
You...
In fact, you probably
are perfect.
Well, how are you?
I'm really well.
Charles, I'd like you to
meet Hamish, my fiance.
Excellent.
How do you do, Hamish?
Delighted to meet you.
Charming surprise to find
Carrie back in the country.
Yes, well, it took a lot of
persuading, I can tell you.
Come on, darling, I told
James I was gonna get you.
He'll begin to think I've totally
lost control over you already.
[LAUGHING]
I'll see you later.
How you doing, Charles?
Not great, actually, suddenly.
I don't know.
I mean...
What the hell's going on here?
Why am I always at weddings and
never actually getting married, Matt?
It's probably because
you're a bit scruffy.
Yeah.
Or it could also be 'cause you
haven't met the right girl.
Oh, but you see, is that it?
Maybe I have met
the right girls.
Maybe I'm meeting the
right girls all the time.
Maybe it's me.
Oh, nonsense.
My lords, ladies, and gentlemen,
dinner is served.
Come on. Odds on you
meet your wife at dinner.
Yes.
Oh, my God.
Charles?
Hi.
Hello.
I'm Alistair.
Great.
And I believe you know Veronica.
Yeah. Hi, V. Hi.
Nicki.
Great.
Tell me, are you married?
No.
Are you a lesbian?
Good Lord.
Um, what made you say that?
Well, it's one of the
possibilities for unmarried girls
and is a bit more
interesting than saying,
"Oh, dear, just never
found the right chap, eh?"
Quite right. Why be dull?
Thank you.
Well, the truth is...
[WHISPERS] Truth is, I have met the right
person and he is not in love with me
and until I stop loving him,
no one else stands a chance.
Oh, bad luck.
Yes, isn't it?
I was a lesbian once at school.
But only for about 15 minutes.
I don't think it counts.
There are 400
different kinds of tea.
And that's not including all
these so-called fruit teas.
I took Veronica out to India at
Christmas to look at the plantations.
Oh, excellent.
I believe you and her
went out there once.
That's right.
VERONICA: Charles was wild.
He insisted on cracking
jokes all the time I was ill.
CHARLES: I was just trying
to cheer you up, V.
Oh, you're that Veronica.
VERONICA: Which Veronica?
Charlie?
Remember Bombay?
When Charles and I
were going out,
he told me he'd had this
interesting journey around India
with Vomiting Veronica, right?
I think that was it.
I don't remember
ever mentioning it.
Maybe... Maybe I did.
Oh, come on, Charles.
I don't think I've ever been
out with anyone less discreet.
What? I don't... See, it's probably
a bit of an exaggeration, isn't it?
It is not.
I remember you going on
about this girl.
Helena, was it, whose
mother made a pass at you?
I remember this!
You couldn't work it
out with her.
It would be impolite
not to accept her advances.
NICKI: That's right!
Mrs. Piggy. Helena was Miss Piggy,
so her mother was Mrs. Piggy.
[STAMMERING] I think perhaps
it was a... It was a...
We've both lost
a lot of weight since then.
[CLACKING]
Ah, great. Speeches.
My lords, ladies and gentlemen,
pray silence for the best man.
When Bernard told me he was
getting engaged to Lydia,
I congratulated him
because all his other girlfriends
had been such complete dogs.
Although may I say
how delighted we are
to have so many of them
here this evening.
I'm particularly delighted
to see Camilla
who many of you
will probably remember
as the first person
Bernard asked to marry him.
If I remember rightly,
she told him to "sod off."
[GARETH LAUGHING]
And lucky for Lydia
that she did.
It's very disappointing.
We had the most adorable
girl at our table,
called Carrie.
Apparently, her fiance is awfully
grand and he owns half of Scotland.
How are you?
Well, I seem to be stuck
in the wedding from hell.
Ghosts of girlfriends past
at every turn.
Next thing you know I bump into Henrietta
and the horror will be complete.
HENRIETTA: Hello, Charles.
Hello, Hen.
How are you?
[SOBBING]
Oh, Hen, I...
Why can't you just
leave her alone?
Haven't you hurt her enough?
Excuse me. I think I'd better
be where other people are not.
Hello. I'm...
I'm S-e-r-e-n-a.
Hello.
I'm just learning.
I'm probably naking tols
of nistakes
No, perfect. Perfect.
Would you like to dance?
Oh, yes.
That would be mice.
[CHUCKLES]
[WOMEN CHATTERING]
[LAUGHING]
It's unbelievable.
[SIGHING]
MAN: Taxi!
Good night, sir.
Thank you.
[SIGHS]
WOMAN:
♪ My true love was true
♪ I, of course, replied
♪ Something here inside
♪ Cannot be denied
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
[MUMBLING]
I know. It's all right. Oh, God,
this is wonderful, ain't it?
[MUMBLING]
[PANTING]
[MOANING]
[GROANING]
LYDIA: Oh, wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
This is no fun. I want
to see my lovely husband!
[BOTH MOANING]
[LAUGHING] Who's a very bad
bridegroom, indeed?
♪ Gonna get along
without you now
without you now ♪
Have you got a boyfriend?
Yes.
What's his name?
Dolph. He's good
at table tennis.
What about you?
No. Afraid not.
Why not?
Don't know.
Because most of
the blokes I fancy
think I'm stupid and pointless,
so they just bonk me
and then leave me,
and the kind of blokes that do
fancy me, I think are drips.
I can't be bothered
to bonk them,
which does sort of
leave me a bit nowhere.
What's bonking?
Well, it's kind of
like table tennis,
only with slightly
smaller balls.
[MOANING]
[CHUCKLING]
[EXCLAIMING]
[LAUGHING]
So good!
[PANTING]
[YELLING IN DELIGHT]
I love my wife.
[MOANING]
And I love my husband!
Do you think we'd better
be getting back?
Oh, we could just
wait a few minutes
and have another go.
You naughty, naughty
little rabbit!
[GASPS]
Found it.
Charles. Charles,
we must talk.
Right. You're right.
The thing is, Charlie,
I've spoken to lots of
people about you. Oh, God.
And everybody agrees you're
in real trouble, Charles.
Am I?
The thing is, you see, you're sort of
turning into a kind of serial monogamist.
One girlfriend after another,
yet you never really love anyone
'cause you never
let them near you.
On the contrary, Hen, I...
You're affectionate to them
and sweet to them. Right.
You were even sweet to me, although
you thought I was an idiot.
I did not.
You did.
I thought U2 was
a type of submarine.
Well, in a way, you were right.
Their music has
a very naval quality.
Be serious, Charles.
You must give people a chance.
You don't have to think,
"I must get married,"
but you mustn't start
every relationship
thinking, "I mustn't
get married."
Hen, you know most of the time
I don't think at all.
I just, you know, potter along.
Oh, Charlie!
Oh, God, the way
you used to look at me!
[SNIFFLING]
I just misread it, that's all.
All the time I thought
you were going to propose
and all that time you were
just working out how to leave.
No, no. I wasn't.
Oh, God.
This is ridiculous.
Hen...
No.
No, Hen! Hen!
No! No!
Hen!
Having a good night?
Yes, yes.
It's right up there with my father's
funeral for sheer entertainment value.
I thought you'd gone.
No. Hamish has to take
the Edinburgh sleeper.
I'm off now.
Keep me company?
[TAPPING]
Here, please.
You want to come up
for a nightcap?
You sure?
Oh, yes.
I think we can risk it.
I'm pretty sure I can resist you.
You're not that cute.
Sorry. Yeah, great.
Morning, Charles.
Breakfast's up.
One month later
Hmm.
Well, it's a bit burnt.
Excellent.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
What are you up to today?
Oh, yeah.
I'm... Well, I'm taking
advantage of the fact that
for the first time
in my entire life,
it's Saturday and I don't
have a wedding to go to.
All I have to do
is not be late for David.
I was gonna go for a job.
There's this new shop called Spank
that wants a sales assistant.
I think I'd be great.
They sell all this funny
rubber stuff.
Oh, no.
Another wedding invitation.
And a list. Lovely.
They say rubber's
mainly for perverts.
I don't know why. I think
it's very practical, actually.
I mean, you spill anything
on it, and it just comes off.
I suppose that could be
why the perverts like it.
You all right?
Yeah, yeah.
It's that girl, Carrie.
You remember? The American.
Uh, excuse me.
Sorry to interrupt.
Do you have the wedding
list for Banks?
Certainly, sir.
Lots of beautiful things for
round about the £1,000 mark.
Uh-huh.
What about things around the
sort of £50 mark? Is there much?
Well, you could get that
pygmy warrior over there.
This? Excellent.
If you could find someone
to chip in the other £3,950.
Or our carrier bags
are £1.50 each.
Why don't you just
get 33 of them?
Yes, well, I think
I'll probably leave it.
Thanks very much.
You've been very...
What'd you get?
[BOTH LAUGH]
Blimey!
Well, I never.
Nothing yet. I'm just,
you know, deciding.
It's nice to see you.
This present thing is great.
[CHUCKLES]
I should've gotten married
years ago.
Did anybody go for the pygmy?
The young man was
thinking about it.
[LAUGHING] Oh, no!
Yeah.
Just get me an ashtray.
Are you free
for about a half hour?
Yeah. Yeah. I'm supposed to meet my
brother, but I can be a bit late.
Oh, good, come with me. You have
an important decision to make.
CARRIE: Now, the crucial thing
is that you mustn't laugh.
Okay, right.
What do you think?
Divine.
Bit of a meringue?
Um...
[GROANS] Oh, don't worry.
We've only just begun.
What do you think?
You're kidding.
But it would be wonderful,
wouldn't it?
Maybe next time.
What do you think?
[CHUCKLES]
Um...
I knew it.
But look, if you could
find a little staff,
it'd be great for
looking after sheep.
Don't be rude.
It's a bit sexy, this.
Well...
If I were your husband,
I would die of pride.
You may be right.
It is dangerous.
You know, there's nothing
more off-putting at a wedding
than a priest with
an enormous erection.
[CHUCKLES]
Blech.
CHARLES: One strange thing is thinking
you'll never sleep with anyone else.
You don't think
you'll be unfaithful?
No. Not once
I'm married.
I told Hamish
I'll kill him if he does,
so I guess
I better stick to that.
Quite right. Yes.
Anyway, I reckon
I've had my fair run at it.
What is a fair run these days,
down your way?
I don't know.
More than one.
Well, come on.
Tell me.
I've seen the dress.
We have no secrets.
[CHUCKLES]
Well.
The first one,
of course, not easily
forgotten, was kinda nice.
Two, hairy back.
[CHUCKLES]
Three, four... Six.
Was on my birthday
in my parents' room.
Which birthday?
Seventeenth.
Oh, we've only reached 17?
Well, you know,
I grew up in the country.
Lots of rolling around
in haystacks.
Okay. Seven, mmm.
Eight, unfortunately,
was quite a shock.
[SNICKERS]
Nine, against a fence. Very uncomfortable.
Don't try it.
I won't.
Ten, ah, was gorgeous.
Just heaven, just...
Oh, he was wonderful.
I hate him.
Eleven, obviously after 10,
disappointing.
Twelve through 17,
the university years.
Sensitive, caring,
intelligent boys.
Sexually speaking,
a real low patch.
Um, 18 broke my heart.
Years of yearning.
I'm sorry.
Twenty... Oh, my God, I can't
believe I've reached 20.
Twenty-one, elephant tongue.
Twenty-two, kept falling asleep.
That was my first year
in England.
I do apologize.
Twenty-three and 24 together.
That was something.
Seriously? Twenty-seven,
oh, now that was a mistake.
Suddenly at 27
you make a mistake?
Yes, he kept screaming.
It was very off-putting. I nearly
gave up on the whole thing.
But Spencer changed my mind.
That's 28. Mmm-hmm.
His father, 29.
His father?
Mmm.
Thirty, uh...
Thirty-one, oh, my God.
Thirty-two was lovely.
And then my fiance, that's 33.
Wow!
So I came after your fiance?
No, you were 32.
Oh.
So there you go.
Less than Madonna, more
than Princess Di, I hope.
[CHUCKLES]
And how about you?
How many have you slept with?
Christ!
Nothing like that many.
I don't know...
I don't know what the fuck I've
been doing with my time, actually.
Work, probably. Yeah,
that's it, work, work.
I have been working late a lot.
[CHUCKLING]
I wish I'd rung you.
But then, you never rang me.
You ruthlessly slept with
me twice and never rang me.
Oh, bollocks!
Help me, please. Please.
You're no longer my brother,
you're just some git I once met.
I'm sorry.
Uh, Carrie,
this is David, my brother.
This is Carrie.
Hi.
We were buying her a
wedding dress.
Pathetic excuse. Who's she
marrying?
Some total penis.
What is it about penises
that they get such great wives?
I was just telling him about,
um, you marrying Hamish
and he said it couldn't have happened
to a nicer fellow. So that's nice.
[CHUCKLES]
Didn't you do it with her once?
Where are you doing it?
Scotland.
Yes.
Beautiful breasts.
He says that's
a beautiful place. Hilly.
You should come
to the wedding, too.
I want as many friends
as possible
to make up for the gruesome
stiffs that Hamish knows.
Well, you better go in.
Bye.
Come on, we're late.
Fuck it.
Um, look.
Sorry, sorry.
Uh, I just...
Well, this is a really
stupid question,
particularly in view of our
recent shopping excursion.
But, I just wondered if,
by any chance...
Uh, I mean, obviously not,
because I am just some git who's
only slept with nine people.
But I just wondered...
Uh, I really feel...
In short, to recap in a
slightly clearer version,
in the words of
David Cassidy, in fact,
while he was still with The Partridge
Family,
"I think I love you."
[STAMMERING] And I just wondered whether
by any chance you wouldn't like to...
Uh... Uh...
No, no, no.
Of course not.
I'm an idiot, he's not.
Excellent. Excellent.
Fantastic.
Lovely to see you. Sorry to disturb.
Better get on.
Fuck!
That was very romantic.
Well, I thought it over
a lot, you know.
I wanted to get it just right.
Important to have said it,
I think.
Said what, exactly?
Said, you know,
what I just said about
David Cassidy.
You're lovely.
HAMISH and CARRIE
One month later
[BIRDS CALLING]
VICAR: It was ordained for lifelong
faithful relationship of conjugal love.
It was ordained for the
welfare of human society
which can be strong and happy
only when the marriage
bond is held in honor.
Into this holy estate these two
persons now desire to enter.
Wherefore if anyone can show
any just cause
why they may not lawfully be
joined together in marriage,
let him now declare it.
[BANGING]
[WHISPERS] Sorry.
VICAR: Please rise.
Do you, Hamish, take this woman,
Caroline, to be your wedded wife?
And do you, in the presence of
God and before this congregation,
promise and covenant
to be to her
a loving and faithful husband
until God shall
separate you by death?
HAMISH: I do.
Do you, Caroline, take this man,
Hamish, to be your wedded husband?
And do you, in the presence of
God and before this congregation
promise and covenant
to be to him
a loving and faithful wife
until God shall
separate you by death?
I do.
VICAR: As a token of the covenant
into which you have entered...
Fuck-a-doodle-doo.
[BAGPIPES
PLAYING]
Awfully nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
How do you do?
Hello.
Ben...
You look beautiful.
Not a meringue in sight.
Thanks.
Blimey.
It's Brigadoon.
[CHUCKLING] It's bloody <font face= "sansSerif" Brigadoon!
Dear old things, as you know,
I've always been proud that there's not
a wedding ring between the lot of us.
Over the passing of the years,
it's suddenly beginning
to distress me.
I'd like to go to the wedding of
someone I really loved, for a change.
Well, don't blame me. I've asked
practically everyone I know.
You haven't asked me.
Haven't I?
No.
Oh, Scarlett.
Would you like to?
No, thank you. It was
very nice of you to ask.
Well, anytime.
[LAUGHING] Quite right, Tom.
That's the spirit.
Now, tonight,
these are your orders.
Go forth and conjugate.
Find husbands and wives.
Excellent plan. What
do you think, Fifi?
Spot a potential hubby
in the throng?
Bugger off, Tom.
Quite right.
A toast before
we go into battle.
To true love.
In whatever shape
or form it may come.
May we all in our dotage
be proud to say,
"I was adored once, too."
[ALL LAUGH]
True love.
ALL: True love!
[STUTTERING] Apparently,
an enormous number of people
actually bump into their
future spouses at weddings.
Which is interesting.
Yes, I met my husband
at a wedding.
Ah!
Good Lord, I seem to have
finished my drink.
If you'll excuse me.
Hello. My name's Scarlett.
Named after Scarlett O'Hara,
but much less trouble.
What's your name?
My name's Rhett.
No. Not really!
No, not really.
In fact, it's Chester.
You kidder.
[CHUCKLING]
I always imagine Americans
are gonna be dull as shit.
I mean, of course
you're not, are you?
Steve Martin's American,
isn't he?
Yes, he is.
You're lovely.
Come on!
Hello, Charles.
Oh, Hen. Hi.
[STAMMERING] I'm sorry. I couldn't
really bear a scene today.
I know, you know, we probably
got tons to talk about,
and all that kind of stuff.
Did I behave that
atrociously last time?
Well, you remember the shower scene
in <font face= "sansSerif" Psycho?
Yeah.
Scarier.
[BOTH LAUGH]
Oh, God, I'm depressed, Hen.
How are you?
Well, I'm cheerful, actually.
I weigh almost nothing.
And, oh, I've got
a divine new boyfriend.
Perhaps you were right, Hen.
We should've got married.
Oh, good God, no. Marry you and
I'd have had to marry your friends.
And I'm not quite sure
I could take Fiona.
Fiona loves you.
Fiona calls me Duckface.
Well, I never heard that.
Look, darling,
come to lunch soon.
Give me a ring, okay?
Oh, still cute!
How's Duckface?
Good form, actually.
Not too mad.
[BAGPIPES PLAYING]
Ladies and gentlemen,
the bride and groom.
[PEOPLE APPLAUDING]
You like this girl, don't you?
Yes.
Yes, it's a...
It was a strange thing
when at last it happened.
And...
[CHARLES SCOFFS]
CHARLES: She's marrying
someone else.
How about you, Fifi?
You identified a future
partner for life yet?
No need, really.
The deed is done.
I've been in love with
the same bloke for ages.
Have you?
Who's that?
You, Charlie.
It's always been you.
Since first we met,
oh, so many years ago.
I knew the first moment.
Across a crowded room.
Or lawn, in fact.
Doesn't matter.
Nothing either of us
can do on this one.
Such is life.
Friends isn't bad, you know?
Friends is quite something.
Oh, Fi.
[EXHALES]
It's not all easy, is it?
No.
Just forget this business.
Not to be.
Matthew, darling.
Where's Gareth?
Torturing Americans.
How thoughtful of him.
Do you actually
know Oscar Wilde?
Not personally, no.
But I do know someone who could
get his fax number for you.
Shall we dance?
[BAND PLAYING]
[PEOPLE WHOOPING]
[EXCLAIMING]
Well, any rings on fingers?
Oh, Gareth, you don't know
how lucky you are.
Finding someone to marry
is a very tricky business.
It's hell out there.
Matthew's trapped with an
evangelist from Minnesota.
My lords, ladies, and gentlemen,
please charge your glasses.
First, and rather unusually,
we have the bride.
[PEOPLE APPLAUDING]
Excellent.
I love this girl.
CARRIE: Thank you.
First of all, I'd like
to thank all of you
who've flown in from the States.
I'm really touched.
And, as for the rest of you,
I would have thought
the fact that lots of frightful
Americans were flying in
was the perfect excuse for
staying away, so I thank you, too.
[ALL LAUGHING]
If my darling dad
had been here today,
he would have been speaking now.
And I know what
he would have said.
"Great dress, babe,
"but why in the hell are you
marrying the stiff in the skirt?"
And I would have given him the
same answer that I give you.
"Because I love him."
As John Lennon said, who
died the same year as my dad,
"Love is the answer.
And you know that for sure."
[PEOPLE APPLAUDING]
Oh, oh, and one more thing.
Someone had told me here,
confidentially,
that if things with Hamish didn't
work out, that he would step in.
I just wanted to say thanks,
and I'll keep you posted.
Bravo!
MAN: And now, my lords, ladies
and gentlemen, Sir Hamish Banks.
Anyone involved in politics
for the last 20 years
has gotten used to being
upstaged by a woman.
[PEOPLE LAUGH]
HAMISH: I didn't expect it to
happen to me on my wedding day.
However, I must also say
that I'm quite happy to
be upstaged by this woman
for the rest of my life.
Oh, dear, is that some
barracking at the back?
Again, something
we politicians are used to.
[STAMMERING] Find a doctor.
Right. Okay.
First of all, I want to extend my
compliments to the bridesmaids.
You did your duty superbly.
And, obviously,
I intend to use you
every time I get married
from now on.
[ALL LAUGHING]
HAMISH: And also, I want to thank all
those wonderful ladies of the parish
who did the flowers
in the church.
The stern old building took on
a look of flushing youth today.
[PEOPLE APPLAUDING]
I remember the first time
I laid eyes on Caroline.
I thought to myself, "If by
any chance she's shortsighted,
"I might just be happy
for the rest of my life."
I thought I could see
my future for the first time.
It was a joyful one,
for years and years to come.
ALL: ♪ For he's
a jolly good fellow
♪ For they are
jolly good fellows
♪ And so say all of us
[ENGINE STARTS]
Good morning,
and a warm welcome to
you all on this cold day.
Our service will begin
in a few minutes.
But first we have asked Matthew,
Gareth's closest friend,
to say a few words.
Gareth used to prefer
funerals to weddings.
He said it was easier to get
enthusiastic about a ceremony
one had an outside chance of
eventually being involved in.
In order to prepare this speech,
I rang a few people
to get a general picture
of how Gareth was regarded
by those who met him.
"Fat" seems to have been a word
people most connected with him.
"Terribly rude"
also rang a lot of bells.
"So very fat and very rude" seems to
have been the stranger's viewpoint.
On the other hand, some of
you have been kind enough
to ring me and let me know
that you loved him,
which I know he would have
been thrilled to hear.
You remember
his fabulous hospitality.
His strange
experimental cooking.
The recipe for
duck a la banana, fortunately,
goes with him to his grave.
Most of all,
you tell me of his
enormous capacity for joy.
And when joyful...
When joyful,
for highly vocal drunkenness.
But I hope joyful is how
you will remember him.
Not stuck in a box in a church.
Pick your favorite of his waistcoats
and remember him that way.
The most splendid, replete,
big-hearted...
Weak-hearted, as it turned out,
and jolly bugger
most of us ever met.
As for me, you may ask
how I will remember him.
What I thought of him.
Unfortunately,
there I run out of words.
Perhaps you will forgive me
if I turn from my own feelings
to the words of
another splendid bugger,
W.H. Auden.
This is actually
what I want to say.
"Stop all the clocks
"Cut off the telephone
"Prevent the dog from barking
with a juicy bone
"Silence the pianos,
and with muffled drum
"bring out the coffin
"Let the mourners come
"Let the airplanes circle,
moaning overhead
"Scribbling on the sky
the message
"'He is dead'
"Put great bows around the
white necks of the public doves
"Let traffic policemen
wear black cotton gloves
"He was my north, my south,
my east, and west
"My working week
and my Sunday rest
"My noon, my midnight,
my talk, my song
"I thought that love
would last forever
[SOBBING] "I was wrong
"The stars are not wanted now
"Put out every one
"Pack up the moon
and dismantle the sun
"Pour away the ocean
and sweep up the wood
"For nothing now can
ever come to any good"
MAN: Bye, now.
I'll take you home, Scarlett.
It was good of you to come.
Must have been the shortest
honeymoon in history.
No, it's fine.
We'll do it some other time.
You know, that thing
you said in the street?
Yes. I'm sorry about that.
No, I liked it.
I liked you saying it.
Charlie, I'll take
Scarlett home, all right?
Yeah.
Darling Fi.
Walk, Charlie?
Yeah. Yeah,
that would be grand.
Never felt like that.
I mean, something
vaguely similar for Jilly,
when I was young.
Jilly?
Labrador.
Yes, it's odd, isn't it?
All these years we've been
single and proud of it,
and never noticed
that two of us were,
for all intents and purposes,
married all this time.
Traitors in our midst.
You know, in a way, I think death is
hardest for the parents, don't you?
I hope I die before my children.
Tom,
there's one thing
I find really...
Well...
It's your total confidence
that you will get married.
I mean, what if you
never find the right girl?
Sorry?
Surely, if that service
shows anything,
it shows that there is such
a thing as a perfect match.
If we can't be like
Gareth and Matthew,
then maybe we should
just let it go.
Some of us are not
going to get married.
Well, I don't know, Charlie.
The truth is, unlike you,
I never expected
the thunderbolt.
I always just hoped that I'd
meet some nice, friendly girl,
like the look of her.
Hope the look of me didn't
make her physically sick.
Then pop the question and
settle down and be happy.
It worked for my parents.
Well, apart from the
divorce and all that.
I'll give you six months
at the outside, Tom.
Yeah, maybe you're right.
Maybe all this "waiting
for one true love" stuff
gets you nowhere.
[ALARM CLOCK RINGING]
[ALARM CLOCKS RINGING]
Hmm?
What the fuck is going on?
[GRUNTING]
I thought we better make
absolutely sure we weren't late.
Excellent wedding hairstyle.
Charles &
Ten months later
CHARLES: Matthew, the best-looking
best man in the world.
Listen.
Thank you for doing this today.
Of course.
I wish Gareth was here.
Bet he does, too.
I'm sorry I was so late.
The others are just
parking the car.
I thought we'd all go with Tom.
Late? So late?
Yeah, it's 9:45.
9:45?
Yep, 45 minutes
till "I do."
Bloody Tom! I told him
to set the alarm for 8:00.
Fuck!
Scarlett.
Oh, hi.
You ready?
Absolutely.
Give me 20 seconds.
[TIRES SCREECHING]
Time?
Honestly?
Yes! Time?
It's about 8:50.
[ALL CHUCKLING]
Bastards.
WOMAN: Jessica, stop jumping
up and down, please.
[GIRLS GIGGLING]
One, two, three, smile!
This is splendid tuck.
Yes, I think I might
say a little word.
Well, as many of you know,
I have been a close observer of
Charles' love life for many years now.
But recently, I'd started
to despair and fear
that really he was
married to us lot.
Apart from the fact that
we won't have his babies.
I don't know about that.
Fortunately, it's all
turned out splendidly.
The girl in question
is, sadly, crazy,
but perhaps
that's why he loves her.
So I'd like to propose a toast to
my Charlie and his beautiful girl
on this tragic day.
So be happy and don't forget us.
CHARLES: Thank you.
To Charles and Duckface.
ALL: To Charles and Duckface!
What do you think?
You look divine.
It does work, doesn't it?
Yes.
I'd like to thank Fiona for those
charming words about my future wife.
And I'd like to take this
opportunity, before the day starts,
to read a little message
from her to you all.
This is exciting.
She says, "If any of you come near
the house, I'll set the dogs on you."
I think that's rather
a nice touch.
[CHUCKLING] "I'll
set the dogs on you."
John, hi.
You made it. Good.
Oh, yes.
I hope me damn sister turns up.
Not much of a wedding
without a bride.
Tom.
Charlie.
John.
Bit of a poor show,
you not having a stag night.
Oh, we did. We did.
We did. We did.
We didn't think it was a very good
idea in this day and age, so...
Really?
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
Fi, you do look lovely today.
Yes, as you can see, I've
abandoned my traditional black.
[CHUCKLES]
Yes, so you have.
From now on, I shall be
all the colors of the rainbow
and fall in love with someone
who fancies me for a change.
Darling Fi.
Oh, look.
What?
Lipstick everywhere.
That won't do at all, will it?
[BELLS TOLLING]
Hi. Hi.
Good luck.
SCARLETT: Hello.
Glad you could come.
MATTHEW: How are you?
Groom's on the right.
Bride's on the left.
Oh, my God!
[WAILING]
[GRUNTS] I thought you'd
gone back to Texas.
Without you, never.
Good luck.
Bride or groom?
It should be perfectly
obvious I'm neither.
Great God!
Bride or groom?
Bride.
Yes, fine.
You know, I've got a
feeling we've met before.
We have.
About 25 years ago.
I'm second cousin Harold's
daughter, Deirdre. You're Tom.
Good Lord!
So you're family.
Yes.
Only very distant.
Well, yes, of course.
[STUTTERING]
You said you were bride?
Yes.
Well, do sit.
Do sit here, Deirdre.
Golly.
Thunderbolt city.
BERNARD: Hello, Matthew.
Hello, Charles.
Bernard, how are you?
Exhausted, actually.
That's funny. Charles.
Hi.
You look lovely.
But then, as you know, I always
did like you dressed for weddings.
And on time!
Yep! Extraordinary thing,
isn't it?
How's Hamish?
Oh, he's fine, I believe.
You believe?
Well, yes, he wasn't
the man for me after all.
You left him?
We left each other.
When?
Oh, a few months now.
March was hell.
By April, it was sordid.
That's absolutely the last time I
marry someone three times my age.
MATTHEW: Charlie?
Charles, time to travel.
Yeah. Yeah.
Coming. Good.
Good.
So why didn't you
get in touch, then?
I did think about it.
I wanted to,
but I was in a state.
So anyway,
I don't want to keep you.
And I'll see you afterwards.
Yeah. Fine, excellent.
Wait.
I'll show you to your seat.
Just showing her to her seat.
Our timing's been
really bad, hasn't it?
It's been bad, yes.
It's been a disaster.
It has, as you say, been
very bad indeed.
God, it's lovely to see you.
Well, good luck.
It's pretty easy.
Just say "I do" whenever
anyone asks you a question.
Um...
Could you just
give me a sec, Matthew?
Yes, of course.
Freshen up at will.
Dear Lord,
forgive me for what
I'm about to say
in this magnificent
place of worship.
Bugger!
Bugger! Bugger!
Can I help at all?
Huh?
No. Thanks.
Sorry.
Vocal exercises.
Big church.
Excellent. Often do
the same myself.
Uh, not exactly the
same vocab, obviously.
Rather more alleluias.
[CHUCKLES]
I'll leave you.
[BELLS TOLLING]
[BABY BABBLING]
Bride's arriving.
Fabulous! We seem to
have lost the groom.
You see if you can stall her,
and I'll see if I can find him.
Roger. Wilco.
Charles.
Hmm?
It's good to see you.
Yeah. Yeah.
Matt, what do we think
about marriage?
Oh, gosh, uh...
Well, I think it's really good...
Hmm.
If you love the person
with all your heart.
[STAMMERING]
Well, exactly.
Quite.
All these weddings.
All these years.
All that blasted salmon
and champagne.
Here I am on my own wedding day,
and I'm still thinking.
Can I ask about what?
Um...
No.
No, I think best not.
I'm terribly sorry,
there's a bit of a delay.
There's a slight problem
with the flowers.
Flowers? What?
Unfortunately, there seems to be
a staggeringly high proportion of hay
fever sufferers on the congregation
and they've been stuck right
next to the damn flowers.
So we're just moving them.
The congregation.
Don't want the damn vows to be
obliterated by the sound of sneezing.
Charles, would it be out of place for
me to say that time is ticking by?
What's happening?
Tell me.
O God.
I just saw Carrie
and she's separated.
Charles. It's your wedding
day.
[WHISPERING]
Should've started by now.
I think I've fooled them so far.
It's a great advantage of having
a reputation for being stupid.
People are less
suspicious of you.
What's your advice?
You've got three choices,
one, go ahead with it.
Two, go outside and say,
"Sorry folks, it's all off!"
Not tempting. Next?
Third...
I can't think of a third.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Hello.
Here you are.
Ready to face the enemy?
Are we?
Yes.
Excellent.
[WEDDING MARCH PLAYING]
Not so tight, Dad!
Dearly beloved,
we are gathered together
here in the sight of God
and in the face
of this congregation
to join together this man and
this woman in holy matrimony,
which is an honorable estate
instituted of God in the time
of man's innocence.
Signifying unto us
the mystical union
that is betwixt
Christ and His church,
and therefore is not
by any to be enterprised,
nor taken in hand unadvisedly,
lightly, or wantonly,
but reverently, discreetly,
advisedly, soberly,
and in the fear of God.
Therefore, if any man
can show any just cause
why they may not lawfully
be joined together
let him speak now, or else
hereafter forever hold his peace.
[RAPPING]
I'm sorry, does someone
have something to say?
VICAR: Yes? What is it?
[WHISPERS]
He's David, I think.
One second.
What's going on?
I thought of a third option.
What?
Will you translate?
What's going on, Charles?
Charles, what?
Translate what?
He wants me to translate
what he's saying.
What is he saying?
I think the groom is
having doubts...
He says, "I suspect the
groom is having doubts.
"I suspect the groom
would like to delay."
I think the groom really
loves someone else.
"I suspect the groom...
That's true, isn't it, Charles?
"I suspect the groom..."
Because, Charlie, this is
for the rest of your life.
Finally, you must marry the person
you love with your whole heart.
And by the way, your flies
are undone.
What's he saying?
He says
he suspects the groom
loves someone else.
[PEOPLE MURMURING]
And do you?
Do you love someone else?
Do you, Charles?
I do.
[SCREAMS]
[YELLING]
Get out of my way!
Let me kill him!
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
Blimey.
At least it's one
we won't forget.
I mean, lot of weddings just
blend into each other, don't they?
Oh, for God's sake.
But this one that will really
stick out in the memory.
For not actually including
a wedding service.
FIONA: Poor girl.
No, I mean it, poor girl!
I mean, she's not my
favorite person in the world,
but I think that may have been an
unforgivable thing that you did today.
I can't bear to think about it.
Poor Hen.
TOM: Though,
let's face facts.
I mean, if you weren't sure you
wanted to marry her today of all days,
i.e., your wedding day,
then it must be the right
decision, mustn't it?
Quite right, Tom.
It was a lovely dress. I'm sure
she'll find it useful for parties.
What did he say, Charles?
Says he blames himself.
TOM: Oh, absolutely not.
MATTHEW: No, you mustn't, David.
They all blame you too.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
No, no, no. If there's music to
be faced, I should be facing it.
Hello.
Hi! You're soaking. Come in. No, no.
I'm fine. I'm fine.
Comes a point when you're so
wet you can't get any wetter.
Okay, I'll come out.
No, please don't.
I just wanted
to check you're okay.
Not busy killing yourself
or anything, but...
But you're fine, so...
I shouldn't have come to the
church this morning. I'm sorry.
No! No!
Wait. It was all my fault.
I mean, I...
I'm the bastard here.
And it definitely sorted out one
thing, which is, marriage and me,
we're very clearly not
meant for one another.
Sorted out another
big thing as well.
There I was, standing
there in the church
and for the first time
in my whole life I realized
I totally and utterly
loved one person.
And it wasn't the person
standing next to me in the veil,
it's the person standing
opposite me now
in the rain.
Is it still raining?
I hadn't noticed.
The truth of it is,
I've loved you from
the first second I met you.
You're not suddenly gonna
go away again, are you?
No. I might drown,
but otherwise, no.
Okay, okay. We'll go in.
But first, let me
ask you one thing.
Do you think,
after we've dried off,
after we've spent
lots more time together,
you might agree
not to marry me?
And do you think
not being married to me might maybe
be something you could consider
doing for the rest of your life?
Do you?
I do.
[THUNDER CLAPPING]
♪ Spring is here,
the sky is blue
♪ Birds will sing
as if they knew
♪ Today's the day
we'll say "I do"
♪ And we'll never
be lonely anymore
♪ Because we're
going to the chapel
♪ And we're gonna
get married
♪ Going to the
chapel
♪ And we're gonna
get married
♪ Gee, I really
love you
♪ And we're gonna
get married
♪ Going to the
chapel of love
♪ Bells will ring,
the sun will shine
♪ I will be hers,
and she'll be mine
♪ We'll love until
the end of time
♪ And we'll never
be lonely anymore ♪
The End
♪ I feel it in my
fingers
toes
♪ The love that's
all around me
♪ And so the
feeling grows
♪ It's written on
the wind
♪ It's everywhere
I go
♪ Oh, yes, it
is
♪ So if you
really love me
♪ Come on and let
it show
♪ You know I love
you, I always will
♪ My mind's made up
by the way that I feel
♪ There's no beginning,
there'll be no end
♪ 'Cause on my love
you can depend ♪
♪ I've been
watching you
♪ But so
far
♪ You never seem
to get
♪ Get the stuff
to deny me
♪ Oh, why don't
you try me?
♪ Get up and
dance
♪ Slam a-jam
to the funk up front
♪ It's the right
time to fall in love
♪ You know what I
want
♪ And you know
what I need
♪ So take my
body, baby
♪ And burn me
up
♪ Get the message
through
♪ That I'm waiting just for you
♪ Get up and
dance
♪ Slam a-jam
to the funk up front
♪ It's the right
time to fall in love
♪ Get
funky
♪ Yo, baby, get
funky ♪