In the beginning, God created
the Heaven and the Earth.
And the Earth was
without form and void...
...and darkness was upon the face
of the deep.
And the Spirit of God moved
upon the face of the waters.
And God said, ''Let there be light. ''
And there was light.
And God divided the light
from the darkness.
And God called the light ''day. ''
And the darkness He called ''night. ''
And the evening and the morning
were the first day.
And God said, ''Let there be
a firmament...
...in the midst of the waters.
And let it divide the waters
from the waters. ''
And God called
the firmament ''heaven. ''
And the evening and the morning
were the second day.
And God said:
''Let the waters under the heaven...
...be gathered together
unto one place...
...and let the dry land appear. ''
The gathering together
of the waters...
...called He ''seas. ''
And He called the dry land ''earth. ''
And God said,
''Let the earth bring forth grass...
... the herb yielding seed and
the fruit tree yielding fruit...
... whose seed is in itself
upon the earth. ''
And the evening and the morning
were the third day.
And God said, ''Let there be lights
in the firmament of the heaven...
...and let them be for signs
and for seasons...
...and for days and years. ''
And God made two great lights:
The greater light, to rule the day...
...and the lesser light,
to rule the night.
He made the stars also.
And God set them in the firmament
of the heaven...
... to give light upon the Earth.
And the evening and the morning
were the fourth day.
And God said, ''Let the waters
bring forth abundantly...
... the moving creature
that hath life...
...and fowl that fly above the earth
in the open firmament of heaven. ''
And God created great whales...
...and every living creature
that moveth...
... which the waters brought forth
abundantly after their kind.
God blessed them, saying:
''Be fruitful and multiply
and fill the waters...
...and the seas. ''
And the evening and the morning
were the fifth day.
And God said, ''Let the earth
bring forth...
... the living creature
after his kind.
And everything that creepeth
upon the earth after his kind...
...cattle and the beast of the earth
after his kind. ''
And God saw that it was good.
And God said:
''Let us make man in our own image...
...after our likeness. ''
The Lord God formed man
of the dust of the ground...
...and breathed into his nostrils
the breath of life...
...and man became a living soul.
And God brought unto Adam
every beast of the field...
...and every fowl of the air...
... to see what he would call them.
And the Lord said:
''It is not good that the man
should be alone. ''
And He caused a deep sleep
to fall upon Adam.
And he slept.
And God made a woman
and brought her unto the man.
This is now bone of my bones
and flesh of my flesh.
So God created man
in His own image...
...in the image of God
created He him...
...male and female created He them.
And God saw everything
that He had made...
...and behold, it was very good.
And the evening and the morning
were the sixth day.
And on the seventh day God rested...
...from all His work
which He had made.
And God blessed the seventh day
and sanctified it.
Eastward, in Eden,
God had planted a garden.
And He said, ''Go into the garden
I have made.
Tend it and keep it.
Of every tree of the garden
thou mayest freely eat.
But of the Tree of the Knowledge
of Good and Evil...
... thou shalt not eat of it.
For in the day
that thou eatest thereof...
... thou shalt surely die. ''
And God blessed them
and said unto them:
''Be fruitful and multiply. ''
Eve. . . .
Hath God said. . .
. . .ye shall not eat of every tree
in the garden?
We may eat of the fruit of the trees
of the garden. . .
. . .but of the fruit of this tree
God hath said:
''Ye shall not eat of it. . .
. . .neither shall ye touch it,
lest ye die. ''
Ye shall not surely die.
For God doth know that in the day
ye eat thereof. . .
. . .then your eyes shall be opened. . .
. . .and ye shall be as gods. . .
. . .knowing good and evil.
The serpent hath said
that we shall not die. . .
. . .that our eyes shall be opened
and we shall be as gods.
Taste it. There's no harm.
lt is. . .
. . .disobedience.
lt will make us wise.
And the Lord God called unto Adam:
''Where art thou?''
l heard thy voice and l was afraid
because l was naked, and l hid myself.
Who told thee that thou wast naked?
Hast thou eaten of the tree...
... whereof I commanded thee
that thou shouldst not eat?
The woman thou gavest to be with me. . .
. . .she gave me of the tree,
and l did eat.
What is it that thou hast done?
The serpent beguiled me and l did eat.
Because thou hast done this...
... thou art cursed above all cattle...
...and above every beast of the field.
Upon thy belly shalt thou go...
...and dust shalt thou eat
all the days of thy life.
I will put enmity between thee
and the woman...
...between thy seed and her seed.
It shall bruise thy head...
...and thou shalt bruise his heel.
Eve...
...I will greatly multiply thy sorrow
and thy conception.
In sorrow shalt thou bring forth
children...
...and thy desire shall be
to thy husband...
...and he shall rule over thee.
Adam, because thou hast harkened
unto thy wife...
...and hast eaten of the tree...
...cursed is the ground
for thy sake...
...in sorrow shalt thou eat of it
all the days of thy life...
... thorns also and thistles
shall it bring forth to thee.
Thou shalt eat the herb
of the field.
In the sweat of thy face
shalt thou eat bread...
...until thou returnest
unto the ground.
For out of it was thou taken.
For dust thou art...
...and unto dust shalt thou return.
l have made a man from the Lord God.
Thy name shall be called Cain.
And the meaning of Cain
is ''possession. ''
Eve again bare a son...
...and his name was Abel...
... which means ''breath of life. ''
And the children of Eve
grew to be men.
Cain was a tiller of the ground...
...and Abel was a keeper of flocks.
At the time of the harvest,
they builded altars...
...and kindled fires upon them.
And Abel brought of the firstlings
of his flock...
...and the fat thereof.
And Cain also brought of the fruit
of the ground...
...an offering unto the Lord.
And the Lord had respect unto Abel
and his offering.
But unto Cain and his offering
He had not respect.
Why art thou angry?
lf thou doest well,
shalt thou not be accepted?
Cain?
Cain.
Where is Abel, thy brother?
l know not!
Am l my brother's keeper?
What hast thou done?
The voice of thy brother's blood...
...crieth unto me from the ground.
Now art thou cursed from the Earth...
... which hath opened to receive
thy brother's blood from thy hand.
When thou tillest the ground...
...it shall not yield
unto thee her strength.
A fugitive and a vagabond
shalt thou be in the Earth.
For dust thou art and unto dust
shalt thou return.
My punishment is greater
than l can bear!
Thou hast driven me out this day
from the face of the Earth. . .
. . .and from thy face shall l be hid.
And l shall be a fugitive
and a vagabond in the Earth. . .
. . .and everyone that findeth me
shall slay me!
Whosoever slayeth Cain...
... vengeance shall be taken
on him sevenfold.
I set a mark upon Cain...
...lest any, finding him,
shall slay him.
And Cain left the presence
of the Lord...
...and dwelt in the Land of Nod,
east of Eden.
And Cain knew his wife,
and she conceived and bare a son.
In the generations of time...
... when his seed began
to people the Earth...
... there were born men
apt in knowledge and craft.
As Jabal, the father of such
as dwell in tents...
...and of such as have cattle.
They made vessels out of the earth...
...jars and pitchers by the skill
of their hands.
And Jabal's brother's name was Jubal.
He was the father of all such
as handle the harp and play music.
And Tubalcain, also...
...an instructor of every artificer
in brass and iron.
And they learnt the secrets
of the ground...
... that it should deliver to them
its fullness and strength.
But the knowledge of good and evil
was in all the people of the Earth.
And God grieved in His heart that men
followed the way of evil...
...and that every imagination...
...of the thoughts of his heart
was only evil, continually.
The Earth disclosed her blood...
...and no more covered her slain.
The deed of Cain was multiplied
a thousand times.
And God said, ''I will destroy man,
whom I have created...
...both man and beast, for it
repenteth me that I hath made them. ''
But the Lord gave Eve another son...
...instead of Abel whom Cain slew.
And Adam called his name Seth.
And from Seth 's seed,
through the generations...
... was Noah born.
And Noah found grace
in the eyes of the Lord.
There dwelt with Noah
his sons: Shem...
...Japheth and Ham.
And his wife,
and his sons ' wives also.
And Noah was perfect
in his generations.
He was a just man,
and walked with God.
Noah.
Noah!
Hearken now to my voice
and take heed.
Now shall I tell thee
the matter of my grief...
...and of what thou shalt do.
The end of all flesh
is come before me...
...for the Earth is filled
with violence through them.
And behold, I will bring a flood
of waters upon the Earth...
... to destroy all flesh.
And everything that is
in the Earth shall die.
Make thee an ark of gopher wood.
Rooms shalt thou make...
...and shalt pitch it within and
without with pitch.
And this is the fashion
thou shalt make it of.
The length of the ark shall be
300 cubits...
... the breadth of it 50 cubits...
...and the height of it 30 cubits.
With thee will I establish
my covenant.
Thou shalt come into the ark.
Thou and thy sons and thy wife,
and thy sons ' wives with thee.
For thee have I seen righteous
before me in this generation.
What is more stupid than this?
A man building a ship on dry land!
A devil is in him
and hath made him mad. . .
. . .and his sons with him!
When shall the Earth see this again?
He hath the sea in his head,
and his house rides up on the waves.
Father, is it indeed God's voice
thou hast heard?
For look, there is no cloud
in the sky.
Not so much as would cover a bird.
The Lord waiteth upon our work.
Then what need is there of haste?
Shall we not do it little by little. . .
. . .under cover of night?
He demandeth every hour of the day.
ln our obedience must be no delay.
Will you question your father's
understanding or doubt his ways?
You should be ashamed.
Yet when shall they be rid
of the work?
All things wait for this.
The ground is unsown,
and the house is unmended.
Give me one to make the roof good. . .
. . .lest when the rain comes the house
will not keep it out.
But, wife!
Shem!
More pitch!
Ham!
We have need of more pitch!
Japheth!
Take the bucket and fill it,
and our work is done!
Shem!
Ham!
Japheth!
Noah.
Come thou and all thy house
into the ark.
I will cause it to rain upon
the Earth 40 days and 40 nights.
Every living substance I have made...
... will I destroy from off
the face of the Earth.
And of every living thing
of all flesh...
... two of every sort,
male and female...
...shalt thou bring into the ark
to keep them alive with thee.
Two. . .
. . .of every sort.
Wife!
Sons! Daughters!
Fear not.
The Lord hath spoken and said:
''Bring two of every kind
to keep them alive. ''
They have followed me and trust us. . .
. . .to mind them and bring them
to safety.
They're good beasts at heart.
They will do no harm to you,
nor each other. . .
. . .for they know of the waters
that will fall upon the Earth.
And God hath chosen them
above all others.
There are more yet to come.
Japheth, help them find their way.
Ham, Shem, load hay and grain.
Wife and daughters,
put oil into the lamps.
And get thy house aboard
the ark in order.
And God shut him in.
ls it the wind that waileth?
No, wife.
lt is the chaff, which
the wind driveth away.
The Lord hath taken hold
of the ends of the Earth. . .
. . .and shaketh it.
They cry to be fed.
We have work to do.
Shem. . .
. . .care for the animals with
hooves that cheweth the cud.
Ham shall tend the camels,
hares, swine and giraffes.
Japheth, the tigers, the lions,
the cats of all kinds.
What shall they eat?
Milk from the cattle and the goats.
Milk? For beasts of prey?
They're only great cats, wife.
Do you not hear them purr?
Be not afraid. He will do thee no
harm, for harm is not in him.
Shem, the red hart has not eaten
of his corn. Fetch him leaves.
The waters prevailed, and all the
high hills were covered.
And Noah only remained alive...
...and they that were
with him in the ark.
When will the rain cease?
When shall we stand again
upon the Earth?
God has told us it shall rain
40 days and 40 nights.
But here we know
neither the day nor the night.
We cannot measure the time by sleep.
We sleep when we will.
When we are rested, we wake.
The moon has no waxing or waning. . .
. . .and the sun no rising or setting.
-We are without knowledge of time.
-Nay, but l know.
Since the time we came into the ark. . .
. . .and the doors shut, and the flood
carried us upon its waters. . .
. . .the days have been 20.
-And two.
-Twenty and two.
How dost thou know
what is hidden from us?
By what rod dost thou
measure the darkness?
By the beasts,
who carry the days within them.
Even as the sun and the moon
divide the seasons into hours.
l know the time by the lowing
of the cow ready to be milked. . .
. . .and the cackle of the hen when
the egg shall be gathered.
l have counted the days.
ln 1 8 days, then, we'll know
the world as before.
Not so. When the rain stops,
still the water will cover the earth.
Neither shall we know
the world as before.
When the waters are dried up. . .
. . .then we shall know.
We shall be alone on the Earth.
No other life.
Where will the ark have carried us?
ln what strange land
shall we be renewed?
The Lord has put
the future into our hands.
All things will be new.
Raven!
And Noah sent forth a raven...
... to see if the waters were abated
from off the ground.
Go forth!
And the raven went forth,
and flew to and fro.
Even until the waters were
dried up from off the Earth.
And the raven returned not
again unto Noah anymore.
Also he sent forth a dove from him.
But the Earth was still seas...
...as it had been in the beginning,
before the dry land appeared.
She hath found no rest
for the sole of her foot.
For the waters are on the
face of the whole Earth.
Eat of the grain
and renew thy strength.
For in seven days l shall send
thee forth again.
And the dove came in to him
in the evening...
...and lo, in her mouth was
an olive leaf, plucked off.
Let us make a rudder and a sail.
For now we know that the waters are
abated from the Earth. . .
. . .and we can find land.
What sail shall discover the winds,
and what rudder find our course?
The breath of God
shall divide the waves. . .
. . .and his hand only
lead us into safety.
And the ark rested in the seventh
month, of the 1 7th day of the month...
...upon the mountains of Ararat.
And the Lord said in his heart:
''I will not again curse
the ground for man 's sake.
While the Earth remaineth,
seed-time and harvest...
...cold and heat, summer
and winter, and day and night...
...shall not cease.
The waters shall no more become
a flood to destroy all flesh.
I do set my bow in the cloud.
And it shall be for a token
between me and the Earth.
It shall come to pass
when I bring a cloud...
... the bow shall
be seen in the cloud.
And I will remember my covenant
which is between me and you.
And every living
creature of all flesh. ''
And sons were born unto the sons
of Noah after the flood.
And of them was the
whole Earth overspread.
And the whole Earth was of one
language and of one speech.
Now these are the generations
of the sons of Noah.
The sons of Japheth: Gomer....
The sons of Shem: Elam, Asshur....
And the sons of Ham: Mizraim, Phut,
Canaan and Cush.
And Cush begat Nimrod.
And Nimrod was a king.
And he set to build a tower
that would soar like his pride.
A tower that would reach unto Heaven.
And his people sang a song
as they built the tower:
''Who can bend the bow of Nimrod?
Or put strength into the arrow
like unto his strength?
Nothing is too mighty for him to do
No power is greater than his
He hath taken the Earth
and made it his own
He stores up the thunder and wears
the lightning like a jewel
The glory of Nimrod
shines beyond the sun
There is none greater
than he in Earth or Heaven. ''
And the Lord came down
to see the tower...
... which the children
of men builded.
And He said,
''Behold, the people is one...
...and they have all one language.
And this they begin to do.
And now nothing will
be restrained from them...
... which they have imagined to do. ''
My bow.
''Let us go down and confound
their language...
... that they may not understand
one another's speech. ''
Stand your ground. Obey me!
Make good what has been brought down.
Am l not Nimrod?
And my voice is your commandment!
What words are these?
Babbling fool!
Madness is in his mouth!
You mock your king's tongue?
Shall a monkey gibber against me?
Therefore is the name of it
called Babel.
There the Lord confounded
their language...
...and scattered them abroad
upon the Earth.
The Lord waited 1 0 generations
for a man called Abram to be born.
He was born in Ur of the Chaldees.
And when he had come of an age,
the Lord said:
''Get out of thy city
and thy country...
...from thy kindred
and from thy father's house...
...unto a land that I will show thee.
I will make of thee a great nation...
...and I will bless thee
and make thy name great. ''
So Abram departed, as the Lord
had spoken unto him...
... with Lot, his brother's son...
...and Sarai, his wife,
whom he loved...
...and all their substance
that they gathered...
...and the souls they had gotten...
...and they journeyed
like strangers on the Earth.
They journeyed not knowing
whither they went.
And yet the land lay before them
as the Lord had promised.
And the mornings and the evenings
pointed the way.
Come! Come!
The hills revealed it.
Lift up now thine eyes...
...and look from the place
where thou art...
...northward and southward...
...and eastward and westward...
...for all the land
which thou seest...
... to thee will I give it...
...and to thy seed forever.
Shall we indeed inherit
this country in peace?
For the Canaanites go about the land.
The understanding of God. . .
. . .is not our understanding.
And what shall be brought about
and how it is perfected. . .
. . .is not in our power to know.
Only in the promise
of what shall come. . .
. . .can we prosper.
And in that trust. . .
. . .have we pitched our tents.
Wife.
Abram.
My husband.
The sun has gone down.
We have labored until evening.
l bring my love beside you
in the tent. . .
. . .as day answereth day.
Let my beloved come into his garden
and eat his pleasant fruits.
Behold.
Thou art fair, my love.
Behold, thou art fair.
l have drawn away from my beauty
as from a stranger. . .
. . .for the years have gone with
the going down of the sun.
Your beauty stands in a sanctuary.
The enemy falters in the street. . .
. . .and sheathes his sword
in the marketplace.
Time. . .
. . .cannot pass the door.
The strong lock of the door is love. . .
. . .and the key. . .
. . .is in my hand.
As the apple tree among
the trees of the wood. . .
. . .so is my beloved among the sons.
His left hand is under my head. . .
. . .and his right hand doth embrace me.
My right arm covers you. . .
. . .as the night covers the day.
But Sarai, his wife, was barren...
...and she had no child.
Yet was the land before them
as God had promised.
And they pitched their tents
in the length and breadth of it...
...from Bethel to Kadesh and Shur,
even unto Egypt.
With Sarai came also her handmaid...
...Hagar, the Egyptian.
They learned the wells
and fertile places...
Five score.
...and Abram prospered.
Six score.
Seven score.
And when they came again
unto Bethel...
... there was division between
the herdsmen of Abram's cattle...
...and the herdsmen of Lot's cattle.
Let there be no strife
between thee and me.
And between thy herdsmen
and my herdsmen, for we are brethren.
Our substance is too great
for us to dwell together.
The land is not able
to bear us together.
ls not the whole land before thee?
Separate thyself,
l pray thee, from me.
lf thou will go left,
l will go to the right. . .
. . .or if thou go right,
l will go to the left.
There below us is the plain of Jordan.
And that way l will go.
Toward the cities of the plain.
The men of the cities are wicked,
and sinners before the Lord.
From here the walls of Sodom and
Gomorrah are white.
But within the walls. . .
. . .is the darkness of men.
Many tribes and their kings try
to claim their domination. . .
. . .and the city walls are refuge
and strength.
God is my refuge and strength.
The plain is well-watered
everywhere. . .
. . .fertile with fruits of the earth. . .
. . .even as the Garden of the Lord.
That is the way l shall take.
And my way is another.
Lift up now thine eyes...
...and look from the place
where thou art...
...northward and southward
and eastward and westward.
For all the land which thou seest...
... to thee will I give it
and to thy seed forever.
Lord God, what wilt thou give me,
seeing l go childless?
Behold, to me thou hast given no seed.
I will make thy seed
as the dust of the Earth...
...so that if one can number
the dust of the Earth...
... then shall thy seed
also be numbered.
But Sarai, my wife, is barren
and she has no child.
I am the Lord that brought thee...
...out of Ur of the Chaldees...
... to give thee this land
to inherit it.
Lord God. . .
. . .whereby shall l know
that l shall inherit it?
Take me a heifer
of three years old...
...and a she-goat of three years old
and a ram of three years old...
...and a turtledove
and a young pigeon.
Divide them in the midst...
...and lay each piece
one against another.
But the birds,
they shall not be divided.
Now have I made my covenant
between me and thee...
...and out of thine own bowels
thou shalt have an heir.
And Isaac shall his name be called.
Yet know of a surety that thy seed...
...shall be a stranger in a land
that is not theirs.
Its rulers shall afflict them...
...pangs and sorrows
shall take hold of them.
They shall be in pain
as a woman that travaileth.
They shall be tried,
like metal in a furnace...
...as also I shall try thee.
I will make a man more precious
than fine gold...
...even a man than
the golden wedge of Ophir.
Go.
Abram.
Behold now.
The Lord hath restrained me
from bearing.
l pray thee. . .
. . .go in unto my maid. . .
. . .according to that law which says:
''When a wife is barren. . .
. . .her maidservant may bear for her. ''
lt may be that l may obtain
children by her.
l give thee my handmaiden. . .
. . .Hagar the Egyptian. . .
. . .to be thy wife.
ls it so. . .
. . .that the promise of many nations
shall be fulfilled?
Even so. . . .
And Abram went in to Hagar
and she conceived...
...and when it came near the time
that she should bear a child...
... Sarai, her mistress,
was despised in her eyes.
Are you not tired?
Let us stay our hands. . .
. . .and eat and drink,
now that the sun is gone.
Fruits of thy kind.
Figs that are dry,
and dates and raisins.
But for me. . .
. . .the fruits that ripen.
Go away from me!
Why weepest thou?
l am ashamed.
For what cause?
Did l not say to thee:
''Go in to my maid that l may
obtain children by her''?
Even so?
Now l am despised by her that
she carries the child in her body.
l am but the grass that is bruised
where she walks.
l look through her eyes and see myself
as one who no longer lives.
The fulfillment of the earth
passes to strangers.
And l am left as l was never born.
But the child is thine. . .
. . .by thy maidservant. . .
. . .and by the love l bear thee.
From the south,
even unto the plain of Jordan...
...came four warring kings:
The kings of Shinar,
of Ellasar...
...of Elam, and Tidal,
king of nations.
These made war with
the king of Sodom...
...and the king of Gomorrah
and the king of Admah...
...and the king of Zeboiim
and the king of Zoar.
Four kings with five.
They joined battle
in the vale of Siddim.
The vale of Siddim
was full of slime pits...
...and the kings of Sodom
and Gomorrah fled and fell there...
...and the victors took captives
and goods and went their way.
And Lot?
And Lot, my brother's son, Lot?
He is taken captive.
Shall the land that is promised to us
have no peace?
And my blood be taken into slavery?
-Eliezer.
-My lord?
Summon Mamre, the Amorite. . .
. . .and Aner and Eshcol, his brothers
who are confederates.
And you, my trained servants. . .
. . .born in mine own house. . .
. . .gather at the tents.
Three hundred eighteen we be.
How shall we prevail against so many?
They have gotten the victory,
and left off watching.
l will divide us
against them by night. . .
. . .and smite them.
Blessed be the most high God. . .
. . .which hath delivered mine enemies
into my hands.
Thou art my shield and
my exceeding great reward.
I am the Almighty God.
Walk before me and be thou perfect.
Thy name shall no more be Abram...
...but thy name shall be Abraham.
For kings shall come out of thee...
...and I will establish
my covenant between me and thee...
...and thy seed after thee, and their
generations, to be their God.
As for Sarai, thy wife,
thou shalt not call her name Sarai...
...but Sarah shall her name be.
And I will bless her and give thee
a son, also of her.
And she shall be a mother of nations.
Thy child.
By my maidservant, and
by the love l bear thee.
The smell of my son is like a field
which the Lord has blessed.
This is my covenant, which ye
shall keep between me and you...
...and thy seed after thee.
Every man-child among you
shall be circumcised...
...as a token of the covenant
betwixt me and you.
Thou hast 24 score and 7
in thy flock.
By each pebble l know you
as good servants.
You are blessed among us
and are indeed our blessing.
My lord.
Behold. Thy son, lshmael,
hath seven years.
Give him thy blessing, l pray. . .
. . .that he may live before God as the
first of thy flesh, and thy only son.
Yet have l told thee how it stands
between me and lshmael.
For God hath said He will bless
Sarah and give me a son also. . .
. . .of her.
Wilt thou indeed believe
what cannot come to pass?
The years have gone by and
the promise is not fulfilled.
With Sarah, thy wife. . .
. . .the time of childbearing is over.
Give lshmael, therefore, thy blessing.
Thou can hope for no other.
Shall the Lord speak
and Abraham not believe?
What is faith if it say,
''This thing cannot be''?
And as for lshmael. . .
. . .God has said ''Behold. . .
. . .l have blessed him and will
make him fruitful.
But my covenant will l establish
with lsaac. . .
. . .which Sarah shall bear unto thee. ''
And so l wait upon his will. . .
. . .even beyond the time.
And Abraham waited upon
the will of God.
And God was silent, as one who
searches the strength of a man.
Three years passed
and two more added...
...and Sarah and Abraham grew old.
My Lord. . .
. . .if now l have found favor
in thy sight. . .
. . .pass not away from thy servant.
We go down towards the city. . .
. . .toward Sodom. . .
. . .where Lot, thy brother's son,
sits in the gate of the city.
Rest yourselves, l pray thee. . .
. . .under the tree.
And comfort ye your hearts.
Where is Sarah, thy wife?
Behold, in the tent.
l will certainly
return unto thee, and lo. . .
. . .Sarah, thy wife, shall have a son.
After l am waxed old. . .
. . .shall l have pleasure. . .
. . .my Lord being old also?
Wherefore did Sarah laugh?
ls anything too hard for the Lord?
l laughed not!
Nay. . .
. . .but thou didst laugh.
At the time appointed
l will return unto thee. . .
. . .and Sarah shall have a son.
We are going. . .
. . .towards the cities of the plain.
l will bring you on your way.
Shall l hide from Abraham. . .
. . .that thing which l do?
Because the cry of Sodom and Gomorrah
is great. . .
. . .and because their sin
is very grievous. . .
. . .l will go down now. . .
. . .and see whether
they have done altogether. . .
. . .according to the cry of it,
which has come unto me. . .
. . .and if not, l will know.
Wilt thou also destroy
the righteous with the wicked?
There may be 50 righteous. . .
. . .within the city. Wilt thou not
spare the place for them?
Shall not the judge
of all the Earth. . .
. . .do right?
lf l find 50 righteous
within the city. . .
. . .l will spare all the place
for their sakes.
What if there be 45 such men?
Or 30? Or even as few as 20?
l will not destroy it. . .
. . .for 20's sake.
Let not the Lord be angry
and l will speak yet but this once:
Peradventure, 1 0 shall be found there.
I will not destroy it...
...for 1 0's sake.
It chanced that when the sun was down,
Lot sat in the gates of the city.
And he lift up his eyes and looked...
...and beheld two strangers
coming into the city.
-What strangers are these?
-Where are they from?
-Two angels of God.
-So fair they are. So fair.
-Where are they?
-What have you done with them?
-Yes, bring them out unto us!
-Bring them, that we may know them!
l pray, brethren, do not so wickedly.
For these strangers
here with us are of God.
Better you destroy all l possess. . .
. . .than any harm should be done them.
Behold, l have two daughters
which have not known man.
Let me, l pray you,
bring them out unto you. . .
. . .and do ye to them
as is good in your eyes. . .
. . .only unto these men do nothing.
This one fellow came in to sojourn. . .
. . .and he will needs be a judge?
Now will we deal worse
with thee than with them!
l cannot see!
Whatsoever thou hast in the city,
bring them out of this place. . .
. . .for the Lord hath sent us
to destroy it.
Take thy wife and thy two daughters
which are here. . .
. . .lest thou be consumed
in the iniquity of the city.
Escape to the mountain,
lest thou be consumed.
Look not behind thee.
The name of our son
shall be called lsaac.
Thy son. . .
. . .and mine.
God hath made me laugh.
All that hear will laugh with me.
Who would have said unto Abraham. . .
. . .that Sarah would have
given children suck?
For l have borne him a son
in his old age.
ln him. . .
. . .are the stars of the heavens. . .
. . .and the sands of the seashore.
And the child grew...
...and Abraham made a great feast
the same day Isaac was weaned.
Cast out this bondwoman and her son.
Who has put this into thy heart?
Did you not see how
he went among us mocking?
l have a great fear there will
come such division in our people.
Like Cain and Abel again. l beg you,
cast out this bondwoman and her son!
The son of this bondwoman
shall not be heir with my son. . .
. . .even with lsaac.
What sayest thou? He is my seed.
l will not cast out the lad,
nor thy bondwoman.
But God said unto Abraham:
''Let it not be grievous in thy sight
because of the lad...
...and because of thy bondwoman.
In all that Sarah hath said unto
thee, hearken unto her voice...
...for in Isaac shall
thy seed be called. ''
And Abraham sent her away,
and she departed...
...and wandered in the wilderness
of Beersheba.
Lord! Let me not see
the death of the child!
And an angel of God
called to Hagar out of heaven...
...and he said unto her:
What aileth thee, Hagar?
Fear not. . .
. . .for God hath heard the voice
of the lad where he is.
And God was with the lad...
...and he grew
and became a great nation.
Here are the generations
of my fathers named. . .
. . .to whom God gave life.
lt has fallen to me that
the past shall not be forgotten. . .
. . .and after me. . .
. . .my son. . .
. . .also shall remember it.
By what descent are ye come?
These are the generations
of which l am made. . .
. . .of Noah, who by faith
prepared an ark. . .
. . .to the saving of this house.
Noah begat Shem. . .
. . .and Shem, Arphaxad. . .
. . .and after him was Salah,
who begat Eber. . .
. . .and his son was Peleg. . .
. . .the father of Reu,
who begat Serug. . .
. . .the father of Nahor. . .
. . .and Nahor begat Terah. . .
. . .whose son was Abraham,
my father.
Here are the names written.
And here shalt thy name be also. . .
. . .lsaac, son of Abraham. . .
. . .when thou takest my place.
Put thy hand upon it.
Abraham....
Abraham!
Here l am.
The night is filled with thy voice.
Here am l.
What dost thou demand of me?
Thy son.
Thy only son.
What sayest thou?
Take now thy son...
... thy only son, Isaac,
whom thou lovest...
...and go into the mountains,
where I shall show thee...
...and offer him there
for a burnt offering.
Wouldst thou l do
even as the Canaanites. . .
. . .who lay their first-born
on fires before idols?
Art thou truly the Lord, my God?
Thou knowest.
No!
Thou wilt not. . .
. . .ask this thing of me!
lsaac. . .
. . .take leave of thy mother.
Mother, l am going on a journey.
A journey?
We are going on a journey
of three days.
-l am going with my father.
-What dost thou tell me?
A journey unto the land of Moriah!
Unto Moriah?
Why unto Moriah?
God hath commanded that
we go there to sacrifice unto him.
Six days must l wait for thee?
Mother, it is a little time.
l have waited for thee
until l was old.
The days are precious to me.
lsaac, lsaac. . . .
What should l fear. . .
. . .if thou goest with thy father?
Father. . .
. . .this was a city?
The city of Sodom.
Lot sat here in this gate.
And here. . .
. . .came the two angels to him.
He overthrew these cities
and all the plain. . .
. . .and all the inhabitants
of the cities. . .
. . .and that which grew
upon the face of the ground.
All the inhabitants?
And lo, the smoke
of the country went up. . .
. . .as the smoke of a furnace.
The Lord, our God, must be obeyed.
All the inhabitants of the cities?
The children also?
Were the children also wicked?
Father?
Shall not the judge
of all the Earth. . .
. . .do right?
Call the nobles to the kingdom!
None are here.
All the princes are nothing!
Father!
The thorns have come up
in the palace.
From generation
to generation it will lie. . .
. . .waste.
Ye shall stretch out upon it
the line of confusion.
Has it not been told from the
beginning, God is He that sitteth. . .
. . .upon the circle of the Earth. . .
. . .that stretcheth out the heaven
as a curtain. . .
. . .and spreadeth them out as a tent
wherein to dwell. . .
. . .that bringeth the princes
to nothing?
Ye shall blow upon them. . .
. . .and they shall wither!
And the whirlwind. . .
. . .shall take them away. . .
. . .as stubble.
My son. . .
. . .the Lord God. . .
. . .appeared unto me. . .
. . .and said unto me,
''l am the Almighty God.
Walk before me. . .
. . .and be thou. . .
. . .perfect.
Behold, my covenant is with thee. . .
. . .and l will make thee. . .
. . .exceedingly. . .
. . .fruitful. ''
Come, let us leave these ruins. . .
. . .and go from here
into the mountains.
ln all things. . .
. . .we must obey Him.
Then on the third day...
...Abraham lift up his eyes
and saw the place, afar off.
The wood.
The fire.
The knife.
But where is the ram
for the sacrifice?
Father!
My son!
There is nothing
He may not ask of thee?
Nothing.
Abraham!
Here am l.
Lay not thy hand upon the lad...
...for now I know
that thou fearest God...
...seeing that thou
hadst not withheld thy son...
... thy only son, from me.
There is the ram for the sacrifice.
Behold, I have tried thee
like metal in a furnace.
I have chosen thee
in the furnace of affliction.
Now will I multiply thy seed
as the stars of the heaven...
...and as the sand which is
by the seashore, innumerable.
Subtitles by
SDl Media Group