Where were you when I laid
the foundations of the earth?
When the morning stars sang together, and all
the sons of God shouted for joy? (Job 38:4,7)
Brother.
Mother.
It was they who
led me to your door.
The nuns taught us there
are two ways through life.
The way of nature.
And the way of grace.
You have to choose which one you'll follow.
Grace does not try
to please itself.
Accepts being slighted,
forgotten, disliked.
Accepts insults and injuries.
Nature only wants to please itself.
But others to please it too.
Likes to lordeth over them.
To have its own way.
It finds reasons to be unhappy,
when all the world
is shining around it.
And love is smiling
through all things.
They taught us that no one
who loves the way of grace,
ever comes to a bad end.
I will be true to you.
Whatever comes.
My son.
I just want to die. Just be with him.
He's in God's hands now.
He was in God's hands the whole time.
Wasn't he?
My all.
My God.
I shall fear no evil.
Fear no evil, for
you are with me.
What did you gain?
Be not far from me,
for trouble is near.
Go on now, we're alright.
We're alright.
Thank you.
You have your memories of him.
You have to be strong now.
I know the pain will...
it will pass and time...
It might seem...
hard, my saying that,
but it's true.
I don't want it to.
Life goes on.
People pass along.
Nothing stays the same.
You still got the other two.
The Lord gives and the Lord takes away.
That's the way He is.
He sends flies to wounds
that He should heal.
I never got a chance to
tell him how sorry I was.
And I...
punched himself in the face for no reason.
He'd sit next to me at the piano and I
criticized where he'd turn the pages.
I made him feel shame.
Why shame?
Poor boy.
How did you come to me?
In what shape?
What disguise?
I see the child that was.
I see my brother.
True.
Kind.
He died when he was nineteen.
Just check this one against this.
She wants to get back together.
But the chapter is closed,
the story has been told.
What do you do?
Experiment.
When you're young it's all about your career.
You don't understand anything.
I just feel like I'm bumping into walls.
The world's gone to the dogs.
People are greedy, keep getting worse.
I try to get into their hands.
Hey, dad.
I'm sorry I said what I said.
I think about him every day. I just
shouldn't have said what I did and I'm sorry.
No, it's just... this day.
What are you thinking?
I know you did everything you could.
How did I lose you?
Wandered.
Forgot you.
Find me.
How did she bare it?
Mother.
Was I false to you?
Lord.
Why?
Where were you?
Did you know?
Who are we to you?
Answer me.
We cry to you.
My soul.
My son.
Hear us.
Life by life.
I search for you.
My all.
My child.
You spoke to me through her.
You spoke with me from the sky.
The trees.
Before I knew I loved you.
Believed in you.
When did you first
touch my heart?
What is this?
- Two alligators.
- Kangaroo.
Jump.
Sweetheart.
Please.
I know.
No. No!
You found it.
You'll be grown before
that tree is tall.
Are you afraid?
Come here.
Come back here, son. Stay out of there.
You see this line?
Let's not cross it, you understand?
Do you understand?
Do you see this line? Look here.
Come back here, son.
Stay out of there.
That's where God lives.
I found it. I found this old bone.
- Set it off.
- No.
Bless this food to our use.
And us to your loving
and faithful service.
And make us ever mindful
of those who are in need.
Amen.
Can you pass the butter, please?
Can you pass the
butter, please sir?
Sir.
- What did you do today?
- We went to school.
After that.
What about the yard?
Did you put the runners in
like I asked?
Yes.
Yes, sir.
Well, it didn't look like it.
Yes.
Mr. Reese liked
Jack's book report...
What is that, sweetheart?
You know this.
Brahms!
- Son.
- Sir.
Reach me my lighter.
Haven't you forgotten something?
Do you love your father?
Yes, sir.
They found him stretched out on
a warm ledge in the afternoon sun.
Admiring his beautiful new coat.
Who do you love the most?
I love you all three the same.
Tell us a story from
before we can remember.
I went for a ride in a plane once.
It was a graduation present.
Mother.
Make me good.
Brave.
Can it happen to anyone?
Nobody talks about it.
Help me be thankful
for everything I've got.
Where do you live?
Help me not to tell lies.
Are you watching me?
I want to know what you are.
I want to see what you see.
Come here.
You're going to close this
door quietly, fifty times.
Count it off.
3, 4, 5,
6, 7, 8.
You got to get it by the root.
Your mother is naive.
It takes fierce will to
get ahead in this world.
If you're good, people will
take adventage of you.
Everyone of these top executives.
You know how they got where they are?
Floating right down the middle of the river.
Don't let anyone tell you
there's anything you can't do.
Don't do like I do.
Promise me that.
I dreamed of being a great musician.
I let myself get sidetracked.
If you were looking for something
to happen, that was it.
That was life. You lived it.
Job imagined he might
build his nest on high.
That the integrity of his behavior
would protect him against misfortune.
And his friends thought,
mistakenly, that the Lord could only
have punished him because,
secretly, he'd done something wrong.
But no.
Misfortune befalls the good as well.
We can't protect ourselves against it.
We can't protect our children.
We can't say to ourselves,
'Even if I'm not happy,
I'm going to make sure they are. '
We run before the wind.
We think that it will carry us forever.
It will not.
We vanish as a cloud.
We wither as the autumn grass.
And, like a tree, are rooted up.
Is there some fraud in
the scheme of the universe?
Is there nothing which is deathless?
Nothing which does not pass away?
We cannot stay where we are.
We must journey forward.
We must find that which is
greater than fortune or fate.
Nothing can bring us
peace but that.
Is the body of the wise man
or the just, exempt from any pain?
From any disquietude? From the
deformity that might blight its beauty?
From the weakness that
might destroy its health?
Do you trust in God? Job,
too, was close to the Lord.
Are your friends and
children your security?
There is no hiding place in all the
world where trouble may not find you.
No one knows when sorrow might visit
his house, anymore than Job did.
At the very moment everything
was taken away from Job,
he knew it was the Lord
who'd taken it away.
Returned from the passing shows of time,
he sought that which is eternal.
Does he alone see God's hand
who sees that he gives?
But does not also the one see God's
hand who sees that he takes away?
Or does he alone see God who
sees God turn his face towards him?
Does not also he see God who
sees God turn his back?
That's a friend of mine.
He owns half the real estate in town.
Frank Johnson.
He started out as a barber.
He built something big.
Now you'd think he's the fourth
person of the holy Trinity.
They never talk about their money.
The wrong people go hungry.
Die.
The wrong people get loved.
The world lives by a trigger.
If you want to succeed,
you can't be too good.
Act like you're scared, act like you're
in trouble. You don't want to fight.
And the minute you see
him blink, crack him.
Ok?
You're going to cover, right?
It's the most important thing.
Come on, Jack. Hit me.
Hit me, come on.
Here it is, hit me.
Come on, son.
What are you doing?
Left. Don't leave your tongue
out or you're going to lose it.
Left. Right.
Left. Harder.
Harder.
Come on son, hit.
Give me something,
show me what you got.
Come on. Go on.
One meal.
Leave the table.
You too?
- You're going to continue to defy me?
- No, sir.
You're interrupting me, I wasn't done yet.
Am I finished?
- No?
- No.
Thank you, your majesty.
Makes up stories.
Or a chain of words.
He says, 'Don't put your elbows on the table. '
He does.
Insults people.
Doesn't care.
I remember when you were born.
They wouldn't let me come home.
The Navy said an officer must be
present for the laying of the cue.
I had to launch.
The next word is volcano.
The next word is socket.
Please pass your answers to each other.
We're going to grade each others' papers now.
No interruptions, please.
Come on, get your pencil out.
Sweetheart!
Honey!
Was he bad?
Will you die too?
You're not that old yet, mom.
Where were you?
You had a boy die.
You let anything happen.
I can't see!
Why should I be good?
If you aren't.
Thank you.
Why's this bare here?
The grass wont grow under the tree.
It does at the Kimbles.
They have a yardener.
They have money.
Of course he inherited it.
I don't want to hear one more
word out of you, not until this is finished.
You're cropping that too close.
You're going to have to keep that watered.
Toskanini.
Once recorded a piece 65 times.
You know what he said when he finished?
It could be better.
Think about it.
27 patents, your father has.
It means ownership, ownership of ideas.
You gotta sew them up.
Get them by the nuts, if you pardon my French.
Be rich.
You make yourself what you are.
You have control of your own destiny.
Can't say I can't.
You see I'm having trouble.
I'm not done yet. Can't say I can't.
Why's he hurt us?
Our father?
Come on Vince! Get it, get it!
Give your father a kiss.
Lies.
Will you do something for me?
Do you promise you'll do it?
Without having to ask what it is? Just have the
confidence in what your father asks of you is right?
Yes sir.
In the next half hour, will you not speak
unless you have something important to say?
What did you do today, my fine feathered friend?
Sit on the front of your chair.
It's better for your posture.
I read that in the paper.
Did you actually buy this from Mr. Ledbetter?
Don't explain, just nod, yes or no?
Be quiet.
What did you say?
Please.
Leave him alone.
Leave him alone!
Come here! Come here!
Get up there!
You turn my own kids against me.
You undermine everything I do.
How do you like it?
Stop it!
Stop.
Where's dad?
He's gone on a trip.
Get her! Get her!
Help each other.
Do not slam that screen door!
Love everyone.
Every leaf.
Every ray of light.
Our gift.
Shut up!
Watch out! Watch out! Go, go!
I say let's bust them.
Yea!
Found a frog!
Lets go set it off in a sky rocket!
He's getting away!
Get back! Get back!
Did it go to the moon?
Where is he?
There he is.
It was an experiment!
Why?
Never do it again.
Promise?
You want to tell dad?
They're just trying to scare you.
Keep your ear there.
Things she got to learn.
I gotta know stuff too.
They say you can't try stuff? They do.
What do you need be afraid of?
You're afraid. I see it.
Right here! Right here!
I can't talk to you.
Don't look at me.
What have I started?
What have I done?
Stick it in there.
I trust you.
You tired?
No. I never get tired.
You did this morning.
No, I was just pretending.
You calling me a liar?
No.
I don't want to fight.
Afraid to?
No, I just don't want to.
If I was to say you're scared,
would you call me a liar?
No.
Then you're scared, aren't you?
Quit it.
Come here!
NO!
I don't want to do
anything you tell me to.
I want to do what I want.
What do you know?
You let him run all over you.
How do I get back?
Where they are.
This one is heavy,
you're going to need two hands.
Careful now, you know what that is?
- Chinese?
That's Chinese, that's very good, yes it is.
Your father went all around the world.
All the way to China.
That's Pan Am Airlines,
that's what your father flew on.
The entire bathroom was stainless steel.
Even the wash basin.
I feel confident the
deal is going through.
Nothing, forget it. I'll tell Molly to go to hell.
That's from Germany.
See that?
Put that down, son.
Can Taylor come over?
Was your family not good enough for you?
It's not going to take
as long as last time?
Al dente.
It's a subjective point,
you know the difference?
Subjective means it comes from your mind.
It can't be proven by other people.
It's good to see you again. Let's go boys.
There are things you can't do.
But there are things I can't do either.
You're not to call me dad,
you will call me father.
- But...
Do not interrupt!
- But you did...
Don't interrupt!
It's your house.
You can kick me out
whenever you want to.
You'd like to kill me.
Dad.
Why was he born?
Please God, kill him.
Let him die.
Get him out of here.
She only loves me!
Defend, oh Lord, this thy child with thy heavenly grace.
That he may continue thine forever.
And daily increase in thy Holy Spirit more and more.
Until he come unto thy everlasting kingdom.
Amen.
See something...
Put your finger over it.
There.
Come on.
What I want to do I can't do.
I do what I hate.
You can hit me if you want.
I'm sorry.
You're my brother.
What was it you showed me?
I didn't know how to name you sin.
But I'll say it was you.
Always you were calling me.
I wanted to be loved cause I was great.
A big man.
I am nothing.
Look, the glory around us.
Trees and birds.
I lived in shame.
I dishonored it all and
didn't notice the glory.
A foolish man.
They're closing the plant.
They gave me a choice.
No job.
Or transfer to a job nobody wants.
Father.
I never missed a day of work.
Mother.
Tithe every Sunday.
Always you wrestle inside me.
Always you will.
You know Jack, all I ever wanted for you was...
Make you strong and,
grow up and be your own boss.
Maybe I've been tough on you.
I'm not proud of that.
I'm as bad as you are.
I'm more like you than her.
It was about all I've done in life,
otherwise I've drawn a zilch.
You're all I have,
you're all I want to have.
My sweet boy.
Are you just going to stand
there like a bump on a lawn?
The only way to be happy is to love.
Unless you love,
your life will flash by.
Do good to them.
Wonder.
Hope.
Brother.
Keep us.
Guide us.
To the end of time.
Follow me.
I give him to you.
I give you my son.