An Education
Come on, girls.
Anybody?
Anybody else?
Jenny. Again.
Isn’t it because Mr Rochester’s
blind?
Yes, Jenny.
I've got an English essay to do by
tomorrow morning.
Right.
So, the only sound I want to hear
coming through this ceiling
is the sound of sweat dripping onto
textbooks.
- Cello?
- No cello.
I thought we agreed that cello was
my interest or hobby?
Well, it already is your interest or
hobby.
So, when they ask you at your
Oxford interview,
“What's your interest or hobby?”
you can say, "the Cello"
and you won't be a lying. Look, you
don't have to practise a hobby.
A hobby is a hobby.
Can I stop going to the youth
orchestra, then?
No.
No, no. The youth orchestra is
a good thing.
That shows you're a joiner-inner.
Ah. Yes. But. I've already joined in.
So now I can stop.
No.
No. Well, that just shows the
opposite, don't you see?
No, that shows you're a rebel.
They don't want that at Oxford.
No. They don't want people who think
for themselves.
No, of course they don't.
Jenny.
Shall I wear, like, Sunday best?
You'd better, I'm afraid.
Just to show my father you're
un jeune homme serieux,
not a teddy boy.
Oh, God. Right.
I need to go. It'll bucket down in
a minute.
All right...
I'll see you at the weekend.
- Bye, then.
- Bye.
- Sorry. Sorry.
Good bye, my love.
Come on. Come on.
Stop it, now! Stop it!
Oh, no. Look, what you've done.
The nice man's waiting for us.
- It fell off.
?
My socks are wet.
Hello.
Look.
If you've got any sense, you wouldn't
take a lift from a strange man.
But I'm a music lover, and I'm
worried about your cello. So...
What I propose is, you put it in
my car and walk alongside me.
How do I know you won't just
drive off with the cello?
Good point.
How much does a new cello cost?
Ten? Fifteen pounds? I don't know.
Let's say fifteen.
No? All right.
Up to you.
Thank you.
And that.
- I'm David, by the way.
- Jenny. - Very good.
How did the concert go?
It was a rehearsal. The concert's
next Thursday.
- What are you playing?
- Elgar.
I think it's a shame he spent so much
time in Worcester, don't you?
Worcester's too near Birmingham.
And you can hear that in the music.
There's a terrible Brummy accent in
there, if you listen hard enough.
Anyway, Elgar and the Jews don't mix
very well.
I'm not a Jew!
No. I am.
I wasn't accusing you.
Can I sit in the car with my cello?
Jump in.
Oh, thank you.
I've never seen a car like this
before. C'est tres chic.
It's a Bristol. Not many of 'em
made.
Where to, madam?
Jenny live round the corner.
Worst luck!
I'll see, what I can do.
I suppose cellists must go to a
lot of concerts.
We don't go to any concerts. We
don't believe in them.
Oh, they're real.
So people say.
Smoke?
I'd best not. I live just up there.
- Why don't we believe in them?
- He'd say there's no point to them.
- Your father, this is?
- Oh, yes.
They're just for fun.
Apart from school concerts,
which are no fun at all,
so we go to those.
They don't help you get on.
Which of course is what is so
wonderful about them.
Anyway, you'll go one day.
I know. I will.
If I get to University,
I'm going to read what I want, and
listen to what I want,
and I'm going to look at paintings
and watch French films,
and I'm gonna talk to people who
know lots about lots.
- Good for you.
- Yes.
Which University?
Oxford. If I'm lucky.
Did you go anywhere?
I studied at what I believe they
call the University of Life.
I didn't get a very good degree
there.
Well, thank you for driving me home.
# Sous le ciel de Paris #
You alright? You got it?
# S'envole une chanson #
Yes, it's fine.
Thank you.
- My pleasure.
# Elle est née d'aujourd'hui
Dans le coeur d'un garçon #
# Sous le ciel de Paris
Marchent les amoureux #
# Leur bonheur se construit
Sur une air fait pour eux #
# Sous le pont de Bercy
Un philosophe assis #
# Deux musiciens, quelques badauds
Puis des gens par milliers #
# Sous le ciel de Paris... #
I don't want to hear any French
singing.
French singing wasn't on the
syllabus, last time I looked.
- Battenburg?
- Oh, thank you.
?
So, where are you applying, Graham?
I'm not sure yet.
When will you be sure?
You can't let the grass grow under
your feet, young man.
I might take a year off.
What for?
?
Maybe do some travelling. Yeah. That
sort of thing.
Travelling? What are you, a teddy
boy?
You know she's going to Oxford,
don't you?
If we can get her Latin up to
scratch.
So while she's studying English at
Oxford,
you'll be the wandering Jew.
Mr. Mellor, I'm not a teddy boy.
I'm an homme serieux. Jeune.
Um... No... Yeah.
An homme jeune serieux homme.
- They're for me!
- Who are they from?
Gosh. Him.
What's this?
Jack, I’m afraid, Jenny has been
sent some flowers from a chap.
- A chap? What kind of chap?
- He's wishing me luck for tonight.
Is that all he's wishing you? Where
he get the money from?
He earns it, I expect.
Earns it? Why isn't he at school?
Um... Can we just go?
Otherwise the good-luck flowers will
actually be responsible for me
actually missing the concert. Which
would be ironic, n'est ce pas?
I don't like it.
Objection noted. Jenny?
Noted.
It's going to be ten bob's worth of
luck here.
I mean, that's a bit much for
a schoolgirl, isn't it?
We can't leave it here.
I mean, I'd burgle a house with
flowers left outside.
They’ll think we’re made of money.
Thank you, Marjorie.
Camus doesn't want you to like him.
Feeling is bourgeois.
Being engagee is bourgeois.
He kills someone and he doesn't feel
anything.
His mother dies and he doesn't feel
I wouldn't feel anything if my
mother died.
Does that make me an existentialist?
No. That makes you a cow.
Une vache.
Well, after I've been to University,
I'm going to be French,
and I'm going to Paris, and I'm
going to smoke and wear black,
and listen to Jacques Brel,
and I won't speak. Ever.
C'est plus chic comme-ça.
- Oh, cranky!
- What?
Wait here.
Hello.
Hello?
Hello. Thank you.
How did it go?
Oh, fine. I think. Well, I didn't
mess my bit up.
Nobody got thrown out of the
orchestra afterwards.
Always the mark of a cultural
triumph.
Listen. I'm glad I ran into you.
What are you doing on Friday?
- Going to school.
- I meant the evening.
Of course. Nothing.
Because I’m going to listen to some
Ravel at St John’s Smith Square.
My friends Danny and Helen will be
going too, so it wouldn't be...
I'll tell you what.
I'll come and pick you up, if your
mother and father disapprove,
then you can have the tickets and go
with one of them.
How does that sound?
- Thank you.
And I'd like you to go with you.
Seven?
All right.
And... Um...
We'll probably go for a spot of
supper afterwards.
Supper.
If you want to.
But the thing is, we'll probably
have eaten.
Well. If you'd like supper, then,
perhaps on Friday you could...
not eat.
Yes. Of course.
- A spot of supper?
- You've heard of supper?
We've heard of it. But we've never
eaten it.
So, you're going to have to tell us
everything.
Otherwise it's not fair.
I won't allow it! - Fine. He's more
then happy for you to take me.
Fine. I will.
- Good.
- Well. Where is it?
- St John’s Smith Square.
- Where's that?
I don't know. I'm sure we could find
out.
It's in Westminster. Right next door
to the Abbey.
How d'you know that?
I had a life before we were married,
you know. He soon put a stop to that.
- There we are.
- Where are we?
We're near Westminster Abbey. I'm
not going all the way over there.
The trouble is, that's where
St John's Smith Square is.
Oh, come on. There must be something
on locally. Where's the paper?
She wants to see someone who can
play.
She doesn't want to see Sheila
Kirkland scratching away.
I'll take her.
And how do you propose to get there?
RAF Helicopter?
- That's him. - Oh, bloody hell.
- Jack!
Oh, by the way... David's a Jew.
A wandering Jew. So watch yourself.
What she mean by that? I've never
said anything like that!
It's just an expression! Look, I've
got nothing against the Jews!
Glad to hear it. Hello.
No. I didn't mean I've got nothing
against you...
No. Of course. I do mean that. - Dad?
- It's not... Sorry. It's just...
You're not the sort of person that
I'd be against. But I wouldn't,
because I'm not that kind of person
who would be against... people.
I'm Jack, this is my wife, Marjorie.
You didn’t tell me you had a sister,
Jenny.
Please.
You're a lucky man, Jack.
Yes, I suppose I am.
This is lovely.
Thank you.
I'm sorry, David. Would you like a
drink?
I'd love one, Jack, but we're
running a little late.
If Jenny's ready, perhaps we'll
shoot off.
Actually, David, Dad has something
he has to tell you.
No, really. It was just a question.
A point of reference.
What's the best way to get to
St John’s Smith Square from here?
It's a straight run, really. Up to
Hammersmith,
take the A4 through Kensington and
you’re there.
- Simple as that.
So, I book us some tickets.
No--- But have her back by ten,
David.
I was hoping she might come with me
afterwards for a stop of supper
with my aunt Helen.
Oh, well, I...
No, no, um...
She's usually in bed by then.
What if I promise that to have her
back by eleven thirty?
Well, it’s Friday night. And you're
going all the way to the West End...
Thanks, Jack. I appreciate it.
All right.
- Bye.
- Bye-bye.
Have a nice time.
Come.
Hello hello.
Are we late?
No. I thought we were gonna miss the
beginning, and then it wouldn’t be
worth going in, and we could go off
dancing or something.
Helen is one of the more reluctant
members of tonight’s audience.
- Hello. - Hello. - Jenny, these are
my friends Helen and Danny.
Shall we?
All right.
Sorry.
That's alright. It's lovely, isn't
it?
It's beautiful. Where did you get it
from?
Oh, I even don't know, Chelsea
somewhere...
Oh, yours is... Well, good for this
sort of concert, isn’t it?
Thank you.
We should go shopping together one
day, you know, if you want.
That would be nice. But Chelsea...
C'est beaucoup trop cher pour moi.
Sorry?
I just said, it's too expensive for
me.
No you didn't. You said something
completely different.
No. Well, I said it in French.
In French? Why?
I don't know.
Well. Chelsea is too expensive for
me, too, really.
But we don't have to worry about
that.
If you want something in Chelsea,
just get David to take you shopping.
Why would David want to take me
shopping?
I booked a table at Juliette's. Will
that kill the mood, do you think?
Oh, I hope so.
God, I always think I'm going to my
own funeral
when I listen to classical music.
That was classical, wasn't it?
Yes. Very classical. As classical as
you can get.
Juliette's it is, then. Heaven forbid
that we should end the evening
reflecting on our own mortality.
# I want a Sunday kind of love #
# A love to last past Saturday
night #
?
Extraordinary woman, Greco. Just
like here Helen.
What about "Chante Francoise Sagan?"
Have you heard about that one?
Wonderful.
I've only got... Well, I think it's
just called "Juliette Greco."
The one with the eyes on the sleeve.
I saved up and got my French
conversation teacher
to bring it back after Christmas.
- You've got a French conversation
teacher? - Yes.
Is that why you suddenly speak
French for no reason?
Never heard her sing? She's
marvellous.
You should see her in Paris, not
here. David will take you.
I'd love to. You'd fit right in.
Better than here, really.
Isn't it wonderful to find a young
person wants to know things.
There's so much I want you to see.
Are you all right to come and have
a look at that Pembroke Villas place
with me on Friday, Danny?
Oh, no. I can't.
There’s a Burne-Jones coming up at
Christie’s on Friday.
Desperate to get my hands on it.
You're thinking of buying a
Burne-Jones? A real one?
I just have a feeling that the pre-
Raphaelites are going to take off.
I love the pre-Raphaelites.
- Do you?
- Yes, of course.
Rossetti and Burne-Jones, anyway.
Not Holman Hunt, so much.
He's so garish.
- Oh, absolutely!
Well, why don't we all go to the
auction together?
Auction? Gosh! How exciting!
Next Friday morning.
Friday. Oh.
You're busy?
Oh, yes.
Tant pis.
Pas de probleme.
Are you sure you're busy?
No. I'm sure I could re-arrange.
That would be lovely.
# You got me wrapped around your
little finger #
# If this is Love, it's everything
I hoped it would be #
# When we kiss, It's as if our lips
agree #
# that we were meant to be #
# When we touch... #
What are you doing?
I can't get this casserole dish
clean. It’s all burnt round...
It's twenty-five to twelve.
We finish tea at seven.
I know what the time is.
How was your evening?
Best night of my life.
Night, mum.
There were like two violins, one
cello, two violas, a harp.
I don't want to hear about Ravel.
I want to know what else was on the
programme.
There was nothing like that. He was
the perfect gentleman.
He just said he wanted to take me
places and show me things.
- Things.
- Plural? Oh my Gawd!
I knew that "Jane Eyre" would
eventually work its magic upon you.
I'm presuming that's what you're so
animated about.
Of course. "Jane Eyre" and Jenny's
new boyfriend.
He's not my “new boyfriend”.
It's true. He's more a man-friend,
actually?
He's got a sports-car, Miss Stubbs.
- It's Maroon.
So, could we call him Mr. Rochester
figure.
I think he must be as blind as
Mr. Rochester.
You may have noticed, I'm trying
to stir the subject away
from Jenny's lurid love-life and into
the matter in hand.
This is clear from this evidence
that most of you know further much
about the former, and next to nothing
about the latter.
Reluctantly I have to admitt that
Jenny is clearly an expert on both.
Excellent as always, Jenny.
- Hello.
Any further bids?
Sold then for sixty guineas.
Hello.
You're late.
We now turn to lot 41,
The Tree of Forgiveness, by Sir
Edward Burne-Jones.
This is a rare opportunity to
purchase a key work
of the Pre-Raphaelite movement.
Who will start me off at one hundred
guineas? - Is it that One?
Yes. That's the one.
Fifty guineas?
Twenty guineas?
Thank you.
Fourty?
Thank you, sir.
Do I hear sixty?
- ?
Eighty guineas?
Thank you, sir.
Another one, madame? One hundred
guineas?
One hundred and twenty?
No further bids?
- Your turn.
- What?
- Any further bids?
- ?
- Anymore?
- Quick.
One hundred and twenty guineas for
the very eager new bidder.
One hundred and forty, madam?
Thank you.
One hundred and sixty guineas?
One hundred and eighty? Thank you.
Two hundred guineas?
Two hundred and twenty?
Another one, madam?
Sold for two hundred guineas.
Thank you.
Your name, please.
Mellor.
Now we move on to lot 42.
Thank you very much. I couldn’t
possible bought it without you.
Just a couple of years ago you could
pick one of those up for fifty quid.
No one was interested. - Oh, I would
have been so interested.
As you can see, I just love things.
That's not a Lockey-Hill!
There aren't many people who come
in here and say that.
- No. Certainly not me.
- Oh, it's beautiful.
- Do you play?
- Thank you.
I used to. I vowed to myself that
one day I'd own one of these.
And now I do and I won't even touch
the bugger.
It's vulgar, putting it on display.
Give it to Jenny.
I think, that would be even more
vulgar.
Play for us, Jenny.
No, no. One day. When I'm good
enough.
She's good enough now.
David, you've never seen me play.
I can come and hear you in Oxford,
when you get there.
We should all go and spend a
weekend in Oxford.
Straw boaters, punting, cream teas,
antiquarian bookshops.
- Boats?
Bit of business, if we can find it.
What about next weekend?
Yes.
I wouldn't be allowed to do that.
I'll talk to them.
You're going to ask my father if you
can take me away for the weekend?
He'd have you arrested.
- We'll see.
- I bet you can't.
- How much?
I'd be careful if I were you,
Jenny.
You don't know who you're dealing
with.
Half-a-crown.
You're on.
How do you know Danny?
Oh, you know. We kept bumping into
each other, and we became pals,
ended up doing a bit of business
together, when it suits us.
What kind of business?
Property. A bit of art dealing.
Some buying and selling. This and
that...
Alright, just be two ticks.
- Okay.
?
Mr. Goldman, good to see you.
Madam.
All right.
Hey.
All right. I got this one.
And... Um...
Go on, then.
Sorry about that.
How do you know those negro people?
They're clients.
Clients?
Schwarzers have to live somewhere.
It's not as if they can rent off
their own kind, is it?
Test results for the Virgil
translation.
We'll start from the bottom.
Patricia. Absent.
Margaret. 48%.
Jenny. 52%.
That would just about scrape a pass
in the exam proper.
Not good enough for Oxford
candidates.
It’s her Latin, isn’t it?
Everyone’s doing their best, Jack.
But what if everyone's best isn’t
good enough? What do we do then?
Well. Perhaps the whole thing’s been
a waste of money anyway.
You don’t mean that.
What’s she going to do with an
English degree?
And if she’s going to spend three
years playing that bloody cello,
talking in French to a bunch of
beatniks,
Well, I’m just throwing good money
after bad.
Well, she might meet a nice lawyer.
She could do that at a dinner dance
tomorrow.
That’s the point of an Oxford
education, isn't it dad?
It’s the expensive alternative to
a dinner dance.
What about private tuition?
Can anybody hear me? How much is
this going to cost me?
Five shillings an hour. Maybe a
little more for A-level.
Five bob! Oh, we spend five bob
here, we spend five bob there,
next thing you know that’s our
savings down the drain.
And what else are we spending five
bob on?
What else are we spending six pence
on?
Oh, nothing. No, nothing. All of
this is free.
This vase is free.
It was, actually. It was a present
from Auntie Vi.
That chair. This sofa. It's all
free.
We don’t have to pay for any of it.
You see, that's the beauty of life,
Jenny.
You don't have to pay for anything.
You know, there's a lovely Oxford
tree growing in the garden,
lucky for you, because that’s Oxford
taken care of.
And there's a whole orchard of
school trees,
so that’s school is free.
And I think there's even a private
tuition tree in there.
I'll just go and check, shall I?
- Jack?
That's all right, Marjorie. Don't
worry. It'll only be a second.
Because I think there's a whole clump
of them
surrounding the pocket money tree.
I'll just go make sure, they're all
nice and safe, shall I?
Oh, by the way, you might be lucky,
there might be a man
with deep pockets growing out there.
Because God know, you gonna need one.
You could always take secretarial
college with Hattie.
- Oh, thanks.
- Charming.
Oh, God, no.
Hello.
Hello. Graham.
Haven’t seen you in ages!
It all went wrong, didn’t it?
The tea-party, I mean.
Was it because of the year off
thing? Because I...
No.
I just have so much work to do if
I’m going to get the grades I need.
Yeah. She’s got no time for boys.
- Bye, Graham.
- Bye.
Yes.
?
- Oh, you do all the Goons.
- No, my Eccles is no good.
- Oh, no, you've got him.
- No. No.
?
Hello.
Oh, Jenny.
David does the most fantastic
Bluebottle.
You came to see my parents?
Oh, why is that so hard to imagine?
Why are you drinking?
It's not Christmas!
Oh, there's a lot of you don’t know
about us, young lady.
We had a life before you came along.
That’s true.
I’m only going on what I’ve seen for
the last sixteen years.
I’m trying to think what you missed.
Nothing much comes to mind.
Right.
Anyway. I’ve got a huge pile of
Latin translation to do.
You didn’t tell us David went to
Oxford.
No. I didn’t.
For all the good it did me.
- Isn’t that funny?
- Extraordinary.
I was just telling Jack that I’m
going back next weekend.
I go and visit my old English
professor every now and again.
See, that’s what you need, Jenny.
Someone on the inside track.
It’s not always what you know, is
it, David?
Too true. Did you come across Clive
Lewis?
Dad's never come across anyone.
He wrote a children’s book called
"The Lion, The Witch and The
Wardrobe"
that did very well, I believe.
CS Lewis?
Well, to us he was just the old
codger
who taught Medieval literature but
I came to know him very well.
We just... got along.
Jenny used to devour those books.
I’d love to meet him.
I’m sorry. I’m being slow on the
uptake.
Would Jenny like to come at the
weekend?
No. Not this weekend. But sometimes,
perhaps... Yes.
How often do you see him?
Not very often. Every couple of
years.
Maybe next time.
Well, I suppose...
Would she have to stay the night?
I wouldn’t recommend driving home
after one of those Oxford dinners.
Clive could get her a room in the
college. That’s easy enough.
Seems like too good an opportunity
to pass up.
It wouldn't be a bother, would it,
David?
# We walk along hand in hand #
Come on!
Just putting a few things into the
bag. Don't worry.
# Yeah, we both understand #
# Mm, sweet nothings #
Come on!
We're nearly ready. Be there in two
ticks.
How can they only be nearly
ready?
I wouldn’t be surprised if three of
them come out then.
The only explanation. They’re making
themselves a friend.
Ladies! Come on! Let’s go.
There. Have a look in the corner.
Open the door.
You should keep that one, if you
want it.
I can only wear so many one day.
Thank you.
What about tonight? We got to put on
a nightie.
I thought I'd share a room with you?
You haven't slept with him?
No.
Good for you.
Really? Do you think so?
Yes. Well, you’re only sixteen. You
don’t want to get pregnant, do you?
No. I wouldn't let that happen.
I want to wait until I’m seventeen.
On my seventeenth birthday,
hopefully.
With David?
Golly. It will be with David, won’t
it?
If that’s what you want.
Anyway. I’ll find you a nightie.
Ta-daa!
Shall we make a move?
# You got me wrapped around your
little finger #
# If this is love, it's everything
I hoped it would be #
Can we get off and have a look
around?
Later. If we have time
Imagine spending three years here.
I know.
Take a bow. It's all about...
Why university girls are
strange-looking?
They can’t all have started off that
way, can they?
I mean, most girls aren’t born ugly,
but most girl students seem to be.
So there must be something about
these places
that make you fat, or spotty, or
short-sighted.
Well, when you look at it like
that...
I mean, that’s proper scientific
analysis.
You can’t argue with science.
I still not quite understand what
you want to do when you get here.
I want to read English.
Books?
Sorry?
You want to read English books?
Reading English is just another way
of saying...
Don't worry, Jenny. You’re wasting
your breath.
Anyway, tomorrow we’ll get more of
a feel for the place.
Absolutely. This place would be good
for a little business.
All of those little old ladies
wandering around...
- Old Ladies?
- This place is rife with stats.
Please explain what stats are.
You’re always going on about them.
- It isn't very interesting.
- But you two are interested.
It's because we're not very
interesting either.
- Oh, no. They're not, really.
- True.
So we have an idiot here, to save us
from ourselves.
Yeah. To put some intelligence and
culture into our brutal lives.
Sing to us! Sing to us1
Please, don't make me sing to you.
Please don't make us talk about
work.
So. Now. Is he Clive, do you think?
Or CS?
I’m confused now. I thought you’d
made him up?
No, we...
Never mind.
“To dear Jenny. With the pleasure
of meeting you."
"Come and see me again soon. Clive.”
Dirty old man.
Bad girl.
We've got these exact same curtains
at home.
Let’s not talk about curtains.
You look beautiful.
David...
There’s something you should know.
I’m a virgin. And I want to stay
that way until I’m seventeen.
I think that’s good. I think that’s
right.
We can still be romantic, can’t we?
Yes, of course. As long as it's not
actually.
Minnie...
Is that me?
Yes. You’re my Minnie Mouse, and
I’m your bubbalub.
Okay. If that's what you want to do.
- Minnie.
- Yes, David?
Bubbalub...
Bubbalub?
May I have a look? Just a peek?
You just want to see them?
Thank you.
I think there's a house for sale
around here.
Really?
Might be worth a look.
?
Jenny...
- Aren’t you coming?
- We don’t go in.
What are you talking about?
Why don't you go and get a nice cup
of tea somewhere.
Helen will look after you.
I don’t need looking after, thank
you very much. David?
I’m not going to tell you a second
time. Run along.
They won’t be long. Either way.
"Either way?"
Well sometimes they find something,
and sometimes they don’t.
And when they do find something, we
often have to leave quite quickly.
They can be a quite naughty,
sometimes.
- Thank you. - Good bye. - Cheerio.
- Catch!
Careful-careful-careful!
Come on.
Helen.
- Pass the ball.
Good.
Jenny!
What? - You can stand there, if you
like. But I won't recommend it.
Coo-ee. Jenny.
Sorry about being a little brisk
back there, Jenny.
It's just the way we do things.
Silly, really.
Hey, don't forget your case.
- Who's coming up for a drink?
- Me? No.
You go. I’ll make my own way home.
Jenny?
Jenny!
It's an old map. A Speed.
Poor dear didn’t even know what it
was.
It's a waste. It shouldn’t spend
its life on a wall in...
wherever the hell we were.
It should be with us. We know how to
look after it properly.
We liberated it.
- Liberated?
That’s one word for it.
Don’t be bourgeois, Jenny. You’re
better than that.
You drink everything I put in front
of you down in one,
and you slam your glass down on the
bar and ask for more,
it’s wonderful.
We’re not clever like you, so we
have to be clever in other ways,
because if we weren’t, there would
be no fun.
We have to be clever with maps,
and...
You want to know what stats are?
Stats are old ladies who are scared
of coloured people.
So we move the coloureds in and the
old ladies move out
and I buy their flats cheap.
That’s what I do. So now you know.
And if you don’t like it,
I'll understand, and you can go back
to Twickenham
and listen to the Home Service and
do your Latin homework.
But these weekends, and the
restaurants and the concerts---
They don’t grow on trees.
This is who we are, Jenny.
Oh. - Oh. - That's nice.
- Come on, you two!
- Come on up!
You can have my olive.
Come on.
I suppose you have homework to do.
You have no idea how boring
everything was before I met you.
"Action is character", our English
teacher says.
I think it means that if we never
did anything,
we wouldn’t be anybody.
And I never did anything before
I met you.
And sometimes I think no one’s ever
done anything
in this whole stupid country, apart
from you.
Okay.
- All right.
There you go.
Good night.
Marjorie, look at this.
"Clive..." Lucky girl.
Never a dull moment with David, eh?
Better than the young man you
brought home for tea.
David’s a lot older than Graham.
Graham could live to be two hundred
years old,
you'll never see him swanning
around with famous authors.
Hasn’t got it in him.
Graham might become a famous author,
for all you know.
Becoming one isn’t the same as
knowing one.
That shows you're well connected.
Very impressive young man, your
David.
I must admitt, life is a little
brighter with him around.
Come on girls. Get your moves on.
?
What the hell are those?
Russian Sobranies.
Where did they come from?
She probably bought them from the
Savoy, or Claridges, or the opera,
or some fancy nightclub.
Who knows, with Jenny?
Paris. You can’t buy them here.
- You never bought them yourself?
- No. I never.
Oh, shut up, you stuck-up cow.
But I’ll bring you some back, if
you like.
- You’re joking?
- Non.
- He’s taking you to Paris?
- Oui.
- This term?
- Peut-etre.
Wait. Isn’t it your birthday next
Thursday?
Might be.
Oh, my God! Your birthday!
I would not like to be you. All
those suppers you’ve had off him.
Ouch.
You've such a Victorian attitude to
sex, you two.
Your parents wouldn't let you
swan off like that, would they?
They don’t know yet.
David will come up with some story.
He usually does.
Yeah. I’ve noticed that.
Chanel perfume, Chanel perfume.
Chanel lipstick, Chanel lipstick.
Those funny cigarettes you were
smoking. Sobranies.
Ten packets each.
How much is that Chanel perfume?
Oh, are you the girl going to Paris,
or are you not? Because...
Tina, top button.
Jenny, the headmistress wants a word
with you.
The legend of Mr. Rochester may have
travelled further than you intended.
Come.
Ah. Miss Mellor.
We’re all very excited about your
forthcoming trip to Paris.
Our excitement, indeed, knows no
bounds.
Some of us can talk of little else.
An older man, I understand.
A word of warning, Miss Mellor.
There may well have been the odd
sixth-form girl who has lost
an important part of herself---
perhaps the best part---
while under our supervision. These
things happen, regrettably.
If, however, we are made aware of
that loss,
then of course the young lady in
question
would have to continue her studies
elsewhere,
if she still has any use for
"A" levels.
Did I make myself clear?
- Can I go now?
- If you want.
What are you doing in there?
But I imagine she's lighting the
candles on my cake.
You're seventeen, not two hundred
and fifty.
- Thanks for inviting me. - That was
Marjorie's idea, not mine.
Not even Jenny's for that matter.
- Dad?
Cake!
Well. Blow them out before the house
burns down!
Okay--- Don't worry.
Bravo.
- Who'd like a piece?
- Me, please.
Come on! Come on! Presents!
Oops!
It's a new Latin dictionary.
Thank you. I needed a new one.
Oh dear.
Snap!
Oh, good grief!
Jenny, you should see this.
it's a special day.
- She’s a special girl.
- I know it.
Bit of help?
Makes your dictionary look
a bit feeble, eh, Graham?
Gosh!
These are for you--- Hello, young
man.
- Oh. David. - Hey, David, would you
like a drink?
I'd love one.
I’d best be going because I have a
stack of homework to do. So...
All right.
Thank you. Bye.
Cheers.
- Good bye, Mr. Mellor.
- Ah. See you, young man.
Thank you.
Wonderful to see you, Graham.
- Good bye, Jenny.
- Bye, Graham.
- Little something warming?
- You know me so well.
- Can I open anything yet?
- Wait for me.
Before you open that lot, I got
a surprise.
Next weekend, we’re all going to
Café de Flore
to celebrate Jenny’s birthday.
Ah. Lovely.
Café de Flore is on the boulevard
Saint-Germain. In Paris.
- What do you mean, Paris?
- You know the one, Dad.
No. No. No, no, no.
No. We don't have any French money.
And besides it's just...
Well. I don’t think it would agree
with me.
Dad!
The French don't like us, Jenny. You
know that.
John Sutton form work, he went there
last year.
They were very rude to him.
I don’t want to spoil anyone’s fun,
but it’s just not for me, Europe.
You'll have to go another time.
You’ve just said you don’t like
Europe.
So, what’s going to change?
It’ll have to be Europe, won’t it?
Because it certainly won't be you.
I'll take her.
- To the continent?
- Why not?
- And leave me here on my own?
- Oh, for God’s sake.
What do you think?
You know, what Jenny likes about
France, Jack?
French films, and books, and music.
Of course I do.
Sorry. Yes, 'cause without saying
she's your daughter.
Jenny likes the joke about how you're
the stick in the mud
and all the rest of it, but I know
that's not who you are.
Otherwise, she wouldn't be, who she
is.
No.
But I can also see that I've acted
out of turn and...
I'm sorry.
What about your Aunt Helen?
An hour late.
We'll make it. I promise.
Okay. There's a flight at eight in
the morning.
Good.
There’s no bed.
Ah. I pushed the boat out and got
us a suite.
A suite!
Well, if work stops us getting to
Paris until tomorrow,
then we can buy us a nice hotel room.
Anyway, it’s a special occasion,
isn’t it?
I would thought tonight of all
nights we only need a bed.
Hold on a second. I’ve got
something.
I thought we might practice with
this.
With a banana?
I thought we might get the messy bit
over with first.
David, I don’t want to lose my
virginity to a piece of fruit.
I’m sorry.
Okay.
I think the moment might have gone.
I think we should wait until Paris.
I’m sorry. Um... Minnie.
I'm an idiot. I'm sorry.
David, if tomorrow night does
happen,
it's only ever going to happen once.
Why will it only happen once?
Because the first time can only
happen once.
So, no baby-talk. No Minnie.
Just treat me like a grown-up, okay?
I know. Let’s go and sit in our
sitting-room.
All right.
Order some champagne.
Room service!
# Quand doucement tu te penches #
# En murmurant: "C'est dimanche, #
# Si nous allions en banlieue faire
un tour #
# Sous le ciel bleu des beaux
jours?" #
# Mille projets nous attirent, #
# Mais, dans un meme sourire, #
# Nous refaisons le trajet simple et
doux #
# De nos premiers rendez-vous... #
# Sur les quais du vieux Paris, #
# Le long de la Seine
Le bonheur sourit, #
# Sur les quais du vieux Paris, #
# L'amour se promene
En cherchant un nid. #
# Vieux bouquiniste,
Belle fleuriste #
# Comme on vous aime,
Vivant poeme ! #
# Sur les quais du vieux Paris, #
# De l'amour boheme
C'est le paradis... #
Do you still feel like a schoolgirl?
It wasn’t too uncomfortable?
Not after the first bit.
It’s funny, though, isn’t it?
All that poetry, and all those songs
about something that lasts no time
at all?
Yeah.
All your exercise books on my desk
in a pile, please.
I bought this for you.
That's very kind of you.
But I can't accept it.
Why not?
It’s because of people like you that
I plough through illiterate essays
by Sandra Lovell about her pony.
But I know where this comes from,
Jenny.
And If I took it, I'll feel like I'd
be betraying both of us.
Jenny.
You can do anything you want. You
know that.
You’re clever and you’re pretty...
Is your boyfriend interested in
clever Jenny?
I’m not quite sure what you’re
trying to tell me.
I’m telling you to go to Oxford. No
matter what.
'Cause if you don't, you’ll break my
heart.
Where did you go?
Cambridge.
Well. You’re clever. And you’re
pretty.
So presumably, Clever Miss Stubbs
won.
And here you are with your pony
essays.
I don't know. These last few months,
I’ve eaten in wonderful restaurants,
and went to jazz clubs, and watch
wonderful films,
heard beautiful music...
- Jenny, you're taking precautions.
- Nothing to do with that.
Isn’t it?
Maybe will our lives going to end up
with pony essays. Or housework.
And yes, maybe we’ll go to Oxford.
But if we’re all going to die
the moment we graduate,
Isn't it what we do before that
counts.
I’m sorry you think I’m dead.
I don’t think you’re dead. I just...
I think you’d better get to your
next class.
Well done, Jenny.
I haven't won anything before. Not
even at the raffle.
Oh, you've bet on the sweetest
looking one,
and he always comes last.
- Let's go. - Come on. - Oh, can we
do it again? I'm feeling lucky!
Come on. Let's go. I don't want to
miss him.
Pick up your 10 bob on your way out.
- I won ten shillings!
Who is this man, anyway?
- Peter Rachman.
- A complete bastard.
Why do you have to see him here?
Because he's not a sort of chap
with an office.
- All right?
- Yeah.
Ladies...
A bottle of your finest champagne,
please.
There he is.
Come on, Jenny. Tell them your good
news. Don’t be bashful.
No. Be Sneezy.
Jenny got two A's and a B in her
mock-A levels.
Like everyone else in this
sophisticated establishment.
The B was in Latin.
- Seriously. Congratulations.
- Excuse us.
Don’t worry too much.
About what?
Someone told me that in about fifty
years
no one will speak Latin, probably.
Not even Latin people. So don't
worry about your B.
He's even more of a bastard than
I thought!
You don't want him to marry your
sister.
Or want to talk to him in a club,
come to that.
You do know what you’re doing, old
chap? With Jenny?
- This is the one, Danny.
- Right.
You see, she’s different.
I just don’t want to see her hurt.
Have you bought any more paintings
recently?
Have I? Yes.
I picked up a little Piper.
A good one, I think.
I’m still trying to work out what
makes good things good.
It’s hard, isn’t it?
The thing is, Jenny, you know,
without necessarily being able to
explain why. See, You have taste.
That’s not half the battle. That’s
the whole war.
Jenny, we should go. It’s late.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Alas. One day, school will be over
forever,
we can talk about art all night.
You’re all right in a taxi, aren’t
you?
Yeah. I'm fine.
Let's go. Come on.
Good night.
Wait here.
David, what are you looking for?
It's just...
What are you doing?
Will you marry me?
What were you looking for?
I thought I had a ring.
It wouldn’t have been the right one.
But it would have done for tonight.
Oh, David.
I’m serious.
You’re very sweet.
What do you think?
Take me home.
All right.
They do need some looking after,
but nothing that will require too
much work.
Just leave them in your potting shed
for a couple of weeks,
and they’ll look after themselves.
Fine. The potting shed.
Who does he think I am? Prince
Rainier of Monaco?
What if I got married instead of
going to college?
Married?
Married.
Well. It would depend who it was, of
course.
Would it? That’s interesting.
Of course it'd. I wouldn’t want you
married off just for the sake of it.
Thanks.
Has somebody asked you?
Yes.
Who?
David?
No. A man I just met walking his
dog.
What did you tell him?
Nothing yet.
Do you have a choice? Or is it too
late.
Of course she’s got a choice.
An interesting one, too, eh?
This is where you’re supposed to
say, “But what about Oxford?”
Well. Looked at it another way,
you wouldn’t really need to go now,
would you?
I wouldn’t need to go. Would you
like to expand on that?
You'd been looking after.
All that Latin! All those essays!
What was the point?
Why didn’t you just send me prowling
round nightclubs?
It would have been less trouble. And
I might have had more fun.
I don’t know about nightclubs.
I know about education.
Anyway, it looks like it might
have turned out for the best.
How?
He wouldn’t want you if you were
thick, would he?
May not an ass know when the cart
draws the horse?
Sings whoop jug I love thee.
And when it says "Sings", it means
you sing a line.
Never mind. Right. Lear...
Does any here know me.
This is not Lear.
Does Lear walk thus? Speak thus?
Where are his eyes?
Ha! Waking? Who is it that can tell
me who I am?
Ooh. Miss. Me. I can.
Oh, Jenny.
What?
Take it off.
Oh my God. Is that what I think it
is?
I'm going to be a bridesmaid!
You know the school rule on jewelry.
Half the girls in this room are
wearing jewelry.
Yes. But none of it is going to ruin
their lives.
We have a difference of opinion
about that.
How far advanced are these
ridiculous plans?
Have you set a date? Have you
decided on a church?
We won’t be getting married in a
church. David’s Jewish.
Jewish? He’s a Jew?
You’re aware, I take it, that the
Jews killed our Lord?
And you’re aware, I suppose, that
our Lord was Jewish?
I suppose he told you that.
We’re all very sorry about what
happened at during the War.
But that’s absolutely no excuse for
that sort of malicious
and untruthful propaganda.
Anyway, I can see you are far more in
need of responsible advice
than I realised.
Nobody does anything worth doing
without a degree.
with the degree. No woman, anyway.
So what I do isn’t worth doing.
Or what Miss Stubbs does, or Mrs
Wilson, or any of us here.
Because none of us would be here
without the degree,
you do realise that, don’t you?
And yes, of course studying is hard,
and boring...
Boring!
I’m sorry?
Studying is hard and boring.
Teaching is hard and boring
So what you’re telling me is to be
bored, and then bored,
and finally bored again, but this
time for the rest of my life.
This whole stupid country is bored.
There’s no life in it, or colour,
or fun.
It’s probably just as well that the
Russians are going to drop
a nuclear bomb on us any day now.
So my choice is to do something hard
and boring, or to marry my Jew,
and go to Paris and Rome and listen
to jazz
and read and eat good food in nice
restaurants and have fun.
It’s not enough to educate us any
more, Mrs Walters.
You’ve got to tell us why you’re
doing it.
It doesn’t have to be teaching,
you know.
There’s the Civil Service.
I don’t wish to be impertinent,
Mrs Walters.
But it is an argument worth
rehearsing.
You never know. Someone else might
want to know the point of it all,
one day.
Where did you find him?
- I can't tell you that.
- Why?
I think he likes you--- Do you like
her?
"I thought you would like her."
You do... you don't...
You don't remember? It's Jenny! You
remember her from the last time?
"No. I don't"
Yes, you do.
You're naughty! You're pardoned?
You're naughty.
Go stick to your own species.
He wants to kiss you, I think.
Isn't that naughty?
- Yes.
We're engaged.
Seriously? No. Really?
- Yeah. - Engaged? - Show her.
Yes. Look!
Gosh. That’s fantastic news.
Ooh, thank you.
Congratulations.
I knew you’d see sense about
university. You’ll stay pretty now.
Thank you. Can I still read?
Of course. But it doesn't have to be
books, does it?
And magazines will do just as well.
And you learn more from them anyway.
Oh, Helen.
You won’t be laughing, David, when
she gets all speccy and spotty.
Danny didn’t seem very pleased
about our engagement.
I've noticed that, too. Thought he
might be a bit jealous.
Jealous?
We're going to keep him away from
you.
I mean, what is supposed to order
for starter, anyway?
And how will I know what is a
starter, or what is it not?
We’ve been through this, Dad.
It’ll be quite clearly marked on
the menu.
Can’t the three of you just go on
your own. Leave me here.
I’ll be perfectly happy with a tin
of seven.
- Hello.
Ready?
I think you’ll like this place, Jack.
Their wine list is as good as
anything I’ve seen in London.
Yes. Someone told me that.
David, probably. Who else would it
have been?
Madam.
I was hoping you’d take us in this.
Hey, you won’t want to drive in
anything else after tonight.
Mind you, it drinks petrol.
- Yes.
I’m afraid We’ll have to stop on the
way in to town.
- I feel like Eamonn Andrews.
- Is that a good thing?
Eamonn Andrews is the poshest person
that Jack can imagine being.
How are you tonight, sir?
- Very well.
You might as well fill her up.
I'm going to make a quick call. I’ll
be two ticks.
Do you think I should offer to help
pay for the petrol?
Would he be insulted, what do you
think?
I know, he said tonight was his
treat.
But does that apply to the petrol,
what do you think?
I'm quiet sure, it does, Jack.
- Jack!
- Come on! It just came off.
- Filled my bill?
- Thank you, sir.
Cheers.
Jenny. Jenny...
Take us home.
What’s wrong?
I'm afraid there’s been--- Jenny's
had a bit of a shock.
What’s happened? - It’s just another
one of David’s little muddles
and misunderstandings.
I don’t want to hear another word
from anybody. Take us home. Now.
Fine.
You can take care of this, can’t you,
David?
Go inside, Dad.
Mr and Mrs David Goldman,
Mr and Mrs David--- You’re married!
Legally, yes, but...
When were you going to tell me?
Soon. It just never seemed the right
time.
You seemed so happy, and I was
happy, and...
You were living with your wife! All
this time!
Round the corner. Byron Avenue.
It’s no wonder we kept bumping into
each other, then, is it?
What number?
- Thirty four.
Don't be like this. Come on.
I have nothing. I didn’t take my
exams. I do--- I left school.
Where’s it all gone, now?
I can get a divorce.
Everything will turn out for the
best.
Go and tell them.
Go and tell them, then go and tell
your wife.
They won't listen now. All right?
I'll come round tomorrow. When
everyone’s a bit calmer.
Please don’t make me tell them on my
own.
You owe me that much. You owe them
that much.
I owe them much more than that.
Hey.
Two minutes. And I’ll come out and
drag you in.
What’s going on?
He’s helping himself to some Dutch
courage before facing you.
Stolen Dutch courage, from the look
of it.
He has something he has to tell you.
He just drove off.
Can you tell us?
Jenny? Please?
I wouldn't worry about it too much.
When I found out---
- Not now Helen!
I tried to tell him.
I’m not speaking to him now, if
that’s any consolation.
It's a funny world you people live
in.
You both watched me carrying on with
a married man,
you don’t think it’s worth saying
anything about.
Please, if you want that
conversation...
You watched David and I help
ourselves to a map,
and you didn’t say much, either.
Come on you. Let's go. Good boy.
Hello.
Hello. Sorry, I think I have a wrong
number. I was looking for my...
I wanted number of my cello lesson.
Oh, no. Don’t tell me.
Good God. You're a child.
You didn’t know about any of this.
Presumably.
No. They never do.
You’re not in the family way, are
you?
Because that’s happened before.
Thank God for that.
No, no, you stay here.
- Did you see her?
- Yes. I saw her.
I didn’t talk to her. There wasn’t
any need.
We have to have this out.
If you won’t do it, I will. I’m
still your father.
Oh, you’re my father again, are you?
What were you when you encouraged me
to throw my life away?
Silly schoolgirls are always getting
seduced by glamorous older men.
What about you two?
Jenny?
Jenny, I'm sorry.
I know I've made a mess of
everything.
All my life I’ve been scared,
I didn’t want you to be scared.
That’s why I wanted you to go to
Oxford.
And then along came David...
he knew famous writers,
he knew how to get to classical
music concerts...
But he wasn’t who he said he was.
He wasn’t who you said he was,
either.
The other day, your mother and I
were listening to...
a programme on the radio about
CS Lewis, and they said
that he moved to Cambridge in 1954.
I said, Well, they’ve got that wrong,
our Jenny wouldn't have his name
in her book,
if he moved to Cambridge.
There’s a cup of tea, and some
biscuits out here.
How do you think we can help?
I want to repeat my last year at
school.  And take my exams.
I got the impression the last time
we spoke
that you didn’t see the point of
school.
Or of me, or of any of us here.
I know. I was stupid.
The life I want, there's no
shortcut.
I know now, that I need to go to the
university.
It gives me absolutely no pleasure
whatsoever
to see our young schoolgirls
throwing their lives away.
Although, of course, you’re not one
of our schoolgirls any more.
Through your own volition.
I suppose you think I’m a ruined
woman.
You’re not a woman.
No, I'm afraid, I think that the
offer of a place at this school
would be wasted on you.
Come in.
I didn't expect to see you again.
This is lovely.
All your books and pictures and...
Paperbacks and postcards, Jenny.
It’s all you need, isn’t it?
Just somewhere to...
I’m sorry I said those silly things.
I didn’t understand.
Let’s forget about it.
A Burne-Jones.
Do you like him?
I do. Still.
Still? You sound very old and wise.
I feel old. But not very wise.
Miss Stubbs, I need your help.
I was so hoping that’s what you were
going to say.
Thank you, Marjorie.
It's from Oxford.
It is my pleasure to inform you that
your application to read English
at Oxford has been accepted.
On behalf of the Faculty of Arts,
staff of the university...
So I went to read English books,
and did my best to avoid the speccy,
spotty fate
that Helen predicted for me.
I probably looked as wide-eyed,
fresh, and artless
as any other student.
But I wasn't.
One of the boys I went out with---
and they really were boys,
once asked me to go to Paris with
him.
And I told him. And I'd love to,
I was dying to see Paris.
As if I'd never been.
An.Education.DVDSCR.xViD, NoGrp, PrisM, xSCR
pee-jay@email.cz