My story begins in London.
Not so very long ago.
And yet so much has
happened since then,
that it seems more
like an eternity.
At that time, I lived with my pet
in a bachelor flat just
off Regent's Park.
It was a beautiful spring day,
a tedious time of the
year for bachelors.
Oh. That's my pet, Roger.
Roger Radcliffe,
a musician of sorts.
No. No, I'm the one with the spots.
My name's Pongo.
And you know, as far
as I could see,
the old notion that a bachelor's
life was so glamorous
and carefree was all nonsense.
It was downright dull.
It was plain to see that
my old pet needed someone.
But if it were left up to Roger,
we'd be bachelors forever.
He was married to his
work. Writing songs.
Songs about romance, of all things,
something he knew
absolutely nothing about.
Oh, he's intelligent
enough, as humans go.
And I think you could say that Roger is
a rather handsome animal in his way.
I could see no reason why my pet
didn't deserve an attractive mate.
At least, I was
determined to do my best.
Of course, dogs are a pretty
poor judge of human beauty.
But I had a rough idea
of what to look for.
Hmm. Unusual breed.
Very unusual.
Oh, surely not.
Well, now, what have we here?
Hmm.
Well, a little too short-coupled.
Nope.
I say... Oh, well I do say!
Now, there's a fancy breed.
Hmm... Perhaps a little too fancy.
Yes. That's much too fancy.
Too old.
Too young.
It was a problem. A real problem.
Well, now that's a
bit more like it!
The most beautiful
creature on four legs.
Oh, now, if only the girl...
Well! She's very lovely, too.
It was almost too good to be true.
I'd never find another pair like
that, not if I looked for 100 years.
Ah, they're heading for the park.
A perfect meeting place,
if I could only arrange it.
Uh-oh. But Roger never
stopped work till after 5:00.
That would be too late.
After 5:00 already.
Fancy that.
All right, Pongo. All right, boy.
Pongo, boy, take it easy!
What's all the hurry?
Pongo, boy, slow down.
I was afraid we'd missed them.
Perhaps they passed on by the park.
Then suddenly, I spotted them.
It was a perfect situation
if I planned it right.
I couldn't depend on Roger.
I knew what he'd do.
He'd settle on the grass, puff
his pipe and that would be it.
No, it was all up to me.
Well...
At first I had no particular plan,
just anything to attract attention.
You know, stir things up a bit.
Pongo, you silly old
thing! Come on.
Come on, let's have it, boy.
Pongo!
For a while, it seemed to work.
At least they had seen one another.
Things were going along first-rate.
But for some strange
reason they left!
Come on, you old renegade.
We're going home.
But I wasn't giving up.
I was determined that, somehow,
they just had to meet.
- Oh!
I beg your pardon. I'm so
sorry. Please excuse me.
- I must say, what on earth!
- Oh, dear!
Oh, really. Good
heavens. Of all the...
- Oh!
- Ah!
Oh, my new spring
suit and my new hat!
I'm terribly sorry.
Please let me help you.
I'm so sorry. Pongo, you...
I don't know what's come over him.
I'm terribly sorry. He's
never acted this way before.
Never mind. Never mind.
Please, just go away.
You've done enough.
Please? Oh.
Oh, I say. Here, take mine.
Oh.
Wilt thou love her, comfort her,
honour and keep her in
sickness and in health,
and forsaking all others,
keep thee only unto her so
long as ye both shall live?
I will.
For the first six months or so,
we lived in a small
house near the park,
a modest little place,
but just right for two couples
who were just starting out.
Perdita, darling,
are you all right?
Oh, of course, dear.
After all, dogs were having
puppies long before our time.
Oh, that's Nanny, a wonderful
cook and housekeeper.
She's such a kind,
understanding soul.
You know,
at times she seems almost canine.
Roger, dear,
tea time.
Tea time!
Be down in a minute
Do you like my new song?
- Such clever lyrics.
- Melody first, my dear.
And then the lyrics, hmm?
Oh, Pongo, it's her.
It's that devil woman.
Oh, must be Cruella, your
dearly devoted old school mate.
Cruella De Vil.
That's it!
Cruella De Vil
If she doesn't scare
you no evil thing will
Oh, Roger.
To see her is to
take a sudden chill
Oh!
Cruella
She's like a spider
waiting for the kill
Roger, she'll hear you.
Look out for Cruella De Vil
Let her in, Nanny.
- Anita, darling!
- How are you?
Miserable as usual.
Perfectly wretched!
Where are they? Where are they?
For heaven sakes, where are they?
- Who, Cruella?
- The puppies! The puppies.
No time for games. Where
are the little brutes?
It'll be at least three weeks.
No rushing these things.
Anita, you're such a wit.
Here, dog, here.
Here, dog.
Cruella, isn't that a new fur coat?
My only true love, darling.
I live for furs. I worship furs!
After all, is there a woman in
this wretched world who doesn't?
Oh, I'd like a nice fur, but
there are many other things...
Sweet, simple Anita.
I know, I know!
This horrid little house
is your dream castle.
And poor Roger is your bold
and fearless Sir Galahad!
Oh, Cruella.
Then of course you have
your little spotted friends.
Oh, yes.
Yes, I must say, such
perfectly beautiful coats.
- Won't you have some tea?
- I've got to run.
Let me know when the
puppies arrive.
- You will, won't you, dear?
- Yes, Cruella.
Don't forget, it's a promise.
See you in three weeks. Cheerio.
Cheerio, darling.
Oh!
At first you think
Cruella is a devil
But after time has
worn away the shock
You come to realise
You've seen her kind of eyes
Watching you from underneath a rock
You're no help.
This vampire bat
This inhuman beast
She ought to be locked
up and never released
The world was such a
wholesome place until
Cruella
Cruella De Vil
Roger, you are an idiot!
- Perdy?
- That witch. That devil woman.
She wants our puppies.
That's all she's after.
Don't worry, Perdy.
They're on to her.
Nothing's going to
happen to our puppies.
What does she want with them?
She can't possibly love them.
Oh, Pongo.
I was so happy at
first, but now I...
Oh, I...
I wish we weren't having any.
Poor Perdita. Of course,
she had no choice.
The puppies arrived
right on schedule,
one wild and stormy
night in October.
Steady, boy.
The puppies are here!
Oh, the puppies are here!
How many?
- Eight.
- Eight?
By George, Pongo! Eight puppies.
Ten.
- Eleven.
Eleven? Eleven puppies, Pongo, boy.
Wait a minute now,
wait a minute, 13!
No, no, no. Fourteen.
- Oh, 15!
- Fifteen?
And the mother's doing fine, love.
You ducky thing, you.
Fifteen puppies?
Why, Pongo, that's marvellous!
It's fabulous!
Why, you old rascal!
Fourteen.
Just 14.
We lost one.
Oh, poor little thing.
Oh, Pongo, boy.
It's just one of those things.
And yet...
And yet I wonder.
Look, Pongo.
Anita!
Nanny. Fifteen!
We still have 15!
Oh, Roger, he's all right!
Thank heaven.
See? He's just as good as new.
Can you imagine, Roger, 15 puppies!
Fifteen. Fifteen puppies!
How marvellous.
How marvellous,
how perfectly... Ugh!
The devil take it. They're
mongrels, no spots!
No spots at all. What a
horrid little white rat.
They're not mongrels!
They'll get their spots.
Just wait and see.
That's right. They'll have
their spots in a few weeks.
Oh, well, in that case I'll take
them all. The whole litter.
Just name your price, dear.
I'm afraid we can't give them up.
- Poor Perdita, she'd be heartbroken.
- Anita, don't be ridiculous.
You can't afford to keep them.
You can scarcely afford
to feed yourselves.
I'm sure we'll get along.
Yes, I know. I know!
Roger's... Roger's songs!
Enough of this nonsense. I'll pay
you twice what they're worth.
Come now, I'm being
more than generous.
Blast this pen.
Blast this wretched,
wretched pen! Ah!
When can the puppies
leave their mother?
Two weeks? Three weeks?
Never.
- What?
- We're not selling the puppies.
Not a single one.
Do you understand?
Anita, is he serious?
I really don't know Roger.
- Cruella, he seems...
- Surely he must be joking!
No, no, no. I mean it.
You're, you're not
getting one. Not one.
And that's final.
Why, you horrid man!
You... You...
All right, keep the little
beasts for all I care.
Do as you like with them.
Drown them!
But I warn you, Anita, We're through.
I'm through with all of you!
I'll get even. Just wait.
You'll be sorry, you fools!
You idiots!
Oh, Roger! You were
magnificent, darling.
He was a bloomin' hero, ma'am!
Indeed he was. A bloomin' hero!
Perdy? Perdy, darling?
We're keeping the puppies,
every single one of them.
My ol' pet Roger, he told
that devil woman off.
He told her off, Perdy. She's gone.
- Darling, she's gone for good.
- Oh, Pongo.
- Come on, Thunderbolt.
Go get him, Thunder.
After him, boy.
He'll get that dirty
ol' horse thief.
Old Thunderbolt's the greatest
dog in the whole world.
He's even better than Dad.
No dog's better than Dad.
What's he going to do, Dad?
Shh. Shh. Let's just wait and see.
Look at him run, the old coward.
That old dirty Dawson!
The yellow-livered old skunk!
I'd like to tear his gizzard out.
Why, Patch, where did you
ever hear such talk?
Certainly not from your mother.
- Watch out, Thunder.
- Don't worry, Penny.
He'll get that yellow-livered...
Well, he'll get him, all right.
Lucky, get down. We
can't see. Get down.
Mother, make him get down.
Come on, Lucky. Down, dear.
Missed him. Missed him by a mile.
I'm hungry, mother. I'm hungry.
Now, Rolly, you've
just had your dinner.
But I am, just the same.
I'm so hungry I could
eat a whole elephant.
Shh!
There he is, behind that rock.
Oh, dear. He shot poor Thunder.
He missed him. Ol' Thunder's
pretending, I think.
See? What did I tell you?
That's one of his tricks.
Lucky, get down.
I'm hungry, Mother. I really am.
Don't miss next week's
episode. Who will triumph?
Ol' Thunder always wins!
And speaking of champions, friends,
Kanine Krunchies is the
champion of all dog biscuits.
Kanine Krunchies can't be beat
They make each meal a special treat
Happy dogs are those who eat
nutritious Kanine Krunchies
Perdy, we better get these
little nippers off to bed
if we're going for a W-A-L-K.
- We want to go, too, Mother.
- Can we, Mother?
We never get to go.
Come along, children. Bedtime.
But we're not a... bit sleepy.
We want to go for a
walk in the park.
- Dad, can we?
- Better do as your mother says.
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven,
eight, nine, 10, 11, 12, 13...
I'm not sleepy. I'm hungry.
Fourteen.
Hmm?
So do what all the smart dogs do
And you'll feel great
the whole day through
You can be a champion, too
if you eat Kanine Krunchies
Remember, friends,
just send five...
Lucky, you little rascal, let's go.
There they go, Horace, me lad,
out for their evening
constitutional.
Oh. A lovely pair of turtledoves.
Around the Johnny Horner
and off to the park.
Yeah, I don't like it, Jasper.
One more pinch and they'll
throw the keys away.
Oh, come off it, Horace. We're
getting plenty of boodle.
Yes, but I've been thinkin'.
You've been thinkin'?
I warned you about thinkin'.
I've got the knob for this
job, so let's get on with it.
Ah, nobody home but
the little ol' cook.
You just leave her to ol' Jasper.
He can handle her
real diplomatic-like.
Yeah, but I still don't like it.
Here, here. Patch, you settle down.
Oh, dear.
Go to sleep now.
Close your little eyes.
That's a good little one.
Who do you suppose?
Good evening, ma'am.
We're here to inspect the
wiring and the switches.
- We're from the gas company.
- Electric, electric.
Electric company.
But we didn't call
for any inspection.
Yes, I know. See, there's a new act
just been passed in Parliament.
Under the heading of the "Defence of the
Realm Act." Article four, section 29.
It's a law. And it's for
your own safety, ma'am.
I don't care what Parliament
Realm or whatever it is says.
You're not coming in here, not
with the Mister and Missus gone.
Oh, now. Come off it, Ducky.
We got no time to palaver.
We got a job to do. Excuse me!
What's the matter with you two?
You got cloth ears? I said
you're not coming in here!
- Oh!
- Oh-ho-ho!
She's a regular little
tartar, ain't she, Horace?
Don't you dare go up there,
you big, long-legged lummox!
Now I mean it.
If you don't get out of this house,
I'll call the police, I will.
Now be off with you,
you big weasel!
Now you've been gone and done it.
You've cut me to the quick, lady.
Why, I wouldn't stay
here if you asked me.
Not even for a cup of tea.
Oy! Horace, me lad, I've got a sneaky
suspicion we're not welcome here.
Pack up. We're leaving.
Sharp's the word and
quick's the action.
Let me out! Help!
I'll call the police. Help!
Goodnight, Ducky. Ta-ta!
Those good-for-nothing hoodlums!
Electric company. Hmph!
Nothing but common sneak thieves.
I'll bet they made off
with the good silver.
Why, I'll bet they
took every last...
The puppies!
The puppies! They're gone!
Patch? Lucky? Rolly?
Oh! They took the puppies!
Oh, whatever will I do?
Those scoundrels!
They stole the puppies.
Police? Help! The puppies.
Police! Somebody help me!
Help! Help! Help!
"Dognapping!" Tsk-tsk. Can
you imagine such a thing?
"15 puppies stolen." They
are darling little things.
Anita and her...
And her bashful Beethoven!
Pipe and all!
Oh, Roger, you are a fool!
Hello?
Jasper! Jasper, you idiot!
How dare you call here?
We don't want no more of
this, we want our boodle!
We'll settle for half!
Not one shilling 'till
the job's done.
- Jasper! Jasper!
- Do you understand?
It's in the blinkin'
papers, pictures and all!
Hang the papers! It'll
be forgotten tomorrow.
- I don't like it.
- Shut up, you idiot!
What?
Not you, miss. I mean Horace!
Why, you imbecile!
Maybe Scotland Yard.
Maybe they found something.
Hello, Inspector?
- Is Anita there?
- Who?
- Anita!
- It's for you.
- Hello?
- Anita, darling.
- Oh. Cruella.
- Oh, Anita.
What a dreadful thing.
I just saw the papers.
I couldn't believe it.
Yes, Cruella. It was quite a shock.
- Is she calling to confess?
- Roger, please!
She's a sly one.
We're doing everything possible.
- Have you called the police?
- Yes, Scotland Yard.
- But I'm afraid...
- Where are they?
You idiot!
- Anita!
- Sorry, Cruella.
Yes. If there's any news,
we'll let you know.
Thank you, Cruella.
Roger, I admit she's eccentric,
but she's not a thief.
She's still number one
suspect in my book!
She's been investigated
by Scotland Yard.
- What more do you want?
- I don't know, darling.
I don't know.
Oh, Rog. What'll we do?
What'll we do?
Perdy, I'm afraid
it's all up to us.
Oh, Pongo. Isn't there any hope?
Well, yes. There's
the twilight bark.
The twilight bark? That's
only a gossip chain.
Darling, it's the very
fastest way to send news.
If our puppies are anywhere in the
city, the London dogs will know.
We'll send the word tonight when our
pets take us for a walk in the park.
There's no one out tonight.
I'm afraid it's too cold.
We've got to keep trying, Perdy.
Perdy, we're in luck!
It's the Great Dane at Hampstead.
Pongo. Quiet, boy!
Do you want to stir up the whole
neighbourhood? Come on. Pongo.
- Perdy, come on!
- Let's go.
Pongo, you old idiot!
Come on, now. We're going home!
What is it, Danny?
Who's on the telegraph?
It's Pongo, Regent's Park!
It's an all-dog alert.
What's it all about? What's the word?
Tell me, Danny! Tell me, tell me!
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
Well, now... Hmm,
that is something.
What, Danny? What's something?
Fifteen Dalmatian puppies, stolen!
Have they called the police?
Scotland Yard?
The humans tried everything.
Now it's up to us dogs
and the twilight bark.
I'll sound the alert!
Prissy, come in here!
Coco!
Be quiet now!
Ah, shut up!
Quiet!
Will you be quiet!
Towser, what's going on?
What is it? What's all the gossip?
'Tain't no gossip, Lucy. It
be all the way from London.
- You don't say!
- Fifteen puppies stolen.
There's no puppies around here,
not since Nellie's last litter.
And they're all grown up.
Well, then, we'd best
send the word along.
It be up to me to
reach the Colonel!
He be the only one
in barking range.
You'll never reach
him at this hour!
Well, I can try!
I'll bark all night if I have to.
Hmm...
Hmm... Sounds like old Towser.
It's an alert. Sergeant!
Sergeant Tibs! I say, Sergeant!
Oh, yes, Captain!
Barking signal. It's an alert.
Report to the Colonel at once.
Yes, sir. Right-o, sir.
Right away, sir!
Colonel?
I say, Colonel!
Colonel, sir? Colonel?
- Colonel?
- What? Who goes there?
Sergeant Tibs reporting, sir.
- Tibs? Tibs? Oh, yes, Sergeant Tibs!
- Colonel, sir...
Look here, Tibs. What's the idea
of barging in at this hour?
- But Colonel...
- Hold on, Sergeant.
You hear that?
- Sounds like an alert.
- Yes, Colonel.
We'd better look into it.
Come along, on the double.
Right-o, sir.
It's old Towser down
at Withermarsh, sir.
By Jove, yes! So it is. Hmm.
Well, I'll see what he wants.
it be the Colonel.
The old boy himself!
He wants the message.
You'd better make it loud and
clear or he'll never get it.
One long howl, two short.
- One yip and a woof.
- Two yips, sir.
- What's the word, Colonel?
- It's from London.
Then it must be important.
Yes, yes, I'll get the rest of it.
Sounds like a number.
Three fives are 13...
That's 15, sir.
Fifteen, of course 15.
Yes, dot, spot, spotted puddings,
poodles...
No, no, puddles.
Puddles, sir?
Fifteen spotted puddles stolen.
Oh, balderdash.
Better double check it, Colonel.
Oh, yes, yes, I suppose I better.
Two woofs, one yip and a woof.
It sounds like puppies, sir.
Of course, puppies.
Colonel, Colonel, sir,
I just remembered.
Two nights past I heard puppy
barking over at Hell Hall.
You mean the old De Vil place?
Nonsense, Tibs! No one's
lived there for years.
Hold on! There's smoke
coming from the chimney!
By Jove, that's strange,
strange indeed.
I suppose we'd better investigate.
I'll send word for ol'
Towser to stand by.
Please stand by.
- What's he mean by that?
- I don't know.
Oh, maybe the ol' boy's
found something!
Oh, I do hope so.
They say the ol' place is haunted or
bewitched or some such fiddle-faddle.
Fiddle-faddle and rot, sir.
Just the same, use extreme caution.
No telling what sort of
hocus-pocus you might run into.
Blast it all, Tibs.
On the double, man.
- On the double.
- Yes, sir. Right away, sir.
Psst!
- Rover. Spotty.
- Hmm. What?
Are you one of the
15 stolen puppies?
No, we're not stolen.
We're bought and paid for.
There's 99 of us all together.
Ninety-nine!
How 'bout that bunch
of little ones?
They have names and collars.
They're not from the pet shops.
- Fifteen of 'em.
- We never counted them.
They're over there by the TV.
- I'd better count 'em.
- Watch out for the Baduns.
Baduns?
Those two blokes,
Horace and Jasper.
They're mean ones, they are.
Hey, look, Horace!
Watch me pot His Lordship
smack on the conk.
How's that for calling 'em, eh?
One, two,
- three, four, five, six...
- Hey, Jasper.
Come on, now, give us a swig,
just a short one.
Now, Horace, this hogwash ain't fit
for a fancy bloke like yourself.
Besides, you'd get crumbs
in it, you cabbage head!
All right.
Guzzle the whole works. I hope it
gives you collywobbles, that's what.
Hey, Jasper. Did you...
Let me see. Six, seven,
eight, nine, 10, 11...
Hey, get down, you runt!
And stay down!
Go on, get out of here
or I'll black your other peeper.
Where was I? Nine...
Nine, three more.
Twelve and... One,
two, three. That's 15!
They're the ones!
Blimey!
What the...
Horace, look what
we got! A tabby cat!
How'd you like a tabby cat stew?
Or a cat casserole?
À la mode.
- What is it, Pongo? What is it?
- Shh. It's the Great Dane.
He has news for us. He'll
meet us at Primrose Hill.
- How'll we get out?
- Uh, the back bedroom window.
It's always open a
wee bit. Come on.
Pongos, you've made it. Good.
- What's the word? What's the news?
- Have they found our puppies?
They've been located
somewhere north of here,
- in Suffolk.
- Oh, thank heaven.
- Can you leave tonight?
- We can leave right away.
I'll go along as far as Camden
Road and give you instructions.
When you reach Withermarsh,
contact old Towser.
He'll direct you to the Colonel
and the Colonel will take you
to your puppies at
the De Vil place.
- De Vil!
- The De Vil place!
Oh, Pongo, it was her!
Oh, someone you know?
Sorry, sir. There's
no time to explain.
Oh, I hope we're not too late.
Good luck, Pongos.
If you lose your way,
contact the barking chain.
They'll be standing by!
Any news, Colonel?
Not a blasted thing.
They're lost or captured,
or something or other.
- Who knows what.
- Colonel, here comes a car.
Come now, Tibs.
Don't be ridiculous.
- They wouldn't be driving.
- Yes, I know, sir.
But it's heading for Hell Hall.
It's stopping at the gate!
It is? Blast it all!
Better see what's up.
- On the double, man. On the double!
- Yes, sir.
Take over, Captain.
Right-o, sir.
I'm sorry, Mr Simpkins.
The answer's no, no, no.
Six down, four to go.
I've got no time to argue.
It's got to be done tonight.
It must be a yes or no
question, Inspector.
Do you understand? Tonight!
But they ain't big enough.
You couldn't get half a dozen
coats out of the whole caboodle.
Coats! Dog-skin coats?
Then we'll settle for half
a dozen! We can't wait.
The police are everywhere.
I want the job done tonight!
How're we gonna do it?
Any way you like. Poison
them, drown them.
Bash them in the head.
You got any chloroform?
- Not a drop.
- And no ether, ei-ther.
Eye-ther!
I don't care how you kill the little
beasts, but do it, and do it now!
Aw, please, miss. Have pity.
Can't we see the rest
of the show first?
We want to see What's My Crime?
Listen, you idiots!
I'll be back in the morning.
The job better be done,
or I'll call the police!
Do you understand?
I think she means it.
Ah... We'll get on with it,
as soon as the show's over.
Will you please sign in, sir?
You'd better get out of here if
you want to save your skins.
- But how?
- Shh.
There's a hole in the
wall there by the door.
Come on, shake a leg.
Psst! Kids, follow me.
Hey, Jasper, look!
It's old Meathead.
Yeah, what do you know,
old Meathead Fauncewater.
Come on, don't crowd.
One at a time. One at a time!
For our last contestant,
meet Mr Percival Fauncewater.
If the panel fails to guess your
unusual crime in ten questions,
you will receive two weeks
vacation at a seaside resort,
all expenses paid.
That is, after you've paid
your debt to society.
Who will take the first
question? Inspector?
Mr Fauncewater, could your
crime be classified as larceny?
- A theft, burglary?
- Straighten out!
Form a queue, along the wall.
Come on. Snap it up, faster.
Mr Fauncewater is a burglar
by trade, but in this case,
his crime was not burglary.
I'm sorry, the answer's no. One
down, nine to go. Miss Birdwell?
If your crime wasn't
robbery, did you,
oh, dear, what I mean is,
do something of a violent
nature, that is...
Come, Miss Birdwell, we're
running short of time.
So sorry. Did you do someone in?
No, Miss Birdwell, I'm sorry.
The answer is no.
Two down, eight to go.
- Mr Simpkins?
- Psst!
Hey, kid, let's go.
Could it be a violation
of a city ordinance?
Uh, no. The answer is...
Hey, get out of the
way, you little runt!
Three down, seven to go. Inspector?
Very confusing, I must say.
Surely, this crime could...
I'm terribly sorry.
We've run out of time.
Ain't that always the way!
Would it be possible
for Mr Fauncewater
to come back next week?
Then we could finish
our little game.
Good night, audience. See you
next week at this same time
on What's My Crime?
Ah. Oh, well.
Come on, Horace.
Let's get on with it.
I'll pop 'em on the head,
you do the skinnin'.
No, you don't, Jasper!
I'll pop 'em off and
you do the skinnin'.
Horace, look!
They're gone. They flew the coop,
right out through this hole.
Here, grab a torch.
We'll run 'em down before you
can say "Bob's your uncle."
There they go, Horace,
up the stairs.
Here, puppies.
Here, puppies! Come on now.
Don't go hiding from
ol' Uncle Jasper.
Oh, I ain't gonna hurt ya.
I thought we was gonna pop 'em off.
Shh! Shut up.
Take a squint in there. I'll
check these other two rooms.
Here, puppies.
Puppies, come on out. Come
out wherever you are.
Horace! Ooh!
It's that mangy tabby cat!
He's the ringleader!
Head 'em off, Horace! Head 'em...
You bungling blockhead!
Back here! Back here!
Shh! Here they come.
Double-crossin' little twerps,
pulling a snitch on us!
After we took care of 'em.
There's gratitude for you.
It ain't fair, Jasper.
Horace, there they go!
Sergeant? I say, Sergeant.
No time to explain. Busy, sir.
Shut that door, Horace!
We'll close in on 'em. Enough
of this Ring Around the Rosy.
Oh, Pongo, I'm afraid we're lost.
It can't be far.
By Jove! It can't be the Pongos.
It's the Colonel. This way.
Colonel? Are you the Colonel?
Oh, Pingo! Pongo?
Our puppies, are they all right?
No time to explain.
There's trouble.
A big hullabaloo. Come along!
Follow me!
Now we've got 'em, Horace.
They've run out of room.
What have we got here?
A couple of spotted hyenas?
Come on, Horace. Give 'em what for.
I'm right behind ya, lad.
Oh!
You clumsy clod!
Hey! I'll knock the
spots off you. Let go!
Let go!
Well, by George!
You mangy mongrel!
I'll knock your blinkin' block off.
Blast 'em, Tibs. Give 'em what for.
No, Colonel. Retreat, retreat!
Yes. Yes, of course. Retreat!
Retreat, on the double!
Help, Jasper! Get me out of here!
Horace, they're fighting dirty!
Oh!
Jasper!
Horace!
Come on, Perdy. Let's go.
I'll skin every one of
them spotted hyenas
if it's the last thing I do.
Dad! Mother!
- I missed you, Mommy.
- Here we are, Mommy.
Oh, my darlings, my darlings!
How'd you find us, Dad?
Lucky, Patch, Pepper!
Hi, Freckles.
Oh, Daddy.
And Rolly, you rascal!
Did you bring me anything to eat?
Everybody here? All 15?
Twice that many, Dad.
Now there's 99 of us!
What? Ninety-nine?
Where did they all come from?
What would she want with so many?
She's gonna make coats out of us.
- She couldn't!
- That's right, dog-skin coats.
Oh, dog-skin coats! Come now, Tibs!
But it's true, sir.
Horace and Jasper were gonna
pop us off and skin us!
She's a devil, a witch!
What'll we do?
We have to get back
to London somehow.
What about the others?
What'll they do?
Perdy, we'll take them
home with us, all of them.
Our pets would never turn them out.
Colonel, sir, lights on the road.
It's a truck headin' this way.
It's the Baduns, Horace and Jasper.
They're following our tracks.
We've got 'em outnumbered, Tibs.
When I give the
signal, we'll attack.
Colonel, sir, I'm afraid
that would be disastrous.
Oh, you think so?
He's right. We'd better run for it.
Out the back way,
across the pasture.
Thank you, Sergeant,
Colonel, Captain.
- Bless you all.
- How can we ever repay you?
Nothing at all. All
in the line of duty.
That's right, sir, routine.
Better be off. Here they come.
Come on, kids, hurry.
- Good luck, Pongos.
- And never fear.
We'll hold them off
'til the bitter end.
Now, what's this?
Out of my way,
you barkin' haystack.
Or I'll knock your
blinkin' block off!
They ain't in here, Jasper.
They're hiding in the hay.
Give me a match.
We'll burn 'em out.
Ready, Captain. Aim.
Fire one.
Fire two.
Hey, there they go,
the little sneaks.
Come on, back to the truck.
We'll head 'em off in half a mile.
They gotta be around
here somewhere.
- I've been thinkin'.
- Now, Horace.
What if they went down
the froze-up creek,
so's not to leave their tracks?
Horace, you idiot!
Dogs ain't that smart.
All clear, Perdy.
- All clear.
- We gave 'em the slip! Didn't we, Dad?
They didn't even see us, Patch!
Shh, children. Children, shh.
My feet are slippery.
I wish we could walk on the snow.
No, son, we can't leave tracks.
Well, any sign of them?
Not so much as one
bloomin' footprint.
And we've been up and down
every road in the county.
We're froze stiff. We're givin' up.
Oh, no, you don't!
We'll find the little mongrels
if it takes till next Christmas.
Now get going! Watch your driving,
you imbeciles! Do you wanna
get nabbed by the police?
Ninety-three,
94, 95, 96,
97,
98...
Oh, Lucky!
Come on, Lucky, boy.
We can't give up now.
I'm tired and I'm hungry
and my tail's froze,
and my nose is froze
and my ears are froze.
And my toes are froze.
Pongo!
Pongo! Pongo!
We'd just about lost hope.
We have shelter for you,
at the dairy barn across the road.
Oh, thank goodness.
Perdy! Perdy!
This way, Perdy.
- The dairy barn across the road.
- Come on, kids.
It's not far. Come on,
this way. Follow the collie.
Just look, Queenie.
- Have you ever seen so many puppies?
- Aren't they adorable!
- Perfectly darling.
- The poor little dears.
They're completely worn
out and half frozen!
They all here, Pongo?
Yes, dear. All 99 accounted for.
The famous Pongos. We were
so worried about you.
Been trying to reach you.
Afraid you'd been captured.
How did you make it all this way?
- And in such dreadful weather.
- With all those little ones.
I'm hungry, Mother. I'm hungry.
- I'm hungry, too.
- Mother, we're hungry.
- We're all hungry.
- I'm sorry, children.
Do they like warm milk? It's fresh.
- Where is it?
- Where is the milk?
Come and get it, kids.
It's on the house.
This way, children.
Around this way.
Don't crowd. You'll
have to take turns.
Rolly, wait your turn, dear.
Don't worry, kids.
There's plenty for all.
Ooh! The little darlings.
Pongo, a few scraps I saved
- for you and the missus.
- Oh, thank you.
It's not much, but it might
hold you as far as Dinsford.
Huh? Dinsford?
There's a Labrador there.
His pet is a grocer.
Oh, I'm terribly sorry.
Quite all right.
Get some rest and don't worry.
I'll be standing watch.
I don't know what
we'd have done if...
- We're very honoured to be of service.
- We're only sorry we can't do more.
Anyone who would think of hurting
these dear little puppies...
- Shh! Duchess!
- They're so dear.
I wish they could stay
with us for always.
Princess, shh! Quiet, everyone.
Let them sleep, the poor things.
They're so exhausted and they
still have such a long way to go.
Hurry, kids. Hurry!
Well now, what have we here?
Well, so they thought they
could outwit Cruella.
Jasper! Horace!
Here's their tracks heading
straight for the village.
Blimey! Oh, it's them, all right.
Work your way south on the side
roads. I'll take the main road.
See you in Dinsford!
Pongo, I've got a
ride home for you.
A ride home? Perdy,
did you hear that?
For all of us?
You mean we don't have
to walk any more?
If we can manage it.
Come on. We'd better hurry.
We've got a ride home!
Come on, children.
See the van down the street?
It's going to London as soon
as the engine's repaired.
And there's room for all of you.
Pongo, there's Cruella.
Yes,
and Jasper and Horace.
Pongo, how will we get to the van?
I don't know, Perdy.
But somehow we've got to.
Mother, Dad,
- Patch pushed me in the fireplace.
- Lucky pushed me first.
- Did not. Did not.
- Did, too. Did, too.
Did not!
- Please, children, don't quarrel.
- Say...
Perdy, I've got an idea.
Pongo, what on earth...
Look, I'm a Labrador!
We'll all roll in soot.
We'll be Labradors.
Say, that is an idea!
Come on, kids! Roll in the soot.
You mean, you want us to get dirty?
Did you hear that, Freckles?
Dad wants us to get dirty.
- Mother, should we?
- Do as your father says.
- This'll be fun.
- I always wanted to get good and dirty.
That's the stuff. The
blacker the better.
- I'm ready.
- Me, too.
How's this, Dad?
Wait. That's enough. Not
too many at a time.
Uh-oh. Rolly, hold on.
You're only half done.
Now, stay right with me.
We're gonna fool the ol' mad lady.
Pongo.
I'm so afraid.
Look, Jasper.
Do you suppose they
disguised themselves?
Say now, Horace. That's
just what they did.
Dogs is always painting
theirselves black!
You idiot!
Well, so far so good.
Come on, Perdy. Better
get on your make-up.
I'll go ahead with the next bunch.
Jasper! Horace!
- Well?
- Aw, now be reasonable, miss.
We're froze clean to our bones.
We've been out all night and
all day, with nothin' to eat.
They're somewhere in this village,
and we're going to find them.
Now get swing!
Do you think they've seen us?
No, but we're running out of time.
Try 'er again, mate.
Hurry, Perdy. The
van's about to leave.
Better hurry.
I'll get the rest.
That ought to do her. She'll
get you back to London.
Better get aboard, miss.
Hey, Jasper.
Come on, Horace.
Hurry, kids!
Come on, kids. Run on ahead.
- She's watching us, Dad.
- Keep going.
It can't be!
It's impossible!
Run for it!
Jasper! Horace!
Jasper!
There they go! In the van.
After them! After them!
Pongo! There she is, Cruella.
Hey, lady, what in thunder
are you tryin' to do?
Crazy woman driver!
Pongo, look!
Jasper!
Ain't nothin' to it.
I'll give him a nudge
and shove him in the dirt.
Perdy, watch out!
- Jasper!
- Horace!
You idiots!
You fools!
You imbeciles!
Ah, shut up!
You've seen her kind of eyes
Watching you from underneath a rock
Cruella De Vil
Cruella De
Roger, after all, that's
your first big hit.
It's made more money
than we ever dreamed of.
Yes, I know.
I still can't believe that Pongo
and Perdy would run away.
Here's a bit of Christmas
cheer for you,
if there's anything
to be cheerful about.
Oh, the dear little things.
Sometimes at night I
can hear them barking.
But it always turns
out I'm dreaming.
Roger, what on earth...
They're Labradors!
No, no. They're covered with soot.
Look, here's Lucky!
Pongo, boy, is that you?
Oh, Pongo, Pongo!
Ho-ho, it's Pongo!
And Perdy, my darling.
And Patch, and Rolly,
and Penny, and Freckles.
They're all here, the little dears.
- It's a miracle!
- What a wonderful Christmas present!
And look, there's a whole lot more!
Look, Anita, puppies everywhere.
There must be 100!
One, two, three and four, is seven.
Two, four, six, and three
is nine, plus two is 11.
- Thirty-six over here.
- Thirty-six and 11, that's 47!
- Eighteen, Roger.
- That's 65!
Ten, 11, 12, 13!
Wait a minute, six more.
Let's see, that's 84.
And 15 plus two, 101!
A hundred and one? Where
did they come from?
Oh, Pongo, you old rascal!
- What'll we do with them?
- We'll keep 'em.
- In this little house?
- We'll buy a big place in the country.
We'll have a plantation,
a Dalmatian plantation.
Roger, that's truly an inspiration.
It'll be a sensation!
We'll have a Dalmatian plantation.
A Dalmatian plantation, I say.
We'll have a dalmatian plantation
Where our population can roam
- I'm hungry, mother.
- In this new location
Our whole aggregation
Will love our plantation home
Dalmatian plantation home