Resync: Xenzai[NEF]
RETAIL Sub
I say there ain't no monster!
But we need men,
and just to treat you fair
and square,
we're payin' double wages
and a bonus
from Frisco to Shanghai
and back, all found.
All dead, you mean,
Don't sign with him,
mates.
You can't buy off the monster
with double wages and a bonus.
You'll never get back to Frisco
to collect your pay.
I got a man here that sailed
on the Golden Arrow
and lived
to tell about it.
Come on, Billy.
Tell 'em
what you saw, Bill.
It was the monster,
all right.
A cable's length long
from beak to tail.
And it came a-bellerin'
out of the night
with one big eye
like a lighthouse.
Whoosh,
We was throwed into starboard,
Ka-rumph,
We were smashed to port.
And then...
it come up at midships
and broke our backs
and sunk us --
40 poor sailor men
drowned dead.
The point is,
this thing is a ship killer!
And it's a miracle
old Billy's alive today.
Tell 'em about its teeth, Billy.
As big as a mainsail,
I swear it.
And its breath --
Ooh, its breath was like
a furnace!
Ooh, you got a pretty strong
breath yourself,
my easy-talkin' friend.
You mind answering
a few questions?
I'm a harpooner by trade,
and monsters interest me --
all kinds.
Keep away from him,
you noisy sea lawyer!
Just want to smell his breath.
I can already smell yours.
Phew!
Boiled down
for his oils, lads,
there'd be free grog
for all hands!
If we could swallow it
on top of his --
There! There they are!
- Here!
- Come on,
Stop it!
Come on, Casey.
This is no place
for a clergyman's son.
Hey!
Hey, Daphne, come on,
Let's shove off!
- Oh,
Hey! What are you guys doin'
to me?!
Don't bother unloading.
Sailing's been canceled.
Canceled again?
This is ridiculous.
We'll see about this.
Driver, you wait here.
Yes, sir.
Is it true about the sailing
being canceled?
Unfortunately, yes,
Professor Aronnax.
The crew deserted
this morning.
But we just have to get
to Saigon.
Isn't there
some other ship?
Not a thing.
I'm sorry.
Next.
Halfway around the world
from Paris,
and --
and now this happens.
There's nothing we can do
about it.
No.
Except pack and unpack.
It's all I've been doing now
for a month.
Oh, professor?
At any rate, San Francisco
will have the honor
of your company
a while longer.
I'm from The Bulletin.
These gentlemen are from
The Globe and The Post.
- How do you do?
- Gentlemen.
We're interested in
your opinion of this monster.
My opinion?
Frankly, it's rather low
at the moment.
But actually, gentlemen,
I don't know any more
about it than you do.
Oh, professor...
uh, just a moment.
Yes?
Professor, what does
the National Museum in Paris
think about it?
I cannot answer that.
Professor, we heard this,
uh, expedition of yours
was to gather facts
about the monster.
I'm afraid
you were misinformed.
My reasons for going to the
Orient are purely scientific --
if I ever get there.
Professor,
doesn't the giant narwhal
reach a length of 80 feet?
Why don't you ask
a fish?
If we could go deep enough,
we'd all be surprised
at the creatures down there.
Well, could such a creature
destroy a ship
or drag it under?
Well, it might
if it were big enough.
Don't you print that.
Please be careful,
professor.
Well, gentlemen, I shall
prepare a statement later.
You do not deny, then, that
such a monster could exist.
ls that correct?
I'm not denying
anything.
Are you sure?
Hey, what are you
drawing there?
A sketch of the monster.
Thank you, professor.
- Good day.
- Back to the hotel, driver.
- Yes, sir.
- Good day, sir.
Now put the wings on it.
Look what they've done
to me.
I made no such claims
as these.
Look at this drawing.
I knew it.
"Living horrors of the deep
were described today
by Professor Aronnax
of the Paris National Museum."
Why, this is the most
far-fetched nonsense yet.
Far-fetched?
I think the proportions are
about right on the monster.
Hmm?
You're not serious,
professor?
Oh, I don't mean flying off
with a ship in its mouth.
But the general size...
You know,
come to think of it,
it is a rather interesting
conception.
Excuse me,
Professor Aronnax.
Oh, no.
No more reporters.
You've done damage enough.
Professor is very busy now.
But I'm not a reporter.
I represent
the United States government.
United States government?
May I come in?
Will he come in?
Of course, sir.
Uh, please do come in,
Mr. Howard.
- Of course.
- Thank you.
I'll be brief,
professor.
I understand that your
destination is the Orient
and that you've been delayed.
What would you say
if we could get you there,
but by a roundabout route,
a cruise of three or four months
through the South Seas?
Would you accept?
Well, uh, I would be interested,
yes, naturally.
Uh, sit down.
Thank you.
I can see no reason
why you and your apprentice
shouldn't consider yourselves
guests of the United States
government
until we can set you ashore
at Saigon, do you?
May I ask, uh, why have you
honored the professor this way?
Well, I think
the honor is ours.
As the foremost authority
on the sea and its mysteries,
you can be
an excellent observer.
Your observations will greatly
influence public opinion,
and we can either confirm
or deny certain rumors.
I knew it --
concerns the monster.
ls that true?
Very much so.
And according to the papers,
you seem to believe
the rumors, professor.
Oh, no. The professor has been
misquoted outrageously.
Yes, I'm afraid
I was misquoted.
However, I have an open mind
on the subject.
All the better.
Your reports would be unbiased.
You see, other nations
besides ours
are forming expeditions,
but I like to think
ours has the advantage
if for no other reason than
you might consent to join us.
Well, it's, uh, very kind
of you, uh...
We accept.
Good.
And now, professor,
if you don't mind,
I'd like you to come downstairs
and meet Captain Farragut.
He's in command of the warship
upon which you're sailing.
And I might add that he has
some rather strong ideas
on the subject of sea monsters.
You mean that his mind
is not open?
Most emphatically not.
We headed south,
and excitement ran high.
Every man aboard was
on the lookout,
and the watch was kept
day and night.
Regardless of his own feelings
in the matter,
Captain Farragut left nothing
to chance.
With traditional thoroughness,
the Navy plan was to cut
the South Pacific into squares
and search each square.
For the first month,
we steamed in circles,
crossing and recrossing
our course.
There was no sign
of our quarry.
False alarms were common,
and they didn't help
our morale.
Blow!
Off the weather bow!
For endless days and nights,
we scoured the South Pacific.
Our hopes began to wane.
It came as no surprise
when Captain Farragut,
on the night
of December 8, 1868,
summoned us to the wardroom.
Gentlemen, I believe
my obligation to this legend
has been dispatched.
I offer these charts
in evidence.
They represent
an accurate record
of 3 1/2 months cruising
under steam
in search of a sea monster.
In my considered opinion,
no such monster exists
or ever did.
Are you abandoning
the search?
There's no other choice,
professor.
If we've gained
nothing else,
we can at least give
the lie to those rumors
and make the newspapers
retract their exaggerations.
It doesn't seem to me
we have proved anything
one way or the other, Captain.
Well, I don't feel justified
in wasting further time.
My decision stands.
We'll set you ashore in Saigon.
Gentlemen.
Cheer up, professor.
You'll forget all about fishing
when you see the gals in Saigon.
I thought
they promised you a bonus
if you harpooned
this monster, Mr. Land.
Ah, knowing full well
I couldn't collect it.
When I get back,
I'm shippin' out on the first
whaler that'll take me.
I won't get rich,
but I won't be sitting around,
picking my teeth
with my harpoon.
Maybe we are lucky.
It might have sunk us.
You scare me.
Be a good loser, professor.
The fish that got away is
always the biggest one.
What a pity, professor.
I know you had visions
of that monster
mounted in the National Museum.
There was Harpoon Hannah.
Had a face
that made you shudder,
lips like fishhooks...
And a nose just like a rudder.
Ahoy!
Ship off the starboard bow!
Hard over!
Head for that ship!
First mate, pipe all hands
to rescue stations.
Aye, aye, sir.
All hands to rescue stations!
I'm thinkin' she went down
with all hands.
Poor devils.
Not a living soul left.
What could have caused
such a fearsome explosion?
Black powder and worse --
a whole shipload of the stuff.
What could've
set it off, though?
She must've struck something.
Or could it be that
something struck the ship?
Huh? What do you mean
something struck her?
You're meanin' the monster,
ain't ya, mate?
Aye, it might be the monster,
all right!
The monster?!
I've seen more monsters
in my Aunt Gussie's fishbowl
than on this whole cruise!
- Sure, it's the monster!
- It is the monster!
Pipe down on deck!
I must insist, professor,
that you keep these
fish stories to yourself.
On deck! Floating object
off the larboard quarter!
There's the monster!
Drummer boy,
beat to general quarters.
Set compressors and prime!
Look alive, there!
Get your range
and fire, Carson,
What's the matter?
She's showing us
her heel, sir!
Well, hit her in the heels,
then, Fire!
Aye, aye, sir.
Run her out smartly!
We hit her, sir!
She's turnin',
She's turnin' around,
Mr. Land,
into the longboat with you,
Stand by to lower away.
Professor...hang on,
Hang on,
Hey! Don't leave us!
Help!
They are the same.
They cannot help.
But they must!
Help!
Can you see anything --
anything at all?
No.
Wait till this fog lifts.
I'm getting numb
all over.
Look, professor.
T-There's something over there.
What is it?
I don't know.
It -- It looks
like the monster.
I don't care what it is,
as long as it floats.
Who could have conceived
such a miracle?
A submarine boat.
You mean
a submerging boat?
But this is incredible.
Men have dreamed
about such miracles.
You know something?
I, I don't like this at all.
Ahoy!
Is anyone aboard?
It...It seems deserted.
I think we are asking
for trouble, professor.
Why don't we wait?
Maybe -- Maybe somebody
will come up.
No. If we wait, this thing is
liable to sink under us.
Huh?
It's quite able to,
you know.
Hello?
ls anyone down there?
Why...
it's as bright as day,
and it isn't oil or gas,
either.
There is great genius
behind all this.
Yes, and great evil.
Don't forget this --
this is an agent of destruction.
Hello?
Ahoy! Anybody there?
Ahoy, there!
Is anybody aboard?
Did you hear that,
professor?
Somebody's calling
from the outside.
Come on,
Wait.
Look at this.
Give me a hand
with this line, mate.
Grab this oar.
Why, Ned, it's you,
Well, I'll be.
Anybody else get off?
Yes. The professor is
down below.
Well, he really got
his monster, didn't he?
You know,
the ship seems deserted,
but I have a feeling
not for too long, and...
and personally, I'm in no mood
to meet the owners.
I'm not anxious to get
in their company myself.
I'll take my chances
in the open sea,
if it's all the same
with you.
My sentiment exactly.
Let me call the professor.
Here. Give me a hand first.
Grab that oar.
We got to flop this over.
Hold it.
Well, I'll be.
I've never seen a barge
like this before.
Hey, this looks
like the galley.
Cook's day off, too.
Let me call
the professor.
Professor?
Can you hear me?
Profess--
Professor, where are you?
Hello. I, I'm in here.
Where?
I...didn't think
I'd ever see you again.
What is it?
Burial ceremony...
under the sea.
You know, Ned Land is here
with a boat.
Yes, yes.
That tall one must be
the leader.
They -- They'll be coming back
any moment!
Go on,
Get away!
Help!
Search the boat.
Aye, sir.
Come with me.
Take him,
Sink that longboat!
All right.
Mind your shovin', mate.
You are from the warship
that attacked me, are you not?
Yes.
We were under the impression
that this was a monster,
not a craft
of human invention.
This is Ned Land,
master harpooner;
my apprentice, Conseil;
and I am Pierre Aronnax
of the Paris National Museum.
Professor Aronnax.
I've heard of you
and studied your writings.
It is fortunate that your
background differs slightly
from that of your companions
in crime.
You may remain.
Take the others on deck.
Wait a minute!
What do you want to do
with us on deck?
I did not invite you here.
You came as an enemy
to destroy me.
But that is not true.
They've done no harm.
Look, don't blame us
because the warship shelled you.
I demand a fair trial,
You've had your trial.
The sea brought you.
The sea shall have you back.
Mind your shovin',
Easy, mate!
But you cannot do this!
This is not civilized,
I'm not what is called
a civilized man, professor.
I have done with society
for reasons that seem good
to me.
Therefore,
I do not obey its laws.
But I am as guilty
as they are!
But...
I will grant you that both
of them and me, too,
enlisted to track down what we
thought to be a monster,
but in that case,
we are no more guilty
than the rest of the world.
I would consider that
guilty enough.
You have a great deal
to learn, professor.
Your book is brilliant...
but it lacks scope.
You have carried your work
as far as terrestrial
science permits.
The real story
of the ocean depths
begins
where you left off --
wonders that defy my powers
of description...
The secrets
that are mine alone...
but which I would be willing
to share with you.
At the expense
of my companions' lives?
I'm sorry.
You would have to choose
between them and me.
Then I cannot accept.
Professor,
I regret your choice.
Take him up...
and secure for sea.
Aye, sir.
But...
All stations ready.
Prepare for diving.
Yes, sir.
All stations ready.
Prepare for diving.
Ahead slow.
What's he up to,
professor?
I don't know.
- Trim your forward ballast.
Three degrees down.
All engines stop.
Service and stand by.
Pick up those two men
in the water.
Aye, sir.
What about the other one?
Take them all below
and confine them to quarters.
I found out
what I wanted to know.
Esmay.
There.
Now kiss.
Now off you go.
Off you go, Esmay.
Come in, gentlemen.
Be seated, please.
Thank you.
Professor.
You may serve them.
Your clothes are being dried
and will be returned
to you shortly.
In the meantime,
avail yourselves
of my humble hospitality.
"Humble," he calls it.
Hey, you do right well
for yourself, mate.
You may call me
Captain Nemo.
I'd like to express
our gratitude, Captain.
We are grateful
to be alive.
I want none
of your gratitude.
You're all under
strictest probation,
and I'd advise you
not to attempt escape.
You understand
your position?
Well, I don't know,
Captain.
Prisoner has a right
to escape, hasn't he?
That is correct.
And a guest
don't need to.
Say, I guess that makes us
a little bit of both, huh?
Ha ha ha --
Consider that a fortunate
compromise, then, Mr. Land.
I tolerate no guests
aboard The Nautilus,
and you already know
the fate of prisoners.
The food is delicious,
isn't it, professor?
Oh, very good.
Never tasted better.
There's a fork
on your left, Mr. Land --
or aren't you accustomed
to utensils?
I'm indifferent to 'em.
May I ask how you are able
to set such a table as this,
Captain?
These dishes come entirely
from my ocean kitchen.
There is nothing here
of the Earth.
How remarkable.
This tastes like veal.
The flavor deceives you.
That is fillet of sea snake.
Hmm?
I suppose
this isn't lamb, then.
That is brisket of blowfish
with sea squid dressing,
basted in barnacles.
It's very good.
In fact,
it's better than lamb.
Yes, my cook excels in preparing
these various products.
You're not finished,
are you?
Well, uh,
just the main course.
Uh, pass the cream,
mate, huh?
The cream is, of course, milk
from the giant sperm whale.
And those delicious fruits
you are eating
are actually preserves
made from sea cucumbers.
Well, I'd never
have guessed it.
They are excellent.
Eat your pudding, Mr. Land.
I ain't sure it's puddin'.
What is it?
It's my own recipe --
saute of unborn octopus.
Nothin' here's fit to eat.
Saute of unborn octopus.
Since we are nearing
the island of Crespo,
you will have an opportunity
of selecting your own food.
Y-You mean we're gettin' off
this submarine?
For a brief
hunting expedition.
Well, that --
that suits me fine.
Me too.
When do we start, mate --
uh, Captain?
Almost immediately.
These two will join
the expedition.
Will you prepare them?
Aye, sir.
Accept one of these cigars,
professor.
Thank you.
Delightful smoke.
Different somehow.
Havana?
Seaweed.
Well, I cannot accuse you
of not making us
comfortable, Captain.
In a way, though, I feel
like a condemned man
who has eaten
his last dinner.
And a very good one, too.
Thank you.
Uh, I am still curious
as to the reason
you spared our lives.
In your case,
I wanted to test your loyalty
to your companions.
I may have use for such
misplaced devotion.
Misplaced?
It comforts me to know
that your life was not
too dear a price to pay
for love
of your fellow man.
I'm afraid
I don't understand.
At the moment,
I don't intend that you should.
But I may have use for you.
And until I make up my mind,
you should find
ample diversion here.
You have literature,
art treasures,
my collections,
and even music if you so desire.
Ah.
We're almost at the island
of Crespo.
All this was once an island.
Although it has now sunk,
it is nonetheless fertile.
We do our hunting
and farming here.
Underwater?
The sea supplies
all my wants.
Fine way to go huntin'.
I knew there'd be a catch
to this.
Seems you can't do anything
on this boat
without getting wet.
Hey, I feel like I'm keepin'
a fish out of work.
Ha ha ha ha!
Hey, wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
Where you goin' with this?
Hey, what are you gonna
do with that, huh?
An expedition
from The Nautilus.
The pair you see trying to
keep pace are your companions.
It's a new experience
for them.
They'll learn quickly.
Would you like
to join them?
Indeed, yes.
I, I would like to meet
these wonders face-to-face.
Very well.
I'll introduce them to you.
A strange twilight world
opened up before me,
and I felt as the first man
to set foot on another planet,
an intruder in this mystic
garden of the deep.
Captain Nemo and I
were not alone.
There were hunters and farmers
from the submarine,
gathering a harvest
at the bottom of the sea.
I could only marvel
at his ingenuity
and envy him his rule over this
forgotten reach of nature.
Here, in abundance,
were various substances
necessary to sustain life --
an underwater larder
filled to overflowing,
and all Captain Nemo's
for the taking.
If I hadn't seen it
with my own eyes,
I wouldn't have
believed it.
Hey, Captain. Captain,
we left a treasure out there --
a whole chest of gold,
silver, and diamonds.
You were sent to get food,
not treasure.
You can't eat
pieces of eight.
Eat? I can eat anytime.
You place an absurd value
on the cheapest
of human commodities.
Aboard The Nautilus, we use such
baubles for ballast.
Ballast?
Well, I could sure
lighten this ship.
The greatest treasures
of all, Mr. Land,
are a sound mind
and a full belly.
Henceforth,
when you're sent for food,
don't stoop to pick up
pennies.
You've been pickin' 'em up,
and picking 'em up good --
"ballast."
Ned, you forget yourself.
Don't try my patience,
Mr. Land.
Rather than watch
your every move,
I know a much easier
solution to the problem.
Cryin' waste!
Ohhhh.
Ned, the professor
wants to see you.
Yeah?
Close the door, please.
Don't think for a minute
that was an empty threat
he made.
You are going to get us
all killed
if you keep on
antagonizing him.
Look at the trouble you got
into wandering off that way.
Why did you do it?
Ask him.
He went with me.
That was
scientific interest.
I, I had no idea
he was after treasure.
Oh, no?
Stop it!
You even helped carry
the chest out, you liar.
We mustn't quarrel
among ourselves.
We must stay together.
It's our only chance.
Chance? For what?
Oh, I know what you want,
professor.
This crazy iron skillet's
turned your head.
You want to play
a waitin' game,
hoping to learn
ol' Nemo's secrets.
Well, I believe we owe
the world that much, Ned.
Have you a better plan?
Yeah --
I want to get off.
Of course, I don't mind goin'
with my pockets full.
I can't believe
you could be so foolish.
Why not? He's got
a king's ransom aboard here.
And don't call it stealin',
because that's the way
he got it.
If we could take this thing
over, we'd be rich.
I'd have a ship of me own,
and you wouldn't have
to be starvin' along
on a professor's pay.
Don't look at me with
those soft-boiled eggs.
I caught the glint of gold in
them when that chest busted.
Ned, listen to me.
I want you
to forget this idea
and promise me that you won't
start anything on your own.
I won't promise that,
professor.
But at least
try my way first.
I know I can win
the captain's confidence,
but I need time
and I need your help.
Can I count on you?
All right.
Well,
I'll go this far --
I won't try
any one-man mutiny...yet.
It is the best way.
Believe me.
There's one thing
you oughta know, professor --
Nemo's cracked.
I have yet to see the day
you can make a deal
with a mad dog.
So while
you're feedin' him sugar,
I'll be figurin' a plan
to muzzle him.
Fool.
He simply cannot grasp
the significance of all this.
Here we are within reach
of the most fabulous discoveries
of all time,
and he patters of gold,
escape, trivialities, nonsense.
Well, that depends upon your
point of view, professor.
What do you mean by that?
I just think that Ned
values his life
above scientific achievement,
that's all.
His life means nothing.
Nor does mine or yours
compared to what's
behind all this.
We can't have him
crossing Nemo.
Today we encountered
a fearsome storm.
An ordinary vessel would've
suffered heavy damage.
Safe and serene, The Nautilus
cruised beneath the tempest.
There was much to occupy me,
so I left my apprentice
to deal with Ned Land.
Although he had apparently
settled down,
I knew he bore
constant watching.
Right, sir.
I'll check all decks below.
Ooh.
Cute, isn't she?
As the voyage continued,
The Nautilus
and its motive power
excited my utmost curiosity.
At my host's invitation,
I inspected the ship.
He seemed determined
to show me everything.
We went to the very heart
of the vessel..
the propulsion unit.
It was apparent that
Captain Nemo had discovered
what mankind
has always sought --
the veritable dynamic power
of the universe.
This secret alone gave him
mastery of the sea.
I can hardly believe
how one could conceive
and build such a craft
and, in a single stroke,
harness power beyond
the wildest dreams of science.
Why, such a secret could
revolutionize the world.
Or destroy it.
See how peaceful
it is here.
The sea is everything --
an immense reservoir
of nature,
where I roam at will.
With seeming indifference,
Captain Nemo held the key
to the future of the world.
As I studied him,
I became aware
that powerful forces were at
work within this strange man.
Think of it.
On the surface,
there is hunger and fear.
Men still exercise
unjust laws.
They fight and tear
one another to pieces.
A mere few feet
beneath the waves,
their reign ceases,
their evil drowns.
Here on the ocean floor
is the only independence.
Here I am free.
Imagine what would happen
if they controlled machines
such as a submarine boat.
Far better that they think
there's a monster
and hunt me with harpoons.
After traveling 10,000 leagues
under the sea,
I still had not solved
the mystery of Captain Nemo.
But when one day he asked me
to go ashore with him,
I felt, at long last,
I was to have my answer.
The prison camp of Rura Pente,
the white man's grave.
But I thought
it had been abolished.
Nothing is abolished that turns
a profit to that hated nation.
You'll see better what I mean
through this.
What is in those sacks
they are carrying?
Nitrates and phosphate
for ammunition --
the seeds of war.
They're loading
a full cargo of death.
And when that ship
takes it home,
the world will die
a little more.
I was once one of those pitiful
wretches you see down there.
Look at it again,
professor.
I don't want you to forget
what you've seen here today.
I've seen enough.
It's burned everlastingly
in my memory.
I did not escape
from there alone.
There were others.
Most of them
are still with me.
The crew of The Nautilus?
They're dedicated men
with a plan for living,
but also a plan for dying.
We seized one of their ships
and fled beyond maps --
a place known to me
simply as Vulcania.
Vulcania.
Sounds remote.
Remote and useful.
It was there that we built
The Nautilus.
You will have the privilege
of seeing all this firsthand.
When our mission
is completed,
The Nautilus is going home.
They're getting up steam,
sir.
Very good.
That ship that flies no flag
sails with the tide.
But the evil in its hold
will never reach
its destination.
You have your orders.
Aye, sir.
Go to your stations.
Go below, professor.
You are going to sink
that ship?
I said, "Go below."
Stay in your quarters.
Stand by, engines.
Half ahead.
Collision speed, Full,
Professor...
Are you all right?
All those men -- they --
they didn't even have a chance.
They were sailors,
same as me --
slaughtered
by that monster
you're tryin'
to make friends with.
Ned, don't.
I don't know how you feel,
professor,
but I feel like a knife
that's just stabbed
a friend in the back.
Go to your quarters.
I've had a bellyful.
Damage report, sir.
Rudder and starboard
diving planes disabled.
Muster a repair party.
We'll make
temporary repairs here.
Aye, sir.
I asked you to leave,
professor.
You also asked me ashore
to show me
man's inhumanity to man.
Why? To justify this?
You are not only a murderer,
you are a hypocrite.
The proof lies out there.
You call that murder?!
Well, I see murder, too,
not written on those
drowned faces out there
but on the faces
of dead thousands!
There are the assassins,
the dealers in death,
I am the avenger.
ls murder a right reserved
for that hated nation
that has taken everything
else from me --
everything but my secret,
the secret of
my submarine boat
and the
energy that propels it?
They tried.
They cast me in a prison,
and when they failed...
When they failed,
they tortured my wife
and young son to death.
Do you know the meaning
of love, professor?
I believe I do.
What you fail to understand...
is the power of hate.
It can fill the heart...
as surely as love can.
I'm sorry for you.
It's a bitter substitute.
Oh, the -- the explosions
scattered everything
all over the place.
I was just trying
to tidy up.
Professor, I-I'd like
to speak to you.
About what?
Well, I, I believe --
I believe things
have gone far enough.
Murder means nothing to him.
I, I think he enjoys it.
You're sure of that, are you?
Quite sure?
Well, I, I can only judge him
by -- by what I observed.
It is not your place
to judge.
You don't know anything
about the captain.
He's already said
that he has use for me,
but what's more important,
the world has a use for him,
and I must make him
understand that.
And when he does,
I assure you that
he will judge himself
far more harshly
than you ever can.
ls that clear?
Whatever you say, Captain.
Now, please go out
and leave me alone.
What did you call me?
Captain?
Yes, I did.
And I must say there is
a certain resemblance.
Seen enough?
I want to talk to you.
You little spyin' hyena.
Did the professor
put you up to this?
It's the professor
I want to tell you about.
You were right.
Nemo has won him over
completely.
You bet I was right.
And I was right
about you spyin' on me.
Look, Ned,
I, I've known all along
that you were stealing food
and treasure.
I didn't tell a soul.
I was glad you did it.
We may need it.
We? Since when
do I need you?
- We need each other.
- Ha!
Ned,
I, I want to be friends.
"I want to be friends"?
I want to escape.
So do I -- with you.
And we have to save
the professor,
in spite of himself.
You once said
you had a plan.
Have you?
Yeah, I got a plan.
Well?
Trouble is, it won't work.
I can't figure
how they navigate this barge!
Nothing's written down --
no courses, no bearings,
nothin',
If we can only figure
where we're headin',
we'd have a chance.
- That's no problem.
- Hmm?
When I was reading
the professor's journal,
I, I learned
about Nemo's plans.
We're heading for a place
called Vulcania.
Vulcania?
Yeah, that's --
that's Nemo's base.
Well,
why didn't you say so?
This is
what I've been waitin' for!
- It was?
- Sure!
Vulcania...
Well, I gotta take a look
at those charts.
Why not?
I'll need all hands.
You keep a watch.
Aye, sir.
Keep your eye peeled
for the mate.
Aye, sir.
Hey, Ned. Ned.
Put them back.
He's coming.
- Shh, Shh,
- All right, all right.
Hurry up.
Hurry up. He's coming.
Phew.
That was close, mate.
Very.
Hey...
This is Nemo's cabin.
Yeah.
He does do right well
for himself.
Maybe...
Ned,
let's get out of here.
If they find us
in his cabin, we --
What is it?
Quick, give me
a pen and paper, quick.
- What for?
- I think I found somethin'.
Ned...
See? All the distances
are measured from that point.
That's right.
It must be.
Get me
those calendars, quick.
Let's see if I can
work this out now.
Longitude...
Quiet. Quiet.
Quiet!
Please be quiet, will ya?
Don't bark so much.
Shh,
Here, here.
Have a cigar.
Hey, she likes 'em,
You want another?
Give me a kiss.
You have quite a way
with animals, huh?
I do better with women,
and they don't eat cigars --
Shh, Be quiet!
You feed her. Here.
All right.
I'll give you a cigar.
Here, have one. You see?
Yes, I love you, too.
I'll find you some more.
Yes. I'll find you
some more.
Stop playin' with her.
- I'm not playing.
- Shh, shh, shh,
Here.
You just be quiet.
Be a nice girl.
Here. Eat them slowly.
You don't have to inhale them.
Here.
We'll complete repairs at base.
He's comin',
Let's go.
Resume speed at 50 fathoms.
Esmay.
I've got to do some research.
I'll need some specimens.
Get 'em.
Specimens? What kind?
The ones in bottles.
Go on, beat it.
And don't get caught.
No.
Well, Ned, you've got
everything here,
from the rarest nudibranchs
to oysters.
Oysters are out of season.
Dump 'em in the sink --
all of 'em.
I just want the bottles.
You can't do that.
These are priceless.
Ned, you're not thinking of
putting messages
into these bottles?
Why, that went out
with Robinson Crusoe.
You've forgotten,
this is the 19th century.
Somethin' else I forgot.
Ooh,
That's for spyin' on me.
Don't let me catch you paddin'
the shadow of my stern again.
Remember that.
I don't like bashin' anybody,
but you had it comin', lad.
And I thought
we were friends.
Sure we're friends.
Go ahead. Hit me.
Hmm?
- Hit me.
- Do you mean that?
Sure, go ahead.
You can't miss it.
Ooh,
Now we are friends.
Oh, all right, shipmate.
Ooh.
Well, now I'll tell you
what I had on my mind.
This may be old stuff,
tossin' messages off in bottles
and settin' 'em adrift,
but I've heard of it
workin'.
- Alcohol.
- Very pure alcohol.
We'll just drain the pollywogs
out and save the grog.
But, Ned...
It's -- It's priceless.
Ohh.
Anyhow --
here, hold this, lad --
this chap I knew got
shipwrecked in the Bahamas --
him and a lady passenger
alone on an island.
Well, they had plenty of time
on their hands,
so they began writin' notes,
puttin' 'em
in old rum bottles,
and settin' 'em adrift.
One of them got through, too,
and they was rescued.
Oh.
Easy. What is it?
I swallowed it.
There was a flabellina oculina
in there.
Poor thing.
Flabellina oculina.
She won't answer
her helm, sir.
Astern full,
- What's happened now?
- We seem to have run aground.
Hey, what's happened?
An accident, Captain?
An incident. Our faulty rudders
put us on a reef.
The tide will float us free
by evening.
Professor, we're off
the coast of New Guinea.
Would you like to go ashore?
No, thank you.
The last time we went ashore,
it was a prelude to murder.
- Check for leaks.
- Aye, sir.
Throwin' away
a chance like that --
the professor's losin'
his ballast.
Smell it --
sweet as an angel's kiss.
Dry land, mate,
coconuts, mangoes, and...
native girls
hungry for affection.
I'd give anything to shake hands
with a tree again.
So would I.
And so would the professor.
I, I know how badly
he wants to collect specimens,
but he won't ask
any favors from Nemo.
What's wrong
with you goin' instead?
Nothing.
What about you?
Me?
I'm a collectin' fool.
There's no harm in asking.
No harm at all, mate.
Captain, I, I wondered,
as long as the professor
is not going ashore,
if I could go
in his place.
I-I'd like to collect
some specimens and --
and take some notes.
You feel qualified?
Qualified?
Why, for years,
the professor and I
have been working together.
And I can row, sir --
got a strong back.
And a strong desire
to escape.
Who, me? I'm no deserter.
Happy to be aboard, sir.
Very well.
Permission granted.
Thank you, sir.
But stay on the beach.
The natives over there
are cannibals.
They eat liars
with the same enthusiasm
as they eat honest men.
Break out the skip.
Aye, sir.
Shove off!
I don't see any native girls
hungry for affection.
Take it easy.
Hey, Ned, we're not
supposed to leave the beach.
Who's leavin' it?
Hey!
- Come here, quick!
- What is it?
Look -- a trail
through the jungle.
You had this in mind
all the time.
You want to escape.
What do you say, mate?
It's a cinch.
I don't think so,
or Nemo wouldn't have
let us come ashore.
Don't forget the cannibals.
Oh, belay the cannibals.
He said that to scare us.
Besides, I, I couldn't leave
the professor.
I figured that.
Just look at me.
I can't get through that jungle.
You'll go faster alone.
Hope you make it, Ned.
I'll make it, all right,
and I'll have every gunboat
in the Navy huntin' ol' Nemo.
Just wait.
We'll be laughin' about this,
havin' a drink together
in Frisco.
Good luck, Ned.
Ohh. Give my best
to the professor.
Hey!
Hey! Wait for me!
Wait for me!
Hey!
Natives -- cannibals.
Hundreds of cannibals.
Captain, Captain,
scores of boats with cannibals.
- Captain, we're under attack!
- Naturally.
Since you invaded their privacy,
they have every right
to invade ours.
They're coming aboard,
Captain.
Get me a harpoon, quick.
Close the hatch,
I'll give the commands
on this boat, Mr. Land.
Stand aside.
Aye, sir.
I gotta see this.
This is amazing.
Hey, Captain,
that's one way to keep
guests from dropping in.
A mild charge of electricity,
Mr. Land --
not very hospitable,
but harmless.
And speaking of hospitality,
may I say that you have abused
mine for the last time?
Well, how's that?
You've continuously
disobeyed my orders.
Who, me?
I told you once
the fate of prisoners.
But since you insist
on being treated as one,
I have no choice
but to oblige you.
- Take him in charge.
- Aye, sir.
Now, wait a minute.
What's this all about, Captain?
You left the beach
with the intention of escaping.
The only reason you came back
is because the natives
forced you to.
You're going to regret
that choice, Mr. Land.
MAN #2 : Ship rounding
the headland, sir.
When we clear this reef,
I'll see that you trouble
my existence no longer.
I should have taken my chances
with the cannibals.
A warship.
- A warship?!
- Put him under guard below.
Take him below.
All engines ready.
We must break free
of the reef.
Aye, sir.
Lighten ship
and drop all ballasts.
Get below! They'll be
shelling us in a moment.
Aye, sir.
Astern full.
Astern full it is, sir.
Hold it!
Let me out of this!
Let me out
of this glory hole!
Professor, professor!
A warship, professor.
Warship?!
We're breaking out.
- Man the watertight doors.
- Aye, sir.
Man the watertight door.
Hey, they're --
they're shutting the door.
Wait!
Let us out!
Wait! We are in here!
Wait!
Take the wheel.
How much water
in the power compartment?
5 feet and rising, sir.
Break out a spare shaft.
- Break out a spare shaft.
- We must use leverage.
Bring it thwartships.
Put the aft end
down to the leak.
And lift with the hoist.
Take up the slack.
Make a strain.
There's no pressure.
The dials are not moving.
We've gone too deep.
Stand by with braces.
Aye, sir.
Quick, braces.
Braces in place, sir.
Man your stations.
Start engines.
The air will clear now that
the fans are operating again.
Are you all right?
Yes, thank you --
much better.
Have we stopped sinking?
Fortunately...
There are limits
beyond which man and his
puny efforts cannot survive.
We exceeded them
by 5,000 feet.
We are deeper now
than man has ever been before.
Giant squid astern, sir!
Emergency speed, all engines!
We're found,
Full repeller charge.
Aye, sir.
Try another charge.
Sorry, sir.
All elements burned out.
Then we shall have to fight
on the surface.
Assemble all hands
in the charge room.
Aye, sir.
Drop all ballasts.
Diving controls,
full "out" position.
We'll be fighting
at close quarters
with the most tenacious
of all sea beasts.
Stay clear of the tentacles.
They'll seize anything
within reach
and hang on to the death.
The only vital spot
is directly between the eyes.
40 feet
and surfacing, sir.
Stand by.
Stay back!
Quick, the stern hatch.
Take your men
down the starboard side!
You men, come with me!
Give me a harpoon,
I'll work behind it.
Stay back here!
Stand clear!
Throw me another arrow!
Watch it!
Watch it! Aah,
Your hand,
No! No!
Aaah, Ugh,
Ugh, Ugh,
Ugh,
Well, I'll be --
Are you hurt bad, mate?
What's up?
What happened?
Aaah,
Mr. Land...
You saved my life.
Why?
That's a good question.
Well, there's only one thing
a fella can do
when he's made a mistake
as big as this.
What?
Get drunk.
Huh?
Yep, glad to hear --
see you like music, too, huh?
We got a lot in common.
Thank you, baby.
How 'bout a drink, huh?
Okay.
Hey, would you like
a-a flabellina oculina?
I've tried 'em --
very good.
Ahh,
Try some?
You know, Esmeralda, you're
the only one on this barge
that understands me.
Give us a kiss.
Your whiskers tickle.
Let me see your whiskers.
Hey, you oughta shave,
honey.
You're beginnin'
to look like Nemo.
Let's try it again.
Oh, come on.
Huh?
Not so loud, Ned.
Not so loud.
Hey, she loves
those flabellina oculina!
I am happy you're out
of jail, Ned.
Yeah, I got the run
of the ship.
Big-hearted Nemo!
Well, the professor's
very happy, too.
After all,
it's the first time
that Nemo has shown
any gratitude.
We don't want none
of his gratitude!
This is awful,
You can tell him that
for the both of us!
Do we, Esmeralda, huh?
Come on.
We're gonna take
a little nap here.
Here --
you lie down there.
Cover yourself up good.
I don't want you to catch cold.
My apprentice tells me
you have taken my journal.
May I ask why?
I keep no log
on The Nautilus,
and I was frankly curious
to read your account
of the giant squid --
in particular,
my narrow escape and rescue.
According to you,
Mr. Land is a hero
in the best tradition
of cheap fiction.
That can only be true
if you consider
your life cheap, Captain.
I might have expected you
to say that.
Actually, he regrets
saving my life
as much as I would regret
saving his.
The only difference is
that I wouldn't have tried.
Then it is that difference
that gives Ned Land
the human dignity
you no longer possess.
May I tell you something?
You seem determined to.
Go ahead.
You protest too much.
I know you were deeply touched
by Ned's gesture,
but you are ashamed
to admit it.
You cannot tolerate
the faith in humanity,
because if you do,
all this --
the structure
of your very existence,
which you built on hate
and vengeance --
all this will collapse around
the naked lie of your life.
You are a beaten man
at war with the dictates
of his heart.
And you are
a very gullible man, professor.
- Gullible?
- Yes.
You're too easily swayed
by sentiment,
individual good deeds over bad,
the crude extremes.
You oversimplify matters.
The world
is more complex than that,
and good must not be measured
on a scale as small
as Mr. Land's brash heroics.
What he would do one day,
he would gladly undo the next.
To be of benefit,
goodness must be constant,
forever building.
It must have strength.
I'm afraid what you seek
is perfection.
You will never find it.
I have already found it...
...here.
It is the world outside
that is imperfect.
If men and nations had this
goodness that I speak of,
I would be willing
to share all this --
my records, everything.
Have you considered
sharing it?
That's the only reason that
you're alive today, professor.
From the moment that you came
aboard The Nautilus,
I had hoped that you would be
the key to a plan
that I had in mind.
I had intended using you
as an emissary.
But now I don't know.
ls it that
you don't trust me?
No!
But you are
ever the optimist.
Do you really believe
they would lay down their arms
and abolish
their slave camps?
Yes, I think
I could persuade them.
Let me try.
We're nearing Vulcania.
I want you to see
the extent of these secrets
for which
they have hounded me,
the knowledge which costs the
lives of those dearest to me,
the power
which is still mine --
enough energy
to lift mankind
from the depths of Hell
into Heaven...
or destroy it.
Perhaps then you will feel
less inclined
to barter such a prize.
We will discuss it
at that time.
We've raised
the island, sir.
Why have we stopped?
There are warships ahead.
Bearing what flag?
No flag, sir.
Very well.
There's your answer,
professor.
We've been ambushed
by the very forces
that you wish to trade with.
Their boarding parties
have already landed.
This is a dark hour
for history, professor.
They'll be over the summit
in half an hour, sir.
I estimate 20 minutes.
Everything must be destroyed
before they reach the lagoon.
Ready to dive.
Aye, sir.
Diving stations!
Ahead full,
Four degrees down,
All engines stop!
- Break out the skiff!
- Aye, sir.
What's all the excitement,
Captain?
What is it, professor?
We are at the base,
and the island is surrounded
by warships.
By warships?
Warships!
Shove off!
Have everything
in readiness aboard,
Aye, sir!
Take cover!
Look!
They're coming,
I'm gonna let 'em know
we're here.
No, Ned, Don't!
Hey! Hey!
You up there!
We're friends!
Don't shoot!
We're friends, I tell ya!
We're the ones that threw
the bottles over!
Hey! We're friends!
We sent the messages!
That's gratitude for ya.
After all we did for 'em.
Then it was you who decoyed
those warships here.
Aye, it was.
Somebody had to strike
a blow for freedom.
We did what we thought
was right, professor.
Right?!
You fools!
This is going to cost
the world
the greatest
discoveries of all time!
He's gone ashore
to destroy everything,
Hey, professor!
Destroy everything?
That sounds like he's gonna
plant a bomb or something,
Every man to his station,
Stand by engines!
Prepare for diving,
Aye, sir!
Shall I take over?
Half ahead,
Four degrees down.
Ahead full,
Slow our engines.
All controls
eight degrees down.
Lash the wheel.
Aye, sir.
Captain.
We are taking The Nautilus down
for the last time.
We understand, sir.
And we're with you.
Wait a minute.
I don't understand.
What's that got to do
with us?
I am dying, and The Nautilus
is dying with me.
Professor.
Yes?
In a matter of minutes,
an explosion such as
the world has never known
will destroy my island...
and all its works forever.
That is why I have brought
The Nautilus here...
to its last deep
resting place.
Here, at least
we will die in peace.
Let every man go to his
quarters and remain there.
Why do you take us down
with you?!
Lock them
in their quarters.
Aye, sir.
Take them out!
I don't want to die!
Don't let them do it,
professor!
Captain,
you cannot do this.
There is more at stake here
than just our lives.
Yours was a dream
of the future come true.
I beg you to reconsider.
A power greater than mine
makes that impossible.
But there is hope
for the future.
When the world is ready...
for a new and better life...
all this will someday
come to pass...
in God's good time.
I'm sorry, Ned.
Don't give up, mate!
We're no part
of any suicide pact!
Put him in his cabin.
Ugh,
Ohh,
Ohh, Ugh, Ugh,
Ugh,
Come on,
I've taken over the ship!
Let's get outta here!
We're on the surface,
so stand by!
Let's get the skiff out
and shove off!
Hey, professor!
Where are you goin'?!
- My journal,
- The island's gonna blow up any second,
I must get my journal,
Shove off!
What's the matter?
Is he hurt?
Hey, we forgot Essy.
Esmeralda, come on,
Quick, quick!
Come on,
Come on, hurry!
In the boat.
Come on, in the boat.
Thar she blows.
Sorry I had to wallop you,
professor.
There wasn't time to stop
for souvenirs.
Perhaps you did mankind
a service, Ned.
There is hope for the future.
And when the world is ready
for a new and better life,
all this will someday
come to pass...
in God's good time.
Resync: Xenzai[NEF]