Drink up, me hearties, yo ho
We kidnap and ravage
and don't give a hoot
Drink up, me hearties, yo ho
Yo ho, yo ho
A pirate's life for me
We extort, we pilfer
We filch, we sack...
Quiet, missy!
Cursed pirates sail these waters.
You don't want to bring
them down on us.
Mr. Gibbs, that will do.
She was singing about pirates!
Bad luck to sing about pirates
with us mired in this unnatural fog.
- Mark my words.
- Consider them marked.
- On your way.
- Aye, Lieutenant.
Bad luck to have a woman on board,
too. Even a miniature one.
It'd be exciting to meet a pirate.
Think again, Miss Swann.
Vile creatures, the lot of them.
I intend to see to it that any man
who sails under a pirate flag
gets what he deserves.
A short drop and a sudden stop.
I appreciate your fervor,
but I'm concerned about the effect this
subject will have upon my daughter.
My apologies, Governor Swann.
- Actually, I find it all fascinating.
- That's what concerns me.
There's a boy in the water!
Man overboard!
Man the ropes! Fetch a hook!
Haul him aboard!
He's still breathing.
Mary, Mother of God!
What happened here?
Most likely the powder magazine.
Merchant vessels run heavily armed.
Lot of good it did them.
Everyone's thinking it, I'm saying it.
Pirates!
There's no proof of that!
It was probably an accident.
Rouse the captain. Heave to
and take in sail. Launch the boats.
Elizabeth, accompany the boy.
He'll be in your charge.
Take care of him.
It's okay. My name's Elizabeth Swann.
Will Turner.
I'm watching over you, Will.
You're a pirate!
Has he said anything?
His name's William Turner.
That's all I found out.
Take him below.
Elizabeth!
Are you all right?
Are you decent?
Yes.
Yes?
Still abed at this hour?
It's a beautiful day.
I have a gift for you.
- It's beautiful!
- Isn't it?
May I inquire as to the occasion?
Does a father need an occasion
to dote upon his daughter?
Go on.
Actually... I had hoped you might
wear it for the ceremony today.
The ceremony?
Captain Norrington's
promotion ceremony.
I knew it!
Commodore Norrington,
as he's about to become.
A fine gentleman, don't you think?
He fancies you, you know.
Elizabeth? How's it coming?
- It's difficult to say.
- It's the latest fashion in London.
Women in London
must've learned not to breathe!
My Lord, you have a visitor.
Mr. Turner! Good to see you again.
Good day, sir. I have your order.
The blade is folded steel. That's
gold filigree laid into the handle.
If I may?
Perfectly balanced. The tang
is nearly the width of the blade.
Impressive. Very impressive.
Commodore Norrington's
going to be very pleased with this.
Do pass my compliments
onto your master.
I shall.
A craftsman is always pleased
to hear his work is appreciated.
Elizabeth!
You look absolutely stunning!
Will! It's so good to see you!
- I had a dream about you last night.
- About me?
- Elizabeth, is that proper?
- About the day we met. Remember?
How could I forget, Miss Swann?
How many times must I ask you
to call me Elizabeth?
At least once more, Miss Swann.
As always.
There. See? At least the boy
has a sense of propriety.
We really must be going.
Good day, Mr. Turner.
Come along!
Good day...
Elizabeth.
Hold up there, you!
It's a shilling to tie up
your boat to the dock.
I need to know your name.
What do you say to three shillings
and we forget the name?
Welcome to Port Royal, Mr. Smith.
Two paces... march!
Right about... face!
Present... arms!
This dock is off limits to civilians.
I'm terribly sorry, I didn't know.
If I see one, I shall inform you.
There's some high-toned
and fancy to-do at the fort.
How could it be that two upstanding
gentlemen did not merit an invitation?
We have to make sure this dock
stays off limits to civilians.
It's a fine goal, to be sure,
but it seems to me, a ship like that
makes this one here
a bit superfluous.
The Dauntless is the power
in these waters,
but there's no ship that can match
the Interceptor for speed.
I've heard of one. It's supposed
to be fast, nigh uncatchable.
The Black Pearl.
There's no real ship
that can match the Interceptor.
The Black Pearl is a real ship.
- No, it's not.
- It is. I've seen it!
- You've seen it?
- Yes.
- You haven't seen it!
- Yes, I have!
You've seen a ship with black sails,
that's crewed by the damned
and captained by a man so evil
that Hell itself spat him back out?
- No.
But I have seen a ship
with black sails.
No ship not crewed by the damned
and captained by a man so evil,
Hell spat him back out,
could have black sails, so couldn't be
any other ship than The Black Pearl.
Is that what you're saying?
No.
Like I said, there's no real ship
that can match the Interceptor...
You! Get away from there!
You don't have permission to be aboard!
I'm sorry, but it's such a pretty
boat. Ship!
- What's your name?
- Smith! Or Smithy, if you like.
What's your purpose in Port Royal,
'Mr. Smith'?
- And no lies!
- All right. I confess.
I intend to commandeer a ship,
pick up a crew in Tortuga,
rape, pillage and otherwise
pilfer my black guts out.
- I said no lies!
- I think he's telling the truth.
If he were telling the truth,
he wouldn't have told us.
Unless he knew you wouldn't believe
the truth even if he told you.
May I have a moment?
You look lovely, Elizabeth.
I apologize if I seem forward,
but I must speak my mind.
This promotion throws into sharp relief
that which I have not yet achieved.
A marriage to a fine woman.
You have become a fine woman.
I can't breathe!
Yes, I'm a bit nervous myself.
Then they made me their chief.
Elizabeth?
Elizabeth!
The rocks!
Sir, it's a miracle she missed them!
- Will you be saving her?
- I can't swim!
Pride of the King's Navy, you are!
Do not lose these.
What was that?
I got her!
- She's not breathing!
- Move!
- I never would've thought of that.
- You've never been to Singapore.
Where did you get that?
On your feet.
Elizabeth!
- Are you all right?
- I'm fine.
- Shoot him!
- Father!
Commodore, do you intend
to kill my rescuer?
I believe thanks are in order.
Had a brush with the East India
Trading Company, pirate?
Hang him!
Keep your guns on him, men.
Gillette, fetch some irons.
Well, well. Jack Sparrow, isn't it?
Captain Jack Sparrow,
if you please, sir.
I don't see your ship... 'Captain'.
I'm in the market, as it were.
He said he'd come to commandeer one.
I told you he was telling the truth.
These are his.
No additional shot nor powder.
A compass that doesn't point north.
I half expected it to be made from wood.
You are without doubt
the worst pirate I've ever heard of!
But you have heard of me.
Commodore, I must protest!
Carefully, Lieutenant.
Pirate or not, this man saved my life!
One good deed is not enough to redeem
a man for his wickedness!
- It seems enough to condemn him.
- Indeed.
Finally.
- Don't shoot!
- I knew you'd warm up to me.
Commodore Norrington,
my effects, please. And my hat.
Commodore.
- Elizabeth... it is Elizabeth?
- It's Miss Swann.
Miss Swann, if you'd be so kind.
Come, dear, we don't have all day.
If you'll be very kind.
Easy on the goods, darling.
- You're despicable.
- Sticks and stones, love.
I saved your life, you saved mine.
We're square.
Gentlemen, my lady,
you will always remember this
as the day you almost caught...
Captain Jack Sparrow!
- Now will you shoot him?
- Open fire!
On his heels!
Take cover, man!
Gillette, Mr. Sparrow has
a dawn appointment with the gallows.
I would hate for him to miss it.
Search up the stairs!
Look lively, men!
Right where I left you.
Not where I left you.
You're the one they're hunting.
The pirate!
You seem familiar.
Have I threatened you before?
I avoid familiarity with pirates.
It would be a shame to put a black
mark on your record. Excuse me.
Do you think this wise, boy?
Crossing blades with a pirate?
You threatened Miss Swann.
Only a little.
You know what you're doing.
Excellent form. How's your footwork?
If I step here...
Good.
And now I step again.
Ta.
That is a wonderful trick.
Except, once again,
you are between me and my way out.
And now...
you have no weapon.
Who makes all these?
I do.
And I practice with them
three hours a day.
You need to find yourself a girl, mate.
Or, the reason you practice three hours
a day is that you already found one
and are otherwise incapable
of wooing said strumpet.
You're not a eunuch, are you?
I practice three hours a day
so when I meet a pirate, I can kill him!
- You cheated!
- Pirate.
- Move away!
- No.
Please?
No! I cannot just step aside
and let you escape.
This shot is not meant for you.
There he is! Over here!
Excellent work, Mr. Brown. You've
assisted in the capture of a fugitive.
Just doing my civic duty, sir.
I trust you will remember this as the
day Captain Jack Sparrow almost escaped.
Take him away.
- Come here, boy. Come here.
- Who wants a juicy bone?
Come here, boy!
You can keep doing that forever.
The dog is never going to move.
Excuse us if we haven't resigned
ourselves to the gallows just yet.
There you go, miss. It was
a difficult day for you, I'm sure.
I suspected Commodore Norrington would
propose, but I wasn't prepared for it.
I meant you being threatened
by that pirate! Sounds terrifying!
Yes, it was terrifying.
But... the Commodore proposed!
Fancy that.
That's a smart match, miss,
if it's not too bold to say.
It is a smart match.
He's a fine man.
He's what any woman
should dream of marrying.
That Will Turner...
he's a fine man, too.
That is too bold.
Beggin' your pardon.
It was not my place.
Has my daughter
given you an answer yet?
No, she hasn't.
She has had a trying day.
- Ghastly weather, don't you think?
- Really bleak.
What's that?
Cannon fire!
Return fire!
I know those guns.
It's the Pearl.
The Black Pearl?
I've heard stories.
She's been preying on ships
and settlements for ten years.
- Never leaves any survivors.
- No survivors?
Then where do the stories
come from, I wonder?
Mama!
- Sight the muzzle flash.
- Aim for the flashes!
I need a full spread, fore and aft.
Mr. Stevens, more cartridges.
Governor. Barricade yourself
in my office.
That's an order.
Don't!
Hello, chum.
Up there!
Miss Swann,
they've come to kidnap you.
- What?
- You're the governor's daughter!
In here!
They haven't seen you.
First chance you get, run to the fort.
Gotcha!
No! It's hot. I'm burning!
Come on!
Come on, me men.
We know you're here, poppet.
- Poppet!
- Come out.
We promise we won't hurt you.
We will find you, poppet.
You've got something of ours
and it calls to us.
The gold calls to us.
The gold.
Hello, poppet.
Parley.
- What?
- I invoke the right of parley.
The Code of the Brethren states
you have to take me to your captain.
I know the Code.
You can do me no harm
until the parley is complete.
- To blazes with the Code.
- She wants to be taken to the Captain.
And she'll go, without a fuss.
We must honor the Code.
Say goodbye!
Goodbye.
- Come on.
- Elizabeth.
Out of my way, scum!
My sympathies. You've no manner
of luck at all.
Come on, doggy! It's just
you and me now.
It's you and old Jack. Come on.
That's a boy! Get your bone!
That's a good boy.
A bit closer!
That's it, doggy!
Come on, you filthy,
slimy, mangy character!
No! I didn't mean it!
This ain't the armory!
Well, well, well. Look what we have
here, Twigg. Captain Jack Sparrow!
Last time I saw you,
you were all alone on a godforsaken
island, shrinking into the distance.
His fortunes aren't improved much.
Worry about your own fortunes,
gentlemen.
The deepest circle of Hell is reserved
for betrayers and mutineers.
So there is a curse.
- That's interesting.
- You know nothing of Hell.
That's very interesting.
I didn't know we was takin' on captives.
She's invoked the right of parley
with Captain Barbossa.
- I am here to...
- You will speak when spoken to.
And ye will not lay a hand on those
under the protection of parley.
Aye, sir.
My apologies, miss.
Captain Barbossa... I am here to
negotiate the cessation of hostilities.
There are a lot of long words there.
We're naught but humble pirates.
- What is it you want?
- Leave and never come back.
I'm disinclined to acquiesce
to your request.
Means "no."
Very well.
I'll drop it.
Me holds are burstin' with swag.
That bit of shine matters to us?
Why?
It's what you've been searching for.
I recognize the ship.
I saw it eight years ago
on the crossing from England!
Did you now?
Fine. I suppose if it is worthless
there's no point in me keeping it.
No!
You have a name, missy?
Elizabeth... Turner. I'm a maid
in the Governor's household.
Miss Turner!
- Turner!
- Bootstrap!
How does a maid come to own
that trinket? Family heirloom?
I didn't steal it,
if that's what you mean.
You hand it over
and we'll leave and never return.
Our bargain?
Still the guns and stow them. Signal
the men and make good to clear port.
You have to take me to shore.
According to the Code...
First...
Your return to shore was not part of
our negotiations so I must do nothing.
Secondly, you must be a pirate for the
Pirate's Code to apply, and you're not.
Thirdly, the code is more what
you'd call guidelines than actual rules.
Welcome aboard the Black Pearl,
Miss Turner.
They've taken Elizabeth!
Mr. Murtogg, remove this man.
We have to hunt them down.
We must save her.
Where do you propose we start?
If you have any information
concerning my daughter, share it.
That Jack Sparrow.
He talked about the Black Pearl.
Mentioned it is more what he did.
Ask him where it is!
He could lead us to it.
No.
The pirates left Sparrow in his cell,
ergo they are not his allies.
We will establish their
most likely course...
That's not good enough!
Mr. Turner, you are not a military man
or a sailor. You are a blacksmith.
And this is not the moment
for rash actions!
Do not think you are the only man here
who cares for Elizabeth.
Please.
- You! Sparrow!
- Aye?
You are familiar with
the Black Pearl?
- I've heard of it.
- Where does it make berth?
Where does it make berth?
Have you not heard the stories?
Captain Barbossa and his crew of
miscreants sail from the Isla de Muerta.
It's an island that cannot be found,
except by those who know where it is.
The ship's real, therefore its anchorage
must be a real place. Where?
- Why ask me?
- Because you're a pirate.
You want to turn pirate yourself.
Is that it?
Never!
- They took Miss Swann.
- So it is that you found a girl!
I see!
If you intend to brave all,
hasten to her rescue,
and so, win fair lady's heart,
you'll have to do it alone, mate.
I see no profit in it for me.
- I can get you out of here.
- The key's run off.
I helped build these cells.
These are half-pin barrel hinges.
With leverage and the proper application
of strength, the door will lift free.
- What's your name?
- Will Turner.
That would be short for William,
I imagine. Good, strong name.
No doubt named for your father.
Yes.
Mr. Turner, I've changed me mind.
If you spring me from here,
I swear, on pain of death,
I shall take you to the Black Pearl,
and your bonny lass.
Do we have an accord?
- Agreed.
- Agreed! Get me out!
- Hurry! Someone will have heard that.
- Not without my effects.
We're going to steal a ship?
- That ship?
- Commandeer.
We're going to "commandeer" that ship.
Nautical term.
One question about your business,
or there's no use going.
This girl, how far are you willing to go
to save her?
- I'd die for her.
- Good. No worries then.
This is either madness or brilliance.
It's remarkable how often
those two traits coincide.
Everyone stay calm!
We're taking over the ship.
Aye! Avast!
This ship cannot be crewed by two men.
You'll never make it out of the bay.
Son... I'm Captain Jack Sparrow.
Savvy?
- Commodore!
- They're taking the Dauntless!
Commodore! They've taken the ship!
Sparrow and Turner!
They're taking the Dauntless!
Rash, Turner. Too rash.
That is, without doubt, the worst pirate
I have ever seen.
Here they come.
Bring her around!
Search every cabin, every hold,
down to the bilges.
Sailors, back to the Interceptor!
Thank you, Commodore,
for getting us ready to make way.
We'd have had
a hard time by ourselves.
Set topsails and clear up this mess.
With this wind we won't catch them.
I don't need to. Get them in range
of the long nines.
Run out the guns!
We are to fire on our own ship, sir?
I'd rather see her at the bottom of the
ocean than in the hands of a pirate.
Commodore!
He's disabled the rudder chain.
Abandon ship!
That's got to be the best pirate
I've ever seen.
So it would seem.
When I was a lad living in England,
my mother raised me by herself.
After she died, I came here,
looking for my father.
Is that so?
My father, Bill Turner?
It was only after you learned my name
you agreed to help.
Since that's what I wanted,
I didn't press the matter.
I'm not a simpleton.
You knew my father.
I knew him. Probably one of the few
who knew him as William Turner.
Everyone else just called him
"Bootstrap".
Bootstrap?
Good man. Good pirate.
I swear, you look just like him.
It's not true. He was a merchant sailor.
A respectable man who obeyed the law.
He was a bloody pirate, a scallywag.
My father was not a pirate!
Put it away, son.
It's not worth you getting beat again.
You ignored the rules of engagement.
In a fair fight, I'd kill you.
That's not much incentive
for me to fight fair, is it?
As long as you're just
hanging there, pay attention.
The only rules that matter are these:
What a man can do
and what a man can't do.
You can accept your father was a
pirate and a good man, or you can't.
Pirate is in your blood, so you'll
have to square with that someday.
Me, for example,
I can let you drown,
but I can't bring this ship into Tortuga
all by me onesies, savvy?
So.
Can you sail under the command
of a pirate?
Or can you not?
Tortuga?
Tortuga.
It is a sad life
that has never breathed deep
the sweet, proliferous bouquet
that is Tortuga. Savvy?
What do you think?
- It'll linger.
- I'll tell you, mate,
if every town were like this one,
no man would ever feel unwanted.
Scarlett!
Not sure I deserved that.
Giselle.
- Who was she?
- What?
I may have deserved that.
Curse you for breathing,
you slack-jawed idiot!
Mother's love!
Jack!
You should know not to wake a man
when he's sleepin'.
- It's bad luck.
- Fortunately, I know how to counter it.
The man who did the waking
buys the man who was sleeping a drink.
The man who was sleeping drinks it
while listening to his proposition.
Aye, that'll about do it.
Blast! I'm already awake!
That was for the smell.
Keep a sharp eye.
Now, what's the nature
of this venture of your'n?
I'm going after the Black Pearl.
I know where it's going to be,
and I'm gonna take it.
Jack, it's a fool's errand.
You know better than me
the tales of the Black Pearl.
That's why I know
what Barbossa is up to.
All I need is a crew.
Captain Barbossa is not a man to suffer
fools nor strike a bargain with one.
It's a good thing I'm not a fool, then.
Prove me wrong. What makes you think
Barbossa will give up his ship to you?
Let's just say it's a matter
of leverage.
The kid?
That is the child
of Bootstrap Bill Turner.
His only child. Savvy?
Is he now?
Leverage, says you.
I feel a change in the wind, says I.
I'll find us a crew. There's bound to be
some sailors on this rock crazy as you.
One can only hope.
- Take what you can!
- Give nothin' back!
You'll be dining with the captain,
and he requests you wear this.
Tell him that I am disinclined
to acquiesce to his request.
He said you'd say that.
He also said if that be the case,
you'll be dining with the crew.
And you'll be naked.
Fine.
There's no need to stand on ceremony,
no call to impress anyone.
You must be hungry.
Try the wine.
And the apples. One of those next.
It's poisoned.
There would be no sense
to be killing you.
Then release me. You have your trinket.
I'm of no further value to you.
You don't know what this is, do you?
It's a pirate medallion.
This is Aztec gold.
One of 882 identical pieces they
delivered in a stone chest to Cortés.
Blood money paid to stem the slaughter
he wreaked upon them with his armies.
But the greed of Cortés was insatiable.
So the heathen gods
placed upon the gold...
a terrible curse.
Any mortal that removes but
a single piece from that stone chest...
shall be punished for eternity.
Shall be punished for eternity.
I hardly believe in ghost stories
any more, Captain Barbossa.
Aye.
That's exactly what I thought
when we were first told the tale.
Buried on an island of the dead
what cannot be found,
except for those who know where it is.
Find it, we did.
There be the chest.
Inside be the gold.
And we took 'em all!
We spent 'em and traded 'em,
and frittered 'em away on drink and food
and pleasurable company.
The more we gave 'em away,
the more we came to realize...
the drink would not satisfy.
Food turned to ash in our mouths,
and all the pleasurable company
in the world could not slake our lust.
We are cursed men, Miss Turner.
Compelled by greed we were, but now...
we are consumed by it.
There is one way we can end our curse.
All the scattered pieces
of the Aztec gold must be restored,
and the blood repaid.
Thanks to ye, we have the final piece.
And the blood to be repaid?
That's why there's no sense
to be killing you.
Yet.
Apple?
I'm curious. After killing me,
what are you planning on doing next?
Look!
The moonlight shows us
for what we really are.
We are not among the living
and so we cannot die.
But neither are we dead.
For too long I've been parched of thirst
and unable to quench it.
Too long I've been starvin' to death
and haven't died.
I feel nothing.
Not the wind on my face,
nor the spray of the sea...
nor the warmth of a woman's flesh.
You best start believing
in ghost stories, Miss Turner.
You're in one!
What are you looking at?
Back to work!
You heard the captain.
Back to work.
Feast your eyes, Captain. All of them,
faithful hands before the mast.
Every man worth his salt,
and crazy to boot.
So this is your able-bodied crew?
- You, sailor!
- Cotton, sir.
Mr. Cotton, do you have the courage
and fortitude to follow orders
and stay true in the face of danger
and almost certain death?
- Mr. Cotton. Answer, man!
- He's a mute, sir.
Poor devil had his tongue cut out, so
he trained the parrot to talk for him.
No one's yet figured how.
Mr. Cotton's parrot,
same question.
Wind in your sails!
Mostly, we figure that means "yes".
Of course it does. Satisfied?
Well, you've proved they're mad.
What's the benefit for us?
Anamaria!
- I suppose you didn't deserve that.
- No, that one I deserved.
- You stole my boat!
- Actually...
Borrowed without permission, but with
every intention of bringing it back.
- But you didn't!
- You'll get another one.
- I will.
- A better one.
A better one!
- That one.
- What one?
That one?
Aye. That one.
- What say you?
- Aye!
Aye!
Anchor's aweigh!
No, it's frightful bad luck
to bring a woman aboard, sir.
It'll be far worse not to have her.
How can we sail to an island
that nobody can find,
with a compass that doesn't work?
The compass doesn't point north, but
we're not trying to find north, are we?
We should drop canvas, sir.
She can hold a bit longer.
What's in your head as puts you
in such a fine mood, Cap'n?
We're catching up.
Time to go, poppet.
Dead men tell no tales.
Chills the bones, how many honest
sailors been claimed by this passage.
How is it that Jack
came by that compass?
Not a lot's known about Jack Sparrow
before he came to Tortuga
with a mind to find the treasure
of the Isla de Muerta.
That was before I'd met him, when he
was captain of the Black Pearl.
What?
- He failed to mention that.
- He plays things close to the vest now.
And a hard-learned lesson it was.
Three days into the trip, the first mate
says, "Everything's an equal share."
"The location of the treasure, too."
So Jack gives up the bearings.
That night, there was a mutiny.
They marooned Jack on an island
and left him to die.
But not before he'd
gone mad with the heat.
So that's the reason for all the...
Reason's got nothing to do with it.
When a pirate's marooned, he's given
a pistol with a single shot. One shot.
That won't do much good hunting,
nor to be rescued.
But after three weeks
of a starving belly and thirst,
that pistol looks real friendly.
But Jack escaped the island,
and still has that single shot.
He won't use it, though,
save on one man.
His mutinous first mate.
- Barbossa.
- Aye.
- How did Jack get off the island?
- I'll tell ye.
He waded out into the shallows,
and waited three days and three nights,
till all manner of sea creatures
became acclimated to his presence.
On the fourth morning,
he roped a couple of sea turtles,
lashed them together
and made a raft.
- He roped a couple of sea turtles.
- Aye.
What did he use for rope?
Human hair.
From my back.
- Let go the anchor!
- Lower the anchor line!
Young Mr. Turner and I are to go ashore.
Captain.
What if the worst should happen?
- Keep to the Code.
- Aye. The Code.
- Ten years of hoarding swag.
- Now we finally get to spend it.
Once we're quit of the curse,
we'll be rich men...
and you can buy an eye
that fits and is made of glass.
This one does splinter
something terrible.
Stop rubbing it.
What code is Gibbs to keep to
if the worst should happen?
Pirates' Code.
Any man who falls behind
is left behind.
No heroes amongst thieves.
For having such a bleak outlook
on pirates
you're well on your way
to becoming one.
Sprung a man from jail,
commandeered a ship of the fleet,
sailed with a buccaneer crew
out of Tortuga...
and you're completely obsessed
with treasure.
That's not true. I am not obsessed
Not all treasure is silver
and gold, mate.
Gentlemen, the time has come!
Salvation is nigh!
- Our torment is nearing an end!
- Elizabeth.
For ten years
we've been tested and tried
and each man here has proved his mettle
a hundred times over
and a hundred times again!
Suffered, I have!
Punished we were, the lot of us,
disproportionate to our crime!
Here it is!
The cursed treasure of Cortés himself.
Every last piece that went astray,
we have returned.
Save for this!
- Jack!
- Not yet.
We wait for the opportune moment.
When's that? When it's of greatest
profit to you?
May I ask you something?
Have I ever given you reason
not to trust me?
Do us a favor. I know it's difficult
for you, but please stay here.
And try not to do anything stupid.
Who among us has paid the blood
sacrifice owed to the heathen gods?
- Us!
- And whose blood must yet be paid?
Hers!
You know the first thing I'm going to do
after the curse is lifted?
Eat a whole bushel of apples!
Begun by blood.
By blood undone.
Sorry, Jack.
I'm not going to be your leverage.
That's it?
Waste not.
Did it work?
- I don't feel no different.
- How do we tell?
You're not dead!
No.
- He shot me.
- It didn't work.
The curse is still upon us!
You! Maid! Your father,
what was his name?
Was your father William Turner?
No.
Where's his child who sailed
from England eight years ago?
The child in whose veins flows
the blood of William Turner? Where?
You two!
You brought us the wrong person!
No!
She had the medallion.
She's the proper age.
She said her name was Turner.
You heard her.
I think she lied to us.
You brought us here for nothing.
I won't take questioning,
not from the likes of you, Master Twigg.
Who's to blame him? Your decisions
have led us from bad to worse!
It was you who sent Bootstrap
to the depths!
And it's you who brought us here
in the first place!
If any coward here dare challenge me,
let him speak!
I say we cut her throat
and spill all her blood. Just in case.
Yeah!
The medallion! She's taken it!
Get after her, you feckless pack
of ingrates!
- Where are the oars?
- There's no oars!
The oars have gone missing!
Find them!
You!
- You're supposed to be dead.
- Am I not?
Pearlie...
Palu-li-la-la-lulu...
Parlili...
Parsnip... Parsley...
Partner...
- Parley?
- That's the one! Parley!
Parley!
Parley?
Damn to the depths whatever muttonhead
thought of parley!
That would be the French.
- Not more pirates.
- Welcome aboard, Miss Elizabeth.
Mr. Gibbs?
Hey, boy, where be Jack?
Jack Sparrow?
He fell behind.
Keep to the Code.
Weigh anchor! Hoist the sails!
Split-quick, you dibbies!
How the blazes did you get
off that island?
When you marooned me
on that godforsaken spit of land,
you forgot one very important thing.
I'm Captain Jack Sparrow.
Well, I won't be making
that mistake again.
Gents, you all remember
Captain Jack Sparrow?
Aye.
Kill him.
The girl's blood didn't work, did it?
Hold your fire!
You know whose blood we need.
I know whose blood you need.
What sort of a man
trades a man's life for a ship?
A pirate.
Here. Let me.
Thank you.
You said you gave Barbossa
my name as yours.
Why?
I don't know.
I'm sorry. A blacksmith's hands.
- They're rough.
- No. I mean, yes, they are, but...
Don't stop.
Elizabeth.
It's yours.
I thought I'd lost it
the day they rescued me.
It was a gift from my father.
He sent it to me.
Why did you take it?
Because I was afraid
that you were a pirate.
That would've been awful.
It wasn't your blood they needed.
It was my father's blood.
My blood.
- The blood of a pirate.
- Will, I'm so sorry. Please forgive me.
So you expect to leave me on some beach
with nothing but a name
and your word it's the one I need,
and watch you
sail away in my ship.
No.
I expect to leave you standing on some
beach with absolutely no name at all,
watching me sail away on my ship, and
then I'll shout the name back to you.
Savvy?
But that still leaves me
standing on some beach,
with naught but a name and
your word it's the one I need.
Of the two of us, I am the only one
who hasn't committed mutiny.
Therefore, my word
is the one we'll be trusting.
Although, I suppose I should be
thanking you because, in fact,
if you hadn't betrayed me
and left me to die,
I would have an equal share
in that curse, same as you.
Funny old world, isn't it?
Captain! We're coming up
on the Interceptor.
I'm having a thought here, Barbossa.
What say we run up a flag of truce,
I scurry over to the Interceptor,
and I negotiate the return
of your medallion?
Now that's exactly the attitude
that lost you the Pearl.
People are easier to search
when they're dead.
Lock him in the brig.
Hands aloft to loose ta'gallants!
With this wind,
she'll carry every sail we've got.
- What's happening?
- The Black Pearl is gaining on us!
This is the fastest ship
in the Caribbean.
Tell them that after they've caught us.
- We're shallower on the draft, right?
- Aye.
Then can't we lose them
on those shoals?
We don't have to outrun 'em long.
Just long enough.
Lighten the ship!
Stem to stern!
Anything we can afford to lose,
see that it's lost!
Apparently, there's a leak.
Haul on the main brace!
Make ready the guns!
And run out the sweeps.
We're gonna need that.
It was a good plan, up till now.
Gibbs!
We have to make a stand.
We must fight!
- Load the guns!
- With what?
Anything! Everything!
Anything we have left.
Load the guns!
Case shot and langrage!
Nails and crushed glass!
With a will!
The Pearl will luff up
on our port quarter.
She'll rake us
without presenting a target.
Lower the anchor on the right side.
On the starboard side!
- It has the element of surprise.
- You're daft, lady. You both are.
Daft like Jack.
Lower the starboard anchor!
Do it, you gobs, or it's you
we'll load into the cannons!
Let go!
They're club hauling.
Hard a port! Rack the starboard oars!
Hard a port!
Keep her steady, man.
- Now!
- Fire!
Fire all!
Stop blowing holes in my ship!
- We need more ideas, lass!
- It's your turn!
- We need us a devil's dowry!
- We'll give them her!
She's not what they're after.
The medallion.
Strike your colors,
you bloomin' cockroaches!
Hands, grapnels at the ready!
Prepare to board!
Pistols and cutlasses, men!
Koehler, Twigg, to the powder magazine!
And the rest of you,
bring me the medallion!
Below!
Thanks very much.
Jack!
Bloody empty!
That's not very nice.
- Where is the medallion?
- Wretch!
Where is dear William?
Will.
Elizabeth!
Monkey!
I can't move it!
Elizabeth!
- Thank you, Jack.
- You're welcome.
Not you. We named the monkey Jack.
Gents! Our hope is restored!
Any of you so much
as thinks the word "parley",
I'll have your guts for garters!
Will.
You godless pirate!
Welcome back, miss.
You took advantage of our hospitality
last time.
It holds fair now you return the favor.
Barbossa!
Will.
She goes free!
What's in your head, boy?
She goes free.
You've only got one shot,
and we can't die.
Don't do anything stupid.
You can't. I can.
Like that.
- Who are you?
- No one. He's no one.
A distant cousin of my aunt's
nephew, twice removed.
Lovely singing voice, though. Eunuch.
My name is Will Turner!
My father was Bootstrap Bill Turner.
His blood runs in my veins.
It's the spitting image of old
Bootstrap Bill come back to haunt us.
On my word, do as I say,
or I'll pull this trigger,
and be lost to Davy Jones' locker!
Name your terms, Mr. Turner.
- Elizabeth goes free!
- Yes, we know that one.
Anything else?
And the crew. The crew
are not to be harmed.
Agreed.
Barbossa, you lying bastard.
You swore she'd go free.
Don't dare impugn me honor, boy.
I agreed she'd go free.
It was you who failed to specify
when or where.
Though it does seem a shame to lose
something so fine, don't it, lads?
So I'll be havin' that dress back
before you go.
I always liked you.
Goes with your black heart.
It's still warm.
Off you go.
Come on.
Too long.
I'd really rather hoped
we were past all this.
Jack. Jack!
Did you not notice?
That be the same island that we made
you governor of on our last little trip.
I did notice.
Perhaps you'll be able to conjure up
another miraculous escape.
But I doubt it.
Off you go.
Last time you left me a pistol
with one shot.
By the powers, you're right.
Where be Jack's pistol?
Bring it forward.
Seeing as there's two of us, a gentleman
would give us a pair of pistols.
It'll be one pistol as before, and you
can be the gentleman and shoot the lady,
and starve to death yourself.
That's the second time
I've watched that man take my ship.
You were marooned on this island before.
We can escape in the same way.
To what point and purpose, young missy?
The Black Pearl is gone. Unless you have
a lot of sails hidden in that bodice...
Unlikely.
...young Mr. Turner will be dead
long before you can reach him.
But you're Captain Jack Sparrow.
You vanished from under the eyes of
seven agents of the East India Company.
You sacked Nassau port
without even firing a shot.
Are you the pirate
I've read about or not?
How did you escape last time?
Last time I was here
a grand total of three days.
Last time...
the rum runners
used this island as a cache.
They came by and I was able
to barter passage off.
From the looks of things,
they've long been out of business.
You probably have your bloody friend
Norrington to thank for that.
So that's it, then?
That's the secret, grand adventure
of the infamous Jack Sparrow.
You spent three days
lying on a beach drinking rum.
Welcome to the Caribbean, love.
We're devils, we're black sheep
We're really bad eggs
Drink up, me hearties, yo ho
Yo ho, yo ho
A pirate's life for me
I love this song!
Really bad eggs!
When I get the Pearl back,
I'm gonna teach it to the whole crew,
and we'll sing it all the time.
You will be the most fearsome pirates
in the Spanish Main.
Not just the Spanish Main, love.
The entire ocean.
The entire world!
Wherever we want to go, we go.
That's what a ship is.
It's not just a keel and a hull
and a deck and sails.
That's what a ship needs.
But what a ship is...
What the Black Pearl really is...
is freedom.
Jack...
It must be really terrible for you
to be trapped on this island.
Oh, yes.
But the company is infinitely better
than last time.
And the scenery has definitely improved.
Mr. Sparrow!
I'm not entirely sure I've had enough
rum to allow that kind of talk.
I know exactly what you mean, love.
To freedom!
To the Black Pearl!
No!
Not good! Stop!
Not good! What are you doing?
You've burned all the food,
the shade, the rum.
- Yes, the rum is gone.
- Why is the rum gone?
One, because it is a vile drink that
turns respectable men into scoundrels.
Two, that signal
is over 1,000 feet high.
The entire Royal Navy is looking for me.
Do you think there is the slightest
chance they won't see it?
But why is the rum gone?
Just wait, Captain Sparrow.
You give it one hour, maybe two,
keep a weather eye open, and you
will see white sails on that horizon.
"Must've been terrible for you
to be trapped here, Jack."
Well, it bloody is now!
There'll be no living with her
after this.
- But we've got to save Will.
- No.
You're safe now. We will return
to Port Royal immediately,
not go gallivanting after pirates.
Then we condemn him to death.
The boy's fate is regrettable, but
so is his decision to engage in piracy.
To rescue me. To prevent anything
from happening to me.
If I may be so bold as to interject
my professional opinion.
The Pearl was listing to scuppers after
the battle. She won't make good time.
Think about it. The Black Pearl.
The last real pirate threat
in the Caribbean, mate.
How can you pass that up?
By remembering that I serve others,
Mr. Sparrow, not only myself.
Commodore, I beg you,
please do this for me.
As a wedding gift.
Elizabeth?
Are you accepting
the Commodore's proposal?
I am.
A wedding. I love weddings.
Drinks all around!
I know. "Clap him in irons," right?
Mr. Sparrow, you will accompany
these fine men to the helm
and provide us with a bearing
to Isla de Muerta.
Then contemplate all possible meanings
of the phrase "silent as the grave".
- Do I make myself clear?
- Inescapably clear.
Shiver me timbers.
Cotton here says you missed a bit.
You knew William Turner.
Old Bootstrap Bill, we knew him.
Never sat well with Bootstrap, what we
did to Jack Sparrow, the mutiny and all.
He said it wasn't right with the Code.
That's why he sent off
a piece of the treasure to you.
He said we deserved to be cursed,
and remain cursed.
- Stupid blighter.
- Good man.
But, as you can imagine, that didn't
sit too well with the Captain.
That didn't sit too well
with the Captain at all.
- Tell him what Barbossa did.
- I'm telling the story!
So what the captain did, he strapped
a cannon to Bootstrap's bootstraps.
Bootstrap's bootstraps!
Last we saw of old Bill Turner, he was
sinking into the crushin' black oblivion
of Davy Jones' locker!
It was only after that we learned
we needed his blood to lift the curse.
That's what you call ironic.
Bring him.
I don't care for the situation.
Any attempt to storm the caves
could turn into an ambush.
Not if you're the one
doing the ambushing.
I go in and get Barbossa to send
his men out in their little boats.
Your mates return to the Dauntless
and blast them with your cannons.
What do you have to lose?
Nothing I'd lament being rid of.
Now, to be honest, there's a risk
to those aboard the Dauntless,
which includes the future Mrs. Commodore.
- It's for your own safety.
- I don't care, I have to tell him!
The pirates are cursed!
They can't be killed!
He's already informed of that. A mermaid
flopped up on deck and told the story.
This is Jack Sparrow's doing!
No reason to fret. A prick of the
finger, a few drops of blood...
No mistakes this time. He's only
half-Turner. We spill it all!
Guess there is reason to fret.
- Beg your pardon.
- Begun by blood. By blood...
Jack!
- It's not possible.
- Not probable.
Where's Elizabeth?
Safe, like I promised. She's set to
marry Norrington, like she promised,
and you get to die for her
like you promised.
So we're all men of our word, except
for Elizabeth, who is a woman.
Shut up! You're next!
- You don't want to be doing that.
- No, I think I do.
Your funeral.
- Why don't I want to be doing it?
- Because...
The HMS Dauntless,
pride of the Royal Navy,
is floating just offshore
waiting for you.
What are we doing here?
The pirates come out,
unprepared and unawares.
We catch 'em in a crossfire
and send 'em down to see Old Hob.
I meant, why aren't we doing
what Mr. Sparrow said we should do?
- With the cannons and all?
- Because it was Mr. Sparrow who said it.
You think he wasn't telling the truth?
Hear me out, mate.
Order your men to row out to the
Dauntless, they do what they do best,
Robert's your uncle, Fanny's your
aunt... There you are with two ships.
The makings of your own fleet.
You'll take the grandest as your
flagship and who's to argue?
But what of the Pearl?
Name me captain, I'll sail under your
colors and give you 10% of me plunder
and you get to introduce yourself
as Commodore Barbossa. Savvy?
And in exchange you want me
not to kill the whelp.
Not at all. By all means,
kill the whelp. Just not yet.
Wait to lift the curse
until the opportune moment.
For instance...
after you've killed Norrington's men.
Every...
last...
one.
You've planned this ever since
you learned my name.
Yeah.
I want 50% of your plunder.
- 15.
- 40.
25.
I'll buy you the hat.
A really big one.
Commodore.
We have an accord.
All hands to the boats!
Apologies. You give the orders.
Gents... take a walk!
Not to the boats?
Hold fire.
This is like what the Greeks
done at Troy.
Except they was in a horse,
instead of dresses. Wooden horse.
A moment, please.
Elizabeth?
I want you to know I believe you made
a very good decision today.
Couldn't be more proud of you.
But a good decision, if made for the
wrong reasons, can be a wrong decision.
Lieutenant.
Elizabeth?
Are you there?
Are you even listening to me?
What have you done?
Stop that! I already feel like a fool.
You look nice, though.
I look nice?
I must admit, Jack, I thought
I had you figured
but it turns out you're
a hard man to predict.
I'm dishonest. And a dishonest man
you can trust to be dishonest.
Honestly, it's the honest ones
you want to watch out for.
You can never predict when they're going
to do something incredibly... stupid.
You're off the edge of the map, mate.
Here there be monsters!
Right.
What would you eat first?
We should decide now so we're ready
when the time comes.
What was that?
Miss Elizabeth!
Make for the ship! Move!
To the ship!
Row, men!
You can't beat me, Jack.
That's interesting.
I couldn't resist, mate.
Sorry!
What now, Jack Sparrow?
Are we to be two immortals, locked
in an epic battle until Judgment Day?
Or you could surrender.
All of you with me. Will is in that cave
and we must save him.
Ready, and... heave!
I need your help. Come on!
Any port in a storm.
Cotton's right. We've got the Pearl.
- Are you gonna leave Jack?
- Jack owes us a ship.
- There's the Code to consider.
- The Code?
You're pirates. Hang the Code
and hang the rules!
They're more like guidelines.
Bloody pirates!
Is it supposed to be doing that?
They're stealing our ship.
Bloody pirates!
Boarders away.
Come on!
Me eye!
I'll teach you the meaning of pain.
You like pain?
Try wearing a corset.
Whose side is Jack on?
At the moment?
No fair!
Ten years you carry that pistol
and now you waste your shot.
He didn't waste it.
I feel...
cold.
Parley?
- The ship is ours, gentlemen.
- Huzzah!
Huzzah! Huzzah!
We should return to the Dauntless.
Your fiancé will want to know
you're safe.
If you were waiting
for the opportune moment...
that was it.
Now, I'd be much obliged
if you'd drop me off at my ship.
I'm sorry, Jack.
They done what's right by them.
Can't expect more than that.
Jack Sparrow...
Captain Jack Sparrow.
...for your crimes against the Crown.
Said crimes being numerous in quantity
and sinister in nature.
The most egregious of these
to be cited herewith:
Piracy, smuggling...
This is wrong.
Commodore Norrington is bound
by the law, as are we all.
...impersonating an officer
of the Spanish Royal Navy,
impersonating a cleric
of the Church of England,
sailing under false colors,
arson, kidnapping, looting,
poaching, brigandage, pilfering,
depravity, depredation
and general lawlessness.
For these crimes, you are sentenced
to be hung by the neck until dead.
May God have mercy on your soul.
Governor Swann.
Commodore.
Elizabeth.
I should have told you every day
from the moment I met you...
I love you.
Watch yourself!
Marines!
I can't breathe.
Elizabeth!
Move!
I thought we might have to endure
some ill-conceived escape attempt,
but not from you.
On our return to Port Royal,
I granted you clemency.
And this is how you thank me?
By throwing in your lot with him?
- He's a pirate.
- And a good man.
If this means the hangman will earn two
pairs of boots instead of one, so be it.
My conscience will be clear.
You forget your place, Turner.
It's right here, between you and Jack.
- As is mine.
- Elizabeth.
Lower your weapons.
Put them down!
So this is where your heart truly lies?
It is.
I'm feeling good about this.
We've all arrived at a special place.
Spiritually, ecumenically,
grammatically.
I want you to know
that I was rooting for you, mate.
Know that.
Elizabeth.
It would never have worked
between us, darling.
I'm sorry.
Will.
Nice hat.
Friends.
This is the day that you will always
remember as the day that...
Idiot. He's nowhere to go
but back to the noose.
Sail ho!
What's your plan of action?
Sir!
Perhaps on the rare occasion,
pursuing the right course
demands an act of piracy.
Piracy itself can be the right course.
Mr. Turner.
I will accept the consequences
of my actions.
This is a beautiful sword.
I expect the man who made it
to show the same care and devotion
in every aspect of his life.
Thank you.
Commodore! What about Sparrow?
I think we can afford to give him
one day's head start.
So...
This is the path you've chosen, is it?
After all, he is a blacksmith.
No.
He's a pirate.
Thought you were supposed
to keep to the Code?
We figured they were more
actual... guidelines.
Thank you.
Captain Sparrow.
The Black Pearl is yours.
On deck, you scabrous dogs! Hands
to braces! Let go and haul to run free!
Now... bring me that horizon.
And really bad eggs
Drink up, me hearties. Yo ho!