Oh I come from a land From a faraway place
Where the caravan camels roam
Where it's flat and immense And the heat is intense
It's barbaric, but hey--it's home!
When the wind's from the east and the sun's from the west
And the sand in the glass is right
Come on down, dance, Stop on by
Hop a carpet and fly
To another Arabian night!
Arabian nights
Like Arabian days
More often than not
Are hotter than hot In a lot of good ways
Arabian nights 'neath Arabian moons
A fool off his guard Could fall and fall hard
Out there on the dunes.
Ah, Salaam and good evening to you worthy friend.
Please, please, come closer--
Too close, a little too close.
There.
Welcome to Agrabah, City of mystery,
of enchantment, and the finest merchandise  this side
of the river Jordan,on sale today, come on down!
Look at this! Yes!
Combination hookah and coffee maker--
also makes Julienne fries
Will not break
It broke.
Look at this!
I have never seen one of these intact before.
This is the famous Dead Sea Tupperware
Listen.
Ah, still good.
Wait, don't go!
I can see that you're only interested
in the exceptionally rare.
I think then, you would be most rewarded to consider...
...this
Do not be fooled by its commonplace appearance.
Like so many things, it is not what is outside,
but what is inside that counts.
This is no ordinary lamp!
It once changed the course of a young man's life.
A young man who liked this lamp was more than what he seemed.
A diamond in the rough.
Perhaps you would like to hear the tale?
It begins on a dark night
where a dark man waits, with a dark purpose.
You...are late.
A thousand apologies, O patient one.
You have it, then?
I had to slit a few throats but I got it!
Ah, ah, ahhh!  The treasure!
Trust me, my pungent friend.
You'll get what's coming to you.
(What's coming to you!)
Quickly, follow the trail!
Faster!
At last, after all my years of searching,
the cave of wonders!
(Cave of wonders!)
By Allah!
Now, remember!  Bring me the lamp.
The rest of the treasure is yours, but the lamp is mine!
Jeez, where'd ya dig this bozo up?
Who disturbs my slumber?
It is I, Gazeem, a humble thief.
Know this.  Only one may enter here.
One whose worth lies far within.  A diamond in the rough.
What are you waiting for?  Go on!
Seek thee out, the diamond in the rough.
I can't believe it.  I just don't believe it.
We're never gonna get a hold of that stupid lamp!
Just forget it.
Look at this.  Look at this.  I'm so ticked off that I'm molting!
Patience, Iago.  Patience.
Gazeem was obviously less than worthy.
Oh, there's a big surprise.
That's an incred--
I think I'm gonna have a heart attack and die from not surprise!
What're we gonna do?  We got a big problem here,a big--
Yes.  Only one may enter.
I must find this one, this...diamond in the rough.
Stop, thief!
I'll have your hands for a trophy, street rat!
All this for a loaf of bread?
There he is!
-You won't get away so easy!
You think that was easy?
You two, over that way, and you, follow me.  We'll find him.
Morning, ladies.
Getting into trouble a little early today, aren't we Aladdin?
Trouble?  No way.
You're only in trouble if you get caught--
Gotcha!
I'm in trouble!
...and this time--
Perfect timing, Abu, as usual!
-Hello!
Come on, let's get outta here!
Gotta keep...one jump ahead of the breadline
One swing ahead of the sword
I steal only what I can't afford.
That's everything!
One jump ahead of the lawmen
That's all, and that's no joke,
These guys don't appreciate I'm broke!
Riffraff! Street rat!Scoundrel! Take that!
Just a little snack, guys!
Rip him open, take it back guys!
I can take a hint, gotta face the facts
You're my only friend, Abu!
-Who?!?
Oh, it's sad Aladdin's hit the bottom
He's become a one-man rise in crime
I'd blame parents, except he hasn't got 'em!
Gotta eat to live,gotta steal to eat,
Tell you all about it when I got the time!
One jump ahead of the slowpokes
One skip ahead of my doom
Next time gonna use a nom de plume.
-There he is!
One jump ahead of the hitmen
One hit ahead of the flock
I think I'll take a stroll around the block.
Stop, thief! Vandal! Outrage! Scandal!
Let's not be too hasty
Still I think he's rather tasty
Gotta eat to live, gotta steal to eat,
Otherwise we'd get along!
-WRONG!
He's got a sword!
You idiots--
we've ALL got swords!!
One jump ahead of the hoofbeats!
-Vandal!
One hop ahead of the hump!
-Street rat!
One trick ahead of disaster!
-Scoundrel!
They're quick--but I'm much faster
-Take that!
Here goes, better throw my hand in
Wish me happy landin',all I gotta do is...
jump!
SNIŽENO GNOJIVO
And now, esteemed effendi, we feast!  All right!
Here, go on--take it.
On his way to the palace, I suppose.
Another suitor for the princess.
Out of my way, you filthy brat!
Hey, if I were as rich as you, I could afford some manners
Oh--I teach you some manners!
Look at that, Abu.
It's not every day you see a horse with two rear ends!
You are a worthless street rat.
You were born a street rat, you'll die a street rat,
and only your fleas will mourn you.
I'm not worthless.  And I don't have fleas.
Come on, Abu.  Let's go home.
Riffraff, street rat. I don't buy that.
If only they'd look closer
Would they see a poor boy?  No siree.
They'd find out, there's so much more to me.
Someday, Abu, things are gonna change.
We'll be rich, live in a palace, and never have any problems at all.
I've never been so insulted!
Oh, Prince Achmed.  You're not leaving so soon, are you?
Good luck marrying her off!
Oh, Jasmine!
Jasmine!
Confound it, Rajah!
So, this is why Prince Achmed stormed out!
Oh, father.  Rajah was just playing with him, weren't you Rajah.
You were just playing with that overdressed,
self-absorbed Prince Achmed, weren't you?
Dearest, you've got to stop rejecting every suitor that comes to call.
The law says you...
...must be married to a prince...
...By your next birthday.
The law is wrong.
You've only got three more days!
Father,  I hate being forced into this.
If I do marry, I want it to be for love.
Jasmine, it's not only this law.
I'm not going to be around forever,...and I...
I just want to make sure you're taken care of, provided for.
Please, try to understand.  I've never done a thing on my own.
I've never had any real friends.
Except you, Rajah.
I've never even been outside the palace walls.
But Jasmine, you're a princess.
Then maybe I don't want to be a princess anymore!
Allah forbid you should have any daughters!
I don't know where she gets it from.
Her mother wasn't nearly so picky.
Ah, Jafar--my most trusted advisor.
I am in desperate need of your wisdom.
My life is but to serve you, my lord.
It's this suitor business.
Jasmine refuses to choose a husband.  I'm at my wit's-end.
Wit's-end.
Have a cracker, pretty polly!
Your majesty certainly has a way with dumb animals.
Now then, perhaps I can divine a solution to this thorny problem.
If anyone can help, it's you.
Ah, but it would require the use of the mystic blue diamond.
Uh, my ring?
But it's been in the family for years.
It is necessary to find the princess a suitor.
Don't worry.  Everything will be fine.
- Everything will be fine.
The diamond.
Here, Jafar. Whatever you need
will be fine.
You are most gracious, my liege.
Now run along and play with your little toys.
Yes...that'll be...pretty good.
I can't take it anymore!
If I gotta choke down on one more of those moldy, disgusting crackers...
bam!
Calm yourself, Iago.
-Then I'd grab him around the head.
Soon, I will be sultan, not that addlepated twit.
-And then I stuff the crackers down his throat!
Oh, I'm sorry, Rajah.
But I can't stay here and have my life lived for me.
I'll miss you.
Good bye!
Okay, Abu.  Go!
Try this, your taste buds will dance and sing.
Hey, get your paws off that.
Why, you!  Get away from here, you filthy ape!
Bye bye!
Nice goin' Abu.  Breakfast is served.
Pretty lady, buy a pot.  No finer pot in brass or silver.
Sugar dates, sugar dates and figs!
Sugar dates and pistachios!
Would the lady like a necklace.
A pretty necklace for a pretty lady.
Fresh fish!  We catch 'em, you buy 'em!
I don't think so.
Oh, excuse me.
I'm really very sorry.
Oh, you must be hungry.
Here you go.
You'd better be able to pay for that.
Pay?
No one steals from my cart!
Oh, I'm sorry sir.
I don't have any money.
Thief!
Please, if you let me go to the palace,
I can get some from the Sultan.
Do you know what the penalty is for stealing?
No, no please!
Thank you kind sir.  I'm so glad you've found her.
I've been looking all over for you.
What are you doing?
Just play along.
You know this girl?
Sadly, yes.  She is my sister.  She's a little crazy.
She said she knows the Sultan!
She thinks the monkey is the Sultan.
-Oh, wise Sultan.  How may I serve you?
Tragic, isn't it?
But, no harm done.
Now come along sis. Time to see the doctor.
Oh, hello doctor. How are you?
No, no, no. Not that one.
Come on, Sultan.
What is it?
Come back here, you little thieves!
With all due respect, your rottenness,
couldn't we just wait for a real storm?
Save your breath, Iago.  Faster!
Yes, o mighty evil one.
Ah, sands of time--reveal to me
the one who can enter the cave.
Yes, yes!
There he is.
My diamond in the rough!
That's him?!?!
That's the clown we've been waitin' for?
Let's have the guards extend him
an invitation to the palace, shall we?
Swell.
Almost there.
I want to thank you for stopping that man.
Uh, forget it.
So, uh, this is your first time in the marketplace, huh?
Is it that obvious?
Well, you do kinda stand out.  I mean,
you don't seem to know how dangerous Agrabah can be.
I'm a fast learner.
C'mon, this way.
Watch your head there.  Be careful.
Is this where you live?
Yep.  Just me and Abu.  Come and go as we please.
That sounds fabulous.
Well, it's not much, but it's got a great view.
Palace looks pretty amazing, huh?
Oh, it's wonderful.
I wonder what it would be like to live there,
to have servants and valets...
Oh, sure.   People who tell you
where to go and how to dress.
It's better than here.
Always scraping for food and ducking the guards.
You're not free to make your own choices.
Sometimes you feel so--
You're just--
--trapped.
So, where're you from?
What does it matter?
I ran away, and I am not going back.
Really?
How come?
My father's forcing me to get married.
That's--that's awful.
Abu!
What?
Abu says that--
--that's not fair.
Oh did he?
-Yeah, of course.
And does Abu have anything else to say?
Well, uh, he wishes
there was something he could do to help.
Hmm, tell him that's very sweet.
Here you are!
They've found me!
They're after you?
My father must have sent them--
Do you trust me?
What?
Yes.
Then jump!
We just keep running into each other, don't we, street rat?
Run!
Go! Get out of here!
It's the dungeon for you, boy.
Hey, get off of me!
Lethim go!
Look what we have here, men--a street mouse.
Unhand him, by order of the princess.
Princess Jasmine.
The princess?
What are you doing outside the palace?
And with this street rat?
That's not your concern.  Do as I command.
Release him!
Well, I would, princess,except my orders come from Jafar.
You'll have to take it up with him.
Believe me, I will.
Jafar?
Oh, uh, princess.
Jafar, I'm stuck!
How may I be of service to you?
The guards just took a boy from the market, on your orders.
Your father's charged me with keeping peace in Agrabah.
The boy was a criminal.
What was his crime?
I can't breathe, Jafar!
Why, kidnapping the princess, of course.
If you could just--
--wow, that hurt!
He didn't kidnap me! I ran away!
Oh, dear!  Oh, how frightfully upsetting.
Had I but known.
What do you mean?
Sadly, the boy's sentence has already been carried out.
What sentence?
Death.
By beheading.
No!
I am exceedingly sorry, princess.
How could you?
So, how did  it go?
I think she took it ...
...rather well.
It's all my fault, Rajah.
I didn't even know his name.
She was the princess.  I can't believe it.
I must have sounded so stupid to her.
Abu!  Down here!
Hey, c'mon--help me outta these.
Hey, she was in trouble. Ah, she was worth it.
Don't worry, Abu.  I'll never see her again.
I'm a street rat, remember, and there's a law.
She's gotta marry a prince, she deserves a prince.
I'm a--I'm a fool
You're only a fool if you give up, boy.
Who are you?
A lowly prisoner, like yourself.  But together,
perhaps we can be more.
I'm listening.
There is a cave, boy.  A cave of wonders.
Filled with treasures beyond your wildest dreams.
Treasure enough to impress even your princess, I'd wager.
Jafar, can ya hurry it up? I'm dyin' in here!
But the law says that only a prince can--
You've heard of the golden rule, haven't you?
Whoever has the gold makes the rules.
So why would you share
all of this wonderful treasure with me?
I need a young pair of legs
and a strong back to go in after it.
Ah, one problem.  It's out there, we're in here?
Things aren't always what they seem.
So, do we have a deal?
Who disturbs my slumber?
It is I, Aladdin.
Proceed.  Touch nothing but the lamp.
Remember, boy--first fetch me the lamp,
and then you shall have your reward.
C'mon, Abu.
Would ya look at that!
Just a handful of this stuff
would make me richer than the sultan!
Don't...touch...anything!  We gotta find that lamp.
Abu, will ya knock it off?
Abu, what are you--crazy?
A magic carpet!  C'mon.  C'mon out.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
Take it easy, Abu.  He's not gonna bite.
Hey, wait a minute.Don't go.
Maybe you can help us.
You see, we're trying to find this lamp.
I think he knows where it is.
Wait here!
This is it?  This is what we came all the way down here to--
Abu-
NO!
Infidels!
You have touched the forbidden treasure.
Now you will never again see the light of day!
Carpet, let's move!
Abu, this is no time to panic!
Start panicking.
Help me out!
Throw me the lamp!
I can't hold on.  Give me your hand.
First give me the lamp!
Yes!  At last!
What are you doing?
Giving you your reward.
Your eternal reward.
It's mine.  It's all mine!---
where is it?  No.
NO!!
Jasmine?
Oh, dearest.  What's wrong?
Jafar...has...done something... terrible.
There, there, there, my dear--we'll set it right.
Now, tell me everything.
Oh, my head.
We're trapped. That two faced son-of-a-jackal!
Whoever he was, he's long gone with that lamp.
Why, you hairy little thief!
Looks like such a beat-up, worthless piece of junk.
Hey, I think there's something written here,
but it's hard to make out.
Aaaaahhhhh!  OY!
Ten-thousand years will give ya such a crick in the neck!
Hang on a second!
Whoa!  Does it feel good to be outta there!
I'm telling ya, nice to be back, ladies and gentlemen.
Hi, where ya from?
What's your name?
Uh, Al--uh--Aladdin.
-Aladdin!
Hello, Aladdin.  Nice to have you on the show.
Can we call you 'Al?' Or maybe just 'Din?'
Or how bout Laddi? Sounds like 'Here, boy!
C'mon, Laddi!'
I must have hit my head harder than I thought.
Do you smoke?  Mind if I do?
Oh, sorry Cheetah--hope I didn't singe the fur!
Yo, Rugman!  Haven't seen you in a few millennia!
Slap me some tassel!
Say, you're a lot smaller than my last master.
Either that or I'm gettin' bigger.
Look at me from the side--do I look different to you?
-Wait a minute!  I'm--your master?
That's right!  He can  be taught!!
What would you wish of me,
the ever impressive, the long contained,
often imitated, but never duplicated--
Duplicated, duplicated,  duplicated, duplicated,  duplicated,  duplicated, duplicated, duplicated, duplicated.
Genie Of The Lamp!
Right here direct from the lamp,
right here for your enjoyment wish fulfillment.Thank youuuuu!
Wish fulfillment?
-Three wishes to be exact.
And ix-nay on the wishing for more wishes.
Uno, dos, tres.No substitutions, exchanges or refunds.
Now I know I'm dreaming.
Master, I don't think you quite realize what you've got here!
So why don't you just ruminate,
whilst I illuminate the possibilities.
Well Ali Baba had them forty thieves
Scheherazadie had a thousand tales,
But master you in luck 'cause up your sleeve,
You got a brand of magic never fails!
You got some power in your corner now
Some heavy ammunition in your camp
You got some punch, pizzazz, yahoo and how,
See all you gotta do is rub that lamp, and I'll say
Mister Aladdin sir, What will your pleasure be?
Let me take your order, jot it down
You ain't never had a friend like me!
Life is your restaurant, and I'm your maitre' d!
C'mon whisper what it is you want
You ain't never had a friend like me.
Yes sir, we pride ourselves on service
You're the boss, the king, the shah!
Say what you wish,  it's yours! True dish
How about a little more Baklava?
Try some of column 'A'Try all of column 'B'
I'm in the mood to help you dude
You ain't never had a friend like me
Can your friends do this?
Do your friends do that?
Do your friends pull this
out their little hat
Can your friends go poof!
Well looky here
Can your friends go Abracadabra, let 'er rip
And then make the sucker disappear?
So don't you sit there slack jawed, buggy eyed
I'm here to answer all your midday prayers
You got me bona fide, certified,
You got a genie for a charg d'affairs!
I got a powerful urge to help you out
So what you wish I really want to know
You got a list that's three miles long, no doubt,
Well So all you gotta do is rub like so, and oh!
Mister Aladdin, sir, have a wish or two or three
I'm on the job, you big nabob
You ain't never had a friend, never had a friend
You ain't never had a friend, never had a friend, You ain't
Never...
Had a...
Friend...
like...me!
PLJESAK
So what'll it be, master?
You're gonna grant me any three wishes I want, right?
-Ah, almost.  There are a few provisos, a couple of quid pro quos
Like?
-Ah, rule number one: I can't kill anybody.
So don't ask.
Rule number  two: I can't make anybody fall in love
with anybody else.
You little punim, there.
Rule three: I can't bring people back from the dead.
It's not a pretty picture, I don't like doing it!
Other than that, you got it
Ah, provisos?
You mean limitations?  On wishes?
Some all powerful genie--can't even bring people back from the dead.
I don't know, Abu--he probably can't even get us out of this cave.
Looks like we're gonna have to find a way out of here--
Excuse me?  Are you lookin' at me?
Did you rub my lamp?
Did you wake me up, did you bring me here?
And all of a sudden, you're walkin' out on me?
Idon't think so, not right now.
You're gettin' your wishes, so siddown!
In case of emergency, the exits are here, here, here,
here,here, here, here, here, here, here, here, here, anywhere!
Keep your hands and arms inside the carpet.
Weeee'rrrrrreee...
outta here!
Jafar, this is an outrage.
If it weren't for all your years of loyal service...
From now on, you are to discuss sentencing of prisoners with me,
before they are beheaded.
I assure you, your highness, it won't happen again.
Jasmine, Jafar, now let's put this whole messy business behind us.
Please?
My most abject and humblest apologies to you as well, princess.
-At least some good will come of my being forced to marry.
When I am queen, I will have the power to get rid of you.
Well, now, that's nice.  All settled, then.
Now, Jasmine, getting back to this suitor business,
Jasmine?
If only I had gotten that lamp!
I will have the power to get rid of you!
To think--we gotta keep kissing up to that scum,
and his chump daughter for the rest of our lives...
No, Iago.  Only until she finds a chump husband.
Then she'll have us banished--or beheaded!
Wait a minute!  Wait a minute! Jafar?
What if YOU were the chump husband?
What?
Okay, you marry the princess,all right?
Then, uh, you become sultan!
Marry the shrew?  I become the sultan.
The idea has merit!
-Yes, merit! Yes!
And then we drop papa-in-law and the little woman off a cliff!
Iago, I love the way your foul little mind works!
Thank you for choosing Magic Carpet for all your travel needs.
Don't stand until the rug has come to a complete stop.
Thank you.  Good bye, good bye!  Thank you! Good bye!
Well, now.  How about that, Mr.  doubting mustafa?
Oh, you sure showed me.
Now about my three wishes--
Dost mine ears deceive me?  Three?
You are down by ONE, boy!
Ah, no--I never actually wished to get out of the cave.
You did that on your own.
Well, don't I feel just sheepish?
All right, you baaaaad boy,  but no more freebies.
Fair deal.  So, three wishes.  I want them to be good.
What would you wish for?
Me?  No one's ever asked me that before.
Well, in my case, ah, forget it.
What?  C'mon, tell me.
Freedom.
You're a prisoner?
It's all part-and-parcel, the whole genie gig.
Phenomenal cosmic powers!
Itty bitty living space
Genie, that's terrible.
But, oh--to be free.
Not have to go "Poof! What do you need?
Poof! What do you need? Poof! What do you need?"
To be my own master, such a thing would be greater
than all the magic and all the treasures in all  the world!
But what am I talking about?  Let's get real here.
It's not gonna happen. Genie, wake up and smell the hummus
Why not?
-The only way I get outta this is if my master wishes me out.
So you can guess how often that's happened.
I'll do it. I'll set you free.
-Aha, yeah, right.
No, really, I promise. After make my first two wishes,
I'll use my third wish to set you free.
Well, here's hopin'.
Alright.
Let's make some magic!
So how 'bout it?
What is it you want most?
Well, there's this girl--
Wrong!
I can't make anybody fall in love, remember?
Oh, but Genie.  She's smart and fun and...
Pretty?
- Beautiful.
She's got these eyes that just...and this hair,
...and her smile.
Ami.  C'est l'amour.
But she's the princess.  To even have a chance, I'd have to be a--
hey,
can you make me a prince?
Let's see here. Uh, chicken a'la king? Nope.
Alaskan king crab? Ow, I hate it when they do that.
Caesar's salad? Et tu, Brute? No!
Aha, to make a prince. Now is that an official wish?
Say the magic words!
Genie, I wish for you to make me a prince!
All right!
First, that fez and vest combo is much too third century.
These patches--what are we trying to say--beggar?  No!
Let's work with me here.
I like it, muy macho!
Now, still needs something.
What does it say to me? It says...
mode of transportation!
Excuse me, monkey boy!  Aqui; over here!
Here he comes,And what better way
to make your grand entrance on the streets of Agrabah,
than... riding your very own brand new...
camel!  Watch out, they spit!
Hm, not enough.
Still not enough. Let's see.  What do you need, what you need?
Yes!!  Esalalumbo,  shimin dumbo!
Talk about your trunk space, check this action out!
Abu, you look good.
He's got the outfit, he's got the elephant,
but we're not through yet.
Hang on to your turban, kid, we're gonna make you a star!
Sir, I have found a solution to the problem with your daughter.
Oh, really?
Right here.
"If the princess has not chosen a husband by the appointed time,
then the sultan shall choose for her."
But Jasmine hated all those suitors!
How could I choose someone she hates?
-Not to worry, my liege.There is more.
If, in the event a suitable prince cannot be found,
a princess must then be wed to...
...hmm...interesting.
What?  Who?
-The royal vizier!  Why, that would be...me!
But, I thought the law says that only a prince
can marry a princess, I'm quite sure.
Desperate times call for desperate measures, my lord.
Yes...desperate measures...
You will order the princess to marry me.
I...will order...the princess...to...
...but you're so old!
The princess will marry me!
The princess will marry...
What? What is that?
That music!
Jafar, you must come see this!
Make way for Prince Ali!
Say hey!  It's Prince Ali!
Hey, clear the way in the old bazaar,
Hey you, let us through, it's a bright new star,
Oh, come, be the first on your block to meet his eye!
Make way, here he comes, ring bells, bang the drums,
You're gonna love this guy
Prince Ali, fabulous he, Ali Ababwa!
Genuflect, show some respect, Down on one knee
Now try your best to stay calm
Brush up your Sunday Salaam
Then come and meet his spectacular coterie.
Prince Ali, mighty is he, Ali Ababwa!
Strong as ten regular men, definitely
He faced the galloping hordes
A hundred bad guys with swords
Who sent those goons to their lords,
why Prince Ali!
He's got seventy-five golden camels!
-Don't they look lovely, June?
Purple peacocks, he's got fifty-three!
-Fabulous, Harry, I love the feathers!
When it comes to exotic type mammals
Has he got a zoo, I'm telling you
It's a world class menagerie!
Prince Ali, Handsome is he, Ali Ababwa
That physique, how can I speak Weak at the knee
Well, get on out in that square
Adjust your veil and prepare
To gawk and grovel and stare at Prince Ali!
He's got ninety-five white Persian monkeys!
(He's got the monkeys, let's see the monkeys!)
And to view them, he charges no fee!
(He's generous, so generous)
He's got slaves, he's got servants and flunkies!
(Proud to work for him)
They bow to his whim, love serving him
They're just lousy with loyalty to Ali!
Prince Ali!
Prince Ali! Amorous he!  Ali Ababwa
Heard your princess was a sight lovely to see!
And that, good people, is why
He got dolled up and dropped by
With sixty elephants, llamas galore
With his bears and lions, A brass band and more
With his forty fakirs, his cooks, his bakers
His birds that warble on key,
Make way
for HIM, for HIM!!
Splendid, absolutely marvelous.
Your majesty, I have journeyed from afar
to seek your daughter's hand.
Prince Ali Ababwa!  Of course.  I'm delighted to meet you.
This is my royal vizier, Jafar.  He's delighted too.
Ecstatic.
I'm afraid, Prince Abooboo--
--Ababwa!
Whatever.  You cannot just parade in here uninvited and expect to--
- By Allah, this is quite a remarkable device.
I don't suppose I might...
Why certainly, your majesty.  Allow me.
Sire, I must advise against this--
--Oh, button up, Jafar.  Learn to have a little fun.
Just where did you say you were from?
Oh, much farther than you've traveled, I'm sure.
Try me.
(- Look out, Polly!)
Hey, watch it. Watch it with the dumb rug!
Out of the way, I'm coming in to land.  Jafar, watch this!
Spectacular, your highness.
Ooh, it was lovely.
Yes, I do seem to have a knack for it.
This is a very impressive youth. And a prince, besides.
If we're lucky, you won't have to marry Jasmine after all.
I don't trust him, sire.
Nonsense.  One thing I pride myself on Jafar,
I'm an excellent judge of character.
Oh, excellent judge, yeah, sure...
NOT!!!
Jasmine will like this one!
-And I'm pretty sure I'll like Princess Jasmine!
Your highness, no.  I must intercede on Jasmine's behalf.
This boy is no different from the others.
What makes him think he is worthy of the princess?
-Your majesty, I am Prince Ali Ababwa! Just let her meet me.
I will win your daughter!
-How dare you!
All of you, standing around deciding my future?
I am not a prize to be won!
Oh, dear.  Don't worry, Prince Ali.
Just give Jasmine time to cool down.
I think it's time to say good bye to Prince Abooboo.
What am I going to do?  Jasmine won't even let me talk to her.
I should have known I couldn't pull off this stupid prince wish.
So move!
That's a good move.
I can't believe it--I'm losing to a rug.
Genie, I need help.
-All right, sparky, here's the deal.
If you wanna court the little lady,
you gotta be a straight shooter, do ya got it?
What?
-Tell her the ...
TRUTH!!!
-No way! If Jasmine found out I was really some crummy street rat,
she'd laugh at me.
A woman appreciates a man who can make her laugh!
Al, all joking aside, you really oughtta be yourself.
-Hey, that's the last thing I want to  be.
OK, I'm gonna go see her...I just...
I gotta be smooth, cool, confident.
How do I look?
Like...
a prince.
Princess Jasmine?
Who's there?
-It's me--Prince Ali.
Prince Ali Ababwa.
I do not want to see you.
-No, no, please princess. Give me a chance.
Just leave me alone.
Down kitty!
How's our beau doing?
Good kitty, take off.  Down kitty.
Wait, wait.  Do I know you?
Uh, no, no.
You remind me of someone I met in  the marketplace.
The marketplace?  I have servants that go to the marketplace for me.
Why I even have servants who go to the marketplace
for my servants, so it couldn't have been me you met.
No, I guess not.
Enough about you, Casanova.  Talk about her!
She's smart,  fun, the hair, the eyes.
Anything--pick a feature!
Um, Princess Jasmine?  You're very...
-Wonderful,  magnificent, glorious, punctual!
Punctual!
-Punctual?
Sorry.
-Beautiful.
-Nice recovery.
I'm rich too, you know.
Yeah!
The daughter of a sultan
I know.
A fine prize for any  prince to marry.
Uh, right.  Right.  A prince like me.
Warning! Warning!
Right, a prince like you.  And every other stuffed  shirt,
swaggering, peacock I've met!
Mayday! Mayday!
Just go jump off a balcony!
What?
-Stop her! Stop her!  Want me to sting her?
Buzz off!
Okay, fine. But remember--bee yourself!
Yeah, right!
- What!?!
Uh, you're right.
You aren't just some prize to be won.
You should be free to make your own choice.
I'll go now.
No!
What?  What?
How--how are you doing that?
It's a magic carpet.
It's lovely.
You, uh, you don't want to go for a ride, do you?
We could get out of the palace, see the world.
Is it safe?
-Sure.  Do you trust me?
What?
-Do you trust me?
Yes.
I can show you the world
Shining, shimmering, splendid.
Tell me princess, now when did you last
Let your heart decide?
I can open your eyes
Take you wonder by wonder
Over, sideways, and under
On a magic carpet ride
A whole new world!
A new fantastic point of view
No one to tell us no
Or where to go
Or say we're only dreaming
A whole new world
A dazzling place I never knew
But when I'm way up here
It's crystal clear
That now I'm in a whole new world with you!
Now I'm in a whole new world with you!
Unbelievable sights, Indescribable feeling
Soaring, tumbling, freewheeling
Through an endless diamond sky
A whole new world!
-Don't you dare close your eyes
A hundred thousand things to see
(-Hold your breath--it gets better!)
I'm like a shooting star,
I've come so far
I can't go back to where I used to be!
-A whole new world!
-Every turn a surprise
With new horizons to pursue
-Every moment, red-letter
I'll chase them anywhere,There's time to spare
Let me share this whole new world with you
A whole new world
That's where we'll be
A thrilling chase, A wondrous place
For you and me!
It's all so magical.
-Yeah.
It's a shame Abu had to miss this.
Nah.  He hates fireworks.
He doesn't really like flying either.
That is...oh no!
You are the boy from the market!  I knew it.
Why did you lie to me?
Jasmine, I'm sorry.
-Did you think I was stupid?
-No!
That I wouldn't figure it out?
-No.  I mean, I hoped you wouldn't.
No, that's not what I meant.
Who are you?  Tell me the truth!
The truth?
The truth...the truth is...
I sometimes dress as a commoner
to escape the pressures of palace life.
But I really am a prince!
-Why didn't you just tell me?
Well, you know, um...royalty going out into the city in disguise,
it sounds a little strange, don't you think?
Not that strange.
Good night, my handsome prince.
Sleep well, princess.
Yes!
For the first time in my life, things are starting to go right.
Hold him!
I'm afraid you've worn out your welcome, Prince  Abooboo.
Make sure he's never found.
Never fails.  Get in the bath and there's a rub at the lamp.
Hello. Al?  Al!  Kid, snap out of it!
You can't cheat on this one!  I can't help you unless you make a wish.
You have to say
"Genie I want you to save my life."  Got it?  Okay.  C'mon Aladdin!!
I'll take that as a yes. Up scope!
Don't you scare me like that!
Genie, I--uh, I-uh...
Thanks, Genie.
Oh, Al.  I'm gettin' kind of fond of you, kid.
Not that I want to pick out curtains or anything.
Jasmine!
Oh, father--I just had the most wonderful time. I'm so happy.
You should be, Jasmine. I have chosen a husband for you.
-What?
You will wed Jafar.
You're speechless, I see.  A fine quality in a wife.
I will never marry you.
Father, I choose Prince Ali!
Prince Ali left!
Better check your crystal ball  again, Jafar!
Prince Ali!
How in the he--
Tell them the truth, Jafar!  You tried to have me killed.
What?  Ridiculous nonsense, your highness.  He is obviously lying.
Obviously...lying.
Father, what's wrong with you?
I know what's wrong!
Your highness, Jafar's been controlling you with this!
What?  Jafar?  You, you traitor!
Your majesty, all of this can be explained.
Guards! Guards!
Well, that's it--we're dead, forget it.
Just dig a grave for both of us.  We're dead.
Arrest Jafar at once!
This is not done yet, boy!
Find him, search everywhere!
Jasmine, are you all right?
Jafar, my most trusted counselor,
plotting against me all this time. This is horrible, just horrible.
How will I ever-
Can this be true?
My daughter has finally chosen a suitor?
Praise Allah!  You brilliant boy, I could kiss you!
I won't--I'll leave that to my--.
But you two will be wed at once!
Yes, yes.  And you'll be happy and prosperous,
and then my boy, you will become sultan!
Sultan?
-Yes, a fine upstanding youth like yourself,
a person of your unimpeachable moral character
is exactly what this kingdom needs!
We gotta get outta here!  We gotta get--
I gotta start packing, your highness.
Only essentials.We gotta travel at light!
Bring the guns,the weapons, the knives!
And how about this picture?
I don't know--I think I'm making a weird face in it.
Oh, boy--  He's cracked.
He's gone nuts.
Jafar? Jafar? Get a grip!
Good grip!
Prince Ali is nothing more than that ragged urchin Aladdin.
He has the lamp, Iago.
-Why that miserable--
But you are going to relieve him of it!
Me?
Sultan?  They want me to be sultan?
Hail the conquering hero!
Aladdin, you've just won the heart of the princess.
What are you gonna do next?
Psst, your line is "I'm going to free the genie."
Anytime.
Genie...I can't.
Sure you can.  You just go "Genie, I wish you free."
I'm serious.  Look, I'm sorry--I really am.
But they want to make me sultan--no!,
They want to make Prince Ali sultan.
Without you, I'm just Aladdin.
Al, you won!
Because of you! The only reason
anyone thinks I'm worth anything is because of you.
What if they find outI'm not really a prince?
What if Jasmine finds out?
I'd lose her.  Genie, I can't keep this up on my own.
I...I can't wish you free.
Fine, I understand.
After all, you've lied to everyone else.
Hey, I was beginning to feel left out.
Now, if you'll excuse me, MASTER.
Genie, I'm really sorry...
Well, fine!! Then just stay in there!
What are you guys looking at?
Look, I--I'm sorry. Abu--
I'm sorry, I didn't-- wait, c'mon.
What am I doing?
Genie's right--
I gotta tell Jasmine the truth.
Ali, oh Ali--will you come here?
Well, here goes.
Jasmine?  Where are you?
--In the menagerie, hurry.
-I'm coming.
Ya got a problem, pinky?
Boy, Jafar's gonna be happy to see you!
Excellent work, Iago!
Ah, go on. -No, really--on a scale of one to ten, you are eleven.
Ah, Jafar--you're too kind.  I'm embarrassed, I'm  blushing.
People of Agrabah, My daughter has finally chosen a  suitor!
Jasmine?
Ali, where have you been?
Jasmine, there's something I've got to tell you.
The whole kingdom has turned out for father's announcement!
No! But Jasmine,
listen to me, please! You don't understand--
-Good luck!
...Ali Ababwa!
-Oh, boy!
Look at them, cheering that little pipsqueak.
Let them cheer.
You know Al, I'm getting reallyyyyyy--
I don't think you're him.
Tonight, the part of Al will be played by a tall,
dark and sinister ugly man.
I am your master now.
I was afraid of that.
Genie, grant me my first wish.
I wish to rule on high, as sultan!!!
Bless my soul.  What is this?  What is going on?
-Father!
Jafar, you vile betrayer.
That's Sultan Vile Betrayer to you.
Oh, yeah?  Well, we'll just see about that!
The lamp!
Finders-keepers, Abooboo.
Genie!  No!
Sorry, kid--I got a new master now.
Jafar, I order you to stop!
Oh, but there's a new order now--
MY order!
Finally, YOU will bow to ME!
-We'll never bow to you!
Why am I not surprised?
If you will not bow before a sultan,
then you will cower before a sorcerer!
Genie, my second wish--
I wish to be the most powerful sorcerer
IN THE WORLD!!!
Genie, stop!
Ladies and gentlemen, a warm Agrabah welcome for
Sorcerer Jafar!
Now where were we?  Ah, yes--abject humiliation!
Down, boy!
Oh, princess--
--there's someone I'm dying to introduce you to.
Jafar!  Get your hands off her!
Prince Ali,Yes, it is he,
But not as you know him.
Read my lips and come to grips With reality
Yes, meet a blast from your past
Whose lies were too good to last
Say hello to your precious Prince Ali!
Or should we say Aladdin?
- Ali?
-Jasmine, I tried to tell you, I'm just--
So Ali turns out to be merely Aladdin.
Just a con, need I go on? Take it from me
His personality flaws.
Give me adequate cause
To send him packing on a one-way trip,
So his prospects take a terminal dip
His assets frozen, the venue chosen
Is the ends of the earth, whoopee! So long,
Good bye, see ya!
-Ex-Prince Ali!
Abu?
Abu!
Oh, this is all my fault--
I--
I should have freed the genie when I had the chance.
Abu!
Are you okay?
I'm sorry, Abu--I made a mess of everything...somehow.
I gotta go back and set things right.
Carpet!
Abu, start digging!
That's it!
Yeah! Alright!
Now, back to Agrabah!  Let's go!
Puppet ruler want a cracker? Here's your cracker.
Shove 'em all right down your throat.  Here, have lots of crackers!
Stop it!
Jafar, Leave him alone!
It pains me to see you reduced to this, Jasmine.
A beautiful desert bloom such as yourself
should be on the arm of the most powerful man in the world.
What do  you say, my dear?
Why,  with you as my queen...
Never!
I'll teach you some respect!
No...
Genie, I have decided to make my final wish.
I wish for Princess Jasmine to fall desperately in  love with me.
Ah, master-- there are a few addendas, some quid pro quo-
Don't talk back to me, you big blue lout!
You will do what I order you to do, slave!
Jafar!
I never realized how incredibly handsome you are.
That's better.
Now, pussycat, tell me more about...myself.
You're...tall, dark...
... well dressed...
Al!  Al, little buddy!
Al, I can't help you--I work for senor psychopath, now.
What are you gonna do?
Hey--I'm a street rat, remember?
I'll improvise.
Go on.
And your beard...is so...
twisted!
And the street rat?
What street rat?
That was--
You!!  How many times do I have to kill you, boy?
Get the lamp!
NO!
Princess--
Your time is up!
Jasmine!
Oh, nice shot, Jaf--
Don't toy with me!
Abu!
Things are unraveling fast, now boy.
Get the point?
I'm just getting warmed up!
Are you afraid to fight me yourself, you cowardly  snake?
A snake, am I?
Perhaps you'd like to see how snake-like I can be!
Rickem, rockem, rackem, rake--stick that sword into  that snake!
You stay out of it!
-Jafar, Jafar, he's our man--if he can't do it,
GREAT!
Aladdin!
Jasmine, hang on!
You little fool!
You thought  you could defeat the most
powerful being on earth!
Squeeze him, Jafar--Squeeze him like a--!
Without the Genie, boy, you're nothing!
-The genie!
The genie!
The genie has more power than you'll ever have!
What!!?
- He gave you your power, he can take it away!
Al, what are you doing?
Why are you bringing me into this?
Face it, Jafar--you're still just second best!
You're right!  His power does exceed my own!
But not for long!
The boy is crazy.  He's a little punch drunk.
One too many hits with the snake
Slave, I make my third wish!  I wish to be...
an all powerful genie!
All right, your wish is my command.
Way to go, Al.
Yes! Yes!
The power!
The absolute power!
What have you done?
-Trust me!
The universe is mine to command, to control!
Not so fast, Jafar!
Aren't you forgetting something?
You wanted to be a genie, you got it!
-What?
And everything that goes with it!
-No!  No!
I'm gettin' out of here!
-Phenomenal cosmic powers!
-Come on, you're the genie, I don't want---
-Itty bitty living space.
-Al, you little genius, you!
Get your blasted beak out of my face!
Oh, shut up, you moron!
Don't tell me to shut up!
-Allow me.
Ten- thousand years
in a cave of wonders ought to chill him out!
Jasmine, I'm sorry I lied to you about being a prince.
I know why you did.
Well, I guess...
this... is goodbye?
Oh, that stupid law.  This isn't fair--I love you.
Al, no problem. You've still got one wish left.
Just say the word and you're a prince again.
But Genie, what about your freedom?
Hey, it's only an eternity of servitude.
This...is love.
Al, you're not gonna find another girl like her in a million years.
Believe me, I know.  I've looked.
Jasmine, I do love you, but I've got to stop
pretending to be something I'm not.
I understand.
Genie, I wish for your freedom.
-One bona fide prince pedigree coming up--  I--what?
Genie, you're free!
I'm free. I'm free.
Quick, quick, wish for something outrageous.
Say  "I...I want the Nile."   Wish for the Nile.  Try that!
-I wish for the Nile.
-No way!!
Oh does that feel good!
I'm free!  I'm free at last!
I'm hittin' the road.  I'm off to see the world!  I--
Genie, I'm--I'm gonna miss you.
Me too, Al.
No matter what anybody says,
you'll always be a prince to me.
That's right.
You've certainly proven your worth
as far as I'm concerned.
It's that law that's the problem.
-Father?
-Well, am I sultan or am I sultan?
From this day forth, the princess shall marry
whomever she deems worthy.
Him!  I choose...
I choose you, Aladdin.
Call me Al.
Oh, all of ya. Come over here.  Big group hug! Group hug!
Do you mind if I kiss the monkey?
Ooh, hairball!
Well, I can't do any more damage around this popsicle stand.
I'm outta here!
Bye, bye,  you two crazy lovebirds.
Hey, Rugman: ciao!  I'm history!
No, I'm mythology!
No, I don't care what I am--I'm free!
A whole new world
A whole new life
For you and me!
Made ya look!