No, please! No! Please!
Davey!
- Come running, lad!
- Please don't!
- Stop it!
- Brand you like a damn steer!
- Bitch!
- No, please!
Hold the bitch! Hold her!
Hold her or I'll cut her tits off!
Go get Skinny! Quick!
Mike, don't!
Skinny!
Think it's funny?
Skinny, get the gun!
Get off of her, cowboy.
- They wouldn't let you settle it?
- You know Skinny.
He says he'll shoot them.
I says, "You can't."
He says, "Get Little Bill."
I says, "He's sleeping."
But he don't care.
He'll shoot them boys soon.
She dying?
She'll live.
She didn't steal nothing
or touch his poke.
When she seen his
teensy little pecker...
...she giggled.
She didn't know no better.
Hang them, Little Bill.
Go to the office and get the bullwhip.
A whipping's all they
get after what they done?
- It ain't no little thing.
- But what they done...
Alice!
Shut up!
- Whipping won't settle this.
- No?
Here's a contract between me and
Delilah Fitzgerald, the cut whore.
I brought her from Boston,
paid her expenses and all.
I got a contract that represents
an investment of capital.
Property.
Damaged property.
Like if I hamstrung one of their ponies.
You think nobody'll fuck her now?
Hell, no!
Leastways, won't pay to do it!
Nobody's going to pay good money
for a cut-up whore!
You boys are off the Bar T.
Got your own ponies?
Yeah, I got four.
Six.
Guess you want no trial, no fuss?
No, sir.
All right.
You did the cutting.
This fall, you bring in
five ponies to Skinny.
Five?
And you...
...bring two.
- You give them over, hear?
- Yes, sir.
The whip.
Maybe we don't need it now.
I'll tell you, come the spring,
Skinny don't have those ponies...
...I'll come looking for you.
- You ain't whipping them?
I fined them instead, Alice.
Skinny gets some ponies and that's it?!
That ain't fair.
That ain't fair!
Haven't you seen enough blood tonight?
Hell, Alice...
...it ain't like they was
tramps or loafers or...
...bad men. They were just...
...hardworking boys that were foolish.
- If they was wicked in a regular way...
- Like whores?
Tend to Delilah.
Go ahead.
I got $85.
I don't know.
If Delilah doesn't care,
what are we so riled up about?
We let them smelly fools
ride us like horses...
...doesn't mean we must let
them brand us like horses.
Maybe we ain't nothing
but whores, but...
...by God, we ain't horses!
I got $112.
That's everything.
And you, Faith?
200.
240... dollars.
Jesus, what you been doing?
Giving Skinny something special?
She laughs.
With what Kate got, and Silky,
me and Little Sue...
It ain't enough.
Not yet, maybe.
You don't look like no son-of-a-
bitching cold-blooded assassin.
Say what?
You call yourself Mr. William Munny.
You have me confused with
someone else, mister.
Shot Charlie Pepper in Lake County?
Hey, Pa!
What, son?
Two more hogs got the fever.
You shot Charlie Pepper.
You killed William Harvey and
robbed that train in Missouri.
Hold on.
Son, get those hogs separated there.
Penny, help your brother.
That one's sick too.
We'll talk inside.
So you're Pete Sothow's nephew?
I thought you'd come to kill me for
something I'd done in the old days.
I could have.
Easy.
I guess maybe so.
You don't look like no meaner-than-hell,
cold-blooded damn killer.
Maybe I ain't.
Uncle Pete says you was the meanest
goddamn son-of-a-bitch alive.
And if I wanted a
partner for a killing...
...you were the worst one.
Meaning the best.
Because you're as cold as snow...
...and don't have no
weak nerve nor fear.
Pete said that?
He did.
I'm a killer myself, but I
haven't killed as many as you...
...because of my youth.
Schofield Kid, they call me.
Why?
You from Schofield?
No, it's on account of my...
...Schofield-Smith & Wesson pistol.
How about it?
How about what?
How about being my partner?
I'm heading north in
through Niobrara to Wyoming.
Kill two no-good cowboys.
For what?
For cutting up a lady.
Her face.
Cut her eyes out, her ears off.
They even cut her teets.
Jesus.
$1,000 reward, Will.
500 each.
I can't move those damn pigs!
Watch your cussing.
Do your best. Go to the
pump and get cleaned up.
Come on.
I ain't like that anymore, Kid.
It was whiskey done it as
much as anything else.
I ain't had a drop in over 10 years.
My wife...
...cured me...
...of drink and...
...wickedness.
You don't look so prosperous.
You could buy her a new
dress with your half.
You could buy your wife a fancy...
She's passed on.
Been gone near three years now.
Don't tell anyone about the reward.
I don't need no one else trying to collect.
Don't see no one.
Change your mind, you could catch me.
I'll ride due west for the
trail headed north into Wyoming.
Let's separate those hogs.
Two others.
I think they got the fever.
Took you boys a while.
A few more days and I was
going to call on the sheriff.
How about that?
The river was all swelled up.
Couldn't cross it.
I bet. Get them horses to the livery.
Take that one over around the back.
Now here's a beauty.
You got my two. This one ain't yours.
We'll see about that.
Bastards! Get out of town!
Get out of here!
You are very sick sons-of-bitches!
Don't come back, butcher!
This here pony...
...I brung for the lady my partner cut.
She's the best.
Better than what I gave him.
She can sell her...
...or do what she wants.
A pony?
She ain't got no face left
and you give her a mangy pony?
She ain't mangy!
Get out of here!
We don't need your goddamn charity!
Get out of our town and don't come back!
Get out of our town!
Did Pa use to kill folks?
I could tell your ma liked
those flowers I gave her.
She ain't a saddle horse no more, Pa.
Ain't used to the feel.
Take care of your sister, son.
Kill a few chickens if you must and
keep those hogs with fever separate.
If you have any problem, go see
Sally Two Trees at Ned Logan's.
Ain't been in the saddle
myself in a while.
She's getting even with me
for the sins of my youth.
In my youth before I met
your dear departed ma...
...I was weak and given
to mistreating animals.
This horse and those hogs over there...
...are getting even for
the cruelty I inflicted.
I used to be able to cuss
and whip a horse like this...
...but your ma showed me
the error of my ways.
I'll be back in 2 weeks.
The spirit of your dear
departed ma watches over you.
- Where'd you get the money?
- We ain't got any!
- You told them cowboys you had!
- We was lying!
Lying?
What if somebody comes to collect?
You going to hump them
a thousand times?
The people come for that thousand
won't tolerate you not having it!
They won't just cut up your face!
You stupid bitches.
Stupid bitches.
Shit!
Damn it! Jesus!
Get your finger?
Hello, Skinny.
You snuck up on me.
Like her?
I heard you done the roof yourself.
Roof?
Jesus, I did practically
the whole damn thing myself.
The Roberts boy carried wood
for me, but that's all.
What's that wood?
I'm building a porch here so I can
sit of an evening and smoke my pipe...
...and drink coffee
and watch the sunset.
Came out here just to
take a look at her?
Them whores...
...been humping all them cowboys been
through town the last two weeks.
Shit.
We got railroad barons
and cattle barons.
You'll be the first billiard baron.
They been humping and telling
every bowlegged one of them...
...they'll pay $1,000 to whoever...
...kills the two boys
that cut up Delilah.
Those cowboys are riding that
beef down to Kansas and Cheyenne?
All week long?
I didn't hear till last night myself.
The word's got all the
way to Texas by now.
Nobody will come clear from Texas.
They got all that money?
Women can lie. Ask where the
money is, they say they got none.
But the five of them could have it.
Maybe.
That much?
You could run off them two cowboys.
I could run off them whores.
They'll just up and
run anyhow, them two.
They'll stay out at the Bar T.
Close to their friends.
Shit, could be nobody won't come at all.
Got to go. I like your house.
It's Will.
Come in out of the sun.
See to Will's horse.
What you doing here?
Just thought I'd drop in on you.
We ain't bad men no more.
We're farmers.
Should be easy killing them, if
they don't go on down to Texas.
How long since you fired a gun
at a man, Will? Ten years?
Eleven.
Easy, huh?
It wasn't all that easy even back then.
And we were young and full of beans.
If you was mad at them...
...over some wrong, I
could see shooting them.
We done stuff for money before.
We thought we did.
What'd these fellows do?
Cheat at cards? Steal some strays?
Spit on a rich fellow? What?
They cut up a woman.
Cut her face, cut her eyes out,
cut her fingers off, cut her tits.
Everything but her cunny, I suppose.
I'll be dogged.
Guess they got it coming.
Of course, Will...
...if Claudia was alive,
you wouldn't do this.
Could you look in on my
youngsters next week?
Got some hogs to separate.
How long will you be gone?
Two weeks, I guess.
What's this Kid like?
Three ways?
I see you still have that Spencer rifle.
And I can still knock the
eye out of a bird flying.
Jesus.
He must be moving right along.
We'll come across him
tomorrow, I reckon.
Got used to my bed.
This ain't going to be like home.
That ain't the only thing I'll miss.
Hell, I'm sorry.
Don't fret it. It ain't nothing.
She don't like it much...
...you riding off with me.
Gave me the evil eye.
You know, Sally's Indian and...
...lndians ain't over-friendly.
I don't blame her.
I won't hold it against her.
She knew me back then.
She knew what a...
...no-good son-of-a-bitch I was.
She ain't allowing that I changed.
She don't realize I
ain't like that no more.
- You know women.
- I ain't the same, Ned.
Claudia straightened me up.
Cleared me of drinking whiskey and all.
Going on this killing...
...don't mean I'll go
back to the way I was.
Just need the money.
Get a new start for them youngsters.
Remember that drover
I shot in the mouth...
...and his teeth came
out the back of his head?
I think about him now and again.
He didn't do anything
to deserve to get shot.
At least nothing I remembered
when I sobered up.
You was one crazy son-of-a-bitch.
No one liked me.
The boys all thought I'd shoot
them out of pure meanness.
You ain't like that no more.
Eagle, he hated my guts.
Bonaparte didn't think too much of me.
Quincy neither, I reckon.
Quincy used to just watch all the time.
Scared.
Like I said...
...you ain't like that no more.
That's right.
I'm just a fellow now.
I ain't no different than anyone else.
No more.
What son-of-a-bitch shot him?
Was it one of them John Bulls?
No, sir.
The would-be assassin is a gentleman
of French ancestry. Or so it seems.
I don't wish to give offense, but...
...the French are known to
be a race of assassins...
...who can't shoot worth a damn.
Any Frenchmen present
are excluded, of course.
Says here a fellow by
the name of Guiteau.
Sure as hell sounds
like a John Bull to me.
Again, I don't wish to give offense...
...when I suggest that
this country select...
...a king or even a queen,
rather than a President.
One isn't that quick to
shoot a king or a queen.
The majesty of royalty, you see.
Maybe you don't wish to
give offense, sir...
...but you are giving it pretty thick.
This country don't need
no queens whatsoever.
- When I heard about queens...
- Shut up, Joe.
What's wrong with you? This dude...
Might be this dude here is English Bob.
Works for the railroad
shooting Chinamen.
Might be waiting for some cowboy...
...to touch his pistol
so he can shoot him.
Is that a fact, mister?
You English Bob?
Pheasants.
Let's shoot some pheasants.
Ten shots.
And let's say $1 a pheasant.
I'll shoot for the Queen, and you for...
...whomever.
That's 8 for me and 1 for you.
That comes to 7 American dollars.
Pretty damn good shooting...
...for a John Bull.
No doubt your aim was
affected by your grief...
...over the injury to your President.
It's the climate that does it.
That, and the infernal distances.
Does what?
Induces people to shoot
persons in high places.
It's a savage country, really.
That's the second one
they shot in 20 years.
It's uncivilized shooting
persons of substance.
Thank you.
Pardon me, gentlemen.
The law obliges you to
surrender all sidearms...
...to the proper authorities
during your visit.
Proper authority?
I can assure you...
...that neither my companion or
I carry firearms on our person.
We rely upon the goodwill of
our fellow man and the...
...forbearance of reptiles.
Unarmed, my ass.
Christ, it's hot.
If I'm going to get shot, I'd
rather it was hot than cold.
Everything hurts me more when it's cold.
- If you hit your thumb...
- Shut up, Fatty!
- I only said...
- Clyde's back.
- With Little Bill?
- No.
Shit.
- You clean my Remington?
- Cleaned and loaded.
Where's Little Bill, for chrissake?
Building his damn porch.
Building his porch?
If you got shot, would you want
it to be a hot or cold day?
I ain't going to get shot.
He's coming?
Of course he's coming.
I just loaded that.
I don't trust nobody to load
my guns for a shooting.
What he say?
Little Bill said he
was building his porch.
You seen that thing?
It was all loaded.
You got three pistols
and you only got one arm!
I don't want to get killed
for lack of shooting back.
He don't have a straight
angle on that whole porch!
Or the whole house, for that matter!
He is the worst damn carpenter.
He didn't say nothing?
Asked what they looked like.
Maybe he's tough but he
sure ain't no carpenter.
Maybe he ain't so tough.
Seem like he was scared?
Little Bill? Him scared?
We never seen him up
against any like these ones.
Killers.
Little Bill come out of
Kansas and Texas, boys.
He worked them tough towns.
Just wondered.
Anybody could be scared.
He wasn't scared, boys.
He just ain't no carpenter.
There's a dignity in royalty which
precludes the likelihood of assassination.
If you pointed a pistol at a queen...
...your hands would shake as if palsied.
I wouldn't point no pistol at nobody.
Always a wise policy.
But if you did, I can assure you...
...the sight of royalty would cause you
to dismiss all thoughts of bloodshed.
You would stand, how should I put it...
...in awe.
Now, a President...
Well, why not shoot the President?
Keep the change.
This Strawberry Alice
person, tell me again.
Down the street to Greely's Beer
Garden and Billiards Parlor.
Say you want a game of billiards.
Billiards?
Even though I don't wish to play?
No matter. They burned the
table in '78 for firewood.
Right.
Quite right.
Mr. Beauchamp, I think a cup of tea...
Hello, Bob.
Boys, this here is English Bob.
Shit and fried eggs.
Been a long time.
Run out of Chinamen?
I thought that you were dead.
You've shaved your chin whiskers off.
I was tasting the soup
two hours after I ate it.
Actually, what I heard was you...
...fell off your horse.
Drunk, of course.
And that you broke your bloody neck.
I heard that one myself, Bob.
Hell, I even thought I was dead.
Till I found out I was just in Nebraska.
Who's he?
W.W. Beauchamp.
This is Little Bill Daggett.
And friends, of course.
From Newton, Hays? From Abilene?
In person.
You work for the railroads too?
I write.
Letters?
Books, Bill. Books.
Actually...
...he's my biographer.
I wouldn't do that if I were you.
It's only a book.
A book?
That means you boys can read.
That means you saw the signs...
...saying surrender your firearms.
But like you told young Andy...
...you're not armed, are you?
Not really, Bill.
Got a Peacemaker, but that
wouldn't worry you, would it?
If you don't see it.
Or better, if you don't hear it.
I'm afraid so, Bob.
I don't like firearms around.
Be very careful with it, sonny.
See what kind of books
Mr. Beauchamp is packing.
Make sure you don't get wet.
No shit.
All he's got is writing
stuff and this book.
"The Duck of Death?"
Duke.
"The Duke."
Good afternoon, gentlemen.
I'll have that.32, Bob.
Now, Little Bill.
You will leave me at
the mercy of my enemies.
Enemies?
You been talking about the Queen again?
On Independence Day?
I guess you think I'm kicking you.
But it ain't so!
What I'm doing is talking!
Hear?!
Talking to all them villains in Kansas!
To all those villains in Missouri!
And those villains...
...down in Cheyenne!
I'm saying there ain't no whore's gold!
Even if there was, they
don't want to come for it...
...anyhow!
What are you looking at?!
Go on!
Mind your own business!
Ever go into town?
On occasion.
To sell a hog, pick up supplies.
I mean, get yourself a woman.
No, I never go into town for that.
A man like me?
Only woman I could get is
one I'd have to pay for.
That ain't right, buying flesh.
Claudia, rest her soul,
wouldn't want me doing that.
Me being a father, and all.
You just use your hand?
I don't miss it all that much.
Goddamn, somebody's shooting at us!
You hit?
I bumped my head falling off my horse.
Ain't shooting at us no more.
Shooting way over yonder.
What the hell's he shooting at?
Beats the hell out of me.
Reckon we in somebody's field?
I didn't see nothing planted.
Shooting at us again.
He's shooting at the whole horizon.
Wait! You'll mark us!
Hey, Kid!
That's the Kid shooting at us?
Kid, it's me! Will Munny!
What the hell's he shooting at us for?
That you?
Yeah, it's me!
Don't go shooting at us
no more! You hear me?
Who the hell you got with you, Will?
It's Ned Logan, my old partner!
Don't go shooting at us, you hear?
We'll get our horses
and come on over there.
You ain't going to shoot, are you?
I ain't!
Chased that horse a damn mile.
- What was you shooting at us for?
- I thought you was following me.
We was. You said if I changed my mind...
Wasn't nothing said about no partner.
This here's Ned Logan.
He's the Schofield Kid,
nephew to Pete Sothow.
I seen two fellows following me.
My guess is you come to kill me.
We never talked about no other fellow.
There's two cowboys. Better there's
three of us, if they got friends.
I can take care of them two myself.
It don't take three.
Ned's an awful good shot with a rifle.
Hit a bird in the eye flying.
Better than you, anyhow.
- You wasn't even coming close.
- Hands off!
Thought I'd check it for you.
Maybe something's bent.
It ain't... bent.
You were shooting all over creation!
You'll share your half with him?
I figure three ways.
Wrong.
Sorry I wasted your time, Ned.
You going back with him?
He's my partner.
He don't go, I don't.
What's it come to, three ways?
Shit!
What are you pissing on about?
What are you looking at?
Looking at?
Clouds.
He's looking at them clouds on
account of we got a storm coming.
I seen them.
You was smart to change your mind.
I'm a real good shot with this rifle.
See that hawk?
I could hit it with one shot.
Hell, I could hit it too.
If I didn't mind wasting a shot.
There ain't no hawk, Kid.
You can't see for shit, can you?
See your canteen?
How far can you see?
Far enough.
- We ain't going to shoot canteens!
- How far? 100 yards?
More.
- See that scrub oak tree yonder?
- Fuck you.
- He's blind, Will!
- I ain't blind, you asshole!
Hold it!
How far can you see, Kid? 50 yards?
You bet your ass I can
see 50 yards, Will.
I can see well enough to
shoot this son-of-a-bitch.
Hold on.
Hear that, Ned?
Kid can see 50 yards. Fine.
Jesus.
Fifty yards'll do just fine.
Now let's move out.
They look like real hard cases, Bob.
Did you kill all 7 of them?
Or just wing some of them?
That you here embalmed on the cover?
"The Duck of Death?"
The Duke.
"The Duke of Death."
You always were good with a
pistol, but 7 of them? Boy!
Protecting that woman.
How the hell do you do that?
It's desirable in the publishing
business to take a certain...
...liberty when depicting
the cover scene.
For reasons involving the marketplace.
From what I read, the writing's not
that much different than the picture.
I can assure you, Mr. Daggett...
...that the events described are
taken from eyewitness accounts.
- Eyewitnesses?
- Yes, sir.
Like the Duck himself, I guess.
The Duke.
Duck, I says.
"'You have insulted the honor of
this beautiful woman, Corcoran'...
...said the Duck.
'You must apologize.'
But Two-Gun Corcoran
would none of it.
Cursing, he reached for his
pistols and would have killed him...
...but the Duck was faster and hot
lead blazed from his smoking six-guns."
I consider that an accurate
depiction of events.
There is a certain poetry to the
language which I couldn't resist.
I was in the Blue Bottle
Saloon in Wichita...
...the night English Bob
killed Corky Corcoran.
I didn't see you there...
...nor no woman...
...nor two-gun shooters.
Nor none of this.
- You were there?
- Yeah, I was there.
First off...
...Corky never carried two
guns, though he should have.
He was called Two-Gun Corcoran.
A lot of folks did call him Two-Gun.
But not because he had two pistols.
He had a dick that was so big...
...it was longer than the
barrel on his Walker Colt.
The only insulting he did
was stick that thing...
...into a French lady
English Bob was sweet on.
The night Corky walked
into the Blue Bottle...
...before he knows what's what,
Bob takes a shot at him!
And misses, he's so damn drunk.
That bullet whizzing by panicked
Corky, and he did the wrong thing.
In his hurry, he shot his damn toe off.
Meantime, Bob here...
...aims real good and
squeezes off another...
...but he misses, he's still so drunk!
He hits this thousand-dollar
mirror over the bar.
The Duck of Death is as good as dead...
...because Corky does it right.
He aims real careful.
No hurry...
The Walker Colt blew up in his hand...
...a failing common to that model.
If Corky'd had two guns
instead of just a big dick...
...he'd have defended
himself to the end.
Wait a minute.
English Bob killed him when
he didn't even have...
Bob wasn't going to wait for
Corky to grow a new hand.
No, he just walked over
there real slow...
...'cause he's drunk...
...and shot him through the liver.
I don't like rocks on my dad-gum back.
- I sure do miss my bed.
- You said that last night.
Last night I said I missed my wife.
Tonight I just miss my dad-gum bed!
You'll miss your dad-gum
roof next, I suppose.
Will?
That business up in Jackson County...
...that really happen?
The way they say it happened?
What business?
Two deputies up close pointing
their rifles right at you.
Got you dead to rights.
You pulled out your pistol
and blew them to hell.
Only took a scratch yourself.
Uncle Pete never seen nothing like you
shooting your way out of that scrape.
Well, I don't recollect.
You don't recollect?
Right.
Ned...
...how many men you killed?
Ain't you going to answer?
What the hell's that to you?
I got to know what kind of fellow I'm
riding with, case we get into a scrape.
How many men you killed, Kid?
Five.
How many?
I done killed 5 of them.
That's including a Mexican
who come at me with a knife.
Why don't you shut up? Get some rest.
You boys're as crotchety
as a couple of old hens.
Actually...
...Mr. Corcoran was faster
on the draw than the Duck...
Than English Bob?
Faster?
Faster was his mistake.
If he hadn't rushed, he wouldn't
have shot himself in the toe.
He would've killed old Bob.
Being a good shot and being
quick with a pistol...
...don't do no harm, but it don't
mean much next to being cool-headed.
A man who'll keep his head,
not get rattled under fire...
...like as not will kill you.
But if the other fellow is quicker...
Then he'll hurry and he'll miss.
Look.
That's as fast as I can draw, aim and
hit anything more than 10 feet away.
'Less it's a barn.
But if he doesn't miss?
He'll kill you.
That's why there's so few
dangerous men around like Bob.
Like me.
It ain't so easy to shoot a
man if he's shooting back.
That'll flat rattle some folks.
- I'll show you something.
- Wait.
Look.
Take that.
Take it.
There's the key.
Just shoot me...
...and you and Bob can ride
on out of here free as birds.
- Is it loaded?
- Wouldn't do any good if it wasn't.
You got to cock it.
Cock it.
Point it.
Go on. Point it.
Now all you must do
is pull the trigger.
Hot, ain't it?
Your finger wasn't even on the trigger.
What if...
What if I gave it to him?
Do it.
You don't...
I guess he don't want it, Mr. Beauchamp.
You were right not to take it.
I'd have killed you.
We could use some rain.
You no-good goddamn
pig-fucking whore!
Sorry, horse.
I brung this for when
we kill them fellows.
Figured we could use some now.
Not me. I don't touch it no more.
It's raining.
I know it's raining!
Give some to the Kid.
You think that Kid really killed 5 men?
When you talked about the time them
deputies had the drop on you and Pete...
I remember there was
3 men you shot, not 2.
I ain't like that no more, Ned!
I ain't no crazy killing fool.
Still think it'll be easy
to kill them cowboys?
If we don't drown first.
Give these keys to the conductor.
He can loose Bob's cuffs as soon
as he's outside the county.
Got my pistols?
I guess you know, Bob, that...
...if I see you again I'll
just shoot in self-defense.
I didn't steal your biographer!
He's staying on his own account!
He can go stuff himself
as well, can't he?!
A plague on the whole
stinking lot of you!
Without morals or laws!
And all you whores!
You got no laws and no honor!
It's no wonder you all
emigrated to America!
They wouldn't have you in England!
You're a lot of savages!
You're all a bunch of bloody
savages! A curse on you!
Nobody's going to come...
...after what Little Bill
done to that Englishman.
Delilah, can't you
get them tables clean?
Cover your face, somebody might hump
you and you wouldn't have to clean.
What do they call that face cover?
A veil.
Yeah. Get a veil!
Rain's coming.
Thank God.
Sure?
You all right, Will?
Fellow asking for Alice.
Tonight? You ain't joshing?
This way, mister.
Must be randy as hell to
come out in this shit.
"No, no! You're wrong,
Little Bill!" he said.
"That's not the Curly J.
That's a Bobbed J!"
He had changed it over.
And I said to him...
..."Jim, you're a liar
and a horse thief!"
He saw nobody would help him none.
He went to start crying and
sobbing and just carrying on.
He said, "God, please,
don't kill me, Bill!
Please don't kill me!"
I said, "It makes me sick..."
Open the window.
"...to see a man carrying two
pistols and a Henry rifle...
...and crying like a damn baby."
So... you killed him?
No.
But I should have.
I can't abide them kind.
You see them in the taverns.
Tramps and drunk teamsters.
Crazed miners.
Sporting their pistols and
acting like they was bad men.
But without any sand or character.
Not even any bad character.
I do not like assassins.
Or men of low character.
Like English Bob.
But Bob was no coward, you know.
He wouldn't cry and carry on like that...
Sheriff...
I don't have any more receptacles.
Maybe you should just
hang the carpenter.
I meant that because of
the... if you hang...
Never mind.
What the hell?
On a night like this!
Who is it?
Deputy Charley Hecker, Bill.
Three fellows just come into town, Bill.
They're down to Greely's.
There's two of them got guns.
What the hell's keeping that Kid?
You suppose he's up...
You look like shit.
You remember Eagle Hendershot?
I saw him.
Will, he's dead.
No, I saw him, Ned.
His head was broke open.
You could see inside of it.
Jesus.
You got a fever.
- Take your drink.
- Worms were coming out.
I'll go find the Kid.
Must be he's getting an advance
on one of the sporting ladies.
If I was to...
If it worked out that I could...
...take a little time
for myself, would you...
I guess you don't want to come.
Give me the pistol.
I says give me over your pistol.
I ain't drunk.
Ordinance says you got to turn
in your firearms to my office...
...day or night.
I guess you didn't see the sign,
because of the weather.
No.
But I ain't armed.
Your friends upstairs got any pistols?
They ain't armed either.
Spilled your whiskey.
What's your name?
William...
...Hendershot.
Well, Mr. William Hendershot...
...what if I was to say
you was a no-good liar?
And if I was to say you shit in your
pants because of a cowardly soul...
...I bet you'd show me that pistol
right quick and shoot me dead.
Is that so?
Maybe, I guess.
But the fact...
...is I ain't...
...carrying no firearm.
Get up.
What's this for, snakes and such?
We don't have any snakes
in here, Mr. Hendershot.
It ain't loaded.
Powder's wet.
You see, Mr. Beauchamp?
Such is the trash I spoke of!
They're in all the saloons...
...in all your prosperous communities!
Wichita!
Over in Cheyenne!
Abilene!
But not in the town of Big Whiskey.
Hurry!
Know what to tell Little Bill?
Look sharp for that lone pine.
Don't miss it.
Not the shirt! Put his boots on!
What are we going to do about Will?
Come on! Let's hope them
horses are still there!
Let the man out, W.W.
He's desiring to leave the
hospitality of Big Whiskey behind him.
Easy. She's got to be able
to turn a dollar a time!
How come they lit out the back window?
They seen you beating on their friend.
They just come for
the billiards, honest.
Billiards?!
They just passing through here?
Going to Fort Buford.
You kicked the shit
out of an innocent man.
Innocent?
Innocent of what?
You done this before?
Plenty of times.
His pistol must've jammed.
Bring that candle in closer.
I can't see.
He wouldn't take no beating
if it hadn't jammed.
He wouldn't give it over and not shoot.
He don't look so good.
He didn't even pull his pistol?
He ain't as tough as you, Kid.
I'd have pulled my pistol.
You did!
Out of the lady and out the window!
- That was your idea! I wanted to...
- We must go.
Already? Darling, I'm
ready for another advance.
- You'll use it all up.
- No more advances on what you ain't done.
Sweetheart, we're just waiting
on this weather to clear!
We'll need more food!
3 days' worth.
3 days?
- We'll kill them tomorrow.
- I don't kill nobody without him.
We don't need him! We can do it.
He ain't nothing but a
broken-down pig farmer.
One of us'll bring food and
some whiskey in the morning!
And some medicine if you got any!
Don't it make you sick hearing him?
Don't you ladies worry!
Me and Ned will kill them two
sons-of-bitches for you!
Claudia.
She's not here.
Is that you, Ned?
I've seen him.
I saw the Angel of Death.
I've seen the river, Ned.
He's got snake eyes.
Who's got snake eyes?
It's the Angel of Death.
Ned, I'm scared of dying.
Easy, partner.
I seen Claudia too.
That's good you saw Claudia, ain't it?
Her face was all covered with worms.
Ned, I'm scared.
I'm dying.
No, don't tell nobody.
Don't tell my kids...
...none of the things I did. Hear me?
All right.
He's gonna die, ain't he?
Maybe.
Suppose he does?
We'll bury him.
That ain't what I mean.
You mean will I help
you kill them cowboys?
I can't spot them myself.
But you could.
You could spot that big
bastard a half-mile off.
And if I spot him?
Then I ride up close and shoot him.
Just like that?
I'm a damn killer. I done it before.
I'm more of a killer than he is.
I thought you was an angel.
You ain't dead.
Some big fellow...
...kicked the hell out of me.
I must look like you now.
You don't look nothing like me.
No offense meant.
It was you those cowboys cut up.
My partners, Ned and that Kid...
...they around?
They went out scouting
when your fever broke.
Scouting?
Out to the Bar T...
...looking for them.
How long I been here?
Three days.
Are you hungry or...
Three days?
I should be.
I thought I was gone.
I wouldn't normally pay no notice
to high country like this.
Trees. But I'm sure noticing now.
Thought I was dying for sure.
I brought your hat.
You left it down at Greely's.
Thanks.
That sheriff...
...still looking for me?
Little Bill?
No, he thinks you went south.
Are you really going
to kill them cowboys?
I guess.
Still a payment coming, isn't there?
The other two, your friends...
...they're taking
advances on the payment.
Advances?
Free ones.
Alice and Silky been
giving them free ones.
I see.
Would you like a free one?
I guess not.
I didn't mean with me. I meant...
...Alice and Silky would
give you a free one...
...if you wanted.
That's all I meant.
I didn't mean I didn't want a
free one because you been cut up.
What I said about you
looking like me ain't true.
You ain't ugly like me.
It's just that we both have scars.
You're a beautiful woman and
if I wanted a free one...
...I'd want it with you
more than the other two.
It's just that...
...I can't on account of my wife.
Your wife?
I admire you for that...
...being true to your wife.
I've known a lot of men...
...who weren't.
I suppose.
Is she back in Kansas?
She's watching over my young ones.
Hang on!
Get the damn iron!
Jesus, boys, my leg's broke!
I'm pinned, boys!
Better finish him.
He ain't dead? You didn't get him?
He got the boy's horse.
Finish him before he gets clear.
Get behind them rocks.
Get over there!
What happened?
He ain't killed?!
What's going on?
He gets in those rocks,
we won't get him.
- Unless we go down there.
- What rocks?
Why don't you shoot?
What's going on?
Shoot!
I ain't very good with one of these.
Keep going, Davey! The rocks!
Get him?
Where is he?
How many more shots do I have?
Two.
Did you get him?
Here, reload this.
- You missed him.
- I got him.
He ain't killed.
Maybe, maybe not.
Got him through the gut, I think.
Think he'll die?
We killed him?
We killed him...
...I guess.
I'm dying, boys!
Then you shouldn't have cut
up no woman, you asshole!
Jesus, I'm so thirsty.
Give me some water, please!
Please, Slim!
I'm bleeding, Slim!
Give him a drink of water, goddamn it!
Give him some water, for chrissake!
We ain't going to shoot!
You won't?
Hold on, Davey-boy!
Here I come now!
Don't shoot, you bastards!
Shit!
They take him water?
Jesus, Johnny! They shot him!
Hold on now!
You murdering bastards!
You killed our Davey-boy!
When do we double back?
After a ways.
Not me.
I'm heading back down to Kansas.
We must kill the other one first.
With any luck, we'll find him
by nightfall or in the morning.
We'll shoot him and head
back with the money.
Want the Spencer?
It's no time to quit.
- You'll lose your share.
- Shut up!
I'll see you, Will. So long, Kid.
I ain't no good with that damn thing.
Me and the Kid'll go over to that ranch
and when we find him we'll shoot him.
We'll meet up with you, get our
money, and head south together.
Suppose he don't go back to the ranch?
He ain't going into town.
He won't stay out in the open country.
He'll hole up at that ranch.
I ain't waiting.
I'll look in on your young ones.
Forget what the Kid said
about the money and all.
I'll bring yours.
Kid's full of shit.
Doing some repairs up here.
They killed one of them cowboys.
Shit.
Parsons said he saw three men,
right after sun-up, headed east.
One was on a dun and another
was on a flea-bitten grey.
He didn't know what the third
one was on, maybe an Appaloosa.
Amos says to ask if the county will
pay for feed for all the horses.
Witherspoon won't sell us no more
.30-30 shells without we pay.
Use my dogs.
Then the county must
take responsibility.
Fatty, get on out there to the Bar
T and make sure that other cowboy...
...stays put and don't expose himself.
I didn't think they'd really do it.
Think they come clear
from Kansas to fuck us?
But that Kid's just a
boy and the other one...
...Will, the nice one, being
so true to his wife...
Wife? He ain't got no wife.
- Yes, he does. He said...
- He ain't got no wife.
Not above ground, anyways.
Murdering whores!
He had it coming...
...for what he done.
And the other one too!
Both of them for what they done!
We got one!
We got one, Sheriff! Out by Cow Creek!
Is he alive?
Yeah! Bunch of us from
Bar T went out looking...
...'cause they killed one of our own.
Come across the bastard
on a roan heading south.
He admit it?
No. But I guess he will soon enough.
Had a Spencer rifle on him.
They messing him up?
Little bit.
Get out there. Find out what
happened to those other two!
See anything out there, Buck?
Hell, yes! Seen about 200
fellows packing rifles.
Got the place surrounded.
Say they want Quick Mike's ass.
I said, "How much?" They says,
"Five." I said, "Dollars?"
They said, "Cents."
I said, "Sold."
Well, I ain't worried!
'Cause I got me some protection.
- Tell you where them others is?
- Nope.
Names?
Only told us his name, Ned Roundtree.
Bring him in.
You'll want to tell me
and Mr. Beauchamp here...
...all about your two
villainous friends.
I'll want the names and whereabouts
of those murderous son-of-a-bitches.
Sure is ripe.
Going to get a lot riper.
Think he's still in there?
He's in there.
He's holding on to his
shit like it was money.
He's in there.
Tell me right off if you see him.
You won't shoot him your own self?
You can shoot him.
You, Mr. Quincy and...
what was the young fellow's name?
Elroy Tate.
No, that's not what you said.
It is.
No, you said...
..."Elroy Quincy out
of Medicine Hat and...
...Henry Tate out of Cheyenne."
Hell if I did.
Go get them whores that
fucked these boys that night.
Strawberry Alice and Silky?
Go on and get them!
Them whores will tell
different lies than you.
And when their lies ain't
the same as your lies...
I ain't going to hurt no woman.
But I will hurt you.
Not gentle like before...
...but bad.
Where you going?
- The shithouse.
- Let me finish this hand.
To protect me while I take a dump?
- You'll get bushwhacked.
- I'll fart on them.
- I'll go with him.
- You can wipe my ass, Thirsty.
Hell with him. He ain't
polite, he should get shot.
That him?
Yeah, it's him.
Go get him. He's all yours.
Assassins!
Shoot!
Come on, goddamn it!
Get him?
Cover me.
- I can't see them!
- Just shoot!
Get him!
Was it like that in the old days?
Everybody riding out, shooting...
...smoke all over, folks yelling,
bullets whizzing by?
I guess so.
Shit, I thought they'd get us.
I was even scared a little.
For a minute.
You ever scared in them days?
I can't remember.
I was drunk most of the time.
I shot that fucker three times!
He went for his pistol
and I blazed away.
First shot...
...I got him right in the chest.
That was the first.
First what?
First one I ever killed.
I know I said I shot five men.
It weren't true.
That Mexican who had a knife...
...I busted his leg with a shovel.
I didn't kill him or nothing.
You killed the hell out
of that fellow today.
Hell, yeah!
I killed the hell out of him!
Three shots while he took a shit...
Take a drink.
It don't seem real.
How he won't never breathe again, ever.
How he's dead.
And the other one too.
On account of pulling a trigger.
It's a hell of a thing, killing a man.
You take away all he's got...
...and all he'll ever have.
I guess they had it coming.
We all have it coming, Kid.
I was watching you.
You weren't followed.
Silky and Faith rode off to the east
and two deputies followed them.
Want to help me count this?
- I trust you.
- Don't go trusting me too much.
In fact, we'll give
Ned his share together.
You'll know I ain't holding out on you.
Ned's share?
He went south. We'll catch up.
He's dead.
What do you mean?
He went south yesterday. He ain't dead.
They killed him. I thought you knew.
Nobody killed Ned!
He didn't kill anyone, he went south!
Why would anybody kill Ned?
Who killed him?
Little Bill.
The boys caught him. Little Bill...
...beat him up.
He was making him answer questions and
beating him up, then Ned just died.
They got a sign on him
says he was a killer.
A sign?
In front of Greely's.
A sign on him in front of Greely's!
These questions he was asking...
...what were they?
About where you and him was.
Then what?
A cowboy come in saying you killed
Quick Mike in the shithouse at the Bar T.
So Little Bill killed
him for what we done?
Not on purpose.
But he started hurting him worse.
Making him tell stuff.
First, Ned wouldn't talk.
Then Little Bill hurt him so
bad, he said who you was.
He said how you was really
William Munny out of Missouri...
Little Bill said, "The
same William Munny...
...who dynamited the railroad in '69,
killing women and children?"
Ned said you done a lot worse and was...
...more cold-blooded
than William Bonney.
Said if he hurt Ned again,
you'd come kill him...
...like you killed the
U.S. Marshal in '70.
That didn't scare him, did it?
No, sir.
Give me your Schofield.
Why?
Give it.
You keep it.
I won't use it.
I won't kill nobody no more.
I ain't like you, Will.
You better ride on back, Miss.
Keep all of it. It's yours.
What about spectacles
and fancy clothes?
I'd rather be blind
and ragged than dead.
You don't have to worry, Kid.
I ain't going to kill you.
You're the only friend I got.
Take this money and give my share...
...and Ned's share to my kids.
Tell them if I ain't back in a week,
to give half to Sally Two Trees.
You keep the rest. Get them spectacles.
You'll go kill Little Bill?
Stay clear of folks you see.
A lot will want to hang you.
Get going.
I'll say this just one more
time, so don't ask me again!
Those on the posse today got one
drink coming from the county budget!
And those who rode
yesterday get another drink.
Hold it!
That's two!
After that, it comes
out of your own pocket!
We'll pull out early in the morning.
We'll chase them clear to Texas,
so don't spend too much money.
We'll divide up into four parties!
We'll hit all the farms and trails...
...in a big circle.
We're bound to find somebody...
...who seen these skunks.
Who owns this shithole?
Fat man.
Speak up.
I own this establishment.
I bought it from Greely
for a thousand dollars.
Clear out of there.
Hold it!
Sir, you are a cowardly son-of-a-bitch!
You just shot an unarmed man.
He should've armed himself if he's going
to decorate his saloon with my friend.
You'd be William Munny
out of Missouri...
...killer of women and children.
That's right.
I've killed women and children.
I killed just about everything
that walks or crawls.
And I'm here to kill you, Little Bill.
For what you did to Ned.
You boys better move away.
Gentlemen...
...he's got one barrel left.
When he fires that, use your pistols...
...and shoot him down like
the mangy scoundrel he is!
Misfire! Kill the son-of-a-bitch!
Any man don't want to get killed,
better clear on out the back.
I'm shot! I've been shot!
You ain't shot.
I don't have a gun. I am not armed.
Pick up that rifle.
Pick it up.
Shells too.
You killed Little Bill.
You ain't armed?
I'm not. I don't have a gun.
I've never had a gun. I'm a writer!
A writer?
- Letters and such?
- Books.
Books.
I don't believe it, you killed
five men. Single-handed.
That's a Spencer rifle, right?
Who'd you kill first?
"When confronted by superior numbers...
...an experienced gunfighter will
fire on the best shot first."
Little Bill said that.
You probably killed him first.
I was lucky in the order.
I'm always lucky when it
comes to killing folks.
Who was next? Clyde, right?
You killed Clyde, or
was it Deputy Andy...
All I can tell you is who'll be last.
I don't deserve this...
...to die like this.
I was building a house.
"Deserve's" got nothing to do with it.
I'll see you in hell, William Munny.
All right, I'm coming out!
Any man I see out there, I'll kill him!
Anyone takes a shot at me...
...I'll not only kill
him, but his wife...
...and all his friends...
...and burn his damn house down!
Nobody better shoot!
Charley, go ahead. Shoot him!
Hell, no! I ain't no deputy!
You better bury Ned right!
You better not cut up nor
otherwise harm no whores!
Or I'll come back and kill every
one of you sons-of-bitches.