They say a daughter
is like a vest to her mother.
It's a girl. 2.8 kilograms.
But I think I'm more like a fur coat.
It's a girl. 4.9 kilograms.
I was born different than other babies.
Their first word was
either daddy or mommy...
...while mine was "more."
Kids, you know,
always bring trouble to their parents.
Mommy.
I pooped my pants.
But I had some big moments, too.
Mommy.
I finished first in the race.
As I grew up,
my mom picked up all sorts of skills.
After I started school...
...she often came to get lectured herself.
You should help your girl
with her study at home.
It was till much later
that I realize that...
...as it turns out,
not every little girl...
...grows up to be beautiful.
It's been three years...
...and your daughter's grades
have remained stable.
That was the first time
I spotted white hair on my mom's head.
I don't know if you remember
what your mom looked like in her youth.
I for one seem to remember...
...my mom only as a middle-aged woman.
When will you ever make me proud?
I'm so happy today.
Now I can officially announce that...
...my daughter, Jia Xiaoling,
was admitted into a fine college.
I've finally made my mom proud.
Even my dad was super excited.
All it took was a little shenanigan
on my part.
Fantastic.
Of course.
I am the best certificate forger
in all of Xiangfan.
Here, this is your own adult
education diploma.
Compare the two.
You won't be able to tell.
The forger guy promised me on his honor
that no one could tell the difference.
Fantastic.
Whose signature is this?
Mine.
Your handwriting is child-like.
Nothing like a dean's.
How dean-like is it now?
Good.
Almost a like doctor's handwriting.
Perfect.
How many letters of admission
do you reckon...
...the Capital Academy of Drama
sends out every year?
Hundreds...
...if not thousands.
And every single one
is signed by the dean.
To think our daughter
will be in such good hands.
Exactly.
Come here.
Huanying.
Is this not Wang Qin?
I didn't think you'd make it.
Well, I have to.
Why didn't you say hello to aunt Qin?
Your mom and I both resent her.
Without Shen Guanglin, her husband,
she's nobody.
Quit gossiping.
She's not really drinking green tea.
She's showing off her watch.
Just wait and see. She's start bragging
even before her butt touches the chair.
The atmosphere is great today.
Reminds me of the past...
...when everyone was in my house
watching TV together.
Ling, you wouldn't know but
it was so much fun.
Speaking of TV,
it just occurred to me that...
...your family was the first to own
a television among us factory workers.
You were so envied.
Even me, the director, was jealous of you.
We couldn't possibly have stolen
your thunder, Director.
Remember that volley ball tournament
you set up back in the day?
That was a huge event
and it was truly glorious.
Are you complimenting me or yourself?
Weren't you the winner that year?
How dare she?
If your mom and I hadn't missed that game
she wouldn't have won.
It would've totally been your mother.
What would my mom have won?
A life-changing opportunity.
Come by the supermarket tomorrow
and I'll tell you.
Now that Ling has gotten
into a great school...
...she'd be an actress upon graduation.
With the right director...
...plus a little luck,
who knows what she'll accomplish?
Absolutely.
What is your daughter studying in the US?
Film directing.
At UCLA.
What can she do graduating
as a director there?
Making films.
Must be a pain in the ass
trying to find a job back home.
- She will stay in America.
- Wouldn't language be a problem?
- She's fluent in English.
- Will she make enough money?
- Eighty thousand per month.
- Where does she even get paid like that?
Hollywood.
Now...
I will set an example for you.
Ling...
here's another red envelope from Aunt Bao.
What are you doing?
You should've told us
you're gonna do that.
Bao Yumei, what do you think you're doing?
You already gave us one. Give it back now.
- Aunt Bao, I can't take this.
- Ying, what is this? It's not for you.
It's for the young lady.
But you've already given one.
Give it back to Aunt Bao.
I'm just happy that my god-daughter
finally got into college.
I'll just put it in your backpack.
Aunt Bao, not the bag.
What's this for? You already gave us one.
Yeah, you did.
Mom, give me my bag.
What's the matter with you?
Kid, leave it be.
We've already received your good will.
Just a token of love.
Put it in the bag.
Mom, give me my bag.
Give it to your husband, Zhang Jiang.
As a tree owes its exuberance
to rich soil...
...children owe their success
to good parenting.
This one has no seal.
A woman born fragile will grow strong
once she becomes a mother.
Please welcome the mother of the prodigy,
Ms. Li Huanying...
...to the stage!
Mom, it's all my fault.
I just wanted to make you proud.
I know I'm such a big loser.
Who says you're a loser?
But I'll be somebody someday.
I have no doubt.
Mom.
A fake college diploma for
an Adult Education Degree?
I was thinking it'd bring in
more gift money.
I'll tell you what, comrade Li Huanying,
you need to start planning now.
For what?
For what you're gonna buy
when your daughter gets rich.
How big a ballpark
are we talking about here?
How about eighty thousand per month,
like Shen Tingting.
- No way, gotta be more than that.
- Ninety thousand then.
In that case,
you deserve a gold necklace.
And this crappy bike of yours,
get rid of it.
It can barely carry me.
Let's get you a car.
Cars are smothering.
It's got windows.
Mom, how do you like that one?
I'll turn it into a convertible
if you find it smothering.
Alrighty then.
Uncle Jia.
We'll see if she
can make it through tonight.
Mom...
...please don't leave just yet.
I'm about to succeed.
If you pass away now...
...I'll blame myself forever.
I'm a lousy daughter...
...who has never even made you proud once.
How I wish I could change that.
During the 80s...
...color film wasn't even available
in China.
So, the videos and photos we can find...
...are mostly black and white.
However...
- ...skillful photographers...
- Mom.
...would use paint to add a touch
of color to those gray pictures.
Mom.
- As color photos came along...
- Mom.
...those sealed memories...
- ...came back to life.
- Mom.
Well-arranged factory buildings
made of red bricks...
...energetic workers in blue uniforms...
...everything seems to be speaking to
us about what a wonderful time it was.
Young people born in the 1950s and 1960s
made up the majority of
the workforce in the era.
They strode on at a brisk pace...
...with a big smile on their faces.
Today, we're going to tour
Triumph Chemical Factory...
...for some first-hand experience
of a simpler time.
Not checkmate yet.
Then I'll make this move.
Again, checkmate.
What's going on?
Wait, what is this?
I was just talking to Ying
and she told me I looked fresh today.
I said it must be the red armband.
That's when this big girl
fell from god knows where...
...and landed on Ying.
- Oh no, someone's crashed.
- She's not from our factory.
Cut the bullshit and hurry.
Take them to the hospital. Now, hurry.
Make way, people.
Come on.
That's right. Good job.
Yeah.
Come on.
HI, MOM
Am I dreaming?
Or did I just time travel?
You are in trouble.
You're a tough one.
Not even a scratch.
Did I pass out?
I don't think so.
You wouldn't have snored if you did.
Don't worry,
we won't be harsh on you...
...but you can't get away with this.
I can see that
you're from an average family.
But then again, the average family...
...is pretty much average.
Just sign this statement that says...
...you take full responsibility
for the incident...
...and that it has nothing to do
with our safety supervisor...
...who, by the name of Zhang Jiang,
played an active role in helping you.
- Here, sign it.
- Zhang Jiang.
- Yep, yours truly.
- Uncle Zhang.
Yeah, sign it.
Uncle Zhang.
Uncle Zhang, it's me.
What are you doing?
I'm telling you,
people frown upon this kind of behavior.
- What is the matter with you?
- Uncle Zhang.
I... Ling.
How about I'm Ding?
What year is this?
What?
What year is it now?
1981.
Year of the Rooster.
I wasn't even born yet.
How did I wind up in 1981?
That character is "xi"?
Li Huanying's family.
Mom.
- Mom.
- What are you doing here? Let's go.
Let's get out of here first, now.
Uncle Zhang, this is an odd situation.
You don't understand.
I'm sure the police will, let's go.
Uncle Zhang, please, you always liked me.
Who likes you? Come with me now.
- Hurry up.
- Zhang Jiang.
- Mom.
- Drop the act.
Ying. She's the one that crashed on you.
You'd better confess everything,
or go talk to the police.
I'll confess.
I'm from the year 2001.
Police it is.
I'm your future...
Wait, Zhang Jiang.
She does look familiar.
Do we know each other?
Definitely.
You are my cousin from the city.
Li Leying.
It's been forever, cousin.
I don't think we've met before.
Yet I recognized you at first glance.
You look just like my aunt.
Do I?
What brought you here, Leying?
Hang on.
I get a question.
Stand up.
I thought your name was Ling.
How come she calls you Leying?
Ling is short for Leying.
Just say it fast.
People usually call me Xiaoling.
I got it.
So, my name is Zhang Jiang,
or Zhang Ji-ang if said slowly.
True.
Ying.
You scared me big time.
The whole factory was talking about
how you were hit by a meteor.
I was worried to death.
Got here as soon as I can.
I can assure you it's not a meteor.
This is my cousin.
Let me introduce you.
Xiaoling.
- Yumei.
- Hi, hello.
The TVs are here.
- TV.
Speed up, girl.
Maybe we should take the next one.
Then she'll be late.
Wang Qin and Ying got the only 2 tickets.
And Wang Qin left early.
She doesn't own a TV, either?
- Nope.
- Stand closer.
Get on now.
I can't. Xiaoling.
Try the back.
Sure.
Come on, people, let's scooch.
How did we get off?
Ma'am...
...do you know where they sell TV?
Over there.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
Aunt Qin.
Who would know she's gonna get filthy rich?
TV.
Order, everyone.
People who have tickets can go wait
in line. Those who don't, step aside.
Coming through.
Slow down.
Tickets only.
No tickets, no going in.
What a coincidence.
I know.
We're the only ones with tickets.
Yeah, we can both get one.
- Are we there yet?
- Let me see.
Close.
Ying.
I like your shirt.
The blue dots are so cute.
- Do I?
- Really? It's simple but elegant.
Don't let her.
Wang Qin, there are more dots on the back.
- Not as good as the front.
- The backside is better.
- And your shoes.
- From the factory.
- And that dress.
- You got one too, remember?
Li Huanying.
I was actually here first.
Then you fell behind waiting in line.
What? I was ahead of you.
I was half-shoulder ahead of you
since the beginning.
Then you tried to push your way up,
which I ignored.
You know? I'm staying right here.
I'm staying right here, too.
Such a funny girl
that she started her own row.
Who would serve her anyway?
I've never seen something like that before.
Do you ever shut up? Li Huanying.
You want a piece of me?
What, you don't think I can take you?
Ladies, please.
Watch your manners.
Look.
There are still ten left.
We can all get one.
Eight for the city thermo power plant.
I'll take one.
- One for me.
- And one for me.
That was close.
- Only one left.
- Mine.
- It's mine. Comrade, I'm here first.
- I'm first.
A new batch will arrive next week.
Maybe one of you can come back next week.
Ying.
Let's be fair.
You stand down this week.
And I'll do the same next week.
You wish.
Comrade, sell it to me.
Comrades,
how about you both take a step back...
...and leave the TV
to someone who needs it more?
- I'm in dire need of it.
- I need it way more than she does.
Comrade...
...excuse me,
is this where you sell TV?
Is it here?
Yeah. Great.
I'll take one.
We only have one left
and it's about to be sold.
Ah, that's too bad.
I've waited so long for this day.
When I was six years old
I lost my eye sight.
How I wish...
...I could feel the colorfulness
of the world...
...through this TV set.
But...
Young lady...
...don't be sad.
Take this.
What is...?
This is...
A radio.
Compared to TV it suits you better.
You can hear.
I can hear.
Now that you put it this way,
I'm not sure what to say now.
Why are you crying?
I'm just thinking...
...thinking about...
...my brother who is deaf.
He's not as lucky as I am.
You have a deaf brother?
And another one who's missing.
What an unfortunate family.
Comrades...
...may I suggest...
...that we let this poor woman buy the TV.
Agree?
Well..
I agree.
What about you, Wang Qin?
And you?
I agree.
I can't buy one anyone.
Yeah, I agree.
Thank you.
Ticket, please.
Ticket?
I need a ticket to buy TV?
Will this kind lady
let me borrow...
...your ticket?
Yeah, Ying.
Why don't you give her your ticket?
You take the ticket...
...and the money, too.
Look what I got.
The very first TV in our factory.
I got the first one.
- Yumei, watch out, careful.
- I know.
What are you thinking?
Are you happy to see me?
Of course I am.
I can make you even happier.
Good for you, girl.
People should be positive!
I'll tell you guys the truth.
That TV Huanying bought
even makes me, the director, jealous.
Of course.
You're not alone on this.
Even the manager would be jealous.
Come on guys, quiet down.
Comrade Huanying
is the first one to own a TV...
...in our factory.
Yeah.
An occasion like this
calls for a speech...
...otherwise it'd feel like
something's missing.
Hear, hear.
- I'll say something then.
- Great.
I'm Ying's cousin...
And I helped her buy the TV.
Wang Qin...
...it's only been an afternoon,
what happened to your mouth?
I think, we should all remember that...
...Li Huanying is the first
in our factory to get a TV.
What?
Is it inflammation?
What inflammation?
It's allergy.
We should always talk about this...
...whenever there's a gathering, such as
your kids getting into college or married.
Yeah!
That's all I have to say.
Well said, Cousin Huanying.
I'll just add a few words
to Cousin's speech.
The 3rd FIVB Volleyball Women's World Cup.
Team China versus Team Japan...
...at the final competition
for the champion.
And the deciding set is about to kick off.
China's turn to serve.
Number 10, Chen Yaqiong,
is going to serve the ball.
Sun Jinfang, nice pass.
Number 3, Lang Ping.
And she scores.
Never knew watching TV is this much fun.
China scores with a block.
Sixteen fifteen.
What more can I do to make my mom happier?
Score.
Seventeen fifteen.
China wins.
Guys, quiet, quiet.
While everyone's thrilled
I'd like to make a speech.
To celebrate the victory of team China...
...this year's factory
volleyball tournament...
...will be for women only.
- Let's show them what we got.
- Great!
Ying, you got lucky with that TV scheme.
I'll see you...
...on the volleyball court.
Wang Qin.
How serious is this inflammation of yours?
There's no inflammation.
I have a sore throat because of my allergy.
Not that.
Your breath stinks.
Oops. I thought it was someone's feet.
You smelt it, too.
It almost killed me.
I dare you to touch me again.
It's not her game to call.
We don't have to go.
Right.
Let's not indulge her.
You done?
Let's go.
If we hadn't missed that game...
...she wouldn't have won.
What would my mom have won?
A life-changing opportunity.
I will not let mom's big opportunity
slip away.
Ying, I think you should attend
the volleyball tournament this year.
Why?
Didn't you hear the director?
"Let's show them what we got."
That's just his catch phrase.
Sir, wanna go grab a drink later?
Absolutely.
Let's show them what we got. Go.
See.
Just trust me on this one.
Something great will happen
if you win this year.
Ling...
...we've been here for more then ten years.
I think we'd know
if it'd be something great.
Yeah.
Ling, you don't come here very often.
Let me show you a good time.
Just tell me what you want to do.
I want to see you play volleyball.
Okay, Yumei.
Tell the girls to come tomorrow.
Have you got no principle at all?
Where are the rest of the team?
They all have problems to deal with.
Did you not make it clear
that this time is different?
I did make it clear.
It couldn't have been more clearer.
I even told them that if they don't show
up, no one's gonna beg them to come.
And that they should never show
their faces again. No show.
Yumei, my dear,
you never fail to impress me.
I'll go.
Maybe Yumei wasn't convincing enough.
If I go myself...
...the girls would at least
show me some respect.
Can't play.
End of the harvest season is days away.
I won't be able to make it.
Indeed.
Yumei told me.
But...
I came to you myself.
What difference does that make?
You guys are so funny,
taking turns to come.
I'm actually quite busy.
I went to sleep fine...
...and woke up like this.
The first half of the night
I couldn't seem to get up.
Like I was possessed or something.
Then the second half, I finally got up...
...and then my hair was gone.
It's OK.
It'll grow back in no time.
You know what,
turn around and let me see.
Is it obvious?
I wouldn't say so.
What do you think?
Right.
If you don't look closely...
How can I possibly not look closely?
How can I possibly go out again?
I don't have time for volleyball now.
I'm trying to get the factory
to approve this new program.
It's called Poems by Yanhua.
How I'm under a lot of pressure
as an artist.
I gave up sport to become a poet.
She never even went to school.
You have foreigners working here?
She's from Inner Mongolia.
Her grandfather moved here
from the Soviet Union.
Let me introduce you.
This is Mao Qin.
Sister Mao.
Don't call me sister.
That's for strangers.
Just call me Muscovite.
Where's my uncle?
He's out.
He still goes scavenging for junks?
He does it as an exercise.
Right.
Mao Qin.
We're here to talk to you about
training.
I can't do it.
I'm starting a business.
I'll tell you something. I went to school
with this guy, Zhang Kaifen...
...who got super rich
selling nothing but tea.
If someone like him could make money,
why can't I?
- Indeed you should make some money.
- Right?
What business will you start?
Something that requires
minimum investment or effort...
...but is lucrative.
They are not coming.
And it has nothing to do
with how convincing you are.
Yumei, your little speech
is not helpful at all.
Ling, there's nothing I can do.
I don't think we have to play
under such circumstance.
We really don't have to.
I don't get it. Why did you have to do
this in the first place?
My cousin was making a big deal of it.
You guys are not unwilling to play.
You're just afraid to lose.
Am I right?
You hate losing to Wang Qin.
But you know what?
If you lose this time,
you'll probably be losers for life.
Reverse psychology...
...doesn't seem to work.
This trick, I'm telling you.
Who is Jia Xiaoling?
Which one of you?
You?
You are Jia Xiaoling?
- Just as you pointed out.
- Boss, say no more.
I'm not even finished.
We came to you because Wang...
What's Wang Shoufeng's sister's name again?
Wang Qin.
Do you know Wang Qin?
Yeah.
We're good friends.
Why?
Did you take her TV?
We didn't.
- You're a really good liar, you know that?
- Let me finish.
Boss, I'm upset that you
won't let me join the action.
Allow me to introduce myself.
My name is Leng Te...
...and this factory is my turf.
If you are smart enough
you'd give the TV back.
If you don't that's fine.
I'll just deal with it my way.
You got five seconds to decide.
Five...
No, this is a misunderstanding.
Four...
Three...
Two...
Boss.
- Boss.
- Help me.
- What are you looking at? Go rescue him.
- You go first, I snapped my toe nails.
My horse...
...my chariot. My horse.
My carriage.
How could Wang Qin do this?
Sending those thugs to threaten us.
We have to attend this tournament
and we have to win.
That'll crash Wang Qin.
Great!
- That's what I'm talking about.
- Right?
But we're short of hands.
They are all occupied.
We'll help them solve their problems first.
How...
Ling knows how.
Me? How should I know?
Where are you going?
All yours now.
You are such a good friend.
I don't want it.
What stupid therapy is this?
I'm not doing it.
What choices do you have?
You're not married yet.
Mommy, do you think my hair
would ever grow back?
If it doesn't grow back...
...mom will be here for you
for the rest of your life.
Mommy...
How about now?
Can't tell the difference, can you?
It works.
Not bald anymore.
I shouldn't go out
and walk him anymore, right?
As long as you two are not out together.
Exactly.
Give me ten more.
Here.
Ling, this is way more profitable
than my dad's scavenging business.
Now all that's left are
Yawen's rice paddies.
Once we're done reaping,
we can play some volleyball.
There are still a lot.
When will we ever finish reaping?
Yumei.
Where did Ling go?
To get help.
Said we need more hands on deck.
Who else could she get?
Then, Chan Ho Nam and Chicken rose
to fame overnight in the final combat...
...and the city was
the Hung Hing Gang's to rule.
That means, all of us
are to be known as Goo Wak Chai.
Bingo.
Right, that Chan Ho Nam you mentioned,
what's his other name again?
Zheng Yijian.
I Can Change?
That's one badass name.
Boss, you think he's related
to our town butcher...
...Aye Don Cheng?
Possibly.
Boss.
We should go to the city and join them.
Maybe you can introduce us.
No probs.
Thank you for sharing
all that information.
From now on, we're friends.
BFF, if you please.
Just let us know...
...if you're ever in need
and we'll help.
Didn't expect you to come to us so soon.
You three, get this area covered.
Ling.
Just reap.
Today, Comrade Li Fenjin...
...returned to the factory
after a three-year excursion.
When seeing his co-workers
for the first time in so long.
Li burst into tears.
Now Comrade Zhao Yanhua from the workshop
will perform one of her original poems.
"Mr. Li, Crying Is Not A Crime"
Yanhua's original poems.
Ling wrote it for her.
Mr. Li.
You can cry, for crying...
...is not a crime.
Have a taste of the...
...long overdue tears.
Reunited with former co-workers, Lao Liu...
...Lao Zhang...
...and Lao Wei.
You should take the chance...
...and let out all your tears.
My dear fellow factory workers...
...I've missed you so much!
Let me.
Good game.
That was amazing.
Except for Yumei, she's the weak link.
She's the worst.
But you know what?
Someone...
...doesn't think so.
Who?
Herself.
Yumei, come on.
We must win.
Relax.
We will be the winners.
Bone fracture.
That last move cased it.
You're just helpless.
Why did you do that last move?
Looks like we're not going
to the tournament.
Triumph Chemical Factory's...
...very first Women's Volleyball Tournament
is about to kick off.
Now, let's give a warm round of applause...
...for players of both teams.
Ling.
Come on.
Ying, don't you think your team name
is a bit too much?
Well, we are the forging workshop.
What's wrong with
representing ourselves?
Ying, Ying.
- The manager's here.
- Yeah, he is.
This is a huge event indeed.
So, can we win?
Relax.
No probs.
It gives me great pleasure
to announce that...
...our factory manager is here today.
Sir, would you do the honor
of addressing the audience?
Bravo!
The game now begins.
Bravo.
You serve first. Here.
Keep moving, girls, come on.
Come on!
What is it?
What happened?
Her hair dropped off.
No.
Hell no.
Guixiang.
Timeout before the game even starts?
Totally unnecessary.
Ling, you have really strong hands.
I didn't mean to do that.
Fortunately, we found out about it now.
Any time later and we're done for.
Let's just quit.
Come on now, we must stay in the game.
Ling, it's not that we won't help you.
You see, there aren't enough people.
- Indeed.
- That's true.
Okay, that's enough.
Ling. Quick, go get Guixiang.
- What about them?
- I'll talk to them.
Coming through.
What is this?
So, Xiaoling helped you with all your
chores and now you're quitting on her?
Ling.
- Where are you going?
- Guixiang left.
Everyone else is giving up.
I have to find her now.
But if you leave now,
we'll be even more shorthanded.
Then what do we do?
We'll go get her.
You back and talk to them.
- Go.
- OK.
Hurry up.
Don't worry.
I'll bring them back.
If not, the five of us can play anyway.
Where's Guixiang?
Yumei went to get her.
- Great.
- Ling.
Now we're one player short and you're the
rookie so just stay away from the ball...
- ...and don't get in our way, get it?
- Right.
Come on.
How did you convince them?
- They always look up to me.
- Come on, seriously.
I promised to lend them the TV for a week.
Come on.
Let's kick their asses now.
And we'll watch TV together.
Alright, let's do this.
Ying.
Mine.
What's the score now?
I can't see anything.
He's like a mountain.
Xiaoling sure is giving it all she got.
Totally.
Otherwise we'd have scored more points.
We're one point away from winning.
Pass me the next ball.
I know.
Comrade Huanying...
...if you feel like you can't go on
I can end the game now.
I have the power.
Referee.
Number 13 in.
No.
God, it's over.
Guixiang.
What is she doing here?
That's OK.
It's just a game.
If we hadn't missed that game...
...she wouldn't have won.
It would've totally been your mother.
Use your hands.
The Forger Ladies have got
some spirit in them.
- Are you alright?
- I'm fine.
Keep playing like this.
Come on, girls!
We can do it!
They act like they've won the game.
Li Huanying.
If we get one more point,
we will win the game.
Don't touch the net.
Wang Qin.
You underestimated us.
They don't call me Little Iron Hammer
for nothing.
It has just gotten interesting!
Who's that girl?
Li Huanying from factory branch one.
Not bad.
Have you noticed?
People give off a certain radiance...
...when they refuse to give up.
Mine.
Where do you think you're going?
Referee.
That one was out of bounds.
No way. It landed right on the line.
How could it be? I was close enough
to see everything. It was out.
- OK, I'll be more careful next time.
- No, next time won't do.
Go explain to the manager now,
so we can start over.
Now you're just making trouble.
How about this?
I give you one point, making it even.
I'll give you all those three points.
I don't want three points.
I want you to go talk to the manager.
And we'll play for it again.
- This game means everything to me.
- I'm not a pro, I'm just a cook.
They called me at the last minute.
Why don't you get off my back?
I'm dying of jealousy.
In previous years,
only the 1st place would receive this.
This year, it's like you
just have to be here.
They're being really generous.
This is a nice mug, even comes with a lid.
This mug is meaningful.
How great is this?
Ling, you're so awesome.
We'd have agreed to play immediately
if you had told us at first.
Indeed.
I didn't mean that.
Now, the manager will present
the award to team Forger Ladies.
Unbelievable.
Just a flashlight for the winning team?
I didn't think it's possible, either.
But that's what they did.
Do you think the factory
is generous this year?
They truly are.
The final champions
don't even get promoted...
...or life-changing opportunities?
Nothing like that?
No.
Xiaoling, what were you thinking?
It's not like we played in the Asian Games.
Even for that we won't get promoted.
- Maybe the Olympics.
- Not even the Olympics.
Trust me.
That's enough.
Look at you.
The director's here.
Huanying, come. I need to talk to you.
Shut the door.
I'm not going.
This is a factory mission.
You must go.
Just do it as a favor to me.
Deal.
What mission?
Perhaps I can take your place.
It's an arranged date.
You go.
My dad.
Hello.
My name is Shen Guanglin.
Uncle Guanglin.
And you are...
Li Huanying.
I'm not--
Wait, who said you can come in?
Ying.
Shen Guanglin?
The manager's son.
How can it be Shen Guanglin?
They're made for each other.
What are you talking about?
If they get together, I'll be damned.
If they get together,
you're the one to thank.
How is that?
Weren't you the one who pushed Ying
to attend the volleyball tournament?
Is she didn't go..
...the manager wouldn't have fancied her
to be his future daughter-in-law.
If Ying didn't show up,
the manager would've picked...
...Fengzhi?
No way, you don't think that Fengzhi,
likes look an eggplant?
You're one to talk.
What about Shuxian?
Like she doesn't look like a potato.
Whenever I make fun of Shuxian
you always act like this.
Shuxian definitely does not look
like a potato.
Who else could've been picked
if not Fengzhi?
I don't know.
Should be Wang Qin.
She wouldn't be so lucky
in a million years.
Speaking of lucky.
Dinner's cancelled.
Boss's mom was rushed to the hospital.
What are you doing here?
Ask yourself, when have you
ever not worried your mother?
If it weren't for you,
she wouldn't be in the hospital?
Get away.
What did the doctor say?
It's serious.
I'm sure she will be fine.
Would you believe me if I told you
I know exactly how you feel?
That's not possible.
I'm nothing like you.
My mom has never stopped worrying
ever since I was born.
And, I've never done anything that...
...made her happy.
My dad is right.
If it weren't for me...
...my mom wouldn't have been
in this condition.
Sometimes I wonder...
...if I weren't her son...
...she would've lived a better life.
How's she?
- The surgery was a success.
- Thank you.
Thank you, doctor.
Thank you, doctor. Thank you.
1981.
I wasn't even born yet.
I can't do anything.
How did I wind up here?
Weren't you the one who pushed Ying
to attend the volleyball tournament?
Is she didn't go...
...the manager wouldn't have fancied her
to be his future daughter-in-law.
If the manager didn't pick her...
She wouldn't be so lucky
in a million years.
My daughter Tingting is going
to study in the United States.
At UCLA.
When will you ever make me proud?
And, I've never done anything
that made her happy.
Sometime I wonder...
...if I weren't her son...
...she would've lived a better life.
For Eternity the Great Wall will stand
Through a thousand years
the Yellow River has run
All this spectacles and magnificence
Surely this can't be a land in decay
That's what standard Cantonese sounds like.
I've sung it four times. You got it?
Still no?
You sounded different each time.
Aunt Wang.
You've been here all this time?
Did I sound different every time.
That's the way it's supposed to be.
There are four different songs.
That's enough, go mind you own business.
Move your feet then.
Let's sort out the lyrics,
Young Master Shen.
Anyone who wants to quit,
now is your time to leave.
Don't force yourselves to work with me
because I'm the manager's son.
Let me tell you something.
As of next month,
my dad is no longer the manager.
He'll be promoted to the party chief.
Why don't you go inside?
What are you sitting out here for?
In my opinion,
we should all work harder.
The show is just a few days away.
Aye.
Comrades, let's get serious.
OK.
Hi.
Are you Shen Guangin?
Could I talk to you in private
for a minute?
Whatever it is, we can talk here.
I have to coach these people.
I understand you went on a date yesterday--
- And I think...
- Well. Let's talk...
...over here in private. Come on.
And you are...
- ...from Women's Federation?
- I'm Li Huanying's cousin.
Cousin who works for Women's Federation.
Not that.
I came to ask you
how you feel about Li Huanying.
If you like her...
I can help.
My meeting with comrade Li Huanying...
...was arranged by my father.
What do you mean?
You have no idea
what kind a man my father is.
Let me put it this way.
Growing up...
...be it school, work...
...or dating,
he made the choice for me every time.
And I'd like for once choose for myself.
I see.
Sorry to bother you.
Bye.
Is today Wednesday?
It's really Wednesday, oh god.
Wednesday?
Are we rehearsing or not?
He booked us for Wednesday, right?
Comrade Cousin...
...wait up.
What?
Earlier, we were surrounded by a crowd...
...so I don't think
you got my point clearly.
I got it alright.
Your date with Ying was arranged
by you father...
...and you'd like to make your own choices.
See. You didn't get it.
This time, it was my own choice, and
I asked my father to set up the meeting.
You mean, you really like Ying?
I'm in love with her.
What?
It's OK.
Rain will come.
Yeah.
Rain will come, and mom will be mom.
You can't change the law of natural.
Right.
You mentioned
that you can help me pursue Ying.
How?
These seats are next to each other,
just pretend it's a coincidence.
Thanks.
See you later.
Ying.
What are you doing here?
Come with me.
- For what?
- For some fun.
You like it?
It's hideous.
Not if it goes with this,
suits you perfectly.
- I don't want it.
- You should wear bright color more often.
I hate it. Don't make me wear this.
I'm done.
Don't waste it.
They don't fit.
I'm not wearing these, it looks stupid.
What shoes are these?
Thank you.
Dinner's ready.
Ying.
You've been waiting?
Ling, am I over-dressed coming to
the movies with you looking like this?
You look stunning.
Ling.
I was looking all over for you.
It's urgent, you must come with me now.
What is it?
Please let me borrow her for a while,
we'll be back in no time.
Not that.
What's the emergency?
I'll come with you, maybe I can help.
I have an emergency.
It's urgent.
No need. Why don't you go in first?
I'll go with him and come back
to you once we're done.
- I'll come right back.
- It's about to start, be quick.
- No worries.
- Come on.
Excuse me.
You're here, too.
Here for the movie?
Thank you for this.
It's OK.
I didn't think my acting was
convincing enough, though.
What are you talking about?
Of course your acting's not perfect.
It's not like you learned how to act.
What?
Nothing.
Rain will come.
Why are you laughing?
Nothing. I just realized that...
Rain will come,
and mom will be mom.
- What's so funny about that?
- What?
- What are you laughing for?
What are you laughing?
Now you're just being silly.
OK, stop hitting me, it's raining.
Let's find a shelter, come on.
I'm not going.
I'd like to take a walk in the rain...
...so when my face gets wet
I wouldn't be able to tell...
...which is rain and which are tears.
Excuse me.
Pardon me.
Sorry.
Excuse me.
Comrade Huanying...
Comrade Li Huanying.
Come over. Here's a seat.
What happened?
Is this your date?
You came alone?
Here, go in.
This way. Go in, hurry.
You turn around, too.
Okay.
This drizzle...
...really sets the mood for romance.
What did you say?
I'll bring you some snacks
for the boating tomorrow.
Who says I'll go boating with you?
What are you looking for?
You are by yourself?
Well, you didn't show up.
What were you doing with Leng Te?
Just a small matter, already dealt with.
Is there something
going on between you two?
Ying, don't you need to use the bathroom?
Now that you mention it, I do.
Wait for me.
Why aren't you with Ying?
You want me to be with her?
There are a dozen of seats
between No.6 and No.7.
How are we gonna sit together?
Sorry, my bad, my bad.
How about this?
Tomorrow I'll get you on
a boating date with her.
Ling.
If you really wanna help,
you need to up your game.
In fact, I've checked.
- We'd be perfect for each other.
- Checked what?
Like names.
You see...
...her name is Huanying
and mine is Guanglin.
Together it means
"a warm welcome."
Sounds good, huh?
You should talk to her more
while on the boat.
Relax.
How romantic is this?
I got it ready the day before yesterday,
was going to give it to her.
Won't it go bad in three days?
Nonsense.
I would never give Ying bad food.
- Please don't give her this.
- I'll eat it instead.
Yum.
Ling...
...boats are ready.
Do we have to take the same boat?
Sure, I'll get in the boat with you.
Ying.
Leng Te wants to sail with me.
He... wants to talk to me about something.
You and Ling.
You two...
You and Ling's cousin.
Family.
In-laws.
Ling.
I don't even know when you were born.
1982.
Next year?
Not that.
I mean, I was planning on
having a baby next year.
Row faster.
Want some?
This is so good.
Why are you staring at me?
Well, we're the only ones here.
Who else am I going to look at?
Ying...
Wanna switch?
Sure.
Are you alright?
I'm OK.
Just my appendicitis.
It's your turn to row.
Why did you stop?
Who are you talking to in that tone?
If you're not feeling well,
you can cough out loud.
I won't mind.
It's not that I don't want to cough.
I dare not.
Fast as you can.
You can do it.
Why bother?
Boss is not on the boat.
What did you call me?
Third brother.
What am I, a dwarf?
How far is the shore?
Close.
Go faster.
I will try.
Faster.
Who is that?
They fell into the water.
People are drowning.
Come on, faster.
Through a thousand years
the Yellow River has run
You need to really push
on that last word.
With some passion.
Since we've decided to sing in mandarin,
accent matters.
The thing is,
we have no idea if your mandarin...
...is standard or not.
I'm the only radio announcer
in the factory.
What do you think?
I thought your dad
got you that job.
You are such a cynical person.
What evidence do you have
that my dad got me that job?
Please, it's so obvious.
Before you were the announcer we didn't
even have a radio station in the factory.
Let me tell you something.
That radio station was going to be built
with or without me.
Anyone can doubt my mandarin
but not you.
Once again, for the record,
me being the announcer...
...has nothing to do with my dad,
the manager.
It was simply because of
this beautiful voice...
...that I'm the only announcer
in the factory.
I agree.
Guanglin does have the best
and the most radio-worthy...
...voice among us all.
You're the best candidate
for the announcer job.
Shen Guanglin.
Ling, to be honest...
...with your help, these last few days.
I think it's over between Ying and me.
Don't be so negative.
For what is worth,
you at least had a nice bath...
...in the river.
Enough with the bath.
I think perhaps Ying heard some rumors...
...that my father did everything for me.
That I'm just another spoiled rich kid.
All the more reason not to give up now.
You should try harder, proving to
them you're not what they think you are.
This show is the perfect opportunity...
...for me to show Ying
and everyone in the factory...
...that I, Shen Guanglin,
am a man in my own right.
I'll be the star of the show.
I'm totally on board with you.
What are you going to perform this time?
A chorus.
How are you gonna be the star
of the show in a chorus?
If we sing well then
we'll be the star of the show.
You know what type of man Ying likes?
Tell me, otherwise how would I know?
There's just one thing missing for you
to be her type.
Not funny enough.
Ying likes guys with a sense of humor.
Someone who makes her laugh.
So you must do something else on the show.
I'll help.
I'm not sure if there's
enough time for that.
Director needs to approve the change.
- He's getting off work.
- Go talk to him then.
Just get on the bike, will you?
I don't know how.
- Ying, come on.
- Ling.
Why did you bring me here?
The talent show has begun.
To see Shen Guanglin's performance.
Why would I want to see that?
He'll definitely crack you up this time.
Let's go see him.
Ling.
I sensed something's off
about you last time.
What are you up to?
I...
Not that. Actually, I came up with the idea
for his skit. So, I'd like you to see it.
You came up with it?
- Why didn't you say so?
- Let's go.
For Eternity the Great Wall will stand
Through a thousand years
the Yellow River has run
All this spectacles and magnificence
Surely this can't be a land in decay
I'm suddenly nervous.
It's OK.
Relax.
Just do it as we rehearsed.
The next performance
is absolutely a wonder.
Presented to you in an unprecedented form.
I can almost hear
the excitement in the air.
Without further ado, please enjoy...
...the following two-role act.
There is... The Duet.
With this look, people will pee their
pants laughing upon your entrance.
Trust me.
One more lap.
No one's clapping.
By this time, the audience
will be fighting for breath.
You sure they will?
Most definitely.
With the look and that walk of yours,
they won't be able to stop laughing.
We still need a plan B, though.
My dad will be sitting in the audience.
How about this?
You can also try to put
your left foot on your right foot...
...and then just do this.
No one's clapping.
One more lap.
Sir, should I go up there and help him up?
Let him get up on his own.
- Are you OK?
- I don't know why...
It's just that...
his performance was so funny.
But I dared not to laugh.
- It's OK, the show must go on.
- What?
Out of my way,
I'm in character. Move.
Let's show Guanglin some support, people.
Sure!
Shen Guanglin, get up!
Shen Guanglin!
Bravo, Shen Guanlin!
Shen Guanglin, good job!
Guanglin, let's try again
from before the fall.
Get away.
Something happened.
No big deal.
But it's okay.
A duet is supposed to be
performed by two people.
Now please welcome
onto the stage my partner.
What do you say?
Please.
Yumei, what are you doing?
Why aren't you going out there?
Ling. I didn't know
it's going to be so awkward.
Do I have to go?
What about the rest of the performance?
It'll be humiliating ending like this.
Even more humiliating than now?
Perhaps I wasn't loud enough.
Please welcome onto the stage...
my partner!
Maybe just the one person
being humiliated is enough.
I think I'll just sit this one out.
I'll go take a look.
- I'm here, partner.
- Yeah.
- Here I am.
- I guess I better leave then.
Where are you going? What about Ying?
My dad's gonna disown me
if I don't leave now.
- Don't go.
- You don't think I'm ashamed.
Not after you finish the performance.
Red underpants.
- I'm sorry.
- Don't touch me.
So...
You alright?
How is my dad doing?
Relax.
You dad left.
Let's carry on.
Carry on my ass.
Come on.
Pull yourself together.
- Where do you think you're going?
- Don't go, stop.
Why are you back now?
Ying laughed. I have to pick a side.
Music.
Are you happy to see me?
Of course I am.
I can make you even happier.
Rain will come, and mom will be mom.
You can't change that which is natural.
Then I just rushed onto the stage.
Yumei wouldn't go whatsoever.
- She wouldn't?
- Bad call.
How was I?
Extraordinary.
And how was Shen Guanglin?
You know what? He did surprise me tonight.
You don't say.
Ling.
You and Leng Te, you two...
Nothing will ever happen between us.
I figured.
You're a catch.
You can do so much better.
My mom used to say that.
See.
Ying...
...you will marry a great guy, too.
How could you know?
I know physiognomy.
As in face reading?
Try it on me.
Let me see.
First of all...
...your future husband
will be young, handsome...
...and powerful.
Please, how can a man have
all these qualities at the same time?
He inherited it.
Right, do you prefer a son or a daughter?
A daughter would be great.
What are the odds?
You will have a daughter.
- Do I?
- You don't say.
You daughter will have...
...big eyes...
...and a slim face,
like a Barbie doll.
So pretty?
Looks aren't even her best traits.
She'll start school
at the age of five...
...and if her grades were ever the first in
her class it'd be considered a setback...
...for she has always been
the first in her school.
At 18, she'll get into this...
...prestigious college...
...called UC something A,
where she studies film directing.
And she makes 80 thousand a month.
How awesome is that?
Eighty thousand.
Ling, I can't say I agree with your values.
I want nothing from my daughter,
except for her to be healthy and happy.
You don't get it.
How do I not get it?
Take me for instance.
I'm like a little piglet,
healthy and happy.
But completely useless.
What the hell are you talking about?
I think you're great.
Well, you're not my mother.
I'd have no problem with that.
I'll tell you what, in our next life.
We must be mother and daughter
in our next life.
Deal?
Come on.
But, next life...
I'll be your mom...
Are you trying to take advantage of me?
How about the life after next life?
You'll be my mother then.
You're up.
Just a minute.
Why are you sewing it up?
It's an original style.
What style?
Looks like a cat made it with its claws.
That's how it's supposed to look like.
These pants make you look young.
Why don't you just put on
crotchless pants then?
Much better.
Did I get drunk last night?
You were pretty hammered,
puking all over.
You didn't puke, did you?
Not at first.
I did when cleaning up your vomit.
- So, Ying...
- Ling.
You go first.
Alright.
I got married.
Here's the certificate.
As a matter of fact, Wentian and I
have been together for three years.
We just never told anyone.
Yesterday, while drinking,
I had an epiphany.
I think I should seize the opportunity...
...so I just stepped up and did it.
But it was a wrong step, you know that?
You're getting back to where you started.
What do you mean by that?
Anyway, how do you know I didn't start
at the right place?
I just know.
You know what?
While it's not too late...
...go get a divorce now.
I'm not going.
Go get a divorce.
What are you doing?
- I'll do it for you then.
- Give me that.
- Give it to me.
- What are you doing?
- Give me that.
- Cut it out.
I think I have a pretty good life.
Why don't you believe me?
How come I've never see you before?
I'm in a different office.
We don't see each other often.
Which office is that?
The boiler office.
So, you're a coal-shoveler?
Don't say it like that.
It's a decent job
that keeps people warm.
You do have some tricks.
Sister, your name is Xiaoling?
What a pretty name.
If we ever have a daughter...
...we'll name her that.
Do you prefer a son or a daughter?
A son.
That's sexism.
No.
Think about it.
If we have a son that takes after her
he'd be a handsome boy.
But if our daughter takes after me
it'd be a tragedy.
Maybe she can have my face
but it's gotta be her body.
Slender and tall.
She should at least
inherit one good set of genes.
What if she inherits neither?
It's OK.
She can be all you.
As long as our daughter
is healthy and happy.
Right?
Couldn't agree more.
Cousin, you and I
may not agree on everything...
...but ever since we met...
...I felt this strange closeness
between us.
It's really unusual.
Ying, let's go.
- Go.
- To where?
To tell everyone the good news.
It'll make them happy.
Sister, you stay. Go.
It's time for me to go back.
Leng Te...
...here.
I asked you out today
to say goodbye.
I'm leaving.
You're leaving?
I have no more business here.
So, did you tell Ying?
Don't worry about that.
I will see her again soon enough.
Can't say the same about you, though.
Ling.
Stop the car.
Where are you going?
Shenzhen.
Ying and Wentian have been going out
for three years.
The whole factory was talking about it.
Also that I've been pursuing Ying
for a week.
The whole factory
was talking about that, too.
I'm sorry.
No need.
It's a perfect albeit awkward chance...
...for me to steer away
from my father's shadow.
I'm gonna be my own boss.
You're so brave.
What are you gonna do in Shenzhen?
Haven't figured that out yet.
The factory set up a new office
in Shenzhen...
...and my dad asked me to run it,
wanting me to gain some experience.
I said no.
I'll get a job myself
and live my life.
I yielded the position
to a female co-worker.
I think her name is Wang Qin.
Let's all work for a better future.
No need to shake hands.
We've both been unlucky.
Come find me in Shenzhen
if thing's don't go so well.
Are you leaving or not?
Coming.
So this is it.
Have a safe trip.
Put your mind at ease,
I'll make it safe come what may.
So this is it.
Ling...
What are you doing here?
You're leaving?
Take this with you.
For the road.
I don't need them.
Zhang Jiang, I'll tell you the truth
now that you're here.
Remember the first time you saw me?
Sure. It's like, "bang,"
and you crashed into the ground.
I'm going away now.
Probably in the same way, with a "bang."
Or, possibly, just a "whoosh."
Could there be smoke?
It really could.
Uncles...
...see you soon!
Girl...
...don't get heatstroke.
What's taking so long?
Take a rest and eat something.
By what means are you gonna leave?
You can't stop talking, can you?
Ling...
...that's some funny tailor work
on your pants.
Ying did it.
Well, she's got some skills.
Not like my mom.
You should see the size of the patch
she put on my pants.
My mom used to have clumsy hands, too,
always patching up my pants.
My classmates made fun of me
so she secretly practiced at home.
In the end,
no matter how worn out my pants were...
...she could always fashion
a cute pattern on them.
Do I?
Like this.
Not bad.
But my mom can't do that yet.
Mom, I finished first in the race.
Ling, here.
Just a minute.
What's wrong, Ling?
Ling, what happened?
But my mom can't do that yet.
Ling.
Xiaoling.
You see, I'm a lousy daughter...
...who has never even made you proud once.
How I wish I could change that.
The 1980s...
...is an era of passion...
...and a time of adventurous spirit.
Back then...
...being a factory worker...
...was the most honorable thing...
...with their standard-issue
blue uniform and bicycle.
For many, memories of the 80s...
...are well kept in old photos.
At that time,
color film wasn't even available...
...in China.
So...
...the videos and photos we can find...
...are mostly black and white.
However, skillful photographers...
...would use paint to add a touch
of color to those gray pictures.
To the canteen?
Excuse me, coming through.
Li Huanying.
Zhang Jiang.
How come you look so young?
Do I?
Maybe it's this red armband I'm wearing.
I don't think that's what it is.
You are a young fella, aren't you?
Well, you're not exactly ripe yourself.
I was rejuvenated.
How did this even happen?
My sweetie.
Ying.
- Let's go.
- Uncle Zhang, please, you always liked me.
Stay still, not quite done yet.
Hurry up, kid.
- All right.
- Don't move.
Are you happy to see me?
Of course I am.
I can make you even happier.
Let me help you.
TV, refrigerator, you name it.
I can get them all for you.
Trust me.
I think we should all remember that...
...Li Huanying is the first in our factory
to get a TV.
Your cousin?
Yes.
She's a cocky one.
What is she doing here?
Trying to make me happy.
What is this?
So, Xiaoling helped you
with all your chores...
...and now you're quitting on her?
Ying.
Why do we have to play this game?
Xiaoling's mom was a volleyball player...
...and now she's probably gone.
But, what does that have to do with us?
She said I look just like her mother.
Let's go home.
Mommy.
Yes.
I'll be your mom in the next life.
No, I'll be your mom in the next life.
You managed to hold up the bun
when you fell.
Mom, I pooped my pants.
Stop laughing.
Bad mommy.
Why does my baby keep pooping her pants?
Because you're so little.
If you're so little, how come you're
in the same class with older kids?
That's because my baby is the smartest.
Aren't you?
Yes.
Let mommy have a sniff.
Mommy.
Li Huanying.
What did you call me, you little brat?
I want to eat skewers.
Let's go.
Can we not eat skewers?
Alright.
How about some crawfish?
Absolutely.
My baby is so gullible.
Are those crawfish?
So many of them...
...biting your tummy.
Mom...
Li Huanying.
What did you call me, you little brat?
I got into the provincial institute of art.
Come again, what?
Ying, I heard it.
Xiaoling got into
the provincial institute of art.
Why is the tuition so expensive?
Mommy, there's like a thousand left
on this account.
Not this.
This is my backup plan in case
you turn out to be a total failure.
How dare you say that?
Don't you believe in me?
I do.
That's bullshit.
What if...
Don't "what if" me.
I forgot to give you this,
take it.
When did you make them?
Does it matter? You will eat it anyway.
Mom, it's snowing.
You should take the bus home.
- It's not that far, I can just walk.
- Come on, buy the ticket now.
Since when did you learn to
care about your mother?
I'll see you get on it.
Can I get a refund for the ticket?
- Aunt Ying, why are you getting off?
- I have some unfinished business.
Mom.
Don't go.
Don't leave me.
My baby...
...you'll live a healthy
and happy life.
I can't.
Transcription by
jantoniot
Resync by