It's almost new.
Three hundred cartridges.
The guy who
gave it to me said...
you can hit
as far as three kilometers.
How much are you asking
for all of this?
One thousand dirhams.
One thousand dirhams?
I'll give you five hundred.
And a goat.
With this rifle, your sons
will kill plenty of jackals.
Here, let one of your boys try.
Let Yussef shoot.
Dad, I want to shoot first.
This is the safety.
Push it in when you're ready.
If he doesn't hit the jackals,
at least he'll scare the shit out of them.
Your turn Yussef.
He shoots better than you.
Good luck,
have a good day.
God bless you.
Kill at least three jackals.
Make sure no one
sees you with the rifle...
if you see someone coming, hide it.
What are you doing?
I told you,
don't spy on her.
What do you care?
Move it.
Five to two.
There's a jackal.
Where?
Over there.
What are you doing,
you idiot?
Zohra doesn't mind.
She doesn't, but I do.
This is between her and me.
You're both pigs.
Next time I'm going to tell Dad.
Stay out of this.
If you want me to stay out of it,
don't do it.
What are you doing?
Hassan said this bullet
could reach three kilometers.
That rock didn't move.
You don't know how to shoot.
Give me the rifle.
See.
Yeah, but that's not
three kilometers.
I bet the bullet
can't hit that far.
These bullets are lame.
You're not aiming right.
What'll you give me
if I hit that car?
I'll shoot.
You see? Nothing.
Let me shoot.
Shoot at it.
See... nothing.
You're right, they're useless.
Where are these kids?
Where are you?
I'm coming to get you...
Base!
You win.
- Yes?
- Amelia?
Yes, sir.
Hi. How's everything?
Everything is okay, sir.
Mrs. Rachel told me.
I am very sorry, sir.
How's Mrs. Susan?
She's better now.
They're going to have to operate, but...
Look, Rachel's flying in tonight.
She's gonna find someone to
take care of the kids so you can go.
Thank you, sir. Thank you.
I really appreciate it.
So, look after them, okay?
Don't tell them anything.
No, no, no. Don't worry, sir.
Don't worry. Okay.
- Put Mike on, please.
- Yes, sir.
Mike? Your dad is calling.
- Hi, Daddy.
- Hi, sweetie. How are you?
Good. Dad, guess what? Today
they brought hermit crabs to class.
Oh, really?
I held one in my hands. It bit me.
It really didn't bleed, but...
Dad? Are you okay?
I'm okay. Everything's fine.
Mariana wanted to take one home.
But the teacher didn't let her. She was...
I don't want to go to sleep.
Mike. Mike.
Did you brush your teeth?
Sleep with angels, my darling.
Sleep well, sweetie.
Amelia?
Could you leave the light on?
You are already sharing a room...
didn't we agree
to sleep with the lights off?
But I'm scared.
There's nothing to be scared of.
But I'm scared that what happened
to Sam is going to happen to me.
No, that won't happen to you.
Sam died while he was sleeping.
No, baby, no, no.
That only happens to some babies
when they're really, really little.
Your brother is already
high in heaven, baby.
I'll sit here with you.
But you can't talk anymore, okay?
Go to sleep.
But today is my son's wedding, sir.
Cancel your son's wedding.
I'll pay for another one,
I'll pay for a better one.
I need you to do this, Amelia.
Everything is ready, sir.
Can't anyone come to take care
of the kids? It's just one day, sir.
How do you expect me to find someone
from here?
Susan's still recovering, and Rachel
can't make it to take care of the kids.
Can't do it. Hold on.
We're really counting on you, Amelia.
I'm sorry, but you have to do this.
- But...
- Goodbye.
How can I be
in two places at once?
I'm just asking you
to take them for today.
I can't, the mister is still home.
And they aren't going out?
No, I don't think so.
Okay, I'll talk to you later.
I can't Amelia.
Please, it's my son's wedding.
Just for the day, Lucia.
I'll be back for them tonight.
And what do I say to Mrs. Catherine?
I don't know.
Tell her they're your nephews.
Right, because they look
so much like me...
with my American looking face!
Are we going to see your house?
Yes. You are going to see my house.
Is it far?
No, no.
What's up?
Hi Auntie.
Great to see you, Santiago.
Mike. Debbie.
Hello!
Hello, hello.
They're really shy.
What? These kids
are coming with us?
I couldn't find anyone to watch them.
Their parents won't return tonight.
Why bring them?
They'll drive you crazy.
Don't worry,
they're very good kids.
Don't you want to
leave them with somebody?
I know a girl who
can take care of them.
Are you crazy?
I have to take them with me.
I can't leave them
with just anybody.
Are you sure, Auntie?
You want to order?
Yeah, I'll have the chicken couscous
and a Coke.
What do you have
that doesn't have fat in it?
Everything is delicious.
I'll have the fried eggplant
and a Diet Coke.
Sorry, we don't have Diet Coke.
- Then a regular Coke.
- Two Cokes.
Richard, why did we come here?
What do you mean, why?
Really. Why are we here?
To be alone.
"Alone."
- Throw out the ice.
- The Coke's hot.
Yeah, but you don't know
what kind of water is in there.
Jesus Christ. Why can't you just relax?
Why are you so stressed?
You are the reason I'm stressed.
You're the reason why I can't relax.
You could if you tried.
You don't think I tried?
You're never gonna forgive me,
are you?
You know what I'm talking about.
Hey. I'm not gonna argue.
Okay.
You just let me know
when you're ready to argue.
If you're not gonna run away again.
- Honey? What happened?
- I'm okay.
Honey, what happened?
What happened?
You're bleeding, you're bleeding.
- Oh, my God!
- She's been shot!
Jesus. What happened?
You're bleeding. Oh, my God!
Stop the bus!
- What happened?
- Stop the bus!
The ball was out.
That was out.
No, it was good.
I'm deaf, not blind.
You're out.
You shouldn't have lost your temper.
We lost the game.
It wasn't my fault,
it was the ref.
If you hadn't been thrown out,
we would've won the game.
Why are you
in a bad mood?
She's always in a bad mood
because nobody's fucked her yet.
I'm gonna fuck your dad
to get rid of my mood.
I'll see you at the J-Pop.
What do you want to eat?
I said I'd meet my friends
from the team at J-Pop.
Didn't you tell me
we would have lunch together?
Dad, I told you I was
going to eat with them.
You never pay attention to me.
My mother always
paid attention to me.
Why do you want to fight?
I miss your mother too.
I'm doing the best I can.
Don't forget
the dentist at three.
Take care.
Do you have a table?
Why all the way in the corner?
Isn't the view nice?
Do you like him?
Hello.
Can I play with you?
Or you can
have a drink with us?
Tell him to speak slowly.
Can you say that
a little slower?
You assholes,
how embarrassing.
What's the matter?
They look at us
like we're monsters.
Oh, come off it.
What are you doing?
Now they're going to meet
the real hairy monster.
Don't forget your appointment
with the dentist. Papa.
I have to go.
I'll see you at your place, then.
What are you doing here?
Something we ate
gave us a stomach ache.
The goats will die
if they don't eat.
Wash your face
and take them out again.
My stomach hurts.
There are other
chores to do then.
Move it. Let's go.
God bless. Bye, bye.
Thank you,
I'll see you tomorrow.
Tell your mother
to prepare dinner.
Did you kill any jackals?
We shot at them,
but didn't hit any.
You have to kill them.
If not, they're going to eat all the goats.
Why did you come home late?
They closed the road,
we took the long way.
Apparently some terrorists
killed an American tourist.
An American?
Yes, the terrorists attacked
a tour bus on the road.
No, there aren't any terrorists here.
You never know.
How do you know
the American died?
That's what they were saying.
The police are looking for the culprits.
You see how easy it is
to get into paradise?
Is this Mexico?
Yes, this is Mexico.
My mom told me
that Mexico is really dangerous.
Yeah... it's full of Mexicans.
Don't talk like that.
It's not true.
I mean, yeah, it's full of Mexicans, but...
How wonderful, you made it.
You decided to bring them?
Hey, what's up?
Oh, son, look how handsome.
You look like Julio Preciado.
Forget Julio Preciado,
he looks like Luis Miguel.
Debbie. Mike.
These are the kids
I take care of.
Say hi to Luis.
Lucio, come here.
This is Mike and Debbie.
He's called Lucio.
He's gonna take care of you, okay?
Take them to play.
Mom, I don't know how you did it,
but it zipped up perfectly.
And it's been 15 years
since I wore this dress.
You haven't changed a bit, Ma.
Working dear, hard work...
that's what keeps you young.
What are you guys laughing about?
Nothing Ma, nothing.
I'll give a buck to the first
who catches a chicken.
Careful with the 'huevos.'
Very good, Debbie got one.
Debbie's the winner.
Okay, now we need another five.
So we have five chickens here.
Okay, now who's going to help me?
You? Okay, come.
Hold it tight, like this.
Grab it right.
Everyone back up...
give me some room.
Someone, help!
Is anybody a doctor? Please, a doctor!
- Where's the nearest hospital?
- It's far away. About four hours.
- Is there anything closer?
- There's a clinic.
But on the south. In the bus
it will take us an hour and a half.
- Away from Ouarzazate?
- Yes. It's the closest thing we've got.
Get down!
- Put that there.
- Okay.
Stop! Stop!
We need your help.
My wife's been injured.
I need your help. Help. Hospital.
Help, come here.
Tell him we need his help!
No, wait! Wait! Wait!
Stop him! Stop him!
Ouarzazate isn't this way.
They're going to start shooting at us.
- Turn the bus around, Anwar!
- It hurts.
- Turn back. Turn the bus around!
- It really hurts.
We got to get somewhere closer.
Is there anywhere else we can take her?
We can take her to my town.
It's near here, and there is a doctor.
We can call Erfoud for an ambulance.
Okay. Okay.
Watch her shoulder!
- Turn this way.
- No, no.
Through the next door. Come on.
We got to call an ambulance.
I need to call my embassy.
Okay. If you have the number
of your embassy, I can go call.
Where are you going?
I'll make the call.
Okay, I got to go make a call.
- Please don't leave me here alone.
- You're going to be all right.
- Can she help?
- Yeah, yeah.
Where are you going? Please
don't leave me here alone.
- Can she help?
- Yes.
Listen, listen. It's gonna be all right.
I'm just gonna go make a call.
Wait, wait, wait, wait. Tell her
she has to keep pressure right here.
She cannot let go.
Does she understand?
Yes.
I'm just gonna make sure help's
on the way. I'm coming right back.
- Please don't leave me.
- Does she understand?
- I'll be right back.
- Richard, no, don't leave me here.
- Richard, don't. Richard!
I'll be back, sweetheart.
Just gonna make the call.
- How's your wife?
- It's bad. I can't stop the bleeding.
- Get her out of there and let's go.
- Where? Where do I take her?
In Egypt in a town like this
they slit 30 German tourists' throats.
- They might do the same to us.
- No, sir, not here.
What do you know? We've got to get
out of here as soon as possible.
It's unbearably hot.
- We have to get back for our children.
- Look, you can't leave us here.
- What is the point in our staying?
- In case we need the bus!
He can drop us off
and come back for you.
- No.
- I'll stay with you if you need me.
Please just wait. Let me figure this out.
We're not gonna risk our lives, so hurry.
I need your phone.
I will pay.
Rachel? Rachel? It's Richard. Listen.
Hey, where are you?
We're still... Listen, listen.
There's been an accident.
Your sister's been shot.
She's been shot.
I don't know. I don't know.
- She's hit in the neck.
- Oh, my God!
Listen, listen, I need you
to call the embassy
and tell them what happened.
And call Mark, okay? Call Mark.
Where are you?
Where are we?
Tazarine. Three hours
southwest of Erfoud.
Tazarine. T-A-Z-A-R-I-N-E.
Three hours southwest of Erfoud.
It's in the desert. It's a village.
- How are we supposed to find you?
- Listen, listen, listen!
- This is urgent, okay?
- Okay.
Call the embassy. They will help us.
And call James!
This is the doctor.
Easy.
Easy, easy. Easy! Easy!
I can't, I can't.
Tell him, easy.
The bullet didn't
touch her spine.
If she stays like this,
she will bleed to death.
What did he say?
He says
she will be fine.
Don't you fucking lie to me.
You tell me what he said.
Tell me what he said!
Hospital. Hospital.
I know, hospital! What can you do?
Is there anything
we can do?
I have to stitch up the wound
to stop the bleeding.
He says he need to sew up the wounds.
What did he say?
He said you need some stitches, honey.
Stitches? What do you mean, stitches?
- What kind of doctor is he?
- He's a veterinarian. But he is good.
And tell him
her clavicle is broken.
He says she has a broken bone
and he has to put a splint on it.
If he doesn't sew up her wound,
she might bleed to death.
- Wait. Wait, wait.
- Richard.
No, no, no, Richard.
We have to
hold her down.
- Richard. Richard. No, no, no, no.
- Wait. Wait. Wait. Wait.
- Richard, don't let him.
- Honey, we have to do this.
It's still bleeding. We got to stop
the bleeding. You gotta do this.
- We have to do this.
- No, no, don't let him.
- Listen to me.
- No, no, no, please.
No, no, no, no. Richard, don't.
- No!
- You got to be still.
- Richard, don't let him! No.
Be strong, be strong.
Here are the sterilized drill bits.
You have cavities
in two molars.
What are you doing?
What's wrong with you?
Get out.
Get out right now.
Yes, I'll let him know.
That's Mr. Wataya's daughter.
Thank you.
Are you Yasujiro Wataya's daughter?
She's deaf-mute...
Face her when you speak
so she can read your lips.
Are you Yasujiro Wataya's daughter?
We are Yoshjo Hamano and Kenji
Mamiya of the Metropolitan Police.
We would like
to see your father.
No, it's nothing bad.
We just want to talk to him.
Do you know
where he is?
Please tell him to call.
Don't be scared.
We just want to talk to him.
Thank you.
Chieko, I waited for you.
I have a meeting so I'll be back late.
I left you a bento box. Papa.
I'm on my way to your place.
Where are you?
Hurry up!
Moroccan officials
are investigating suspects...
in the shooting of
an American tourist.
Officials said the shooting
took place...
Are you ready?
Yeah, I'm just going to get my bag.
The cops came again?
Yeah. They hadn't come in nine months.
But these were different cops.
Did they come to ask
about your mother's death?
No, but they're probably going
to ask my dad about the same things.
They're just not convinced,
are they?
Believe it or not,
I liked one of the cops.
Idiot.
Did you put on some panties?
Are you sure
it was here?
An American stopped me.
I was scared.
He was covered in blood.
Where was the bus stopped?
Over there.
Captain Alarid... Captain Alarid.
I found cartridges.
We found four.
Here's one.
Did you search all over?
Yes, the whole mountain.
They're from around here.
Find out who has
a .270 caliber rifle.
Hassan Ibrahim?
- Yes.
- Drop your weapon.
I don't have a weapon.
Drop it now.
I told you to drop
your weapon.
This is just my knife.
Get on the ground.
What did we do?
Get down on the ground...
face down.
Don't look at me.
What did we do?
Take these skins to Najib,
see if he wants to buy them.
Why did you shoot at the bus?
I didn't shoot at anyone.
Then who?
It wasn't me.
That was your rifle.
I sold it yesterday.
Who did you sell it to?
Do you know where
Abdullah Adboum lives?
Yes.
You have to go over those mountains.
Who lives
in this area?
We live here with our mother.
Abdullah lives on the other side.
If you're lying, I'm going to
come back and cut your balls off.
You can come back
anytime you like.
Don't walk
between the graves.
Papa... Papa...
What happened?
The police...
they're looking for you.
Me? Why?
No, not for you...
they're looking for us.
Looking for you?
Why?
Because of the tourist.
What tourist?
The American...
Yussef killed her.
Liar, we both did.
What are you saying?
Yussef started shooting
at the cars...
because Hassan said
that the bullet could go far.
Liar, you started shooting at the cars.
But you killed her.
What are you saying?
Yussef killed the American
and he spies on Zohra naked...
and Zohra lets him watch her.
That's garbage.
It's not garbage.
She's a street girl and he spies on her.
Time to drink!
This song is dedicated
from Luis to Patricia...
the most beautiful bride
in the world.
I think Aunt Amelia has to dance.
Amelia, can I have this dance?
I don't think your wife
would like that.
Ohh, she passed away 10 years ago.
Come on Amelia.
Let's go dance... You have
something white on your face.
Don't get excited,
it's only cake.
Today, near Tazarine,
there was an incident.
An American was shot.
Authorities say it
could have been a robbery.
But, the American government was
quick to suggest a terrorist link.
Minister Hassan Hazal
has said...
that terrorist cells have been
eradicated in our country...
and one act
of vulgar banditry...
followed by superficial evaluations
the U.S. places on it...
cannot ruin our image
or the economy.
I want to call the kids.
Richard, I want to talk to the kids.
We can't move you right now.
- We'll call them later.
- I want to talk to the kids.
I got to talk to them.
I got to talk to the kids.
You have to turn on the
air-conditioning, my husband is ill.
No air-conditioning,
no gasoline near. I'm sorry.
Please, it's too hot.
We can get dehydrated.
What did he say?
He says we can't turn on
the air-conditioning
because it uses the gas.
Oh, fuck that. Come on.
Fuck you.
Tom, where are you going?
Get back. Wait there. Get back.
- Look, we're leaving.
- You're not leaving us.
There's old people here.
The heat is really getting...
Wait for the ambulance,
and then you can leave.
There's a man in the bus
who almost fainted,
and there's a woman who needs to
get back in time to take her medication.
- We can't leave him here.
- Well, let him come, then.
His wife's in no condition to travel.
There's people in no condition
to be kept waiting.
Can't you see that?
Please wait. The ambulance
is gonna be here any minute, right?
It's gonna be here any minute.
So I'm asking you all to please wait.
Thirty minutes.
We're giving you thirty minutes.
Who are they?
My cousins.
Is he deaf-mute
like us?
No, but he understands some.
What is your name?
Chieko.
My name's Haruki.
It's whisky.
Do the cops come around here?
Sometimes.
You smell good.
Welcome home... may I help you?
Are you sure
you want him to come now?
Is this Detective Mamiya?
The deaf-mute girl you met this
afternoon asked me to call.
Yes, her.
She says she needs to talk to you,
alone... about her father.
Why did you do this?
Answer me, damn it!
We were testing the rifle.
Are you idiots?
You killed a woman.
And you...
You got naked
so your brother could watch?
Zohra got naked lots of times
so Yussef could watch her.
Is it true or not?
Why did you do this to us?
Where's the rifle?
I told you,
a hunter gave it to me.
What hunter?
A Japanese hunter...
gave it to me.
I've got a picture.
She can get it.
Go get it.
He's holding the rifle
he gave me.
We're going to Najib's house.
If the cops come,
tell them we went south.
This Abdullah doesn't live
in the area you told us.
Are you playing with us?
He lives in the area
he told you.
He lives there?
You're going to take us.
They're over there.
The police, the police.
Run... run.
Get down.
Mom, stay here tonight.
I can't, I have to get these kids home.
It's almost dawn.
But this fucking guy
is really drunk.
Drunk my ass. I'm fine.
I'll be right back.
Stay a little while,
the party's just starting.
I would like to, but these kids
have soccer practice tomorrow.
See you soon, Son.
Congratulations, my darling.
Take care of my grandchild.
I'm dying to be a grandmother.
Seriously, you're not drunk man?
Drunk my ass.
I'm fine. I'll be back.
Remember, they got you once already
and you got in a lot of trouble.
Bye, Ma...
If things don't work here,
I'll meet you with the 'gringos.'
Hey, be careful.
I'll cross the border
through Tecate...
that will get us to
San Diego super fast.
Papers?
- Where you coming from?
- From Mexico.
From a wedding.
Where you from?
From Valle de Guadalupe.
Valle de Guadalupe.
Where you headed today?
To San Diego. We're going...
I'm taking them.
- Who are they?
- Her nephews.
Her nephews.
They don't look like you, ma'am.
No, no, no, no. I'm in charge of them.
- Do you have their passports?
- Yes.
Is there a problem?
Should there be one?
Wait right here just a minute.
Don't say anything.
Let me do the talking.
But you're provoking him.
I was just kidding.
Can you open your trunk, sir?
- What?
- Open your trunk.
Yes, yes, yes.
Close it up.
Get back in the vehicle.
Glove compartment, ma'am.
Purse?
All right.
What now?
Motherfucker...
Ma'am?
- You said you were in charge of them?
- Yes.
We need the parents' letters
of permission.
Parents' letters?
What's that?
Hey there, sweetie.
Tell me, is this lady here your auntie?
No, she's not my auntie.
She's in charge.
- Are you drunk, sir?
- Me?
- Are you intoxicated?
- No.
Sir, I'm gonna ask you
to step out the vehicle.
- Why?
- I need you to step out the vehicle now.
I need you to step out the vehicle now!
- Sir, can I explain?
- No, you cannot explain!
I'm telling you
that you will step out the vehicle!
Don't make me ask you again!
Wait, sir. Get back into the vehicle.
What you're gonna do now
is you're gonna follow me
to the secondary inspection area.
- Can I explain?
- No, you cannot explain.
Sir, you will shut your mouth
and you will follow me...
I heard you... stop shouting.
You will park your vehicle
and you will get out.
Don't shout at me.
You will shut your mouth and you will
do as you're told. Follow me!
Stop shouting at me.
Step out of the vehicle as told.
Easy Santiago, please.
Upon passing this van, you'll turn to
the right and park your vehicle.
I got a port runner.
What are you doing?
I got a port runner! Tecate border!
Officer Brigg, Tecate border!
What are you doing, Santiago?
What are you doing!
See, I told you!
You shouldn't have brought them.
Santiago, stop acting like a
madman and stop the car.
Please, Santiago, stop!
Shut those kids up!
Shut them up!
Sweetie, everything is okay.
Don't cry.
Please stop, Santiago.
Motherfuckers, fucking gringo assholes,
here they come.
Get out. Get out.
Are you crazy? Where?
Get out. If they catch us,
we're all screwed...
I'll lose them,
then come back for you.
Get out, for Christ sake!
Santiago, calm down.
Aunt Amelia, get out...
for the love of God!
Get out, kids.
Come on, come on, get out!
Santiago is going to
come back soon and...
the sun is going to rise.
I want to go home now.
Be careful, baby.
Thank you.
Is that your daughter?
Yes. The third of five.
- Do you have kids?
- Yeah.
- Just two?
You should have more.
What about you?
How many wives you have?
I can only afford one.
Come on! Find another ambulance!
Do something!
Why can't you call
another ambulance?
They just told me
the ambulance isn't coming.
And you know we don't
have another ambulance.
There isn't another ambulance.
What do you mean, there's no
other ambulance? What do you mean?
Fucking move! Fucking find me
an ambulance! Find me an ambulance!
He wants to know how
he will get his wife out of here.
Tell him they said
his embassy will deal with it.
- Your embassy will deal with it.
- What can my embassy do?
This is your fucked-up country! It's your
responsibility! You do something!
The Americans
stopped the ambulance.
They want to send a helicopter,
but there are problems.
He says it's your embassy
who stopped the ambulance
and they will send a helicopter.
Now I'm supposed to wait for
a helicopter? Fucking do something!
Fuck you! Fuck you!
- How's your wife?
- We can't stay here any longer.
- Stay away from me.
- It's gonna get dark soon.
People are not feeling well.
It's dangerous.
Don't you push me!
Fuck that! We're leaving!
Shut up! Shut up! Shut up! Shut up!
Take it easy!
- Shut up! Shut up!
- Calm down. Come here.
- Get off me!
- Calm down!
If you leave, I'll kill you. I'll kill you.
Come with us. Come with us.
Are you all right?
No, we need help now.
We need help now. Do you understand?
I'm doing everything I can do.
I've got the State Department
on the other line right now.
They're doing everything they can do.
Due to some political problems
that are being resolved...
I don't give a shit about
political problems. I need help now.
Everybody is doing everything they can.
Okay? I don't know what else I can do.
It's all over the news.
Everybody is paying attention
and doing everything that they can.
Richard...
Stop! Stop! Stop! Stop!
Good evening.
The doorman called to say
you wanted to talk to me.
I don't understand.
Could you speak slowly?
I'm sorry.
What was it
you wanted to tell me?
Do you have tea?
"My father had nothing to do
with my mother's death."
What's this?
When your mother jumped off the
balcony, your father was asleep?
You saw her jump?
You've already told the other officers?
What are you talking about?
Does your father still hunt?
There was an incident involving a rifle
in your father's name.
That's why we want to talk to him.
Understand?
Your father isn't going to jail.
We just need to talk to him.
I have to go.
I really have to go.
What are you doing?
Please stop.
No, this is wrong.
You're just a girl.
Enough, stop it!
Give me that rifle.
They're going to kill us.
I killed the American. I was the
only one who shot at you.
They did nothing... nothing.
Kill me, but save my brother, he did
nothing... nothing.
Save my brother...
he did nothing.
Help!
What's happening?
Why are we hiding
if we didn't even do anything wrong?
Because they think
we did something wrong, baby.
That's not true. You're bad.
No, sweetie. No, I'm not.
I just did something stupid.
Sweetie, I have to go look for help.
- Stay here and don't move, please.
- I'm not staying here alone.
Honey, you have to take care
of Debbie, baby.
I'm going with you.
I won't be long. I promise. Stay here.
Don't move. Okay?
I won't be long, baby.
Drink.
I have to go and get two kids
I left behind in the desert. Please?
They're Americans.
- When did you cross?
- I didn't cross. I live here.
Please, please, help me find those kids.
Stand here. Don't move.
Attention, Dispatch.
I think I got the suspect.
Ma'am, you're under arrest.
You want to turn around
and put your hands
behind your head, please.
I live with those kids, I swear!
- Turn around.
- Please, sir, those kids will die!
Thank you.
Then we'll get you some water.
They're alone.
They are children,
they will die.
You're gonna take me to them, okay?
Ma'am, are you with them?
Richard?
What?
If I die, you take care of the kids.
Especially Mike. He really needs you.
You're not gonna die. You can't die.
You just can't.
Don't you ever leave them again.
I will never leave them.
- I peed my pants.
- What?
I couldn't hold it in and I peed.
I've got to pee again.
Do you have a pan we could use?
A pan?
Could you give us
a few moments alone?
Yeah, of course.
There.
Now sit.
I can't.
Yep. Yeah, I can.
Forgive me, my love.
When Sammy died,
I didn't...
I ran.
- I was scared.
- I was scared, too.
- It wasn't my fault.
- It wasn't your fault.
He wasn't breathing.
I couldn't...
I love you so much.
I'm forgetting his face.
Hello? Richard Jones?
I'm very sorry about
what happened to your wife,
but you can be sure that the culprits
will be punished.
What the fuck is taking so long?
Well, the Moroccan government
wouldn't let us use their airspace.
They refused to acknowledge
that this was an act of terrorism.
What about the ambulance?
Taking your safety into consideration,
Mr. Jones, we didn't believe
it would be appropriate
to send a Moroccan ambulance.
Stay put. We settled the matter.
A helicopter should arrive soon.
- How long?
- Soon.
No! How long?
There's no need to apologize.
It's a miracle
we found those kids, ma'am.
I don't know how you could have left
them alone like that out in the desert.
- How are they, sir?
- That's none of your business.
You know how many kids die every year
trying to cross this border?
I raised these kids since they were born.
I take care of them day and night.
I feed them breakfast
and lunch and dinner.
I play with them.
Mike and Debbie
are like my own children.
But they are not your children, ma'am.
Plus, you've been working
in this country illegally.
What about my nephew, Santiago?
I don't have any information on him.
We located the father in Morocco.
He was very angry,
but decided not to press charges.
Thank you.
Nevertheless the government
of the United States
has deemed that you are
seriously breaking the law,
and is determined to immediately
and definitively deport you.
Sir, I've been here for 16 years.
I have my things here. I rent a house.
I made a life here, sir.
You should have thought
about that beforehand.
I want to talk to a lawyer.
If you attempt to take this to trial,
I can assure you,
you'll only be prolonging the inevitable.
I recommend you accept
voluntary deportation.
The sources of the attack
are not yet known.
But it is clear that Moroccan
and US government officials
are working quickly
to secure the area for all citizens.
Locals reported Susan Jones,
an American mother of two...
Mr. Jones, I'm Ken Clifford,
the US ambassador.
We will find these people.
Whoever they are, we will find them.
Thank you very much.
That's all I have to say now.
Mr. Jones?
I'm going to have to
operate immediately.
Is she gonna be all right?
It's probable.
We're gonna try to save her arm.
She's been bleeding internally
and there's been some clotting,
so there's a high risk of gangrene.
But is she gonna be all right?
Excuse me, sir.
- Yes?
- Amelia?
Yes, sir.
Hi, how's everything?
Everything is okay, sir.
Mrs. Rachel told me.
I am very sorry, sir.
How's Mrs. Susan?
She's better now.
They're going to have to operate, but...
Look, Rachel's flying in tonight.
She's gonna find someone to
take care of the kids so you can go.
Thank you, sir. Thank you.
I really appreciate it.
So, look after them, okay?
Don't tell them anything.
No, no, no. Don't worry, sir.
Don't worry.
Okay.
Put Mike on, please.
Mike? Your dad is calling.
- Hi, Daddy.
- Hi, sweetie. How are you?
Good. Dad, guess what? Today
they brought hermit crabs to class.
Oh, really?
I held one in my hands. It bit me.
It really didn't bleed, but...
Dad? Are you okay?
I'm okay. Everything's fine.
Mariana wanted to take one home.
But the teacher didn't let her. She was...
I felt sad for her 'cause
she went to the principal's office.
You know what she did?
She started crying.
She was really crying.
And the teacher had to send her
to the principal's office
'cause she was really crying.
Mr. Wataya, this officer
has been looking for you.
Good evening, I'm Lieutenant Mamiya.
Good evening, how can I help you?
Sir, there was an incident and...
I'm sorry to bother you, but...
do you own a .270 caliber
Winchester M70 rifle?
Registration number...
UK-9023.
I don't remember the number,
but I did have a rifle like that.
Is it true that you gave that rifle
to a Mr. Hassan Ibrahim...
who lives in Morocco?
Hassan Ibrahim?
He says he was
your guide in a hunt.
Hassan? Yes,
I remember him well.
He was a good guide and a very
good man, I gave him the rifle in thanks.
Did anything happen?
That rifle was used
in an attempted murder...
and the Moroccan police want
to confirm it's not off the black market.
No, I gave it to him.
Is Hassan OK?
I don't know about that.
Am I legally involved?
Not for the moment, but can you
come down to the station tomorrow?
I have a few questions.
Can I leave now?
Good night.
Excuse me.
I heard from your daughter...
about your wife on the balcony.
I'm very sorry.
What balcony?
About how your wife killed herself
by jumping off the balcony.
My wife never jumped off a balcony.
She shot herself in the head.
My daughter was the first to find her.
I've explained it
to the police many times.
Don't bother us with that anymore.
I'm very sorry sir, we won't
bother you anymore.
Good night.
Another shochu.
Susan Jones, who was wounded
in a terrorist attack in Morocco...
was discharged from a Casablanca
hospital this morning, local time.
The American people finally have
a happy ending, after five days...
of frantic phone calls
and hand wringing.
In other news...