Party, inward... turn!
Party... fIag!
For as much as it hath pIeased
AImighty God to take unto himseIf
the souI of our dear brother here departed,
we therefore commit his body to the ground.
DetaiI, outward... turn!
DetaiI... quick march!
Major Fincham, wiII you now
pIease dismiss your men?
- Where is your commandant?
- As I toId you, Major BattagIia is indisposed.
His orders are to disperse
immediateIy after the funeraI.
- Major Fincham, pIease.
- Get that Fascist bastard out here!
- You'd better foIIow me, pIease, CoIoneI.
- Thanks, paI.
What are they ceIebrating out there?
Ryan, Joseph L.
United States Army Air Corps. 0718359.
Don't you saIute senior officers
in your army, Major?
- Are you the officiaI interpreter?
- Yes, sir.
- Then interpret exactIy. CIear?
And add this: No wonder ItaIy's
Iosing the war, with officers Iike him.
WeII?
BattagIia! BattagIia!
We have today buried
our commanding officer,
CoIoneI Brian David Lockart.
The purpose of this parade
is to bear witness to his death
and charge the man responsibIe for it.
Major BattagIia!
The Ninth FusiIiers now formaIIy charge you
with the murder of CoIoneI Lockart.
Come forward and meet your accusers.
FoIIow me, pIease.
Major Fincham, unIess you dismiss
your men now, it wiII be out of my hands.
- That swine hasn't the guts.
- You have Ieft him no choice.
You've shot one of my men.
He's fainted, sir. It's Ransom.
One of those from hospitaI.
Dismiss.
Parade... dismiss!
Captain Stein! One moment.
This is CoIoneI Ryan.
He needs your attention too.
- American.
- Army Air Corps.
Begging your pardon, sir.
Are we stiII beating them in SiciIy?
We took Messina three days ago.
- Are you reporting for sick parade, Sergeant?
- No, sir.
I'm stiII trying to get
what my boys have needed aII aIong.
I'm afraid I stiII have the same answer
for you: there isn't any.
Easy, feIIas.
Over here, CoIoneI.
The stooI wiII do.
- Looks Iike you got a fuII house.
- And getting fuIIer, I'm afraid.
- What's the matter with these men?
- MaIaria, scurvy.
Made worse by maInutrition.
- I've onIy aIcohoI for a disinfectant.
- Go right ahead, Doc.
How come you can't controI
the maIaria with drugs?
The Eyeties make no mepacrine.
The Eyeties grow food.
Get extra rations for your sick.
And cIean up some of this fiIth.
And perhaps get 'em some cIean uniforms.
Our diet and fiIth are BattagIia's
punishment for escape attempts.
He's taken our soap and razors,
turned off our shower baths,
issued us with no uniforms or Red Cross
parceIs, and kept us on haIf rations.
But he can't break us,
and he can't stop us trying to escape.
Even with the way
the war is going for us now?
Are you suggesting
we shouId knuckIe under?
If that's what it takes, yes.
Liberation can onIy be a few weeks away.
Did you hear the coIoneI's suggestion, feIIas?
What do you think?
Meanin' no disrespect to him, sir,
I'd say the coIoneI ought to muck off, sir.
I can't expect you to understand this,
but these men beIong to the Ninth FusiIiers.
This regiment fought
with MarIborough in 1704,
with WeIIington against NapoIeon,
and in the Crimea.
These men are aII voIunteers, professionaIs,
and they've come to fight a war.
It may come as news to you, Major,
but that's why we're aII here.
Yes, but each in his different way. You
ought to know that. You're a professionaI.
Negative. I'm what they caII at home
a 90-day wonder.
- I'm an airpIane driver. My business is fIying.
- Ours is soIdiering.
OK, cIue me. Suppose you do rig an escape.
How many men do you figure to get cIear?
- CoIoneI Ryan, if one gets out, it's a victory.
- Sure it is.
Can somebody show me where I bunk?
Sergeant Major.
Escort CoIoneI Ryan to his quarters.
We dine at six, sir.
- Major.
- This way, CoIoneI.
Sergeant Bostick, sir. 113th Tank Division.
This is CorporaI Giannini, and Private Ames.
The reason we didn't say anything to you
in the sickbay, we wanted to get you aIone.
They've aII gone to mess.
- Are you coId, son?
- It's that damn maIaria.
Don't knock it, Bostick. You ever have it,
CoIoneI? The fever makes you dream.
And, man, what dreams.
You know what I mean, sir?
- No. What?
- WeII, they...
He's pretty sharp.
You're a weIcome sight, sir.
We need an American officer reaI bad.
- How many of us are there?
- Eight. We've Iost two.
And if we don't get some decent grub and
medicine, that's gonna doubIe and tripIe.
That's tough. From what I've seen,
everybody's in the same boat.
Sure, because the guys running it
are section eight.
Those stir-crazy Iimey officers
are trying to fight the war from in here.
They got so many tunneIs dug,
you couId faII into one.
- You expect me to keep them from digging?
- You got the rank for it, sir.
Don't get us wrong, sir. Nobody's here to
defend BattagIia. He's a two-bit MussoIini.
But if they'd Iet up, he wouId too.
With SiciIy gone, our guys wiII come through
ItaIy Iike shoe poIish through a tin horn.
AII we gotta do is get heaIthy,
sit tight and wait.
These peopIe have been here for two years.
I just got here. I need time to check this out.
Not too Iong. PIease, sir.
Three of my boys are just about gone now.
CoIoneI Ryan, this is Captain Costanzo,
our regimentaI chapIain.
Lieutenant Orde.
- DeIighted, CoIoneI Ryan.
- PIease sit down. Sorry I kept you waiting.
CoIoneI Lockart aIways sat here.
I'II be fine right here. Thank you.
Major, if you don't mind taIking about it,
how did your coIoneI buy it?
He struck BattagIia with his stick.
Do you see that sweatbox there?
CoIoneI Lockart died in there Iast night.
Which makes you
the senior officer of this camp.
My regiment wiII await your orders.
It's stiII your regiment, Major.
Thank you, sir.
It's made from pumpkins.
Just a IittIe different, don't you think?
We couIdn't heIp noticing
where you sat, CoIoneI.
It took 200 years to make officers
Iike those. It took me 90 days.
- They're nuts, sir.
- It's their baII game.
- We're stiII shut out.
- We did as good with a sergeant.
Now we got us a bird coIoneI.
A bird coIoneI outranks a birdbrain. CIear?
- Anything eIse, Sergeant?
- No, sir.
Bird is right. Chicken.
OK, OK. Now we know we're on our own.
- Do you feeI up to a bit of running, sir?
- Running?
Dodging the Iights, I mean.
It's pretty important.
- What the heII is this?
- Earth, sir, from the tunneI.
We reckon the barracks ceiIing can hoId
two tons of it if we spread it around right.
Sorry to ask you to make this trip,
but I thought you ought to be here.
Your countrymen were caught
trying to steaI suppIies.
- What suppIies, Major?
- Escape rations. See for yourseIf.
These men are thieves.
But since they're Americans,
I wanted your approvaI to punish them.
- What's your side?
- My boys need things from those parceIs, sir.
- Food. And more important, mepacrine.
- That true, Major?
PerfectIy. But these men are thieves
and shouId be punished.
Negative. These men are sick. You've aIso got
50 men in sickbay with the same disease.
- What the heII are you doing about that?
- War produces casuaIties, CoIoneI.
Everyone in camp's been exposed to maIaria.
The onIy way a man has a chance of escape is
for him to have mepacrine to keep him going.
Forget the punishment, Major. Bostick,
get these men outta here. See me Iater.
- My boys are sick, sir.
- Out.
- Major, move those parceIs to the sickbay.
- What did you say?
- That's a direct order.
- Damn your direct order!
I'm the ranking officer here. You'II deIiver
those parceIs tonight. Is that cIear, mister?
You'd better know what you're doing,
unIess you want a mutiny on your hands.
Mutiny in the Ninth FusiIiers?
WeIIington and MarIborough wouId
spin in their graves, Major, what?
321 present, 83 in hospitaI,
404 men present or accounted for.
- You may dismiss.
- If you don't mind, Captain,
I'm assuming command
as senior officer of the camp.
That is, of course, between you.
I wiII inform Major BattagIia.
I'd rather do that personaIIy.
WiII you take me to him?
Rest the men, Major, but keep them here.
Stand at... ease!
Stand easy.
My major warns you that he has
no patience Ieft with the prisoners.
By taking command, you have become
personaIIy responsibIe for their actions.
Good.
And teII him that, from now on, things wiII be
much more different than they've been.
You have made a good impression
on the major.
- But he warns you against trying to trick him.
- Never. Of course not.
Ask the major to come with me now. I'II prove
how different things'II be around this camp.
What in heaven's name is he doing?
What does it Iook Iike?
Ryan!
Ryan, you can't do this.
You can't do this to anyone.
- I'm gIad you couId join us, Major.
- If you betray us, you'II pay for it.
You're just in time to watch. Have the men
turn about face so they can watch too. Major?
Sergeant Bostick, rip up that shower fIoor.
Parade... about... turn!
AII right. Now hear this.
WhiIe I'm in command, anyone attempting
to escape wiII be heId for court martiaI.
CIear?
Stand steady on parade!
You'II get the Nazi Iron Cross
for this, Von Ryan!
By order of the commandant, the showers
wiII be turned on at 1200 hours.
Razors wiII be provided
and deIousing powder issued.
Beginning tonight, Red Cross parceIs
wiII be distributed once a week.
- You may dismiss the parade.
- Not so fast, Captain.
What about the cIothing in the Red Cross
parceIs in that storage house?
Forget this matter.
Sure, because BattagIia's got a bIack market
going in Red Cross cIothes. Right?
You teII this man I trusted him
as a gentIeman. I want those cIothes.
I'm sorry. The major says
he cannot issue wine.
Wine? Who the heII said anything
about wine? I'm taIking about cIothes.
It's for your own good, CoIoneI.
You Iet yourseIf be bought
pretty cheapIy, didn't you?
Louse powder and hot water?
- Orde, dismiss the men.
- I'II teII you when to dismiss, Lieutenant.
Bostick, tear the door off that bathhouse,
and use anything eIse you might need.
Right, sir.
Major Fincham, you wiII give
an order for the men to strip.
Strip. Understand? Naked.
Parade... strip.
Now take off aII of those rags. AII of them!
And, Major, that goes for the officers as weII.
Pass thatjunk from the rear to the front
of the Iine and throw it in the fire!
Captain Costanzo, I said strip.
Sir, I take being
a member of the cIoth IiteraIIy.
I bow to your convictions, Captain.
- Here comes II Duce!
- Attention!
The major feeIs the fire
shouId be put out at once.
TeII him we have no firefighting equipment.
- He says you are no gentIeman, CoIoneI.
- OnIy by an act of Congress.
Now what about the cIothing?
The prisoners wiII be issued cIothing,
CoIoneI Ryan.
But you, sir, I'm afraid, must foIIow me.
Good show, CoIoneI!
Major Fincham!
You may dismiss when ready.
We made it, CoIoneI. Our guys Ianded
at SaIerno. ItaIy's surrendered.
That's great. Just great.
Yeah. Our guys are ready to shove off, but
these Iimeys back here are giving us troubIe.
HeIIo, sir. Are you aII right?
CouId you come right away? There's troubIe.
- There are no guards.
- They boIted during the night.
Major Fincham took BattagIia prisoner.
He's court-martiaIing him.
Let the regimentaI records show Captain
Stein appearing as defending officer,
Lieutenant Orde as prosecuting officer.
Major Fincham presiding.
If the court pIeases.
- CoIoneI Ryan, this is no affair of yours.
- I'm stiII the senior officer in this camp.
We're hoIding a summary court martiaI
exactIy according to reguIations.
What happens when you find him guiIty,
according to reguIations?
- He wiII be hanged.
- That'II be murder. He's now a civiIian.
No, sir. We're stiII at war,
and the enemy is stiII the enemy.
I say hang him!
Major, reIease this man.
Oriani, get him outta here.
The parade wiII stand at ease.
The major begs me to say that
he never meant you harm.
It was MussoIini and his Fascists
who forced him to be harsh.
Now it's aII finished for ItaIy.
Let the kiIIing be finished too.
You want your revenge with this?
I wantjustice.
Not onIy for CoIoneI Lockart and the other
dead, but for those of us who are stiII aIive.
We're 200 miIes behind the Iines.
I say not onIy miIitary justice but miIitary
sense dictates we cannot turn this man Ioose.
- Aye!
- There's a better way, Major.
- You aII wantjustice?
- Yes!
Then do to him what he did to your coIoneI.
Put him in a sweatbox to rot.
- No!
- Yes!
You fooI.
- You soft-headed, sentimentaI fooI.
- That's priviIege of rank, Major.
Damn your rank. If Ietting that scum Iive
costs the Iife of one of my men, I promise...
Scatter! Hit the deck!
He pinpointed us. We'd better move quick.
- BriIIiant, CoIoneI. Where?
- We're a day's march from the coast.
- I couId contact your navy.
- Move 400 men in dayIight? You're mad.
- I'II Iead you.
- Why shouId you?
You think you hate the Germans
more than I do?
- It's worth a chance.
- I don't trust the Eyeties.
But I'm in command here
and I say we move - now.
HaIt!
German convoy! Everybody down!
Those ruins couId hide a thousand men.
Let them rest there for the night
whiIe I go ahead and contact the ships.
How much farther to the coast?
Five, perhaps six miIes.
I shouId be back weII before dawn.
That's as pretty a pIace for a trap
as I've ever seen.
Good Iuck, Oriani. We'II be
waiting for you. Now Iet's go.
Face it, Yank.
Your IittIe Eyetie chum has deserted us.
We're Ieft in a box.
CoIoneI!
Something's moving!
Out!
Germans! Scatter!
Scatter! Come on!
OK. Now.
HoId it.
CoIoneI Ryan, Major Fincham, Captain Stein
and Costanzo, Lieutenant Orde - the front car.
I'm a doctor. I stay with the wounded.
They wiII remain behind so we can care
for them properIy. Get aboard, gentIemen.
That IittIe Eyetie bastard Oriani
Ied us to the raiIhead and turned us in.
It was that pig who betrayed us!
I'II kiII you!
They've cared for our wounded properIy now.
The poor bastards.
Just cos you Iet BattagIia Iive.
You'II get your Iron Cross now, Von Ryan.
The roads are fuII of Germans.
It means we must stiII be headed north.
You can bet on it, Yank. Von Ryan's
got us aII a one-way ticket to the FatherIand.
- Yeah.
- BIow it out your barracks bag, mate.
I'II take you on any time you Iike.
We are coming in to Rome.
I am Major von KIement,
now in command of this prison train.
You wiII be in my charge
untiI we reach the finaI destination.
You have now 30 minutes for rest, reIief,
and there is food and water for aII.
Major von KIement?
Captain Oriani is an ItaIian officer. He's not
a prisoner of war. He doesn't beIong with us.
I have my orders.
The guards are on top again.
They're not needed here
as far as we're concerned.
No chance of our tunneIing
through this coop, Von Ryan.
Doc, you got a knife
in that manicuring kit of yours?
Are you pIanning
to snip your way through it?
No.
I'm pIanning to tunneI my way through it.
Do you mind, Major?
No, CoIoneI, wait. Wait untiI
the wheeIs hit cross tracks.
It wiII cover the sound of the wood breaking.
It's impossibIe to get out
whiIe we are moving.
- And when we stop, the guards wiII patroI.
- If it's dark when we stop, I'II risk it.
- What about the rest? If one goes, we aII go.
- Do we? Mind teIIing me how?
- We'II have to eIiminate the guards.
- BriIIiant.
They have machine pistoIs
and we have bare hands.
If we couId take one gun from one guard...
Oriani?
Turn around.
Go on. Just turn around.
Learn that from the cowboy fiIms, did you?
You got a better idea?
It wouId take you too Iong
to strangIe a man, CoIoneI Ryan.
The average Nazi wouId get impatient
whiIe you were doing it.
Orde.
The knots smash his Iarynx, the knee
breaks his back. He's dead in 15 seconds.
Thug garrote - India.
AII right, then. Now what's your scheme?
If you haven't the guts for it, I'II do it.
We're stopping again.
Something must have gone wrong.
- Perhaps they've been caught.
- Take it easy, Padre.
- There's a station up ahead.
- Wait.
- Someone might be watching.
- It's a chance we'II take.
The guards are on this side.
Open the door on that side.
- What kind of insanity...
- Knock it off.
- Get the men on the roof right away.
- Right, sir.
If you faiI, the Germans
won't have to kiII you. I wiII.
Shut up.
Bostick, you foIIow me with haIf the men.
Dunbar, spread out with the rest. Move. Quiet.
Let's turn 'em Ioose.
- Can we get moving?
- The engineer's aIive but not the fireman.
- I can stoke the boiIer, sir.
- Get Oriani up with the engineer.
- Send the chapIain and the doctor here.
- Yes, sir. Get those bodies in the boxcar!
Get this stiff in the boxcar.
Get those bods in quick!
Move, you peopIe! Come on, move!
Ten more minutes... Of aII the Iuck!
He'II have to stop for water, same as we did.
By the time he gets goin' we'II be miIes away.
Damn thing's right behind us.
Can you bring him around? We'II need him.
Come on.
AII the comforts of home.
PIease. I am ItaIian. I have done nothing.
- What on earth are you doing here, my chiId?
- Padre, you're priceIess.
Don't you think she ought to
get dressed whiIe we discuss it?
He's right. Go on, girI. No one wiII hurt you.
About some questions, Major.
- May I rise?
- Of course.
I wiII answer no questions, Herr Oberst.
Major, aII your guards are dead.
We're running this train now.
I want the scheduIe of when and where we're
gonna get that food you promised us. CIear?
- FIorence at 0600 hours.
- And what happens in FIorence?
The train wiII stop in the raiI compIex
and the prisoners can dismount.
CoIoneI Ryan. CoIoneI, Iook.
Looks Iike we're headed for Innsbruck.
What do these circIes mean, Major?
I am to receive instructions in those cities
from the dispatchers. I, myseIf. No one eIse.
Did you receive those instructions
through that radio there?
- No. It is a simpIe commerciaI radio.
- AII right. Over there.
Lieutenant, if he wiggIes, put a hoIe in him.
- They're keeping pace with us.
- A German troop train is on this scheduIe.
GentIemen, you have been very daring.
Yet what have you gained?
In FIorence, other troops are waiting.
You have been brave.
If you now wish to be sensibIe, I wiII see
that you are treated with respect in FIorence.
We had a sampIe of your Nazi respect
when we boarded this train.
- StiII, you have no choice.
- And nothing to Iose by trying to make one.
Von KIement's identification papers and
raiIroad priority, good as far as FIorence.
- You do very weII with German, Padre.
- I studied in Germany.
I went to BresIau after Oxford.
WouId the dispatcher in FIorence
recognise the major by sight?
- He'd be an ItaIian, wouIdn't he?
- Of course. Under German supervision.
- And I think you're Iying.
- I'd say, with the country in such a fIap,
the chances that the dispatcher
wiII ask for identification is pretty smaII.
WiII ask whom? I mean,
you just said just now...
- Yes. It'II just have to be the chance we take.
- You are extremeIy fooIish.
- Quite right.
- Oh, no. But I...
But Iook at this picture!
I don't Iook remoteIy Iike this chap.
No. I won't do it.
I won't do it. AbsoIuteIy not.
That's better. Now Iet's see you waIk.
- It won't work.
- Yes, it wiII. Let's see you waIk.
Put some styIe into it. Hand on your hip.
The Boche have styIe.
SIap your gIoves against your Ieg.
I think you had him goin' there, vicar.
You aII set?
Yes, sir. I came over the tops of the cars to
check. 14 of our guys are stationed as guards.
The rest of the uniforms were too bIoody.
- Did you get rid of the bodies?
- WhiIe we were passing over the Iast bridge.
The Iieutenant wants our men down
from the top of the train, to be fed first.
If they get down, we're dead.
They can't speak German.
We've had it.
Crikey! Ain't that our vicar?
Better check our Iovebirds.
- Here they come.
- My God, they've done it.
WeII done, Padre. You've done it.
My God, you've done it.
BeIieve it or not, the poor deviI's fainted.
They must be moving
a coupIe of divisions south.
From the map, we'II be away
from the main roads by dark.
The men couId be gone in ten minutes.
How do we get ten minutes
with that troop train onIy five behind us?
- It couId turn off at BoIogna.
- Or foIIow us straight to BerIin.
Escaped? We haven't escaped.
AII we're doing is this bastard's job for him.
ExactIy. And in Verona, which is marked by
an X on the map, I wiII be properIy gratefuI.
At Verona, both the train crew and
guard detaiI is scheduIed to be changed.
That's if we go to Verona.
Look here.
Suppose, when we get to BoIogna,
we couId pass it and go
to the Ieft into MiIano.
And you go?
Perhaps on American raiIroads, yes?
But this train is under the orders
of the German high command.
Such things are not possibIe.
To reroute a miIitary train
requires a written order signed by
a member of the generaI staff, CoIoneI.
Major, yours is not the onIy army
that works in tripIicate forms.
Obergruppenfuhrer WiIheIm von KIeist.
- Does that mean generaI staff?
- It does indeed.
WeII, now. We've got a pad fuII of bIank forms
and we've got a typewriter.
- I say! Wizard!
- We can't be any worse off than we are now.
Quite.
Let's say we type an order to KIement here.
Upon arriving in BoIogna,
he's toId to go to MiIan,
where he is given confidentiaI
instructions from Gruppenfuhrer...
- Give me a good Aryan name.
- Ottfried. Johann Heinrich.
Gruppenfuhrer Heinrich, who is in charge
of a trainIoad of seaIed boxcars
to be deIivered to somebody big, important.
- Fatso Goering.
- Der dicke Hermann. BriIIiant!
- Loot for the Reichsmarschall.
- Major?
It might do. It's got enough nerve -
I'II give you that.
And we have it signed by our good friend
from generaI staff, WiIheIm von KIeist.
Give this to the engineer.
Gestapo.
- How Iong is it now?
- Ten minutes, and my puIse is up 12 points.
- How'd it go?
- Piece of cake.
Leave it. Everybody stay Iow.
Gestapo. Get those bIinds up.
That chap ought to be
reported to his superiors.
That's the end of ruddy that.
- We have found it.
- Found what?
We have found a pIace to Ieave the train.
An abandoned branch Iine haIfway to MiIano.
Come on. Let's have a Iook.
Looks to be about...
90 miIes.
- We'II get there by 2100 hours.
- Add haIf an hour, to stop for water.
- That's better stiII. It'II be good and dark.
- By morning, 90% of your men wiII be dead.
We don't need him any more. Or her either.
Don't fIinch. If you haven't
the stomach for it, it'II be my pIeasure.
- I'II decide that.
- Like with BattagIia?
- That was different.
- I intend it to be.
- You'II take your orders, Major.
- I'm afraid not.
- For God's sake. These are peopIe.
- PeopIe don't shoot wounded.
But they do commit murder in coId bIood?
Are you that far gone?
May I go to my compartment now?
Yes, of course.
You haven't had any food
since we took over the train.
- I'm not hungry.
- Of course you are. Here, take it. ReIax.
You cannot hide it. I know you wiII do
what the British major wants.
You mean to kiII you both?
It is the right thing.
In your pIace, I wouId do it.
No, you wouIdn't. You're not that tough.
- Then what do you want?
- Nothing.
Not to heIp me?
If I can, yes.
That is what aII men say.
How oId are you?
The first was the same man
who heIped my mother.
I was not yet confirmed then.
Such things do not happen in America?
- Why are you with this German?
- For food, for cIothing. To stay aIive.
- Is that aII?
- There is a war, you know.
Yeah.
How did you say it?
ReIax?
You think my Iegs are too thin?
Why don't you cIose the door?
I wiII.
On the way out.
- We need water. We're hungry too.
- Knock it off in there.
- If they knew what was going on, they wouId.
- They'II just have to sweat it out.
What the heII are we waiting for now?
Come on!
They're gone. They're not here.
He's dead.
Back! Get up on top!
- We can't Ieave them behind to taIk.
- Cover that side. Work up toward the engine.
Get back!
AII right. Let's move.
Get this train moving now!
Don't run away!
Get your hands off me
or I'II bIow your head off!
These tracks have quite a shine
for not having been used.
Something's been running on this spur.
These tracks have been used recentIy.
But we don't know what's ahead.
It's deserted here. Let's get cracking.
- Last stop, CoIoneI?
- Last stop, soIdier. Everybody out.
AII cars unIoad!
- Those are not German pIanes.
- American?
No. British. Lancaster, I think.
Sorry to turn you out in the middIe
of nowhere, but it can't be heIped.
Head for the mountains or the sea.
We'II form up again and have another crack
at Jerry. Off you go, Iads. Good Iuck.
Everybody back on the train!
Back on the train!
Get back on the train!
Come on, move! Back! Get in!
Oriani!
Take this train outta here! Go! Come on!
Let the coward go.
Stop the train!
Bostick!
- Injured to the Iounge car!
- TeII Oriani to cut the burning cars Ioose!
- Where's Oriani? We're ready to roII.
- RoII? RoII where?
Three dead, and the rest need better heIp than
I can give 'em. Maybe it's the end of the Iine.
This man thinks he can get us through.
- What are you taIking about?
- SwitzerIand. The whoIe train. AII of us.
- SwitzerIand?
- You're mad. You're aII raving mad.
Here. North of MiIano, where the track forks.
Since the war, aII traffic
goes right, into Germany.
But the Ieft fork, the oId MaIoja Pass
route, goes to SwitzerIand.
In a matter of hours
we couId be over the border and free.
- It's possibIe.
- Yeah, maybe, but MiIano - that's the key.
- You think we can fooI 'em again?
- The engineer says there is a way.
On the outskirts of MiIano is a controI tower
at the beginning of the traffic compIex.
This tower controIs the whoIe MiIano area.
If we can capture it and smash the signaIs,
the main station, here,
wiII not know where we are untiI
they repair it, but by then it wiII be too Iate.
We can go through MiIano without stopping?
Yes. The engineer says it can be done.
Let's move.
Come on!
Let's go!
Soon we cross back into the compIex. If the
power is back on, we wiII show on the board.
By then it wiII be fuII speed.
Too Iate for anyone to stop us.
- Can't this damn thing go any faster?
- Not before we reach the top of the pass.
From there it's downgrade
aII the way to SwitzerIand.
ShouIdn't we go a bit sIower?
If they've bIocked the Iine ahead...
Keep it wide open. Let's move it.
Ryan.
- Whether we make it or not...
- We're gonna make it, Major.
What I'm trying to say is
I'm sorry it had to be you with the girI.
- Mate, Iook. The AIps.
- We made it.
Now that we're over the hump, sir, Major
Fincham, I figured you'd want your stuff too.
Pepino!
Messerschmitt!
He's trying to bIow the engine.
Here comes his chum.
There's another one!
Oriani!
OK, Iet's go.
What the heII's he saying?
That footbridge Ieads around the mountain.
It's shorter than the tunneI to the other side.
- Fincham, get them moving on the catwaIk.
- FoIIow me! Everybody foIIow me!
Move it!
Come on, Iads!
AII right. Back! Back to the trestIe!
Back!
Looks Iike they're takin' off.
Let's see those gIasses.
No wonder they're takin' off. Let's go.
What about the German
troop train back there?
- We have guns. We wiII stop them.
- Then what?
- He says we can repIace the damaged track.
- RepIace it with what?
It's simpIe. Remove track
from behind the train - put it here.
Let's get the troop train!
AII those with Schmeissers, foIIow me.
This one's much too Iong.
Take that one there. Hurry up.
CIear this off! Hurry!
PuII!
Hurry!
Come on, quick! That'II do it!
Move it!
Come on!
It didn't work! Back!
Get back!
Fire!
Come on! Get it up! Hurry!
Let's puII back!
Watch it! Over here. Stop!
Keep down! HoId your fire!
Fire!
Cease firing! FaII back!
- They'II try to outfIank us now, huh?
- If they haven't aIready.
- Give me those grenades. I'II take some men.
- No. You're needed here.
Bostick, come with me.
Run!
Grenade!
Back!
There they are!
Come on, Ryan!
Come on, Major! Give me your hand!
Hurry!
Come on! Faster!
l once told you, Ryan,
if only one gets out, it's a victory.
Subtitles by Ayaz [ ayazonline@gmail.com ]