[CHIMP CHATTERS]
You lose.
Again.
I changed your flight sequence.
That's enough.
Pay attention.
Pericles, stop! Or no treat!
How well do I know you?
Hey, there you are.
Was the homo sapien mean to you?
We all know it's just rocket envy.
-Ever consider a boyfriend?
-Do I enjoy being miserable?
-I'll stick with my chimps.
LEO: Hey.
-I'm teaching him.
-You're teasing him.
He's gene-spliced, chromosome-
enhanced. He can handle it.
When you frustrate them, they lose
focus. They even get violent.
Hey, Pericles,
you're gonna be a daddy.
-Thought I saw a smirk on his face.
-The female was the aggressor.
Hey, Leo. You got a postcard.
Leo!
It's been two years.
When are you coming home?
Not too quick.
I'm enjoying that apartment.
-No, we miss you!
-Are you flying yet?
-Or are the chimps doing the work?
- We got something to tell you.
When you gonna make
that kind of commitment--
MAN 1 : Captain Davidson,
report to the bridge.
FRANK : Found it.
HANSEN: It's moving like a storm.
It is. It's an electromagnetic storm.
LEO: The digital clocks are stopped.
MARIA: It's beautiful.
-So is the sun till you get close.
HANSEN: This is weird.
HANSEN: I hear frequency patterns.
-Tune them in.
HANSEN: It's electronic communication
from Earth, from all time.
HANSEN:
The storm's bouncing it back to us.
We'll start with a pass
through the core.
T ake radiation gamma-ray reading.
Get your monkey ready.
Sir, this is a waste of time.
We have standard procedures--
-l' m aware of the procedures, but--
-No manned flights.
We send an ape. If it's safe,
we talk about a pilot.
Why don't you just allow me
to do my job?
He's the canary, that's the coal mine.
He launches at 1 6:00.
Just follow your sequence
and come home. Understand? Home.
VASICH: Stand by. Alpha pod launch
in 30 seconds.
VASICH: Chart his course
to the eye of the storm.
LEO:
Okay, Pericles, start sequence one.
Activate reading systems.
LEO:
Ignition.
VASICH: Have him start
taking perimeter readings.
-What's wrong?
-He's off-course.
Lock on him.
He can't respond, sir.
-There's a surge in the heart rate.
-Light him up again.
I can't.
He's gone.
He's trained to come back.
You think he's still alive?
-Sir--
-For now, we just sit tight and wait.
I'm gonna run some sequences
to see what he did wrong.
HANSEN: The signal is breaking up.
VASlCH: He must be panicking.
ALEXANDER:
He'll return to the Oberon.
HANSEN:
I can 't hold him.
VASICH:
That's it, we lost him.
FRANK: Wanna send up another chimp?
-It's too dangerous.
VASICH:
I won 't waste another pod.
Shut down launch operations.
Sir?
Delta pod has launched.
Your flight is not authorized!
I' m going to get my chimp.
VASICH: Bring that thing back here!
Return to base!
Never send a monkey to do a man's job.
I got a visual on Alpha pod.
Oberon, come back!
Oberon, come in!
-l' m getting a mayday, sir.
-Alpha pod?
-I don't know, but it's strong.
VASICH: Put it up.
Mayday! Mayday! Come in!
Request-- We 're going down! Mayday!
Delta pod, abort.
[APES YELL]
This one looked at me.
T ake your stinking hands off me,
you damn dirty human!
GORILLA BOY 1 :
Stinking humans!
GORILLA BOY 2:
You guys smell!
Hey, where am l?
What is this place?
Here! I'm open! Come on!
Dribble it down! Take it!
GORILLA 3:
Make way! Clear the path!
GORILLA BOY 4:
Get the humans!
GORILLA BOY 2:
You guys smell!
GORILLA BOY 4:
Take this!
GORILLA BOY 1 : Stupid human!
ARI: Stop it!
-Who said to throw stones at humans?
-My father.
Well, he's wrong.
-And you can tell him I said so.
-Human-lover.
GORILLA 5:
Move along!
Are you trying
to put me out of business?
These are the skankiest, scabbiest...
...scuzziest humans I've ever seen.
-You don't want them?
-I'll take the whole lot.
I must be out of my mind.
I'll have to make it up on volume.
All right, get them out...
...and get them clean! Chop, chop!
Let's go!
Keep it moving!
Come on! Hurry up!
LIMBO: Gentlemen to the left!
Ladies to the right, please!
Don't be afraid.
Come on.
Very touching. I can't see
for the tears in my eyes.
Come on. That one's
crawling with lice.
Check the teeth
on that little one. Nice.
Stay back. Back!
Get in there!
Move! You too!
How many times have I told you to
wear gloves when you handle humans?
You normally hack off a limb, Limbo.
Yes, general. That's true.
LIMBO: Unfortunately,
they're worth more intact.
Keep your eye on this one.
He's feisty.
Were these the ones
raiding the orchards?
I know an old country remedy
that never fails.
You gut one human,
and you string the carcass up.
The Human Rights faction
is on me already.
Do-gooders. Who needs them?
I' m for free speech as long as they...
...keep their mouths shut.
My niece wants one
for her birthday.
Excellent. The little ones
make wonderful pets.
But be sure
you get rid of it by puberty.
One thing you don't want in your
house, it's a human teenager.
Any one you'd like, sweetheart.
That one.
Oh, isn't she pretty.
I'll get that for you, sir.
And I have a pretty new collar...
...just for you.
Compliments of the house.
You stink of humans.
It's disgusting
the way we treat humans.
It demeans us as much as them.
Ari, let's go.
Get them marked!
I got orders to fill!
Next!
Not you again.
I can't stand by while humans
are being mistreated and tortured.
The only reason I put up with your
nonsense is because of your father!
You want me to stop?
Give up the business.
Hey, I do the job
that nobody else wants!
I don't see you bleeding-hearts
spending all day...
...with these dangerous,
dirty, dumb beasts.
They can be taught
to live with us as equals.
I'm gonna prove it.
LIMBO:
Don't do that.
Stay back.
Well, now there's your proof.
Now I'm gonna have to put him down.
Help me.
Please.
Please help me.
You're giving me such a headache.
I don't need this aggravation!
Sell him to me.
Are you crazy? He's wild.
They're both wild.
Then I'll buy them both.
That would be expensive.
That would be...
...very, very expensive.
I'm sure we can...
...you know, come to a deal.
You know?
Deliver them to my house.
SANDAR:
Semos, help me!
Rise when your master enters.
Wild humans...
...in my house.
This one seems different.
How could he be different?
You can't tell one from the other!
My guests are here.
Keep the savage ones out of sight.
Especially from General Thade!
SANDAR:
You'd better be nice to him!
And wash your hands before dinner.
Senator, good evening.
Dear, you look lovely tonight.
But I'm having a bad hair day.
Yet, she spends a fortune grooming.
And I'm worth every penny.
Would you like to freshen up?
We're fine.
-How'd these monkeys get like this?
-How else would they be?
-They'd be begging me for a treat.
-What tribe are you from?
U.S. Air Force. I'm going back to it.
Finish your work.
Please, everyone sit.
We just returned
from our country house.
-How was it?
-Boring.
I find it relaxing being away
from the bustle of the city.
NOVA:
There was no place to go.
Nothing but trees and rocks.
-All you did was nap.
-Exactly.
Time away from politics...
...is what I needed.
We'd lose ourselves for days
in the forest when we were young.
Now I can barely climb a tree.
T rite but true:
"Youth is wasted on the young. "
Oh, how did I get so old so fast?
Living with your daughter
would age any ape quickly.
SANDAR:
You've been a stranger lately.
I apologize for my lateness, senator.
I stopped to see my father.
-How's my old friend?
-Slipping, I'm afraid.
I'd like to see him more,
but these are troubled days.
The humans infest the provinces.
We encroach upon their habitat.
They breed while we grow soft
in our affluence.
THADE:
They outnumber us four to one!
Why can't we simply
sterilize them all?
The cost would be prohibitive.
Although scientists tell me...
...these humans
carry terrible diseases.
How would we know?
The army burns the bodies
before they' re examined.
Father?
At times, perhaps, the senate feels
that the army has been...
...a tad extreme.
Extremism in defense of apes
is no vice, senator!
Your ideas threaten our prosperity!
The human problem
can't be solved with money!
We tried that once,
and all we got was...
...a welfare state that nearly broke us.
I think the city has about
as much diversity as I can handle.
This garment was made
by one of my humans.
And can you deny the skill?
Obviously, they' re capable
of a real culture.
Everything in the human culture
takes place below the waist.
Bow your heads!
We give thanks
for the fruit of the land.
Bless us, holy father, who created
all apes in his image.
Hasten the day when you will return
and bring peace to your children.
-Amen.
GROUP: Amen.
Next you'll be telling us
these beasts have a soul.
Of course they do.
The senator's daughter
flirts with blasphemy.
Is there a soul in there?
Do you have a towel?
I've lost my appetite.
I' m bored by these society dinners.
-I came to see you.
-Oh, how sweet.
You've wasted your time.
My feelings haven't changed.
I still care about you.
You only care about my father's
influence. And your own ambition.
I know about the trouble
you caused today.
-I could have you arrested.
-I'd do it again.
You feel so much for these humans...
...yet you feel nothing for me.
A moment, sir.
What is it?
We found something.
We think you should see it.
There's a curfew.
If they see you, they kill you.
You stay here, you're already dead.
Can you take me to
where we were caught?
Not without my family.
APE 1 :
This is where I saw it.
THADE:
Go on.
APE 2: Something fell from the sky
with wings of fire.
APE 2: There was a thunderous sound
and the ground itself shook.
-You weren't dreaming this?
-lt was no dream, sir.
Look.
-You told no one?
APE 1 : No, sir.
APE 1 :
We had to come right to you.
You did exactly the right thing.
You smell that?
Don't start now. We're off-duty.
And I'm starving.
You're hurt.
How did you get away?
-Who are you?
-Somebody trying to get out.
She promised to take me back.
This is a house-human.
He thinks he's better than us.
Hey!
We'll go together.
[APES LAUGH]
[APES CHATTER]
[NOVA SCREAMS]
Good night, little girl.
[SCREAMS]
You go this way.
The rest of you, come with me.
ATTAR:
Send a squad to the north gate! Hurry!
Wait! Someone's coming.
You're lucky I found you first.
Come on. I can reason with them.
-We know how apes reason.
-How can we escape?
Don't get involved with these humans.
Why did you help me?
Why would you take that chance?
Because...
...you're not usual.
Show me a way out. I'll show you
something that will change your world.
Trust me.
When I was little...
...I used to sneak outside the city,
where no one could find me.
I can show you.
If we're caught, no one can protect us!
Trust me.
What about her?
-A human child won't survive.
-Bon can take her. Hide her at home.
Check every house!
APE 1 : Have you seen any humans?
-No.
Hurry!
-Father.
-I'll be right beside you.
Come on!
No!
BIRN:
Stop!
[GROANS]
-Where are the other humans?
-Through the tunnels.
When you find them, kill them all.
Except for the troublemaker.
I want to talk to him before he dies.
Sir, the senator's daughter is with them.
-They took her?
-She's helping them. I saw her myself.
She had no choice.
They threatened her life.
I'll report to the Senate. They'll beat
their chests and ask for my help.
They are weak without you, sir.
-Your dad was brave.
-What do you know?
[SHRlEKS]
Let me go.
Thade will come soon.
We can still go back.
I can't now.
That's where I flew in.
You did that?
No, my retroburners.
-I'm sure he'll explain.
-He can't explain what can't exist.
Talking monkeys can't exist.
Apes.
Monkeys are further down
the evolutionary ladder.
Just above humans.
Calm down, will you?
[SHRlEKS]
-What's wrong?
-Afraid of water. Apes can't swim.
We drown.
That's why every day we pray for rain.
How long can a human
hold its breath underwater?
Thought you were afraid of water.
Two dead monkey--
Apes down at the bottom.
Someone else knows you' re here.
-What's that?
-A frequency with...
... my ship so I can talk to them.
It talks?
With radio waves.
Sorcery.
Not sorcery, science.
I have contact.
They' re already here.
They must be waiting for me.
LEO:
lt'll lead us to them.
We' re in control now.
We' re the 800-pound gorilla.
Who are you?
Captain Leo Davidson.
Pilot, U.S. Air Force.
-From planet Earth.
-Your apes let you fly?
They live in zoos and do what we say.
This is hostile.
I got 36 hours...
...to find my friends
and I'm out of this nightmare.
What happens to us?
Where do we go?
You go nowhere. He belongs to me!
Stop!
You, I've had enough of!
Take it easy, little fella.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
I wouldn't hurt my property.
But I'll make an exception.
No harm done. Come here, kid.
Come here.
You're not hurt, right? You're young.
Oh, these kids.
They bounce right back.
Play dead.
-Kill him.
-Slave trader.
You kill him, you lower
yourself to his level.
Exactly.
She is extremely smart.
I've heard her talk
about apes and humans.
"Separate but equal. "
"T o each his own. "
Something like that. Right?
LIMBO:
Whatever it is, I agree.
Can't we all just get along?
I'm probably just in the way.
So why don't I just get going?
He'll lead them to us.
Then we'll make him our guest.
Cuff him.
Ow! These things hurt.
-What are you doing?
-You could use that against us.
-Who invented that?
-lt was gonna save us.
-We're better off now.
-We?
-You're so difficult.
-Like a slave?
-That's not what--
-Shut up!
That goes for all species.
If ever I thought those humans were
capable of kidnapping my daughter--
Don't blame yourself, senator.
You've been compassionate with them.
Look how they've repaid you.
Can you find her?
If you untie my hands.
What do you want?
Declare martial law.
Give me absolute power...
...to rid this planet of humans
once and for all.
Now is not the time to be timid
or indecisive.
I' m the one who can bring
your daughter back alive.
He's not in the city.
We underestimate this human.
I'll hunt him down.
Your father sent me.
You must come quickly.
Warn the outposts.
Don't let the humans pass.
I understand, sir.
Apart from my father,
I rely on you most.
We are not just soldiers.
We are friends.
I'll depend on you.
Yes, sir.
-So many questions I want to ask.
-Me too.
ARI:
These "zoos"--
What are they? This word is
not familiar.
-Our last apes are in zoos.
-What happened to them?
Gone.
After we cut down the forests...
...the ones who survived...
...were locked up in cages.
LEO:
Used for scientific experiment.
-That's horrible.
-We do worse to our own kind.
I don't understand.
You seem intelligent.
Smarter we get, the more
dangerous our world becomes.
I knew it. You're sensitive.
Uncommon quality in a male.
Why don't your apes object
to the way you treat them?
They can't talk.
Maybe they choose not to,
given the way you treat them.
Apes in cages. Right.
THADE:
Father.
I don't have much time.
T ell me about this human...
...who troubles you.
I will capture him
with little trouble.
No. You're not telling me everything.
You believe he is not born
of this world.
Has he come alone?
Yes.
More will come looking for him.
How can you possibly know?
I have something to tell you.
Something my father told me...
...and his father told him.
Back along our bloodlines to Semos.
In the time before time...
...we were the slaves
and the humans...
...were the masters.
Impossible.
Break it.
What you hold in your hand
is the proof of their power.
Their power of invention.
Their power of technology.
Against this, our strength
means nothing.
This has the power
of a thousand spears.
I warn you.
Their ingenuity goes hand in hand
with their cruelty.
No creature...
...is as devious, as violent.
You must find this human quickly.
Do not let him get to Calima.
The forbidden area?
Calima holds the secret
to our true beginnings.
Damn them.
I will stop him, Father.
Damn them all to hell.
What is it?
DAENA:
They' re to keep us away.
LEO:
What's on the other side?
It leads to the sacred
ruins at Calima.
-What is that?
-Calima? That's where, well...
...according to our holy writings,
creation began.
Where the Almighty
breathed life into Semos...
...the first ape.
In the time before time.
It is where Semos will return.
Most educated apes consider
such religious notions as fairy tales.
Metaphors we use to explain our origins.
I doubt if there ever really was a Semos.
LEO:
My crew is there, so we' re going.
Doesn't he ever stop?
-They' re scared of water?
-We'll cross somewhere else.
No time. Gets dark,
we're going right through.
Semos smiles on me.
I win again.
You win too often.
What's hidden up your sleeve?
All of them.
Cheater!
-Who's in charge here?!
-I am, sir!
-I didn't know--
-This camp is a disgrace.
ATTAR: Some humans have escaped!
-lf they come, we will crush them.
These humans are different.
They travel with apes.
[LAUGHING]
You find this amusing?
No, sir.
I'm assuming command.
This camp will be prepared!
Just grab the reins.
Hold tight. We're gonna
cross the river.
Horses are great swimmers.
They'll carry you across.
Good luck. Have a nice ride.
Leave me. I'll only slow you down.
-Letting him go?
-No. He'll ride with us.
No, wait. Wait. This is suicide.
Only a human would think
that this could work.
[GASPS]
Hear my prayers, Semos,
father of all apes.
[HORSE WHINNIES]
No! No! I'm on your side!
Come on!
[ROARS]
[GASPS]
Come on! We have to swim.
Hey!
I won't let go of you!
Come on!
[GROWLS]
No, no, wait. There's no need now.
-Says who?
-Them.
They tried to kill me like
I was nothing but a miserable--
Human?
Ow.
You're hurt.
She was holding on pretty tight.
The soldiers will cross downstream.
We should move quickly!
ATT AR: They crossed the river.
-You didn't stop them?
ATT AR:
Horses carried them.
Horses?
Our horses, sir.
[CHATTERS]
Forgive me, my friend.
I' m not angry with you.
Father was taken from me.
He was a great leader
and a direct descendant of Semos.
ATT AR:
Now it's time for you to lead.
Form the divisions.
Form divisions!
[CHATTERS]
Full battle ready!
Sound the call to march!
T omorrow we reach Calima.
He'll stay like that all night.
A soldier, isn't he?
A general. Well, he was
until he opposed Thade.
When Thade ruined his career,
my father took him in.
He was a great soldier.
Attar was his best pupil.
ARI:
Now they're enemies.
I'd like to see your world.
They'd probably prod you and poke you
and throw you in a cage.
You'd protect me.
They think you'll save them.
After you meet your friends,
we'll never see you again.
Well, I didn't promise them anything.
No.
You just dropped in from the stars.
They're not here.
LEO:
Hello?
They were never here.
You said they'd come for us.
LEO:
That's impossible.
What is it?
It's my ship.
These ruins are
thousands of years old.
I was just here a few days ago.
This is what I was
picking up. The Oberon.
ARI:
What are you doing?
It has a power source
that lasts forever.
Maybe I can access
the ship's visual log.
Then I can figure out what happened.
Mayday! Come in, guidance!
Request instructions!
Going down!
We were searching for a pilot
in an electromagnetic storm.
I got pushed forward through time.
We haven 't had any communications
since we crashed.
This planet is uncharted, uninhabited.
The apes we 've brought along with us
are a lot stronger...
...and a lot smarter...
... than we ever imagined.
Apes are out of control.
One male named Semos...
... who I raised myself,
has taken over the group.
We have weapons but I don 't
think we 'll last long.
Maybe I saw the truth,
but I wouldn 't admit it.
They were good students--
They' re all dead
because they looked for me.
We' re alive because of you.
Who are they?
Your story is spreading.
They want to see...
...this human who defies the apes.
Send them all back.
Where? They left their homes
to be with you.
I saw them.
How many?
As far as I could see.
Thade has all his legions.
The senate's capitulated.
He answers to no one now.
You' re gonna have to get your people
out of here.
They won't listen to me.
This is a fight we can't win.
Break up and scatter.
I'll draw them off.
I'm who they want.
LEO:
All right? Come on!
Let's go!
LEO:
Come on!
You've gotta make them understand.
It's over. No help is coming.
You came.
Stop!
Come closer and identify yourself!
How dare you show your face here?!
It is not my decision.
I wish to speak to Thade.
[SNARLS]
Why have you come?
T o be with you.
A trade?
You' re proposing that?
Yourself for the humans?
Even when you were a child,
you took in stray humans.
Your family indulged you.
Look what you've become.
I've been...
...mistaken.
Forgive me.
So you want to be human?
Then wear their mark!
Let her return.
THADE:
She'll die with her friends tomorrow.
We were searching for a pilot
in an electromagnetic storm.
We haven 't had any communications
since we crashed.
I' m so sorry.
I' m responsible for all of this.
And l' m never going home.
Just like them.
The apes are out of control.
I can't go home, either.
Maybe we' re not so different.
No. We' re very different.
You care about everybody but yourself.
Doesn't matter. Apes, humans.
My planet, your planet.
The universe rewards cruelty with power.
No.
Not always. Not if we fight back.
I' m just not sure how.
Better take care of that.
KRULL:
I respect your courage.
But my advice to you is
to put that away...
...and head for the mountains.
There's one possibility.
I want those people behind the ship.
-Not hiding, they need to be seen.
-And us?
You'll be in front. You're the bait.
-I won't move.
-You won't be there.
-I can do this!
-I know. I need you back with them.
We got one shot.
LEO:
Listen!
I got an idea.
We may have a chance.
I need you behind the ship.
Hey, we can win this.
It's been done before. On my planet.
Men have done amazing things in history.
That history belongs to you.
Sometimes even a few
can make a difference, okay?
This is the day you've waited for!
You get to stand up to the apes!
Leo!
You know you can't defeat Thade's army.
We might confuse them.
It could give us a chance.
You don't understand Thade.
He'll keep coming for you.
No matter what.
That's what I'm counting on.
Get behind the ship!
LEO:
Get children behind the ship!
Come on, move! Now!
-Let me go.
-No.
-Let me prove I can help!
-I need you here.
Help clear them back.
-What?
-I'm part of this!
-Get back!
-No!
BIRN:
I'm staying!
Send in the first wave.
[ROARS]
Here they come.
Now!
Oh, God.
Come on.
Jesus!
Wait.
Now! Go!
With that weapon,
we cannot defeat them!
I'm tired of this human.
No! Wait!
My fight is with Thade, not you!
Then your fight is with me!
[ENGINE ROARS]
Semos.
Pericles. A better landing than me.
Sir, the prophecy is true.
Semos has returned to us.
Come on.
Let's go explain evolution
to the monkeys.
[PERICLES CHATTERS]
He'll turn us into slaves!
Kill him!
Listen. This is where you're from.
We brought you here. It's true.
We lived in peace together. Semos...
...killed everybody.
He's lying!
Help me!
My friend, kill him!
Everything I have believed is a lie!
ATT AR:
You and your family have betrayed us!
I won't help you anymore.
Ari....
[GRUNTS]
You okay?
You came home.
It's safe.
You can come out now.
What? It's over?
I was just getting ready
to make my move.
ATT AR:
We'll leave the graves unmarked.
No one who comes will be able
to tell apes from humans.
They'll be mourned together...
...as it should be, from now on.
T ake good care of him, okay?
I can promise you
I won't put him in a cage.
[BEEPS]
It found the storm
that brought me here.
You know...
...it would mean much to everyone...
...if you would stay.
Would mean much to me.
I have to leave now.
I have to get back.
You know, one day,
they'll tell a story...
...about a human who came
from the stars...
...and changed our world.
Some will say it was just
a fairy tale...
...that he was never real.
But I'll know.
Oh.
Keep it.
You know, I'd like to thank you...
...for opening my eyes to a brave new
world of trade with the humans.
Yeah, no problem.
Farewell, spaceman.
All right, kids, who wants
to buy some aspirin?
Maybe you'll come back.
MAN: Z.D. C. Air Route Traffic
Control to unidentified aircraft.
Unidentified craft, do you copy?
-Copy that.
-You 're entering restricted airspace.
-Permission to land!
- You 're off-target. Abort!
I can't!
[POLICE CAR SIRENS]
POLICE APE 1 :
Stay where you are!
POLICE APE 2:
Show your hands!
POLICE APE 3:
Keep your hands up!
Subtitles by
SDI Media Group
[ENGLISH SDH]