HAVANA, CUBA
-
We swap in parts from Ford
Plymouths and Cadillac.
My grandfather bought it in 1957.
When he died it passed to my father.
Then my brother and now to me.
Look at this,
this is an engine from a boat.
- No way.
- Yeah!
Whatever it takes
to keep it running!
This is a cuban spirit.
Your spirit, keep it up.
Never ever lose that.
Dom..
It's your cousin..
He's in trouble, come quickly!
Please don't do this,
Understand my problem.
You know how I make a
living on my car.
Not my problem bro.
Dominic Toretto..
I heard about you.
Welcome to my island.
Why you hooking up
my cousin's car?
In the morning, I gave it to him..
He can't pay.. I take the car.
I just need a few more days.
Few more days isn't
part of the deal.
Make a deal
you gotta give up to it.
You make a deal
You gonna give up to it.
Gonna give up to it?
So you are one of those types..
Take everyone's ride and then
ship it back to the states.
You should show your
people some respect.
You watch your mouth.
Now you got a problem.
- I'm gonna keep it about the cars.
- You scared me there!
You want a car?
Get it the right way.
- How?
- Race war.
I already own it, bro.
Not that car.
Mine.
Dom, his car is the
fastest car in the Island.
Do you know what he
has in that hood?
Do you know, it doesn't matter
what's under a hood?
The only thing that matters is
who's behind the wheels.
- You think so?
- I know so.
Then race his car.
We ain't racing a quarter mile here.
We race the cuban mile.
Done!
I'd wish you what
you're trying to do.
My car is the slowest
car on the Island.
What else?
Pull the seats the doors
the battery..
Leave the motor,
take it off.
- Laughing gas?
- Nah, Fed. This is cuban NOS.
You guys are crazy.
What are you doing?
Why you messing
with the west-gate.
Used to play.
It's in emergencies.
You know that's way too much
booze for that engine.
- It's going to be fast.
- It's gonna be bomb.
Only needs to go a mile.
Be fast!
Be safe!
But don't be last.
Racers ready..?
Go..!
Stop.
That car belongs in the trash bro.
- Where are we going?
- I don't know. Let's go.
- Go straight..
- Come on in.
Adios, Toretto.
See if this one works.
That's impossible..
Look out.
A Deal's a deal.
You own my car.
And you earn my respect.
Keep your car
your respect is good enough for me.
Cousin.
Sorry bout your car,
Your's was too slow
for a Torreto anyway.
Your Impala.
Are you serious?
-
Look at that smile
I love it when you smile.
Make me happy
I think this place makes you happy.
Like it speaks to you.
You remember that guy?
The Racer and his dad.
- The one with the boat engine.
- Yeah!
- yeah.
- Of course.
I was looking at them, and I..
And I couldn't help but too imagine
what you'd be like, if you were dad.
No, no, no.
I'm not pregnant.
Is that what you want?
It's not about what I want
or what you want..
It's about why
we haven't asked the question.
Can I help you with that?
- What?
- You need a hand?
Yeah, I think I do.
Sounds like you're
not getting any fuel.
Yeah.
Have a look inside that solenoid.
See if we can get
some power into it.
What brings you to Cuba?
The same thing that brings
everyone else to Cuba.
Culture. People. Beauty.
What brings you to Cuba?
- Work!
- Must be casual Friday.
How is that honeymoon going Dom?
Your fuel relay is missing.
I know.
I'd love play games.
Beaten the bests alone.
I'm kinda in a rush,
so if you got something to say...
Oh this is a very different game
that I can assure you.
This..?
There is something much greater
at work here.
This is fate.
- I choose to make my own fate.
- Not today.
This is the road you take
to your apartment every morning.
What else is different, Dom?
The Santiago's closed?
Did you have to cross two blocks
to go get your cuban coffee?
So, what is it?
Black, no sugar?
Yeah.. I've put a lot of work
into getting you here in today.
Now that I'm here,
what do you want?
I want you to work for me.
Work for you?
I could have saved you
a lot of time then.
See, I don't work for anyone.
You can't walk away from this Dom.
We're gonna have this
conversation one way or the other.
See that's the funny
thing about fate.
It's cunning.
It can bring you beautiful things,
and it can also bring you
moments like this.
I will hear that you
want to work for me.
You're gonna betray your brother,
abandon your code,
shatter your family.
See, your team..
Is about to go up against the
only thing they can't handle.
What's that?
You.
Oh, and Dom,
I wouldn't mention this to anyone.
They are gonna be hitting us
with everything they've got.
So, we wanna engage
with maximum speed.
Neutralize the shooters
and then move on to our objective.
There are two things
I want you to keep in mind,
Number one,
I choose you for this squad
because you are the most
fearsome warriors on the planet.
And number two,
You go out there, you do your job.
And you take them down.
Everyone... and I mean
everyone..
Manice and pedice at the mall.
Later on today.
Alright, show 'em what you got.
I don't wanna play anymore.
Alright, let's go, come on,
let's go, let's go.
- Final 2 minutes.
- Quite the junior section.
Oh yeah. That's moms
they come out to sport the kids.
Except there seems to be more moms
than kids,
Way more like moms and..
Yeah, it's a big soccer job.
Let's go girls.
So your intel was spot on...
A democly 7 EMP weapon
went missing in the gulf.
Arms dealer from the
Liberation front have it in Berlin.
- Shit.
- This thing can wipe out..
An entire electrical grid
in a major city.
No lights, no power,
instant stone age.
Chloe, Maya...
You can't let her run
by you like that.
- Let's go, let's go.
- Hey, Hobbs.
It's a class 4 WMD.
You have the no idea what's
at stake here...
Yes..!
I know exactly what is
at stake here, okay?
If Pink Butterflies
beat my Red Dragon
that means we lose the championship.
Which means I have 20 little girls
who are crying..
And that's not a good thing.
Which then means I have to spend
a lot of time in ice cream shops
and lot of time in Tay-Tay concerts.
- Tay-Tay?
- Yep? Taylor Swift.
You gotta be shitting me
Get it together.
Let's go girls.
We need to do this,
Lot of lives are at stake.
I need to be clear here.
US Government can not sanction
this operation in anyway.
You're on your own.
This thing goes sideways
you don't just get burned,
you go to prison.
And there's nothing we can do
to get you out.
Let me tell you something.
The only thing that I love
more than saving lives..
Is my daughter.
So you don't shut up with this
government bullshit right now
and start showing some team spirit
and respect for the Red Dragons.
I'm gonna have all 20 of them lined
up kick you right in the Tay-Tay.
Go, Dragons!
Say it again.
- Go, Dragons!
- Good boy.
Go Dragons..
Yeah, he's open... Yup!
Yes!
That is my daughter right there!
Yes, come here.
- Awesome.
- Nice job.
Dad's gotta go to work?
Oh yeah,
daddy's gotta go to work.
Now, you gonna need to get a team
that you can trust.
Oh, I already got one.
- Hey, Dom.
- Hey, Hobbs.
We got a job in Berlin,
and I need a favor, brother.
No problem.
I'll grab the team and
meet you in Berlin.
Good.
You were only to supposed
to create a diversion, Roman.
That was a diversion.
How many of the damn explosives
did you use?
I do not know, Tez.
All of it?
- Wait, all of it?
- Roman, Jesus!
- Right.
- Yeah, more of you fan club, eh?
They're still on us.
These guys are taking it personal.
Roman, we just blown up their
facility and stole their EMP.
Other than the
doctor's cold fingers,
I'd say it's about as
personal as it can get.
- Phase 2.
- Phase 2?
So you just gonna keep
that to yourself?
What happen to Phase 1?
What about that part?
Yeah, remember the airplane?
Everyone drove their
cars out but you.
I told you my engine seized up.
Seized up?
Just follow my lead, okay?
Roman, whatever you do.
Don't think.
Tez, drop it.
Bomb's away.
Split now!
Holy shit!
Look out..!
- Rock n roll.
- Just so you know.
You miss some.
I'll just wait for it.
I hate you, Tej!
You good?
I'll see you when it's done.
Alright. Great job, team.
Let's break up and meet
me at the safe house.
Hell of a job, brother.
When we can get back
to the base. Beers on me.
You lost your god damn mind,
Toretto!
Toretto you put hands on that thing,
you're gonna have the whole world
coming for you including me.
I do not know what you're doing
but you better think
about this, Toretto.
It ain't too late to stop this.
It is now.
That some..
What?
Wait a second, what
are you talking about?
- Dom taking the EMP.
- Bullshit.
Where are you?
It's too late for me.
Get out of here.
I saw that look in his eyes.
I've seen that look before.
Dominic Toretto just went rogue.
I got his phone records, y'all.
It's a whole bunch of calls
to untraceable numbers.
Burner phone, right?
Nah. Scrambled.
Faked number. They got
some sort of micro-router..
..to bury the signal patterns
which means Dom is clearly..
..communicating with somebody
that is above our pay grade.
Look,
I do not know Dom as well as you,
but if we just look at the facts.
Dom's been having highly encrypted
conversation with some
mysterious person.
He took out Hobbs.
He stole the EMP,
now he's disappeared.
So what're you saying?
Maybe we should
consider the fact that..
Hobb's right.
Dom did go rogue.
- Letty.
- Before you judge the man,
Remember you're breathing
now because he saved your life.
You just gonna let her
bump yourself like that
I'm just hanging out.
That was a little risk.
What you gonna do.
Email her?
Long wait fellas.
Thank you.
Well, this is an
exciting new look.
It's a little tight on
the crotch as always.
What boyband bus did she fallen off?
He's my new junior associate.
He's working with me on this.
All yours.
Mr Nobody and I
have been given the authority
to get you out of this.
All you have to do is agree
to the terms and you're free.
Restraining wills, talking about,
what terms?
Confess to your crimes in Berlin.
Treason,
international espionage.
Massive destruction
of scenic property.
You do that, we close the case.
And?
And the DSS blacklist.
Germany love that.
Officially you're a criminal.
Woah, woah, woah.
You need to work on
your delivery alright.
Unofficially.
You're off the books.
Come work with me.
- I'm not a criminal.
- Luke Come on. Labels.
There is no confession.
There are no back room deals.
Got myself into this,
I'm gonna get myself out of it.
You know that.
As you and that's
what I told them.
Well, there you have it.
Good luck in the course, man!
What about your daughter?
You know, if you're not
gonna do it your country,
at least do it for your kid.
Big mistake kid.
Hold on. Look, look.
He's still working from the manual.
I mean, he doesn't even
really know the rules.
Give him a break.
Luke?
I appreciate that.
- It's good to see you, old man.
- You too.
Rule No.1:
know your audience.
I gave you your shot,
you shit the bag.
Now I'm gonna show you
how to get this done.
- You're dead cop!
- Dead!
Well, well, well...
Luke Hobbs behind bars.
Would you look at that?
The bad cop got it's day.
That color looks good on you.
Yeah. Look a whole lot better
with your blood on it.
Yeah. Good luck with that, Hercules.
Roaming gone bad. Huh?
Such a cliche.
Ah well.
Welcome to the club.
I wouldn't get that twisted son.
We ain't in no club.
We got nothing in common.
And unlike you,
I ain't gonna be here long.
You put the shovel did you?
Cause it's 38 feet of
steel and concrete.
What's up big dog?
Now you get to dig in.
Wanker.
Move..
Say that again.
If I say it again,
It will be two corpse.
I'm going to enjoy this.
Welcome back, Dom.
Nice job out there.
Excited about tonight?
Dom in this?
You're with me now.
- Showing me your shoe collection?
- Yup.
A pair for every occasion.
There's enough guns here to
outfit a small army.
Oh this is just the
tip of the iceberg.
You know what I like about you, Dom.
You're a genuine outlaw.
I mean, you're a man who
lives by his own rules.
Which was surprising because when I
saw you in Cuba, I heard about a
guy who almost killed
you with a motorcycle and
you.. let him keep his car?
- That confused you.
- Oh.
Of course I could've
taken his car.
It's about something bigger.
This way...
I changed them.
That's not your responsibility.
- That's how I am.
- Is it?
Let me ask you something Dom,
what's the best thing in your life?
- Family.
- No, it's not.
Mind if you're being honest?
It's the 10 seconds between
start and finish, when you're not
thinking about anything.
No family,
not obligations, just you.
And freedom.
I gotta tell you. This whole
thing in the world...
Robin Hood nonsense
you've been doing recently...
It's bullshit. It's not you.
Be who you are.
Why live only a quarter
mile at a time,
when you can live your
whole life that way?
Hey..!
Sure those muscles will give you.
All show and no..
Well I got plenty of goal.
You must have misplaced that.
When I kicked your ass up in
that office of yours.
Yeah.
Just like you Brits,
rewriting History, huh?
All I know. It was not
me who was thrown out
of a 4 storey window.
Jumped.
I jumped out of a 4 storey window.
Saving my partner's life.
Because where I'm from,
we don't settle fight
by throwing bombs.
Well, that's funny, because
where I'm from,
we don't need women
to run to the rescue.
Do you really believe you
could stand in front of me?
And beat me in a straight up
old fashioned fist fight?
Let me tell you something.
Me and you...
One on one, no one else around.
I will beat your ass
like a Cherokee drum.
Maybe one day we will find out.
Oh, you better hope
that day never comes.
I said no, Mr. Nobody.
I'm not leaving this cell.
I'll get out my way.
The right way.
- Get back to your cell.
- It's just a malfunction.
- Get back!
- Just a malfunction.
Don't let him get away.
Hobbs!
I've been waiting a
long time for this.
Keep waiting!
Rubber bullets, big mistakes.
Took longer than I expected.
- 2 questions.
- Yeah.
- My daughter?
- With your sister.
- Toretto?
- That's interesting you ask.
This is my new base,
Next level stuff for you.
Listen, I don't wanna
talk to you about this,
Hey, listen guys. Thanks..
Wow, handcuff. What is this?
It's called the abuse of power.
You told me to round 'em up.
I told you that...
hand..
Cut 'em loose.
Oh man, this is embarrassing.
I'm sorry guys, what do I have?
This is how you treat old friends?
Friend?
We don't even really know
who the hell that guys is.
It does not matter who I am,
As in like Nobody ok?
Nobody, then who is he?
He's nothing
he's like less than me.
Clearly we're getting nowhere,
with nobody.
I've been 4 hours here,
my ribs are sore.
I don't know about y'all,
but I'm out.
- I wouldn't recommend that.
- What?
Well,
thanks to your past Berlin job.
You all made interpol's
top 10 most wanted list.
Top 10? Uh-huh.
That's alright.
Well, not you.
What do you mean?
You just missed the cut,
you're number 11.
- So.
- I missed it?
- Yeah.
- That's impossible.
What number did they come in at?
Six, eight, nine...
Ten.
She's Ten? That's impossible,
there is no way she's 10.
Oh, She's definitely 10.
How about we focus
on someone who
we're not gonna find out
in anybody's list.
We are waiting hard
confirmation, but...
I believe that's the cyber
terrorist known as Cipher.
Wait, no, Cipher's an organization.
Not a person.
Not according to our sources.
- What does she want?
- I don't know.
Cipher is like a digital active God.
They, she, can manipulate
world systems under shadows.
Anything that can be hacked..
And here is the kicker.
You will never find her.
Linked to any other.
Her digital identity is scrubbed
every few seconds worldwide.
So basically, she
is the boogeyman.
Yeah, she is.
One of the hottest boogeyman
I have ever seen, I mean...
If y'all know her, tell her
to get extra boy.
- What are you, 12?
- That was my scene.
Let's just say.
People are scared of the
hacker group Anonymous.
But even anonymous
won't mess with her.
What the hell does any of this
have to do with us?
Probably nothing, Letty.
But...
I do find it interesting,
apparently for some reason.
She's now working with this guy.
He's already delivered a fully
operational EMP into her hands.
Detonate that,
they can turn any city in
the world into a war zone.
So what is it that
you're suggesting?
Maybe we find Dom huh?
Well, first let's catch him
and then figure out
- why he's turned.
- So you'all want us...
To track Dom.
And I know Roman, I know
it's kinda a big job.
- It's impossible.
- Which is why...
I'm bringing in an
extra pair of hands.
Ah. My day just got a
whole hell of a lot better.
Mr. Nobody you want to tell me
why you just put me in a room
with this tin crumpled tin criminal,
some bitch.
You got a big mouth
for a small head.
Coming from prisoner 6753.
Don't think we've forgotten
everything that you've done.
We're not...
teaming up with this guy.
Let's get one thing clear.
I ain't on your team.
I don't care about you, you crew...
Your little family.
I'm here for Cipher.
You here to apply for a job,
asshole?
You don't think that tight t-shirt
is cutting off the
circulation to your brain.
You should get bigger size.
Cipher came to me first.
Wanted me to steal
Nightshade for her.
When I said no,
she went off to my brother.
Oh Yes.
Brother Owen who
could forget him?
Former hell-raiser
and current guest,
at a nasty little black site prison.
Cipher corrupted him
left him for dead.
So if I get a shot to take her down,
believe me, flicks
up, I'm taking it.
You're taking my boot
right up your ass.
Guys, guys, guys. The fastest way
to find Cipher is through Toretto.
Now aside fromm myself,
there's only two men in the world,
that have ever managed
to actually track him..
Down with any success.
And guess what.
They're both standing in front
of me right now. So like it or not,
you two are gonna work together.
You got that?
I'll take that as a \x22yes.\x22.
Am I the only one seeing this?
Oh, this oughtta be good.
Use God's eye?
We put our lives on the line..
Running around the world
trying to figure this thing out.
You can find anybody, right?
Let's use it to find Dom.
Roman, that is a great idea.
Did you hear that? Great idea.
- And no, no! No pointing out.
- Mr. Nobody.
Let's find it up.
Got him. He's in London.
Wait, we have got a
2nd match in Hong Kong.
- And another in Seoul.
- In Tokyo.
And just about every other
major city on planet.
And so God's eye is where we start.
Cipher's already created an evasion.
Masked her location by..
Pinging random spots
all over the globe.
But it was a good
thought Roman.
So she's made my
programme obsolete.
And that Ramsey..
- is why are you here.
- See, simple solutions...
aren't gonna cut it here slick.
Why are you looking at me
when you're saying that?
Wait a second, wait, wait.
Simple solutions might just cut it.
In order for God's eyes to
give up all this false pings,
Means they have to
be using a free relay.
Watch these two.
Which means it has a decaying
sync quantanizer.
Which we can reverse.
And track it back to
the originating source
and find Dom's true location.
That was my idea.
That's what I was saying, remember?
Alright.
Let's try this.
It's working..
Now you wanna take your manual
and start organizing for response...
Let's get a hold of
our internatio...
He's still..
Yes, like the first baby.
Yes, we're tracked his location.
We wanna mobilize.
Let's get a hold of a, better.
No one respects you, over.
Get away from me.
Alright they are not in China..
- Or Russia.
- Europe's there.
But this one's not going away.
That's interesting.
What?
Because that's here.
It scrambles your senses.
Don't worry,
It'll wear off in an hour.
Probably.
Hello, Deckard.
Nice to see you again.
Look at this,
bodies lying in pool Dom.
Your family's already replacing you.
You chose the loosing team.
I guess your brother
is smarter than you.
Smart move by putting God's eye
into the mainframe.
Irritating to make me have to come
all the way down to get it, but.
Nice gun.
Dom!
You're gonna turn
your back on family?
Just like that?
Let's go.
You okay?
That wasn't him.
I don't know what she's got on him.
But that wasn't Dom.
- Bryan would know what to do.
- No.
We can't bring Bryan
and Mia into this.
We agreed on that.
I know.
Back there was that for her,
for me, or you?
Or was it either necessary?
Necessary?
Nothing is necessary.
Everything is a choice.
I simply made one but so did you.
You could have stopped me,
but you chose not to do.
I wonder what Letty
thought about that.
The problem of putting your foot
on a Tiger's neck...
is you can never let it up.
I think I need to remind you
why you chose to be here.
Dom.
Sorry.
You shoudn't have come.
Now they are going to get me away.
Now she has the three of us.
You wanna see him?
See papa.
Papa.
When I realized I was pregnant.
You had just find
out Letty was alive.
So I decided when Letty and you
go back from your honeymoon.
I was going to tell you.
And then she took us
before I hugged the child.
I call him Michaels.
That's a middle name.
I thought his father should
give him first name.
I'm sorry, Dom.
There is nothing to be sorry for.
Whatever happens...
Just save our son.
Your son.
Good visit?
I know. I know what
you're thinking.
I just let the guards go,
so there is only two opponents
in the room.
Rhodes has the gun, so you'll
take him out first, I know you.
And then you're thinking.
Elena is a cop,
maybe the two of you
can fight your way out of here.
So much to think about.
Let me make it easier for you.
Do with it as you wish.
Have you heard of choice theory Dom?
There's a bunch of accidents,
but only two you really need
to concern yourself with,
One.
The only person's behavior
we can control is our own.
And two, the only thing we
can truly give another person
is information, so let me
give you some.
You see this cameras in here?
The moment you make a move,
highly paid men with weapons,
will make there way into this room.
With one very specific instruction.
It's not to save me.
It's to kill your son.
And that's a lot of bullets.
And it only takes one
for you to loose everything.
So, I have to ask you, because...
I know family is so
important to you.
Is that really a choice
you wanna make?
Because I'm ready as you are.
I pull this trigger, and
God knows I wanna..
I'll kill everyone on this plane...
I still couldn't get in there.
Because you could
manipulate this system.
Since I'm alone!
I got no choice!
I don't think so.
You want to see the old Dom?
Watch.
Damn it..
She wiped it off.
Took God's eye.
That was the one thing
we could use to find him.
We lost everything.
- Yeah, princess?
- Find him to rail.
I've got couple of minutes to spare.
If you want me to send
you to the hospital again.
- Yo Rules!
- First off,
- That's not my name.
- Little nobody.
- Don't call me that.
- Oh that's definitely stinky.
Great do me a favor, and tell
your majesty over there,
that we're gonna find Toretto.
We find Toretto together as a team.
When this is all over,
y'all can have me to
slap that whickest biscuit
right off his face.
Wait a minute, guys.
I think Decker's
actually onto something.
How do you think
Dom and Cipher got
into the country
without us knowing?
- Ghost flights.
- An untraceable aircraft
it's all internet
conspiracy stuff.
It's not.
Satellites and radar grids...
All across the globe shift.
Like an ocean. And they've got
channels that open and close.
And theoretically, if you
know the right people who...
Know the right patterns.
You can fly right through
the blind's box...
can't be be intercepted.
So you know where Dom is headed?
Yeah, New York.
You see that Elle..
You guys...
are gonna get along just great.
Which proves, rule number two,
you never lose everything.
Fire up the chopper.
Guys, have a bowl
and a Big Apple.
Why are we driving like this again?
Because Dom took God's Eye,
so we need to stay off the grid.
But like this?
Hey.
So before I have to open my mouth...
Let me ask you man,
what are we doing here?
That's a good question, Roman.
Let me show you.
Welcome to our new
base of operations.
Now seriously,
what is this place?
This... is heaven.
The agency garage.
We call it a toy shop.
This is where we have every vehicles
seized from drug
dealers of East coast.
Now. Mr nobody said..
If we're gonna have a chance
of catching Dom..
We're gonna have to
be damn fast.
Maybe this could help.
We got a tank.
750 horsepower.
6.6 liter V8 Duramax engine.
With the M153 probe remotely
operated weapon station on top.
You didn't get this
from drug dealers.
No. No that...
T96 army weaponry.
See the army developing
machines like this
the soldiers could drive from a
mile way so they can stay safe.
And alive. But luckily..
There is a back up driver seat for
those of us who like to get war..
Hands on.
I'm sitting there alone the whole
time when this thing feeling badly
and she's getting fat.
No one is getting hands on it.
She doesn't go on some streets.
I'm in love.
Again? No. No...
That's a million dollar show car.
The point is to not draw attention.
It's reverse psychology.
Dom will never see it coming.
It's neon orange,
The international space station
would see it coming.
Go choose anything less inspeculous.
No no.
This is ridiculous. Hey my man,
you can put that down right there.
This is a gift. A real gift.
I know what you're doing.
I like your beard.
You're blanta.
Black santa?
You know I'm serious.
Put it down right here..
What are you doing?
Engine mis-firing,
I gotta check it out.
No. That's not part
of the plan, Dom.
Clearly..
But unless you want the engine
to cease on the job,
You got five minutes.
I want another visual.
I got an ATM
I don't like this.
I want to see Toretto.
There are no more cameras.
Then find something.
Punch in on something reflective
A car mirror, anything..
- You know who I am?
- That's why I'm here.
You know what I'm capable of.
It's why I'm here.
I'll give you until
I finish my cup up.
And I'm.. thirsty.
I'm not here to waste your time.
Oh no.
No, you've already taken everything
I have of value, Mr. Toretto,
What more could you possibly want?
To give you something back.
Talk to me.
Something's not right here.
First time I saw my son...
It's behind a bulletproof glass.
When he reached me,
I couldn't hold on.
It's the worst pain
I ever felt..
I know you know
exactly how it feels.
Maybe we could change that..
When I warned you, I think,
you are about to suggest
something really dodgy Mr Toretto.
It's why I'm here.
Just punch in on something,
I'm not liking this.
Something is not right.
- Rhodes, you close?
- Yeah.
- Good girl.
- The delivery truck's moving.
Captain Deckard Shaw,
distinguished himself
by acts of gallantry
at the risk of his life above
and beyond the call of duty.
His bold actions saved the lives of
hostages and his team mates.
Recommendation: Victoria Cross.
Highest honor the British Government
has ever given.
To a traitor.
Some about this old memory just
doesn't add up to me.
Then don't do the same
kind of funny math,
It says a DSS agent who has a
soul to stop a valid stolen EMP.
Sound familiar huh?
Wanna give me a hand?
- On three?
- Yeah.
One two.. easy.
You know, you can tell this in
another letter..
But maybe we could've caused
some serious damage.
- Yes, we could.
- Yeah.
Shame I'd have to punch you,
head of defend,
when this is all over.
Ah well.
With all due respect, Captain,
When this whole thing is over
we're gonna find a location
and I'm gonna knock your teeth
so far down your throat.
You're gonna stick a toothbrush
right up in your toothbrush shelf.
Get me God's eyes.
- God's eye active.
- Thanks.
Let's find us some Russian.
That spy is my little lie...
Minister of defense.
We land back in Moscow by nine.
Here's the latest defense report,
All the items in yesterday's meet.
Upload this coordinates
to Dom's nav.
Copy that.
He's in the third car.
That's a guard class limousine.
Where's my team?
- Where's his team?
- There's no sign of 'em yet.
They are off the grid.
Probably just bunker down somewhere.
Closing in on him.
You guys ready?
One thing I can guarantee you Dom.
No one's ready for this.
I want every with
chip with the exploits
in a two mile radius
around that motorcade now.
There's over a thousands of them.
Hack 'em all.
It's zombie time.
I'd buckle up if I were you.
AUTO-DRIVE ACTIVATED.
Sorry.
Target the motorcade.
And here they come.
What is going on?
Ouch.
Drive fast!
Police escort down..
Take out the lead and follow cars.
Drive! Drive!
Two more down.
There's more cars ahead of us.
Shoot their engines.
Oh God!
We got locked cars in cyber shock...
Send backup! Send S.W.A.T!
And take yourself a
goddamn boy scout...
- Just send us some help!
- Now that's Dom.
Faster, faster!
The motorcade has turned on 7th.
Perfect. Make it rain.
Target immobilized.
Your turn.
- Who the hell is that?
- What is he doing?
What the hell
are you waiting for?
Shoot him!
Come on, come on!
I'm out.
Shit.
Don't worry sir.
This car is bulletproof.
You'll be safe in here.
- Give me the case.
- Give him the case.
These are nuclear launch codes.
We cannot give it to him.
What is he doing now?
He just cut a hole
in our gas tank.
Good work, Dom.
Meet you at the pick-up.
I think I know
where my team's at.
- Where?
- Right in front of me.
This is on you.
Get out of there, Dom.
Guys, I know why Dom's here.
Police scanners are saying
he's stolen Nuclear Football.
It's over, Toretto.
Get your.. out of the door now.
That's how you wanna play this?
Let's play.
Don't do this, Dom.
He's stomped foot.
- What're you doing?
- It's a trap!
Now I know what it feels like
be every cop ever chasing us.
I'm gonna get a
little close enough.
Oh, so you just gonna take Dom?
Little Nobody has clearly
lost his little mind.
I'm on him.
Easy, work together.
- No, no.
- Wait, wait, wait!
Oh shit.
I will take the short cut.
The path!
Watch these people.
Mr. Sexy coming through!
Not this time, Dom.
Stretch him out.
Hold them.
He gotta have about
2000 Horse Power in that thing.
Try 3000..
Try Five.
Get out of there.
I'm working on it.
Stop working on it, and do it..
No, no no...
It's my Bentley.
No!
Take that case and run!
Move!
They thought...
this was gonna be a streetfight.
You can wait for it Torretto.
No!
Letty, stop!
What are you gonna do?
I don't know why you're doing this,
but I know one thing.
You love me.
And you're not gonna to shoot me.
You should've given him the case,
cause I won't chase you.
Okay.
I will just take it
from a dead girl.
You willing to die for it?
Let's go then.
Anything?
They're gone.
And D.O.D confirmed
it was a nuclear football.
He's got an EMP and
nuclear launch codes.
I don't know what it is,
but they're building
towards something.
Deckard?
He didn't make it.
I'm disappointed in you, Dom.
You'd have Letty just walk
away with the codes.
- You've got the codes!
- Rhodes got the codes.
You made the choice
to let her go.
And now I have to make
one on my own.
They are adorable little things,
aren't they?
I hope I don't hurt him.
Look, Cipher, I did exactly
what you asked me to do.
Don't do this.
- This is your doing.
- My doing?
Please don't hurt him.
I'm begging you.
I don't want you to beg.
- I want you to learn.
- Learn what?
I understand why you did
what you did. I really do.
But it was the wrong choice.
This is a consequence, Dom.
No! No! No...
Wait. Wait.
Don't you do it!
No!
Can you pull up the footage
of the guy in the ally.
- Traffic cams.
- I got you.
I knew it.
I recognize that guy.
That's Connor Rhodes.
I met him when I was working
with Shaw's brother.
He wanted us to get the
Nightshade device him.
Connor Rhodes.
He's also linked to some
who I like to be dead.
Mose Jakande.
Warlord who tried to get God's eye.
Which means that's twice that
Dom has messed up Cipher's business.
Everything you're feeling right now,
that's rage, sense of loss.
It's not real.
It's the survival instinct wired
deep into our brains.
To ensure continuation of species.
When early men went visit
a watering hole...
If they didn't watch their child,
they get snatched by a crocodile.
Your brains would create a painful
but a structural memory.
So it will never happen again.
This idea of family
that is so core with you,
that rules your world...
It's a biological lie.
You don't have to accept it.
I don't!
Did you really could think
you could destroy two of my teams.
Without any repercussions?
I wouldn't have even
looked your way..
If you hadn't done that.
You didn't even know you had a kid.
You can thank me for that.
And start doing the job
I'm asking you to do.
Help you start a war.
Is that what you think I want.
That's so limited.
I didn't take that
football to start a war..
Anymore than I took your son
to start a family.
Taking your son got me the codes..
The codes will get me the nukes,
and the nukes will
get me what I want...
Today, tomorrow...
and every day after that.
What's that?
Accountability.
The second I fire off
one of those nukes..
I put the superpowers of this world
on notice that...
...when they cross line,
...I'm gonna be there
to hold the responsible..
Because the truth is, Dom...
...To the world out there...
...I'm the crocodile
at the watering hole.
You've got one last job to do.
Cipher..
If I were you,
I would kiss my son.
Because whether you value it or not,
all of this...
Your plane, your security and you...
...are still on this
earth because of him.
The problem we have
with tracking Cipher
is there's nothing to trace then.
Now we have trace information.
And we're getting
snapshots of this data
before it's scrubbed off the net.
How do you erase someone's
bank accounts? Always just...
The Longitude.
Given the fact that Dom
hit the Russian Motorcade
safe to say it's Russia.
Go ahead, bring up the map.
Great, let's start here
run the possibilities.
Yalta, Poltava.
Looks like they just threw
letters together.
- Konyert.
- It's Vladupi.
What are you doing here?
Thought I was gonna check in on you
from time to time,
To see you how you're doing.
By the way, not so hot.
But there's nothing in Vladiven.
It's just ice..
That why...
Could've sworn there was a
secret Russian naval base
with the retrophilic
cold war Submarines.
Well, technically,
it's not Russian anymore.
Base was take by a terror grope
of military separatists
about a month ago. And the
Russians haven't taken it back.
So there is a little
window of opportunity.
Russia made submarines,
nuclear football,
it sounds like everything we do
our legs gonna be bombed off.
Sounds like you're still
a No. 11 on the list.
It sounds like you've changed
since you look funky.
Facial hairs and came in.
Guys... guys. Hey.
We gotta call this in
all the way up the chain.
That's good thinking champ.
Except unfortunately the
Russian Minister of Defense.
Got himself involved in little
incident on US territory
and two governments
aren't talking to each other.
By the time they do...
It will be too late.
So, any other suggestions?
Yeah, I got one.
How about we just
stop them ourselves?
You're talking about a
Russian Military Base.
Separatists.
Whatever. It's suicide.
It's stopping world war 3.
What's it gonna be rook?
You're gonna close your eyes
on this one too?
Pray that the apocalypse
doesn't come knocking on
your mama's front door?
Or are you're gonna saddle up,
be a man and save the
entire goddamn world
I know, thank god
they read it out.
What's that?
- Rule number three.
- Which is?
There are no rules.
What did I told you, Luke?
I knew he'd get in three.
Areal transport leaves in an hour.
Take whatever vehicle you want.
- All bets are off.
- Bets are off?
See you later...
I got an nuclear attack submarine.
Letty I don't like telling
you this one thing,
but the game's changed.
Before we were trying
just to catch Dom,
but now after all of this...
I want you to know,
if I have to...
I'm gonna put him down..
Then you might have to
take us both down.
This ain't right, man.
This ain't funny.
I come from a different
kind of lifestyle.
Ladies know me.
They know where I'm at with.
I try to take a piss,
I ain't even recognize myself.
That's entirely too
much information.
I'm just saying.
Well, one thing is for sure.
Dom's gotta be either working
with them or making a train
cause no one will be this insane
to hit this place in a damn army.
I wouldn't be so sure about that.
Speak of the Dom.
Alright, Dom, you're one step
closer to that family reunion.
400 meters to base.
Prep the EMP.
Let's take these defenses down.
We have a possible
threat incoming.
Raise the barricade, quick.
We've lost power,
get to your positions now.
Gates are open.
Let's get this party started.
- EMP's are charging.
- How long?
60 seconds.
Alright, Dom,
you've one pulse left in that EMP.
That sub is heavily insulated.
You're gonna need to be right
underneath it, or this won't work.
Come on.
Engaging target.
He's beneath the Sub.
I'm loosing control,
mayday, mayday.
Yes, two birds with one stone.
We've got control of the sub.
Dom, we are good.
Head over to the Rendezvous.
Ok Matty...
...Let's take this baby for a spin.
Damn!
I think Cipher just rebooted
Sub's command system.
What the hell is he talking about?
In terms...
She just carjacked a submarine.
We can't let it get away.
That's the control room.
If you can get me
into that row house
I can tap with network
and counter hack Cipher.
Keep it from flowing into water.
No, what we need to do is
get me on that sub.
I find the weapon's room
and I can pull the lunch chip
before she can fire
any of those nukes.
That is too crazy.
- Just think it's too dangerous.
- We'll do both.
Knock, knock!
Five vehicles just reached the base.
They just don't give up, do they..
Come on, let's move, team.
Double time, double time.
Letty, let's go.
Change of plans, Dom.
I'm sending you the co-ordinates,
head there immediately.
- I'm done. I want my son.
- I'll tell you when you're done.
Your team is in play, now leave road
and follow my instruction.
Go! Go!
Move, move!
Get out of here, go go!
Ok, how do you like this?
- Remote link has been separated.
- I'll take care of this.
Hi Ramsey.
She's regaining control.
I mean she's good.
They are entering
the Weapon's stream.
Oh that's cute.
Go, pull pull!
Roman, guard by the chip, c'mon.
Oh she's sick.
Gonna have to do better in that way.
Ok,
now you're starting to piss me off.
Ramsey,
how much time we talking to you?
You're smart,
but no smart enough.
She's locked me out.
Tej, I can't stop. Now
you're gonna have to pull that chip.
I can't.
This thing's going into attack mode.
The door's not gonna open
until you pull the chip.
Tej we got no idea what the hell
we are looking for.
I got it.
What in the hell are you guys doing?
It wasn't me, okay?
It will be labeled
Guardians Go.
- Ok. I got something.
- What?
It says haha.. slack
slack back
...smoke, dear jack
na jack.
Do you understand that?
Oh yeah, that's sick.
Quite a show.
Arming the nuke..
Nuke's going hot,
she's trying to fire this thing.
- Roger that, we're moving out.
- Disable that chip, now.
Roman, what are you seeing?
- Come on, Talk to me.
- I don't see shit. I'm holding on.
Now we're on countdown.
What the hell is going on man?
We are about to launch a nuclear
missile, what the hell is going on.
Pull the damn chip.
Countdown. Countdown.
Look for a countdown.
What countdown?
The missile needs to
activate for launch.
The countdown timer
won't be in Russian.
Countdown.
Show 'em what we could.
No. No. No.
Press that.
I got it.
Something is wrong. It won't launch.
Get that sub out of there.
Now!
Roman.
You alright?
There's nothing alright
about any of this. Let's go.
What about the missiles?
We got the chip,
no nukes for her.
Well done. Let's go.
Guys we got company.
A lot of company.
Alright team, here is the plan.
There is a Sea lock
at the opening of the bay,
We get there first, and close it,
we can stop the submarine
from escaping into open water.
And disappearing forever.
I've got the location.
It's 10 miles south west.
10 miles?
Like I make it in 10 seconds.
What's the matter Roman,
you forgot the snow time?
Loving that Lambo now?
Alright everyone, hold you
over that launch trip later.
Right now I want that sub,
beneath water,
where no one can find it.
Find me the fastest
route out of that bay.
Copy that.
Why are they shooting at me?
I think off you're in that
orange Lamborghini I don't know.
Shut up Tez.
Go on.
Do you really wanna
put that car in gear?
Do you?
I don't think so.
They're heading for the sea lock.
They're trying to trap
the sub in a bay.
I should have taken care of this
a long time ago.
Rhodes, check his team out.
I'm on it.
Roman, get in front of me.
Ok, y'all wanna play it rough?
Now it's my turn.
Yeah, baby!
Guys,
we got snow mobile on the right.
They're going to flank us.
All there?
Oh shit!
Tej!
Roman hold tight.
I'm on the way.
I don't wanted no swimming. No!
Really Tez?
No. No. No.
Oh shit.
Roman, grab your door.
Tez!
Grab the door Roman.
It's all gone.
Oh Shit.
Roman, hang on.
Tej!
No, man. Get me off this thing.
No!
Alright,
I've had enough of this shit!
Number 11 my Ass.
Don't shrink it.
We got a sub to catch, get in.
What?
Pressure is on alert
in the cargo hold.
Drop it to 10 thousand feet.
I know what these people
meant to you.
So I'll let you pick
the first target.
I'm not picking target
from a mile away.
I'd stand face to face,
and look 'em dead in the eye.
Ok.
That would wipe in the ass.
I'm enjoin the remains.
You don't go get any ideas.
You aren't placed out
of a good history.
No shit.
Let's go start fight.
She's gonna kill himself.
Pull up surveillance, right now.
Surprise.
Pierce must be dead.
You're driving.
I said it from the beginning.
No way, I'm not driving.
We have a security breach in the
cargo foil. Take care of it now.
Jesus Mum, you should
pose to avoid the nerves.
Oh, shut up, don't be such a baby.
Get to the pilot,
he's got the second key.
Wait for my signal.
Give Cipher my regards.
He gave this, this day,
thinking out.
No, don't touch.
You can track Cipher with this,
but you can't do this on your own.
There's gotta be two of you.
Fine, I got contacts.
Now you're gonna take your brother.
- No.
- Yes.
Do I don't know where he is...?
His copy's fake,
I can see everything inside his..
- It's called the God's eyes.
- Yeah, well. Whatever.
There's no way
I'm using Owen, alright?
He's a lost cause.
He's your brother, Deck.
He's my son.
He's our family.
And our family that died...
Bloody shit happening.
You lied about, I mean,
I can't believe you.
You've got me upset,
you really upset your mother.
Call yourself a brother?
Oh come on, mum. Ok.
Every time!
- Owen.
- In position.
Go.
I'm in.
I've got the package to lay on.
It's all personal.
You made me miss my son?
What do you think you're doing?
Looking at you dead in the eye.
That was for Letty.
- Rhodes.
- He is no longer with us.
Rhodes picked the wrong target.
Congratulations Dom.
You just killed your son.
You are wrong.
I just saved him.
Need to took your foot
off the tiger's neck.
You're welcome.
It's gonna get noisy.
This is for your relief.
Good?
Let's go.
Go stop him, do not let him
get off this plane.
That truck's had enough munition
to take us all out.
We don't give 'em a target.
Everybody get in
front of us, line up
- we will take the hit.
- What?
I need to switch cars, right now.
- Roman, here comes the bad part.
- What?
Hang in there guys!
We're almost through the lock.
It's easy for you to say,
when your ass ain't on fire.
Hold on little mate.
It's gonna be a little scary,
It's gonna be a lot of fun.
Is the music good?
They're locking on.
Sorry guys,
I got no trick for us..
- What do we do now?
- We start praying.
Hell yeah!
That's Dom!
- This guy in our side now?
- Who the hell cares?
He just saved our asses.
Good to be riding
with you again man.
Torretto's through the way
for them.
Someone give me something.
- Torpedoes are ready.
- Then launch them.
- Take the wheel.
- I ain't taking shit.
- Take the wheel!
- Where are you doing?
This is crazy!
- Left or die!
- What?
Turn the goddamn wheel to the left,
really requesting.
Boom, baby!
That's alright!
Thank you the same.
Where is that smile?
There is!
You're gonna shoot a baby
You shoud...
You aren't gonna wanna see this?
Is that you or him?
Him.
Good.
The torpedo's missed,
they are gonna reach lot
before the sub does.
To hell they are.
Get ready for this.
Oh shit!
We're going to
need a bigger truck.
- Get us out of here.
- Why are you always yelling?
- This shit's crazy!
- Look out!
That's not good.
We got this.
That's my girl.
Sub's too close.
We ain't making it
to the gate in time.
We just gonna let it get away?
Not if I know Dom.
You loose. Dom.
I destroyed two of your teams
I killed your red headed boyfriend.
And I put two killers on you
untraceable plane.
You lost the minute
you interrupted my honeymoon.
Put a heat-seeker on him now.
Now!
There is a goddamn heat seeker
coming at us.
Oh my...
come and get it.
Guys!
Dive..
This... This is for my son!
Dom!
You aren't pulling this Deckard.
Like I'm need a gun
to take care of you,
How did you find me?
You want to see the old Dom?
Watch!
Resourceful.
It belonged to us before Cipher.
You pulled my family through.
A mother.
I'll make sure
that never happens again.
To anyone.
There is only one
flaw in your plan.
What's that?
Only one of us has a parachute!
Told you this would be fun!
Boys!
You know I've never left you,
right?
I know.
You know I never will..
I've so much to tell you.
Yeah you do,
and you can start with that.
Now, that's...
Dominic Toretto.
Hey Dom!
You're just towing it out there?
We need to get up out of here.
Cause this all kinda neuclearism
happening under this ice.
Relax! Without the trigger chips,
those nukes are harmless.
Ok. So we good then.
Lemme go and get my
young selfie levels up.
You realize this is
a classified, right?
Not today.
We have to get up out of here man.
I'm freezing.
It's Okay.
Don't worry,
he's gonna be here soon.
I get it, y'all got a lot in common.
Computer hacks,
god's eyes, gigs, nerd.
..you know, but we got a
lot in common too! Alright?
- Like what?
- We walk in the room,
and we are oozing sex appeal.
Me and you?
There's a problem.
I am asking the real
question right now.
Is it gonna be...
the Nerd or...
the dark knight?
This time I like both of you.
A'rigt!
Yeah..yea!
But just before we
get into all of that,
Let me ask you one question.
- You can ask me anything.
- Anything.
What's my last name?
When you guys pick around with then
I guess you can let me know.
It's gonna be a Parker.
That's all that really matters.
Jones, Miss Parker.
Hey Miss Parker.
- Hey.
I wanted to thank you.
No need.
Cipher's still on the loose.
There's been some
reports she's in Athens.
But she won't be
nuking any city anytime.
So, thanks to you guys.
- So, I got you a parting favor.
- This can't be...
Full re-instatement.
You got you job back.
That is if you want.
If I want?
You know after 16 years.
I figured it's time
for a little break.
Wow.
Daddy's stayin' home.
- Nobody.
- Get in touch!
Ah, hang on a second.
This could be interesting.
What made you think I would do it?
Brother-hood.
I saw that look in your sight man.
I knew you wanted revenge.
Glad I did it.
Can't believe you
went to see my mama.
Come on.
All this fuss of you.
Yes.
Alena,
I promise to keep our son safe.
And now.. he always will be.
I want to introduce
you to the most
important person
in my universe.
Who will never give up on me.
You've heard me say.
"That you never turn
your back on family."
And I wanna thank you all
for never turning your back on me.
You wanna meet them?
Alright!
Everyone...
Meet Bryan.
Hey Bryan.
Yeah,
I guess he's my turning secret.
Thank you for giving us family.
-