I used to want to\nsave the world.
But I knew so little then.
It is a land of\nmagic and wonder.
Worth cherishing in every way.
But the closer you get...
the more you see the great\ndarkness shimmering within.
And mankind?
Mankind is another\nstory altogether.
What one does when faced with the truth..\nIs more difficult than you think.
I learned this the hard way.
A long long time ago.
And now...
I will never be the same.
Yeah.. Si.
Hello Diana.
- Hello Diana.
- Hello.
Diana!
Come back!
- Looks very good.
- Very good.
How is she?
She's good.
- Keep working.
- I will.
Niobi.
Diana!
Diana I see you.
Where are you going? Slow down!
Hello mother.
How are you today?
Let's get you back to school\nbefore another tutor quits.
But don't you think it's\ntime to start my training?
Antiope thinks I'm ready.
Does she?
I could begin showing\nher some things.
She should at least be\nable to defend herself.
From whom?
In the event of an invasion.
Isn't that why I have the greatest\nwarrior in our history...
leading an entire army General?
I pray there will never\ncome when she has to fight.
But you know a\nscorpion must sting...
- A wolf must hunt.
- She is a child.
The only child on the island.\nPlease let her be so.
But mother...
There will be no training.
What if I promise to be careful?
It's time to sleep.
What if I didn't use a sword?
Fighting does not\nmake you a hero.
Just the shield then\nno sharp edges.
Diana you are the most precious\nthing in the world to me.
I wished for you so much so I\nsculpted you from clay myself.
And begged Zeus\nto give you life.
You've told me this story.
Which is why.. tonight\nI'll tell you a new one.
The story of our people\nand my days of battle.
Yes!
So you will finally understand\nwhy war is nothing to hope for.
Long ago when time was new...
and all of history\nwas still a dream...
the gods ruled the earth.
Zeus king among them.
Zeus created beings over\nwhich the Gods would rule.
Beings born in his image...
fair and good\nstrong and passionate.
He called his creation "Man".\nAnd mankind was good.
But Zeus' son.. grew\nenvious of mankind...
and sought to corrupt\nhis father's creation.
This was Ares the God of War.
Ares poisoned men's hearts\nwith jealousy and suspicion.
He turned them against\none another...
and war ravaged the Earth.
So the gods created\nus the Amazons...
to influence men's\nhearts with love...
and restore peace to the Earth.
And for a brief time\nthere was peace.
But it did not last.
Your mother The Amazon\nQueen led a revolt...
that freed us all\nfrom enslavement.
When Zeus led the gods\nto our defence...
Ares killed them one by one...
until only Zeus\nhimself remained.
Zeus used the last of his\npower to stop Ares...
striking such a blow the god\nof war was forced to retreat.
But Zeus knew...
that one day Ares might\nreturn to finish his mission.
An endless war...
where mankind would finally\ndestroy themselves...
and us with them.
So Zeus left us a weapon.
One powerful\nenough to kill a god.
With his dying breath Zeus\ncreated this island...
to hide us from the\noutside world...
Somewhere Ares\ncould not find us.
And all has been\nquiet ever since.
We give thanks to the gods\nfor giving us this paradise.
And the God Killer?
The God Killer?
The weapon that is strong\nenough to kill a God.
Can I see it?
The Gods gave us many gifts.
One day you'll know them all.
This great tower.. is\nwhere we keep them.
The God Killer.
It's beautiful.
Who would wield it?
I pray it will never\nbe called to arms.
But only the fiercest\namong us even could.
And that's not you Diana.
You see? You are safe...
and there is nothing you\nshould concern yourself with.
You keep doubting\nyourself Diana.
- No I don't.
- Yes. You do.
No I don't.
You Arestronger than you believe. You\nhave greater powers than you know.
- But if you don't try harder...
- Diana!
Are you hurt?
No Mother I'm fine.
- I was just...
- Training.
Seems I'm not the revered\nqueen I should be.
Disobeyed betrayed\nby my own sister...
No mother. It was me.\nI asked her...
Take her to the palace.
Off you go.
You left me no\nchoice Hippolyta.
You neglect your duty\nif she cannot fight.
You speak of a time\nthat may never come.
He might never return. He could\nhave died from his wounds.
Ares is alive.
You feel it as I\ndo in your bones.
It is only a matter of\ntime before he returns.
The stronger she gets the\nsooner he will find her.
Hippolyta I love her as you do.
But this is the only way\nto truly protect her.
You will train her harder\nthan any Amazon before her.
Five times harder...
ten times harder.
Until she's better\nthan even you.
But she must never\nknow the truth...
about what she is...
or how she came to be.
Harder.
You are stronger\nthan this Diana.
Again.
Never let your guard down.
You expect the\nbattle to be fair.
A battle will never be fair.
Anti­ope!
Lay still..
You're bleeding.
- I'm sorry...
- Wait Diana.
What had I done?
I'm sorry.
Where did this fog come from?
There... Go forward.
There he is!
- The pilot! I can see him.
- He's there!
Wow.
You are a man.
Yeah. I mean...
Do I not look like one?
Where are we?
Temiscira.
What?
Who are you?
I'm one of the good guys and\nthose are the bad guys.
What?
The German. Come on we\nneed to get out of here.
- The Germans?
- Diana!
Step away from her.. now!
Ready your bows!
They have guns. Right?
Fire!
Come on!
Stay down!
Shield!
No!
No.
No. No.. Antiope.
Anti­ope hey.
Diana.
- The time has come.
- No.
You... you must...
What? What Anti­ope?
God Killer!
- Diana go...
- Go where?
- Where?
- Go...
No please no. No no!
- No!
- Anti­ope!
No!
- You.
- No..
No mother no.
He fought at my side\nagainst the invaders.
What man fights against\nhis own people?
These aren't my people.
Then why do you\nwear their colors?
I can't tell you that.
You need to tell us now!
What's your name?
I can't tell you that either.
We should kill him now\nand be done with it.
If he dies...
we know nothing about who\nthey are and why they came.
My...
Name is Captain Steve Trevor pilot\nAmerican Expeditionary Forces.
Serial number 8141921.
Assigned to British\nIntelligence.
What the hell is this thing?
The lasso of Hestia compels\nyou to reveal the truth.
But it's really hot.
It is pointless and\npainful to resist.
What is your mission?
Whoever you are you are in\nmore danger than you think.
I am a...
I'm a spy.
I'm a spy. I'm a spy.
British Intelligence got word...
that the leader of the German Army Gen.\nLudendorff.
would be visiting a secret military\ninstallation in the Ottoman empire.
I posed as one of their\npilots and flew in with them.
According to our Intel the\nGermans had no troops left...
no money no\nmunitions of any kind.
But our Intel was wrong. The German\nhad the Turks building bombs for 'em.
And not just bombs new weapons.
Secret weapons.
Invented by Ludendorff's Chief\npsychopath Dr.. Isabelle Maru.
The boys in the trenches\ncalled her "Doctor Poison".
And for good reason.
From what I could tell if Dr. Maru\nwas able to complete her work
millions more would die.\nThe war would never end.
I was there to observe and\nreport nothing more...
but I had to do something.
Which is.. I need more time.
Unfortunately Dr.. we\ndon't have more time.
This work this...
Get that man!
Now!
But if I can get these notes back to\nthe British Intelligence in time...
it could stop millions\nmore from dying.
It could stop the war.
War? What war?
The War.
The war to end the all wars.
Four years...
27 countries... 25 million dead.
Soldiers and civilians.
Innocent people...
Women and children slaughtered.
Their homes and their\nvillages looted & burned.
Weapons far deadlier\nthan you can...
ever imagine.
It's like nothing\nI've ever seen.
It's like the world's gonna end.
Should we let him go?
And risk him bringing\nmore men to our shores?
We can not hold him\nforever my queen.
Mother excuse me...
but after everything the\nman said this must be Ares.
What are you talking\nabout child?
Forgive me Senator but the man\ncalled it a war without end.
Millions of people already dead.
Like nothing he's ever seen.
Only Ares could do such a thing.
We can not simply let him go.\nWe must go with him.
I will not deploy our army and\nleave them scare defences...
to go and fight their war.
It's not their war.
Zeus created man to be just and\nwise strong and passionate...
That was a story Diana!
This much you do\nnot understand?
Men are easily corrupted.
Yes but Ares is behind\nthat corruption!
It is Ares who has these\nGermans fighting..
And stopping the God of war\nis our fore ordinance.
As Amazons this is our duty.
But you're not an Amazon\nlike the rest of us.
So you will do nothing.
As your queen I forbid it.
Strange.
Is it true you saved his life?
Who told you that?
He did.
Ah.. I didn't see you come in.
Would you say you are a...
a typical example of your sex?
I am...
above average.
What's that?
It's a...
Oh...
It's a watch.
A watch?
Yeah it's a watch.
Tells time.
My father gave it to me.
Went through hell\n'n back with him.
Now it's for me and good\nthing it's still ticking..
What for?
Because it tells time.
When to eat sleep\nwake up work...
You let this little thing\ntell you what to do?
Yeah...
Can I ask you some questions?
- Where are we?
- Temiscira.
No I got that before but I mean..\nWhere are we?
What is this place?\nWho are you people?
Why does the water do that?
How come you don't know what a watch is?\nHow can you speak English so well?
We speak hundreds of languages.
We are the bridge to a greater\nunderstanding between all men.
Right.
You know I didn't get a\nchance to say this...
earlier but thank you for\ndragging me out of the water.
Thank you...
for what you did on the beach.
So...
you are here to let me go?
I tried but it's not up to me.
I even asked them to\nsend me with you..
Or anyone.
In Amazon..
The Amazons.
The Amazons?
It is our sacred duty\nto defend the world.
And I wish to go..
But my mother will not allow it.
Well...
I can't say I blame her.
The way this war's going...
I don't wanna let\nanyone I care about near.
Then why do you want to go back?
I don't think "want"\nis the word right?
I guess I gotta try.
My father told me\nonce he said...
"If you see something wrong\nhappening in the world...
"you can either do nothing\nor you can do something."
And I already tried nothing.
Nice outfit.
Oh thank you.
Now.. I'll show you the\nway off the Island...
and you'll take me to Ares.
Deal.
I am leaving on that?
We are..
Yeah we're leaving in that?
Do you not know how to sail?
Of course I know how to sail.
Why wouldn't I know how to sail?\nIt's just...
It's been a while.
I am going mother.
I cannot stand by while\ninnocent lives are lost.
If no one else will defend the\nworld from Ares then I must.
I have to go.
I know.
Or at least I know I\ncan not stop you.
There is so much...
So much you do not understand.
I understand enough.
But I'm willing to fight for those\nwho cannot fight for themselves.
Like you once did.
You know that if you\nchoose to leave...
you may never return.
Who will I be if I stay?
This belonged to the greatest\nwarrior in our history...
our beloved Anti­ope.
Make sure you're worthy of it.
I will.
Be careful in the\nworld of men Diana.
They do not deserve you.
You have been my greatest love.
Today...
you are my greatest sorrow.
Should you have told her?
The more she knows the\nsooner he will find her.
How long until we reach the war?
The war which part?
The Western Front\nin France is...
400 miles long from the\nAlps to the North Sea.
Where the fighting is\nthe most intense then.
If you take me there I'm\nsure I'll find Ares.
Ares as in.. the God of War?
The God of war is our responsibility.\nOnly an Amazon can defeat him.
With this.
And once I do...
the war will end.
Look. I appreciate\nyour spirit...
but this war is...
It's a great big mess.
And there's not a whole lot\nyou and I can do about that.
I mean we can get back to London\nand try to look for men who can.
I'm the man who can!
Once I find and destroy Ares...
the German armies will be\nfreed from his influence...
they will good men again\nand the world will be better.
Great.
You will see.
What are you doing?
I thought maybe you wanna...
get some sleep.
What about you? Are\nyou not sleeping?
Does the average men not sleep?
Yes we sleep. We just\ndon't sleep with a...
You don't sleep with women?
No I mean I do I sleep with...\nI sleep with...
Yes I do..
But out of the...
confines of marriage.
Not polite to assume you know?
"Marriage"?
Weird! You don't have that...
You go before a judge...
and you swear to love honor\nand cherish each other...
Until death do you apart.
And do they.. love\neach other till death?
Not very often no.
Then why do they do it?
I have no idea.
So you cannot sleep with\nme unless I marry you..
I will sleep with you if you want.\nI'll sleep right there.
There is plenty of room.
- Then fine if you don't mind...
- No it's up to you.
- I'm just fine.
- Coming to sleep with you.
Okay.
You know where I come from\nI'm not considered average.
You know um.. being a spy...
You have to show a\ncertain amount of...
vigor.
Have you never met a man before?\nWhat about your father?
I have no father.
My mother sculpted\nme from clay...
and I was brought\nto life by Zeus.
Well that's neat.
Sorry.
Where I come from..
Babies are made differently.
You refer to\nreproductive biology.
- Yes yes.
- Yeah I know.
I know all about that.
I mean I refer to that\nand other things.
The pleasures of the flesh.
Do you know about that?
I've read all 12 volumes of Clio's\ncriticism on earthly pleasures
12 huh?
Did you bring any\nof those with you?
You would not enjoy them.
I don't know. May be.
No you wouldn't.
Why not?
They came to the conclusion that man\nare essential for procreation...
but when it comes to pleasure...
Unnecessary.
No.
Goodnight.
How long until\nwe're operational?
Two days sir.
We'll have it up\ntonight Captain.
Sir the men have had\nno food no sleep.
Do you think I have had a\nneat food or rest captain?
Do you hear me making excuses?
No.
Your men they are\nweak complacent.
You've let them forget for an\nattack can happen at any time.
From any cover!
So let's you & I remind them...
Shall we?
- Doctor.
- General.
Progress?
Not enough.
It is over General.
Germany is giving up.
Von Hindenburg has recommended\nthe Kaiser sign the armistice.
We have run out of time.
As soon as the Kaiser\nsees the newest weapon...
he will not sign the armistice.
But without my notebook...
We will get your book!
It is you that I\nbelieve in not it.
I know what you can\nand will succeed...
It is what you're put\non this earth to do.
Something did come\nto me last night.
A different type of gas.
For you.
To restore your strength.
I have got it! I have got it!
And if it's what I think...
It's going to be...
terrible.
Morning!
We got lucky. We caught a\nride we make some good time.
Welcome to Jolly old London!
It's hideous..
Yeah it's not for everybody.
- Good morning Darling.
- What a babe.
Oh no!
Gentlemen eyes to yourself.\nThank you so much.
Come on!
Why are they holding hands?
Probably because\nthey're together.
No... No.. We're not together\nI mean in that way.
This way.
To the war!
Well technically the war is that way.\nBut we gotta get this way first.
And where are we going?
We gotta get this\nnotebook to my superiors.
Hey! Hey...!
No. I let you go. You\ntake me to Ares.
- We made a deal Steve Trevor.
- Yeah.
And a deal is a promise.
And a promise is unbreakable.
Oi damn it alright.
Come with me first\nto deliver this...
and then we'll\ngive you a ticket...
to the war.
Deal?
- Let's go.
- Diana...
What are you doing?
You can not do that because\nyou're not wearing any clothes.
Let's go... Let's go\nbuy some clothes.
What do these women\nwear into battle?
They don't...
A baby!
No no.. No babies.
One's not made out of clay.
Come on.
Diana! Please.
Thank God! You're not dead!
Hurray!
I did think you're dead till\nI got your call you know?
He's been gone for weeks..\nNot a single word.
Very unlike him.
I am introducing myself.\nIt's Etta Candy.
I am Steve Trevor's secretary.
What is a secretary?
Well I do everything.
I go where he tells me to go and\nI do what he tells me to do.
Well where I am from\nthat's called slavery.
I really like her.
Fantastic. Ladies after you.
Oh.. I do I like her.
Is this what passes for\narmor in your country?
Ah. Well "Oh my". It's fashion.
Keeps our tummies in..
Why must you keep them in?
Any woman with a tummy\nwould ask that question!
Conservative but\nnot entirely unfun.
Try it on at least.
Very well..
No!
Come on!
How can a woman\npossibly fight in this?
Fight?
We use our principles.
I mean that's how we\nare gonna get to vote.
Although I am not opposed to\nengaging in a bitter fist stickups..
Should the occasion arise.
Lovely.
It's itching. It's choking me.
Can they blame it?
Etta.
Where is she?
She's trying on up to number 226.
Ms. Candy the whole point\nwas to make her look less
distracting.
May I?
Yeah really? Specs?
Certainly she's not the most\nbeautiful woman you've ever seen?
Better.
Yep that's not gonna work.
Please put the\nsword down Diana.
Diana!
Let me try it by myself.
After you sir.
Etta...
Why don't I meet you\nback at the office?
And meanwhile I'll take\nthis for safekeeping.
Oh no I don't think so.
You gotta put the sword down Diana.\nPlease.
- It doesn't go with the outfit.
- At all.
Put the sword down\nfirst of all.
Promise me you'll protect\nit with your life.
Yes... no.
You can trust her.\nJust hand that over.
- Shield.
- And the shield to her..
You got it? Thanks Etta.
This is easy.
There we go.
What is it?
Hopefully nothing. Come on.
- Steve why are we hiding?
- Shh! Come on come on!
Captain Trevor.
I believe you have something that\nis the property of Gen. Ludendorff.
Ah it's the bad guy convention.
Give us Dr. Maru's note book.
Where I put that thing?
Stand back!
Or maybe not.
Oh tough luck.
Is there anything else\nyou wanna show me?
Where do you think you're going?
I'm sorry but you're clearly\nunder Ares' control.
- Diana.
- Let me help you get free.
Where will I find Ares?
He's... He's dead.
Cyanide.
Stay here. I'll be right back.
Come on! Gentlemen please!
Let him speak!
Yes thank you gentlemen...
Germany is an immensely\nproud nation.
They will never surrender.
Now look. The only way\nto end this war...
Colonel I need to\ntalk to you outside.
And restore world peace...
is to negotiate...
an armistice.
There's a woman.
What is she doing here?\nGet her out..
Ger her out..
Sorry.
Blind sister she got lost\non the way to her bathroom..
I think it's this way.\nSorry guys.
Our only aim at this time...
must be to achieve peace...
at any cost!
Why you been not hearing speech?\nHe is talking of peace.
Not right now!
Trevor what the hell were you thinking\nbringing a woman into the counsel?
The Intel that I brought\nback is time sensitive.
This is one of Dr..\nMaru's notebooks.
Notebook or notes...
We need to get it\nto Cryptography.
And I need a immediate\naudience with the generals.
You do not just barge in here.
Sir with all due respect..\nWhat I saw in my last trip...
will change the course of war.
Captain Trevor!
I heard we lost you in\none of your mission...
and yet here you are\nback from the dead...
and I see you brought\na friend with you.
My deepest apology for\ninterruption sir.
No no no... non sense.
Thanks to this young woman...
the room was finally quiet enough\nfor me to get at least a few words in.
Sir Patrick Morgan\nat your service.
Diana princess of the...
"Prince". Diana Prince.
She is...
and I..
Are...
working together.
She actually helped me bring\nthis notebook back here.
That's from Dr. Maru's lab.
I think the information it contains\ninside will change the course of the war.
My.. God.
- Dr.. Poison herself.
- Yes.
Yes.
Intriguing.
Any further intelligence?
Sadly not sir.\nCryptography had no luck.
It seems like it's a mixture\nof two languages...
but as if they failed to\ndetermine which two languages.
Ottoman & Sumerian.
Surely someone else in\nthis room knew that.
Who is this woman?
She is my...
secretary sir.
And she can understand\nOttoman and Sumerian?
She's a very good secretary.
Sir if this woman\ncan read it...
we should hear\nwhat she has to say.
Yes very well.
It's a formula...
for a new kind of gas.
Mustard gas hydrogen\nbased instead of sulfur.
Hydrogen based...
Gas masks would be useless\nagainst hydrogen.
The book says they plan\nto release the gas...
At the front?
When?
It doesn't say.
Wait. In "front" of what?
Sir...
that is the evidence we need.
You have to find out where\nthey are making that gas.
You have to burn\nit to the ground.
Destroy it.
Ludendorff was last\nseen in Belgium.
We can't be seen in sending troops\ninto German-occupied Belgium...
As we are negotiating\ntheir surrender.
Sir I have seen that\ngas with my own eyes.
If it is used it will kill\neveryone on both sides.
They will all die.
Yes that's what\nsoldiers do Captain.
Send me in.. with some\nlogistical support.
At least give me the chance to take\nout Ludendorff's operation myself.
Are you insane?
I can't introduce rogue\nelements this late in the case.
Sir I can take...
Now more than ever...
the armistice is off\nparamount importance.
It must be negotiated\nit must be signed..
It's the best way of\nstopping the war.
Captain you will do nothing.
And that's an order.
Yes sir.
I understand sir.
I don't!
Diana I know this confusing...
- It is not confusing! It's unthinkable!
- Who is this woman?
She is with me she is with us.
I'm not.. I am not with you!
You would knowingly\nsacrifice all those lives.
As if they mean less than yours.
- Diana let's talk about it outside.
- As if they mean nothing?
Where I come from generals don't\nhide in their offices like cowards.
That's enough! They fight\nalongside their soldiers.
They die with them\non the battlefield!
- That's enough! My apologies.
- You should be ashamed.
- My apologies.
- Diana... Diana!
- All of you should be ashamed!
Please slow down!
Is that your leader?
How could he say that?\nBelieve that?
And.. and you!
Was your duty to simply\ngive them a book?
No!
You didn't stand your ground.\nYou didn't fight.
Because there was no chance\nof changing anything.
This is Ares and he's not\ngoing to allow negotiation
nor a surrender!
The millions of people you\ntalked about they will die.
We are going anyway!
You mean you were lying?
I'm a spy! That's what I do!
How do I know you're not\nlying to me right now?
I'm taking you to the front.
We are afraid you're gonna die.
This is a terrible idea.
We're gonna need reinforcements.
These are the reinforcements?
Yep.
Are these even good men?
Well relatively.
Even in Africa gentlemen we\nhaven't seen such luxuries.
The luxury that we have now is like...\nis like we can't stop making money!
So my uncle the\nPrince and I...
Which prince is that?
I decided to extend\nyour profanity...
But seriously which prince?
Hey Sultan Angoora\nNext Kashmir...
Care to talk for a minute?
Gentlemen excuse me one second.
- A bar... Well a pub.
- You hypocrite.
I've been racing those peacocks\nall night and you've...
Oh my goodness gracious.
That's a work of art.
Sameer Diana. Diana Sameer!
Hi Diana. You can\ncall me Sammy please.
"Sammy".
Oh Sameer I wouldn't...\ndo that if I were you.
Sameer is a top undercover man.
He can talk the skin off a\ncabbage many ways as you can.
He doesn't look that\nimpressive to me.
You do for me.
Your eyes as soft\nas your smile.
And your eyes...
looks like they want something.
I know Chinese too tricky girl.
But can you recite\nSocrates in ancient Greek?
Oh you're done.
Where is Charlie?
Voila!
At least this Charlie\nis good with his fists.
That's not Charlie.
That's Charlie.
Steven!
May god grow a flower\nupon your head son.
Good to see you.
So what were you fighting about?
I mistook his glass for mine.\nThat happens.
This man is no fighter.
Charlie is an expert marksman.
Means he shoots people.
From very far away.
You never know what hit 'em.
So how do you know who you kill\nif you can't see their face?
I don't. Trust me\nit's better that way.
You fight without honor.
Who gets paid for honor?
So what's the job boss?
Two days tops.
We need supplies and\npassage to Belgium.
What's the going rate?
Better be a good pay.
Yeah well here's the thing.
I told you it was\ngoing to be quick.
And there's a lot to\nbe gained by this.
It's for a great cause...
Freedom.
Friendship...
ending the war friendship...
- Okay You have no money.
- No.
All I want now is a picture\nof that beautiful face.
You will not need a photo...
because I'll go with you.
What?
What is this?
We're gonna drop\nher up at front!
- "Dr..opping her off"?
- Yeah.
Question sweetheart I am not\ngonna get myself killed...
with helping every last human.
- That's no I mean.
- Here's the little thief now!
I am both frightened\nand aroused.
Oh here they are! Sorry I'm late.\nSir Patrick!
Yes that's what I\nwas gonna mention.
- Sir Patrick.
- No... No...!
Gentlemen sit. Ms.\nPrince sit..
I assume you are here\nplanning something...
that's going to get you\neither court martial or killed.
And I assume you are\nhere to stop us.
No.
Not at all in fact..
Well look.
I was an younger man once.
And had I been in better health I like\nto think that I might do the same.
It's very very honorable\nthing you're doing.
Therefore..
I am here to help.
Unofficially of course.
What's your plan?
If there's another weapon's\nfacility find it and destroy it.
Along with Ludendorff and Maru.
In that case to\nallay suspicion...
our charming Etta could run\nthe mission from my office.
"Run"...
Also.
There is enough\nhere for a few days.
Thank you sir.
You're very welcome.
Take great care all of you...
and good luck.
Fresh ice-cream.
Hello miss would you\nlike to buy an ice cream?
- Me?
- You hungry?
Yes.
Thank you.
Eight pence please sir.
There you go and\nkeep the change.
Thank you very much sir.
- What you doing?
- It's wonderful!
Yeah.
- You should be very proud.
- Thank you very much!
You should be very proud.
I hope I got niches here. The\nchief's expecting us before dark.
Chief?
Oh yeah. A smuggler.
Very reputable.
A liar a murderer\nand now a smuggler.
Lovely.
Careful I might get offended.
I wasn't referring to you.
Really?
I wanna recover from pretending\nto be somebody else.
I shot people on your\nbeach smuggle a notebook.
A liar murderer and smuggler.\nYou still coming?
It's awful.
That's why we're here.
The gas will kill everything.
What kind weapons\nkills innocents?
In this war...
Every kind.
You were absent at the\ncounsel meeting General.
I see you are negotiating the terms\nof the armistice without me.
- On the Kaiser's behalf.
- I'm on your insistence.
We could easily win this war if\nonly you had a little faith.
We don't.
There are shortages of food...
meds and ammunition.
Every hour we delay costs\nthousands of German lives.
One attack and the\nworld could be ours.
As we speak my chemistry...
We stand against you and your...
witch.
Ludendorff enough!\n24 hours from now...
this war will end.
It is over.
It's over for you.
It is over for all of you..
But the mask won't help.
They don't know that.
Let's go.
Time to stage a demonstration\nfor the Kaiser!
You're late.
Cowboy sneak attack chief!
How are you?
- Good to see you pal.
- Big mike.
- Good to see you.
- Oh yes!
Good to see you my friend.
Yah beauty!
Who is this?
And I am Diana.
Where did you find her?
She found me.
- I plucked him from the sea.
- Well. It's a long story.
You don't have to talk\nabout that right now.
What's there?
British tea from the Germans...
German beer for the British.
And Edgar Rice Brurroughs\nnovels for both.
And guns!
Well... May we get what we want?
May we get what we need.
But may we never get\nwhat we deserve.
Bang!
Strange thunder.
German 77's.
Guns big ones.
It's the front out there.
- The evening hay.
- So who do you fight for in this war?
I don't fight.
You're here for profits then?
No better place to be.
Nowhere better to be than in a\nwar where you don't take a side.
I have no where else.\nThe last war took
everything from my people.\nWe have nothing left.
At least here...
I'm free.
Who took that from your people?
His people.
Don't go...
Don't go there. Do not go!
Don't go in there.
You are safe.
You are safe. Are you okay?
Shut up you woman!
Stop making a fuss!
God!
He sees ghosts.
Hey you're gonna get cold.
Oh I do...
Don't worry about Charlie. He\ndoesn't mean any alright?
These animals why are\nthey hurting them?
Because they need to move quick!
- Like us!
- But this is not the way.
I could help them.
There is no time.\nCome on woman!
Mama!
That man... he's wounded.
There is nothing you can\ndo about it Diana.
We must keep moving.
What is this?
You wanted me to take you to war.\nThis is it.
Then where are the Germans?
Couple of 100 yards\nacross the field.
- The trench is...
- Watch out!
Chief! Oh it's good to see you.
Oi chief's back! Chief's back!
Alright let's move.
Help me please.
They have taken everything...
houses food...
and those who\ncould not escape...
they were taken away as slaves.
Where did that happen?
In Veld... On the other\nside of No Man's Land.
Diana we have to go.
We need to help these people.
We have to stay on mission!
Next safe crossing is\nat least a day away.
- What are we waiting for?
- We can not leave without helping them.
These people are dying.
Nothing to eat and\nin the village...
- enslaved it there!
- I understand that.
Women and children!
We need to make our next\nposition by sunset.
How can you say that? What\nis the matter with you?
This is No Man's Land! Diana!
Means no man can\ncross it alright?
This battalion has been\nhere for nearly a year...
and they barely gained an inch.
Alright? Because on the other side\nthere are a bunch of Germans
pointing machine guns at every\nsquare inch of this place.
This is not something you can cross.\nThis is not possible.
So what? So we do nothing?
No we are doing something.
- We are we just...
- Steve.
We can't save\neveryone in this war.
Steve...
This is not what we\ncame here to do.
No...
but it's what I'm going to do.
Diana!
What the bloody hell\nshe's playing at?
Engage fire!
She's taking all the fire!\nLet's go!
Sniper! Stay down!
Stay down! That's an order!
Come on!
She's done it! Let's go!
Steve!
Let's go!
Come on go!
Stay here I'll go ahead.
- What the...
- Let's move.
We need more firepower.
Sniper!
Move!
Get in!
Charlie bell tower.
Come on Charlie. Shoot him.
It's okay.
Follow me. Give me some cover.
Good!
We're gonna put this on our\nback and when I say go..
- Lift hard!
- All right.
Diana! Shield!
Go!
Stay very very still\nfor me my friends.
Please. It's so important.
Thank you very much.
This has been such an honor\nfor me taking you photograph.
Thank you so much.
For obvious talk of shooting...
you cannot shoot.
Not everyone gets to be where\nthey want to be all the time.
Me I'm an actor.
I love acting.
I didn't want to be a soldier.
But I'm the wrong color.
Everyone's fighting their\nown battle Diana.
Just as you're fighting yours.
Oh it's too much. I wish you...
Thank you.
Hi.. I'm on the phone...
Ah it's "Veld" V-E-L-D.
It's a tiny village.
It may not even be on the map.
Ooh! I found it!
Did you find\nLudendorff's operation?
No. No but I located him.
And oh lucky you he's\nonly a few miles away...
At German High Command.
The German High Command?
And to Intel report...
Ludendorff is hosting a gala..
Sort of a last Hara...
before the Germans\nsign the armistice.
And then the Kaiser himself\nis going to be there.
As well as Dr... Maru.
Actually the Gala could\nbe perfect cover.
- Captain Trevor.
- Yes sir.
You're under no circumstances\nto go anywhere near that...
gala tomorrow night.\nDo you hear me?
You'll be jeopardizing\neverything we've worked for.
You can not compromise\nthe armistice.
- Sir there will be no armistice...
- Steve!
Once Ludendorff bombs\nthe entire front line.
Hold on one second sir.
We shouldn't be bothered about\nsetting the peace agreement.
- Why not?
- Ares would never let...
What?
What is that?
Of course it makes\ncomplete sense.
Ares developed a weapon\nthe worst ever devised.
- Ares? You mean Ludendorff.
- No.
I mean Ares.
Ludendorff is Ares!
Sir this is our last chance...
our final chance to find\nout where the gas is...
and to learn how Ludendorff\nplans on delivering it.
No... No.. No. I forbid it.
Do you hear me? I forbid it.
Sir I am losing you! Sir?
- Hello?
- Sir...
How likely is he to\nrespect my wishes?
Not very like convinced.
Sammy Sammy no no.
Sammy I have to work.
I gotta rustle up with a German uniform\nI took to plough the course tomorrow.
That's easy boss. Come on.
There's nothing we can\ndo till tomorrow.
You said yourself Steve.
- Thank you.
You did this.
We did.
Do you have dancing on...
Paradise Island?
Oh dancing yeah of course.
These people are just...\nswaying.
Okay if you're gonna be\nfighting the God of war...
I might as well teach you\nhow to dance you poor thing.
Alright probably\nwithout the gun.
If you would...
Well...
If I'm going to the Gala I'll\nneed to know how to dance.
- You aren't going to the Gala.
- Of course I am.
- No.
- Why wouldn't I?
Well for one you don't\nknow how to dance.
I would argue with this they\ndon't know how to dance.
Be polite. Be polite.
All right. Give me your hand.
Like so.
And I'll put my arm...
around you like so.
And we just..
What do you call it? Sway?
We'll just sway.
You're awfully close.
Nice Ritz.
I see.
I haven't heard him\nsing in years.
It's started to snowfall.
Touch it.
It's magical!
It is isn't it?
Yes yeah.
Is this what people do when\nthere are no wars to fight?
Yeah.
Yeah this... and other things.
What things?
They have breakfast.
They really love a breakfast.
And they love to wake up...
read the paper and go to work.
They get married.
Makes some babies and\ngrow old together.
I guess.
What is that like?
I have no idea.
The villagers gave them to us.
- A gracious gift.
- And they call us heroes.
You are.
Hey fellas I know that...
I said this job was 2 day's...
and a deal is a deal.
You can't last without us.
Yeah.
We all know Diana is capable\nof taking care of herself.
I'm worried that\nyou won't make it.
No more money.
We have been paid enough.
No Charlie.
Who will sing for us?
- Yeah.
- Oh no please.
Sing?
You asked for it.
The reeds are green.
The sweetest hours I could live.
You must think I was\nborn yesterday.
I know it sounds\ncrazy but it's true.
Every word.
Wait... wait.
There is a whole island\nof women like her?
And not a single man among them?
How do we get there?
And she thinks..
That Ludendorff is\nAres the god of war?
And only by killing\nhim will the war end.
Don't be daft. You saw\nwhat happened out there.
The way she dropped\nthat machine gun next.
The way she took out the tower?
May be it's true.
I think it's true.
I believe it's true.
Steven son you don't really\nbelieve those rubbish thing?
Diana Diana hide in..
How the hell do\nwe get into that?
I see only a couple of guards\nin the door to distract.
Yeah it won't\nlook suspicious...
when I wanna come\nsauntering out of the woods.
I could get in.
You are not going in\nthere it's too dangerous.
- Too dangerous?
- Yes too dangerous.
And you are too distracting.
Look I will go in\nthere follow them to..
Where ever they are working on\nthe gas or better yet where it is.
- I'm coming with you.
- No you are not coming with me.
What you're wearing isn't\nexactly undercover.
I don't know.
I would say she was pretty\nundercover on that battlefield.
It's just gonna we can't get you there.\nIt's all scouted out we'll put back...
But as long as he's still\nalive it doesn't...
You cannot go into German\nhigh command and kill anyone.
You just can't. You\nhave to trust me.
- Oh Wow!
- Where did that come from?
Oh can I drive it?\nPlease let me drive it!
Yes I'll be your chauffeur.
Come on... come on.
Stay put!
Where this come from?
A field over there.\nIt is full of them!
Chief I think you and\nme scope out the area...
in case we need to beat\nthe haste and retreat.
- What do you say Diana?
- Huh?
Colonel.
Steve they have invitations.
Don't worry. Play it cool\nyou go this you got this.
Your invitation please.
Thank you sir. The\nColonel and I wish...
many blessings and all my\nlove to fall up in your head.
Your head must be empty. Find\nthe invitation you idiot.
I am sorry.
I am so sorry I must apologize\na thousand times my master.
I made the most horrible the\nmost unforgivable mistake.
- I lost the Colonel's invitation.
- What?
You saying we travelled all the\nway through the mud and rain...
- Only for you to loose my invitation?
- No I am a bug.
Not even a bug I'm\na dung of a bug.
And you're right master...
Blessing will up on us.
This is ridiculous.
I'm not gonna be spending\nmy evening out here.
You stupid idiots!\nMove your car!
What are you supposed to be?
What are you doing?
Excuse me.
I don't drink.
Have we met?
No but I have\nbeen watching you.
Following your career.
You are Dr... Isabel Maru.
The most talented chemist\nin the German army.
I am a friend.
I hope I'm not causing any...
I know you and General\nLudendorff are...
very close.
We work well together.. Yes.
Tell me some one like\nme behind you...
I could provide a lot more.
And who are you?
A man who shows you appreciation\na genius like yourself deserves.
I love fire. Don't you?
It is like...
a living act of entropy.
The ultimate weapon\nof destruction.
Reminding us that in the end...
everything eventually returns\nto the ash it came from.
There is something\nreassuring about it.
I see all of that in your eyes.
Perhaps you could show me\nwhat you're working on.
I hear it is...
I hear it is extraordinary.
I appreciate your\ninterest in my work...
but I'm loyal to\nGeneral Ludendorff.
Besides...
Now I see your attention is...
elsewhere.
Enjoying the party?
I confess I'm not sure what\nit is we're celebrating.
A German victory of course.
Victory?
When I hear peace\ncould be so close.
Peace?
It's only an armistice...
and an endless war.
Thucydides.
You know your ancient Greeks?
They understood...
that war was a god.
A god that requires\nhuman sacrifices.
And in exchange...
war gives man purpose...
meaning a chance to rise...
above his petty\nmortal little self...
and be courageous...
Noble!
Only one of the many\ngods believed in that.
And he was wrong.
You know nothing of the gods.
Herr General.
Enjoy the fireworks.
What are you doing?
- Out of my way!
- Diana look at me.
If you kill Ludendorff\nbefore we find the gas...
we won't be able\nto stop anything.
I will stop Ares!
What if you're wrong?
What if there's no Ares?
You don't believe me.
I can not let you do this.
What I do is not up to you.
Diana!
Diana...
The gas.
The villagers!
What they cheering for?
Diana!
What did they fire?
The gas.
- It was Ludendorff.
- I saw him he was in the tower.
Wherever he goes you follow.
How will you find us?
I know how.
Diana!
They are dead.\nThey are all dead.
I could have saved them.
I could have saved them\nif it weren't for you.
You stopped me\nfrom killing Ares!
- No!
- Get away from me!
I understand everything now.
It isn't just the Germans\nthat Ares has corrupted.
It's you too.
All of you.
I'll find Ares...
and I'll kill him.
Diana!
That smoke...
it's the chief!
He followed Ludendorff.
Follow the smoke!
Hey! Diana Over there!
Come on. Let's go!
Ooh! What a surprise.
Strange.
Unfortunately I have\nanother matter...
to attend to.
What are you?
You will soon find out.
As magnificent as you are you\nare still no match for me.
We'll see about that.
I am Diana Temiscira...
daughter of Hippolyta...
Queen of the Amazons.
And your wrath upon\nthis world is over.
In the name of all that it\nis good in this world...
I hereby complete the\nmission of the Amazons...
by ridding this world of you...
forever!
Diana?
Diana!
I killed him.
I killed him but nothing stops.
You kill the god of\nwar you stop the war.
Exactly what we have to do now.
We need to stop the gas.\nCome on.
No. All this should\nhave stopped.
Diana...
The fighting should have stopped.\nWhy are they?
I don't know! I don't know.
Ares is dead.
They can now stop fighting.\nWhy are they still fighting?
Because maybe it's them!
Maybe...
Maybe people aren't always good.
Ares or no Ares...
Maybe it's just who they are.
- Diana...
- No.
Diana we can talk\nabout this later.
- I need you to come with me.
- No no!
After everything I\nsaw it can't be!
Can not be!
They were killing each other.
Killing people they cannot see.\nChildren...
Children!
No it had to be him.\nIt can not be them!
Diana people... I...
She was right.
My mother was right.
She said the world of\nmen do not deserve you.
They don't deserve\nour help Steve.
- It's not about deserve!
- They do not deserve our help.
Maybe we don't!
But it's not about that.\nIt's about what you believe.
You don't think I get it after\nwhat I've seen out there?
You don't think I wish I could tell\nyou that I was one bad guy to blame?
It's not!
We are all to blame.
I am not.
But maybe I am!
Please.
If you believe that\nthis war should stop...
if you want to stop it...
help me stop it right now.
Because... if.
If you don't there will be thousands more.\nPlease please come with me.
I have to go.
Hey!
- Where is Diana?
- We are on our own.
- What?
- What did you see Charlie?
Seems like a bunch\nof gas pumps...
but I can't see where\nthey're taking them.
How are we gonna get in there?
I have got an idea.\nCome on guys.
Come on!
Who's there?
Sir Patrick.
You were right Diana. They\ndon't deserve our help.
They only deserve destruction.
You...
You are him.
I am.
But I'm not what\nyou thought I was.
What is that?
Future.
I'm not your enemy Diana.
I'm the only one who\ntruly knows you.
And who truly knows\nthem as you now do.
They always been and\nalways will be...
weak cruel selfish...
and capable of the\ngreatest horrors.
All I ever wanted was...
for the Gods to see how\nevil my father's creation was.
But they refused.
I am Diana of Temiscira...
So I destroyed them.
Daughter of Hippolyta...
and I am here to complete her...
The God Killer...
My dear Child..
That's not the God Killer.
You are.
Only a God can kill another God.
Zeus left the child he had\nwith the queen of the Amazon.
As a weapon to use against me.
No. You liar.
I compel you to\ntell me the truth.
I am.
I'm not the god of war Diana.
I am the God of truth.
Mankind...
Stole this world from us.
They ruined it day by day.
And I the only one wise\nenough to see it...
was left too weak to stop them.
All these years I have\nstruggled alone...
whispering into their ears.
Ideas inspiration\nfor formulas...
weapons...
but I don't make them use them.
They start these\nwars on their own.
All I do is orchestrate an armistice\nI know they cannot keep...
in the hope they will\ndestroy themselves.
But it has never been enough.
Until you.
When you first arrived I\nwas going to crush you.
But I knew that if\nonly you could see...
what the other gods could not...
then you would join me and\nwith our powers combined...
we could finally end all the\npain all the suffering...
destruction they bring.
And we could return this world to\nthe paradise it was before them.
Forever.
I...
I can never be a part of that.
My dear I don't\nwant to fight you.
But if I must...
- Steve!
- Come on let's go!
Sammy let's go!
Get these things out of here.
Oh my dear you have\nso much to learn.
Oh my God!
What are we gonna do?
There is not much we can do...
if that's who I think it is.
But we can stop that plane.
If we could get on the radio...
we can ask flying\ncorp to shoot her down.
No. If it crashes it will wipe\neveryone out for 50 square miles.
We gotta ground it!
Bad news. It's on a timer.
If we ground it here\nit's the same thing.
Is it flammable Chief?
Yes you said it's hydrogen.\nIt's flammable.
I need you guys to clear\nme a path to that plane.
- No Steve!
- Hey Steve!
Come on!
Come on! This way! Steve!
- Come on Steve.
- Ahead! Go!
Steve!
Let's see what kind of\ngod you really are.
You will help me\ndestroy them Diana.
Or you will die.
Come on! Let's move let's go!\nGo. Go. Go.
- Now!
- Go! Run!
Is that all you have to offer?
It is futile to\nimagine you can win.
Give up Diana.
Chief! Anything left?
I got nothing.
- Anything!
- No!
Steve.
No!
Yes Diana!
Take them all!
Finally you see.
Look at this world.
Mankind did this not me.
They are ugly...
filled with hatred...
weak...
Just like your captain Trevor.
Gone and left you nothing.\nAnd for what?
Pathetic!
He deserved to burn!
Look at her and\ntell me I'm wrong.
She is the perfect example\nof these humans...
and unworthy of your\nsympathy in every way.
Destroy her Diana.
You know that she deserves.\nThat they all do.
Do it!
Diana!
Diana...
What?
We have to go.
What are you saying?
Steve...
Whatever it is I can do it.
No.. No..
- Let me do it.
- No.
It has to be me.
I could save today. You\ncan save the world.
I wish we had more time.
What? What are you saying?
I love you!
You are wrong about them.
They are everything you say...
but so much more.
Lies!
They do not deserve\nyour protection!
It's not about deserving.
It's about what you believe.
And I believe in love.
Then I will destroy you!
Goodbye brother.
I used to want to\nsave the world.
To end war and bring\npeace to mankind.
But then I glimpsed the darkness\nthat lives within their mind
and learned that inside\nevery one of them...
there will always be both.
A choice each must\nmake for themselves.
Something no hero\nwill ever defeat..
And now I know...
that only love can\ntruly save the world.
So I stay...
I fight and I give...
for the world I know can be.
This is my mission now.
Forever.
Subtitled/Corrected by Asmita/BioHapzard.