Dora!
Fagle!
Huh?
All right.
Hold still now.
Mmm-hmm. Yes.
Well...
Oh, sorry.
No, thanks.
Well, you're
in good health.
So how's Judith
and the kids?
Good. Everyone's good,
you know.
Danny must be, what?
About to be bar mitzvahed?
Two weeks.
Well, mazel tov!
They grow up fast,
don't they?
Hmm...
Yeah, you put the...
That's right, you put the...
You following this?
Okay?
So...
This part is exciting.
So, am I right?
So, okay So...
So, if that's that,
then we can do this.
And that's Schrödinger's Paradox, right?
Is the cat dead?
Or is the cat
not dead?
Messages,
Professor Gopnik.
Thank you, Natalie.
Oh, Clive, come in.
So, what can I do for you?
Dr Gopnik, I believe the results
of the physics midterm
were unjust.
Uh-huh? How so?
I received
unsatisfactory grade.
In fact, F,
the failing grade.
Yes. You failed the midterm.
That's accurate.
Yes, but that is not just.
I was unaware to be
examined on the mathematics.
Well, you can't do physics without
mathematics, really, can you?
If I receive the failing
grade, I lose my scholarship,
and I feel shame.
I understand the physics.
I understand the dead cat.
But you can't really
understand the physics
without understanding
the math.
The math tells how it really
works That's the real thing.
The stories I give you in
class are just illustrative.
They're like fables, say,
to help give you a picture.
I mean...
Even I don't understand
the dead cat.
The math is how
it really works.
Very difficult.
Well, I'm sorry, but I...
What do you propose?
- Passing grade.
- No, no.
Or perhaps I can
take the midterm again.
I know now it cover
the mathematics.
Well, the other students
wouldn't like that, would they?
If one student gets to retake the
test until he gets a grade he likes?
- Secret test
- No...
- Hush-hush.
- No.
That's just not workable.
I'm afraid we'll just have to bite
the bullet on this thing, Clive...
Very troubling.
Sy Ableman.
Hello, Sy
Larry Gopnik.
Larry. How are you,
my friend?
Good How you been, Sy?
Fine Can
we talk, Larry?
What? You...
Uh...
Hello? Larry?
Call back!
Clive!
That was Sy Ableman.
He said he
got disconnected.
Out in a minute.
I gotta wash my hair.
I'm going out tonight.
I'll be out in a minute.
Jesus Christ!
Why is Uncle Arthur
always in the bathroom?
He has to drain his
sebaceous cyst. You know that.
Will you set the table?
Why can't he do it in the
basement or out in the garage?
I had 20 bucks in it,
too. Inside the case.
Twenty bucks?
How come?
Bought a lid from Mike
Fagle a couple of weeks ago.
Still owed him 20.
He already
gave you the pot?
Yeah. But a couple of weeks
ago, my funding got cut off.
Fagle said he'd pound the crap
out of me if I didn't pay up.
What funding got cut off?
Where do you get your money?
What happened?
Rabbi Turchik took his
radio Had money in it.
That fucker!
Yeah. I think he said
he was confiscating it.
He's a fucker. Where
do you get your money?
Mike Fagle's
gonna kick his ass.
Last week he pounded the
crap out of Seth Seddlemeyer.
He's a fucker!
- Fagle or Seth Seddlemeyer?
- They're both fuckers!
Out in a minute!
Are you still in there?
Yeah,
I'll be out in a minute!
Arthur!
- Yeah?
- Dinner!
Okay,
out in a minute!
We should wait.
Are you kidding?
Mr. Brandt keeps mowing
part of our lawn.
Does that matter?
What?
Is it important?
It's just odd.
Mom, how long is Uncle
Arthur staying with us?
Ask your father.
Honey.
Did you talk to Sy?
Sy?
Sy Ableman That's
right, he called But I...
- You didn't talk to him?
- No.
You know the problems that
you and I have been having?
Mmm-hmm.
Well, Sy and I
have become very close.
In short, I think it's time that
we start talking about a divorce.
Sy Ableman?
This is not about Sy.
You mentioned Sy!
Don't twist my words,
Larry.
A divorce? What have I done?
I haven't done anything.
Larry, don't be a child.
You haven't done anything.
I haven't done anything.
Yes! Yes, we haven't
done anything.
And I'm probably
about to get tenure.
Nevertheless, there have
been problems, as you know...
- Well...
- ...and things have changed.
And then, Sy Ableman.
Sy has come into
my life, and I...
Come into your... What does
that mean? You barely know him.
Oh, please We've known the
Ablemans for 15 years, Larry!
Yes, but you said
we hadn't done anything.
I haven't done anything.
This is not some
flashy fling, Larry.
This is not about
woopsy-doopsy.
Sy Ableman?
- I'll be out in a minute!
- Oh, Jesus Christ!
Look, I didn't know any other
way of breaking it to you
except to just tell you
and treat you like an adult.
Is that so wrong?
Where do I sleep?
- What?
- Arthur's on the couch.
Look, Sy feels
that we should...
Esther is barely cold!
Esther died three years ago,
and it was a loveless marriage.
Sy wants a get.
- A what?
- A ritual divorce.
He says it's very important.
Without a gett,
I'm an aguna.
A what?
What are you
talking about?
You always act
so surprised.
I have begged you
to see the Rabbi.
Messages,
Professor Gopnik.
Yes, thanks for coming,
Clive. Have a seat.
We had, I think, a
good talk the other day,
...but you left something...
- I didn't leave it.
Well, you don't even know
what I was going to say.
I didn't leave anything.
I'm not missing anything.
I know where everything is.
Well then, Clive...
Where did this come from?
This is here, isn't it?
Yes, sir.
That is there.
This is not nothing.
This is something.
Yes. That is something.
- What is it?
- You know what it is, I believe.
- And you know I can't keep it, Clive.
- Yes, sir.
I'll have to pass it on
to Professor Finkle,
along with my suspicions
about where it came from.
Actions have consequences.
Yes. Often.
No, always! Actions
always have consequences!
In this office, actions
have consequences.
- Yes, sir.
- Not just physics,
...morally.
- Yes.
And we both know
about your actions.
No, sir.
I know about my actions.
I can interpret, Clive I know
what you meant me to understand.
Meer sir my sir.
"Meer sir my sir"?
Mere surmise, sir.
Very uncertain.
You little brat fucker!
You snuck 20 bucks
out of my drawer!
Studying Torah,
asshole.
You little brat!
I'm telling Dad!
You gonna tell him you've been
sneaking it out of his wallet?
You know what I'm gonna do, you
little brat, if you don't give it back?
Dad?
Dad, you've
gotta fix the aerial.
Hello, Larry. Have you
thought about a lawyer?
- Dad!
- Honey, please!
We're not getting
channel four at all.
Can we
discuss it later?
I can't get F Troop.
Larry, the
children know.
Do you think
this is some secret?
Do you think this is something
we're going to keep quiet?
Dad, Uncle Arthur is
in the bathroom again,
and I'm going
to the Hole at 8:00.
- Out in a minute!
- Ow! Stop!
- She keeps doing that!
- What's going on?
Arthur?
Yes?
What are you doing?
Working on the Mentaculus.
Any luck, um,
looking for an apartment?
No.
- Sy.
- Good to see you, Larry.
I'll get Judith.
No, listen, actually, I'm
here to see you, if I might.
Such a thing
Such a thing.
Shall we go
in the kitchen?
You know, Larry, the way we
handle ourselves in this situation,
so important.
- Uh-huh?
- Absolutely.
Judith told me that she
broke the news to you,
and she said that
you were very adult.
- Did she?
- Absolutely.
The respect she has
for you...
- Yes?
- Do you drink wine?
Because this is
an incredible bottle.
This is not
Mogen David, Larry.
This is a wine A Bordeaux.
- You know, Sy...
- Open it.
Let it breathe.
Ten minutes.
Letting it breathe,
so important.
Thanks, Sy,
but I'm not...
Listen, I insist, Larry.
There's no cause for discomfort.
I'd be uncomfortable
if you didn't take it.
Larry, listen.
These are signs.
Tokens, Larry.
I'm just...
I'm not ungrateful.
I just don't know
a lot about wine,
...and given our...
- It's okay.
...respective...
Larry, we're
going to be fine.
Want some of this,
fucker?
Fuck.
Would you read this?
Tell me what you think?
Okay.
Boy! You should have
worn a hat.
Let's see
some hustle, Mitch.
Larry?
Hi, Arlen.
Larry, I feel that as head of the
tenure committee, I should tell you this.
Though it should be no cause for concern,
and you should not at all be worried.
Okay.
But I feel
I should mention it,
even though it will carry
no weight in our decision
on whether or not
to grant you tenure.
So again,
no cause for concern.
Okay, Arlen
Give what any weight?
Well...
We've received
a number of letters
denigrating you
and urging us not to...
Not to grant you tenure.
From who?
Well, they're anonymous,
so we dismiss them completely.
Well, what do they say?
Well, they
make allegations...
Well, allegations...
Assertions.
And though we give them
no credence at all, Larry.
Well, I'm not really
at liberty
to discuss the specifics of
the committee's deliberations.
But I think you're saying these won't
play any part in your deliberations?
None whatsoever.
So what are they?
Moral turpitude,
you could say.
Uh-huh. Can I ask? Are they...
- Are they idiomatic?
- Hmm?
The reason I ask, I have a
Korean student. South Korean.
A disgruntled South Korean, and I
meant to talk to you about this...
Oh, no, no They're competently,
even eloquently written.
A native English speaker.
There's no question about that.
- Uh-huh.
- Let me reiterate.
No cause for concern.
I only speak because I
would feel odd concealing it.
- Yes.
- Yeah.
Best to Judith.
I gotta get
my radio back.
Maybe the fucker lodged
it up his fucking asshole.
I gotta get it back, or Mike Fagle's
gonna pound the crap out of me.
Way up his asshole.
Good afternoon.
Go scrub up, Mitch.
Been hunting?
Is that a...
It's gonna be
a boat shed.
Uh-huh.
That's great.
- Mr. Brandt...
- I said scrub up, Mitch!
Isn't this a school day?
I took him out of school today
so he could hunt with his dad.
Uh, Mr Brandt,
that's just about at
the property line there.
I don't think
we're supposed to get
...within, what, 10 feet...
- Property line's the poplar.
- The...
- Poplar.
- Well, even if it is, you're just
about over it. - Measure.
- I don't have to measure, you
can tell it's... - Line's the poplar.
What's going on?
Nothing.
- Larry?
- Yeah?
Did you go to
Sieglestein Schlutz?
No, I...
Not yet.
Larry.
Appointment Monday.
Where are you going?
I'm going to the Hole.
What? At 5:00?
We're stopping at Laurie Kipperstein's
house so I can wash my hair.
Hi, Mr Gopnik.
- You can't wash it here?
- Uncle Arthur's in the bathroom.
I'll be out
in a minute!
- Are you ready?
- Huh?
- We're meeting Sy at Embers.
- I am?
Both of us.
I told you, Larry.
Larry.
How are you?
Sy.
Hello, Judith.
Hello, Sy.
Larry, I want to
thank you for coming.
It's so important that we be
able to discuss these things.
I'm happy to come
to Embers, Sy.
But I'm thinking, really,
maybe it's best to leave
these discussions
to the lawyers.
Of course Legal matters,
you let the lawyers discuss.
You don't mix
apples and oranges.
I have begged you
to see the lawyer.
I told you,
I'm going Monday.
Monday is timely.
This is not...
Please, Embers is not the forum
for legalities You're so right.
No, Judith and I wanted
merely to discuss, uh,
practicalities.
Living arrangements.
After all, this is an issue
where no one is at odds.
Living arrangements?
I think we all agree
that the children
not being contaminated
with the tension,
the most important.
We shouldn't put the kids
in the middle of this, Larry.
The kids aren't...
I'm saying "we."
I'm not pointing fingers.
No one is playing
the blame game, Larry.
I didn't say
anyone was.
Well, let's not play "He
Said, She Said," either.
- I wasn't! I...
- All right. Look, look, look.
Let's just take a step back and
we can diffuse the situation.
You know, Larry,
sometimes I find that
if I count to 10...
One,
two,
three,
four...
Or silently.
Really, to keep things
on an even keel
leading up to
Danny's bar mitzvah...
A child's
bar mitzvah, Larry.
Sy and I think it's best if
you move out of the house.
Move out?
- Well, it makes eminent sense.
- Things can't continue as they...
Move out?
Where would I go?
Well, for instance, the
Jolly Roger is quite livable.
It's not expensive.
The rooms are
eminently habitable.
This would allow you
to visit the kids.
There's convenience in its
favor They've got a pool.
Wouldn't it make more sense
for you to move in with Sy?
Larry.
Larry, you...
You are jesting.
I think, really,
the Jolly Roger
is the appropriate
course of action.
Listen here,
you little fucker,
I want my money!
Stop it!
I'm gonna get it!
Give it back!
You owe me 20 bucks,
you little shit!
- Don't worry about it!
- Give it, brat fucker!
- I'm gonna get it! I'm gonna get it!
- Brat! Fucker!
- What's going on?
- Nothing.
- What was that?
How's the Torah
portion coming?
Can you maybe
use the hi-fi?
- What?
- Can I borrow this?
I'm taking some stuff to,
you know, the Jolly Roger.
- Dad!
- Sure, Dad.
Dad! Chinese guy!
Culture clash.
With all respect, Mr. Park,
I don't think it's that.
- Yes.
- No,
it would be a culture clash if
it were the custom in your land
to bribe people
for grades.
Yes.
So, you're saying
it is the custom?
No, this is defamation.
Ground for lawsuit.
Let me get this straight.
You're threatening to sue
me for defaming your son?
Yes.
- But it would...
- Is this man bothering you?
Is he bothering me? No.
I, uh...
See, look...
If it were defamation,
there would have to be
someone I was defaming him to, or I...
All right,
let's keep it simple.
I could pretend the money never
appeared That's not defaming anyone.
Yes. And passing grade.
- Passing grade?
- Yes.
Or you'll sue me?
For taking money.
So he did leave the money?
This is defamation!
It doesn't make sense. Either
he left the money or he didn't.
Please.
Accept the mystery.
Give me that, fucker.
He's very
good with numbers.
I think his social skills
have held him back.
Such a sweet man, though.
Arthur has
a good heart.
And he never complains,
unlike me.
Sometimes I don't
give him enough credit.
He tried to tell me about this
thing he's working on, this...
The Mentaculus.
He says it's a probability
map of the universe.
Does he go out
socially at all?
He tries. He's been going to the
singles mixers at Hillel House.
I should talk.
I'm not doing any better.
How is Judith?
Fine. She's fine.
Sometimes these things
just aren't meant to be.
And it can take a while before
you feel what was always there.
- For better or worse.
- I never felt it!
It was a bolt
from the blue.
What does that mean?
Everything that I thought was
one way turns out to be another.
Then, it's an opportunity to
learn how things really are.
I don't mean to sound glib.
It's not always easy deciphering
what God is trying to tell you,
but it's not something you have
to figure out all by yourself.
We're Jews.
We've got that well of tradition
to draw on, to help us understand.
When we're puzzled,
we have all the stories
that have been handed down from
people who had the same problems.
Have you talked to
Rabbi Nachtner?
Why not see him?
What's the Rabbi
gonna tell me?
If I knew,
I'd be the Rabbi.
The air out
here is magnificent.
I'm telling you, if someone
could bottle this air,
they'd make
a million dollars.
Hello, Larry.
Good to see you.
Oh. Rabbi Scott.
I thought I was going
to see Rabbi Nachtner.
He was called away
on an etz monim.
Ruth Brynn's mother is in the
hospital and she isn't doing well.
Rabbi Nachtner asked me to
cover for him. Come on in.
And she wants a gett.
A what?
- She wants a...
- Oh, a gett.
Uh-huh. Sure.
I feel like the carpet's
been yanked out from under me.
I don't
know which end is up.
I'm not even sure
how to react.
I'm too confused.
What reasons did she
give for the rupture?
She didn't give reasons
Just that,
you know, things
haven't been going well.
And is that true?
I guess.
I don't know.
She's usually right
about these things.
I was hoping that
Rabbi Nachtner could...
That he would...
He would... Yes?
Well, with the benefit
of his life experience.
No offense.
No, of course
not I am the junior rabbi.
And it's true, the point of
view of somebody who's older
and perhaps had similar
problems might be more valid.
And you should see the senior
rabbi as well, by all means.
Or even Marshak,
if you can get in.
He's quite busy,
but maybe...
Can I share
something with you?
Because I, too, have had
the feeling of losing track
of Hashem,
which is the problem here.
I, too, have forgotten
how to see him in the world,
and when that happens,
you think,
"Well, if I can't see him,
he isn't there. He's gone."
But that's not the case.
You just need to
remember how to see him.
Am I right? I mean...
The parking lot here.
Not much to see.
But if you imagine
yourself a visitor,
somebody who isn't familiar
with these autos and such,
somebody still with
the capacity for wonder.
Someone with
a fresh perspective.
That's what it is, Larry.
Because with
the right perspective,
you can see Hashem, you
know, reaching into the world.
He is in the world,
not just in shul.
It sounds to me like you're looking
at the world, looking at your wife,
through tired eyes.
It sounds like she's
become a sort of thing...
A problem.
A thing.
She is seeing Sy Ableman.
- Oh.
- They're planning...
That's why
they want the gett.
Oh I'm sorry.
It was his idea.
Well, they do need a gett
to remarry in the faith.
But... This is life.
You have to see these things
as expressions of God's will.
You don't have to
like it, of course.
The boss isn't always right,
but he's always the boss.
That's right!
Things aren't so bad.
Look at
the parking lot, Larry.
Just look at
that parking lot.
Are we eating already?
Sarah's going out.
Ow! Cut it out!
What's going on?
Isn't Dad eating?
He's at
the Jolly Roger.
Oh, yeah.
How are you, Larry?
Jesus, I am so sorry
- to be seeing you under these
circumstances. - Oh, well...
I always thought you
and Judy were rock solid.
This is so terrible, Larry.
This is devastating.
Well, you know,
the way I look at it,
it's an opportunity for me to
really sit down and figure things out
and look at the world afresh
instead of just, you know,
settling for the routine, tired
old way of looking at things.
Really?
I don't know,
maybe not.
Well, legally,
I have to warn you,
it's never easy
for the husband.
Unless, of course,
there's some question
of the wife having violated
the marriage contract?
Oh, no, no
Nothing like that.
Although she is planning to
marry Sy Ableman, but they...
Sy Ableman!
- Yes. But they...
- Esther is barely cold!
She passed
three years ago.
Well... Still, this changes
the complexion, Larry.
Sy Ableman.
Not in the sense that... T
here hasn't been hanky-panky.
To my knowledge.
- Oh? - No I'm fairly
certain this is not an issue.
And in fact,
Judith wants a gett.
A what?
A ritual divorce.
- Oh.
- So that they can remarry in the faith.
Uh-huh.
Yeah, sure, uh...
Well, not really
a legal issue.
Okay, um...
Good. Good.
Well...
On the other thing, the
neighbor's property line,
I've asked Solomon
Schlutz to take a look.
There's very little to do with
real estate that'll get by Sol.
Okay Good
How do you...
I guess
I'm a little worried.
How do you...
I have money pressures...
Our fee structure?
We bill by the hour.
Dave Sieglestein and
Solomon Schlutz bill at 110.
The associates, me,
for instance, bill at...
Call for Mr Gopnik
Danny at home.
You can take it here.
0809.
Danny?
- Hey, Dad.
- Are you all right?
Are you all...
F Troop is fuzzy.
What?
F Troop is still fuzzy.
- Dad?
- Is everything okay?
Clive?
Clive!
You little bastard! You
gonna send your mother next?
Little bastard!
I want to see you!
Hold on.
Professor Gopnik,
it's Dick Dutton again.
Dick Dutton.
Hello?
Hello, Mr Gopnik?
This is Dick Dutton from
the Columbia Record Club.
I'm calling because
it's now four months,
and we have yet to
receive your first payment.
There's some mistake.
I'm not a member
of the Columbian Record Club.
Sir, you are Lawrence Gopnik
of 8419 Fern Hill Road?
No, I live
at the Jolly Roger.
Excuse me?
No, I...
Well, yes, okay.
- Yes, you are Lawrence Gopnik?
- Okay.
"Okay" means...
Okay, yes,
Lawrence Gopnik, yes.
Okay, well, you received
your 12 introductory albums,
and you've been receiving the monthly
main selection for four months now...
The monthly main selection?
Is that a record?
I didn't ask
for any records.
To receive the monthly main
selection, you do nothing. You...