Monggo mirsani
At one time, Deep in the
country of France...
There lived a handsome prince, who
lived in magnificent palaces.
Though he had
everything he wanted...
Prince was cruel and selfish.
Sir, it's time.
He imposes high taxes on the people to
fill the castle with beautiful things.
We did it.
And party with great people.
On one night there was an intruder
who arrived at the castle.
He sought refuge from the storm.
As a reward he offers
a rose to the Prince.
Disgusted by the poor performances
jeered her prince gift,
Then, the woman warned her to
not be fooled by appearances...
Because of the beauty,
indeed there is in him.
And, when she drove back, old
woman transform herself...
be beautiful and
fascinating woman.
The prince tried to apologize,
but it was too late...
because he had seen no
love within the prince.
As punishment, he changed the
prince into a horrible creature...
and left a curse on the palace,
and all who live in it.
Day turned into years, the prince and
his servant have been forgotten.
Magicians keep them
remember loved ones,
but the roses he
had a magic roses.
lf he can learn to love each
other and love unrequited,
when the last leaf falls then,
the curse will disappear
lf not, he will be damned
as bad beast forever.
Years passed He fell into
despair and loss of hope...
waiting to see who will learn
to love the horrible creature?
Small town
Quiet village
Every day like any other day
The small town Full
of little people
Waking up to say:
Bonjour! Bonjour!
lt was the baker with
his tray as usual
The same bread ready for sale
Every morning the same
Since the morning we come
For a poor provincial towns
Good morning, Belle!
Good morning, Monsieur!
Did you lose something else?
Looks like.
The problem is l can not
remember what it was.
l'm sure it will
come back to me.
- Where are you going?
- Go to the bookstore.
lt was about two lovers.
Sound boring.
strange girl, no doubt
always confused
Never in keramainan Because the
head was covered with clouds
No doubt, this girl Belle
Bonjour Good afternoon
How are your family
How are your wife
l need six eggs was
very expensive
There must be a better
life than this place
Look at the only nerd in town.
You're where?
2 cities in the North.
l do not want to go back.
- Have you got a new one?
- l'm afraid there is not.
but you may have read.
thanks.
Your library makes it so great.
OK.
Bye.
Look at this girl she
is surely strange
l doubt if he's healthy
His nose is always a dreamy
way, stuck facing book
For us it was a girls 'Belle'
ls not this awesome
This is my favorite part
Because you'll know
This, when he met
the handsome prince
but he would not meet him
Until part three
There's no doubt why the
name of the 'Beauty'
There is no iota of similarity
Behind the face of
reasonable Kuyakin him odd
Very different from us all
He does not like us.
He's different with
us all the 'Belle'
Look at him.
My future wife.
Belle is the prettiest
girl in the village.
- That makes her the best.
- But he is predictable.
You're very athletic.
- l know. She is beautiful.
- Yes. You got us.
Yes, since the war
l lost something.
He's the only one who
gave me the spark.
l dont know the meaning.
When l first saw and met him
l told you she was beautiful
and l are interested
ln this city just him
As beautiful as me
And l want to woo
and marry Belle
Look, look at him he's not great
Mr. Gaston Oh, he is handsome
Stay tuned .. my heart, l
was difficult to breathe
He was tall, sinister,
handsome and ruthless
That will never happen, ladies.
Lunch Bonjour
You call this bacon?
Beautiful flower
10 yards!
Excuse me!
l picked up the knife!
Let me through!
this fish
Smell
Mrs wrong Maybe so
There must be a better
life than this place
See, l will make 'Belle' wife
Look at him, a strange
but special girl
She was the girl who most insane
He is disabled and the
poor, he does not fit here
Good morning, Belle.
What book is it?
Have you read it?
Not that it was but a book.
For your dinner table.
Tonight?
Sorry, not tonight.
- ls it true? - No.
- So get on with life? - The selling
expensive to make the sweetest prey.
lt makes Belle very tempting.
What is the name?
Pride.
That is interesting.
How moment lasts forever?
How can a story never dies?
We must hold on love
Not easy, but we try
Sometimes we get
caught happiness
Somehow, place and
time stood still
Love lives in our
hearts and will always
Belle, can you give me...
thanks.
l also need... no, no.
No.
Actually this.
- You think it's a little weird?
- Strange?
Daughter's strange. Where
did you have the idea?
People are talking.
This small village.
Small mind also.
But smaller also means secure.
Even back in Paris a girl
like you is very great.
You're different.
People mocked him.
Until they imitate.
Please tell one
another about it.
Your mother without fear.
Without fear.
So what can l bring
to the market?
Rose. As in painting.
- You asked every year.
-And every year you bring him.
l'll bring you more.
l promise to you.
- Bye, Dad. - Bye, honey.
Come on, Phillip.
- You know the way.
- See you tomorrow.
Good. Tomorrow with roses.
Take care of yourself.
What is he doing?
Laundry.
Come on, come on.
Blue Bird
that fly away.
- lt was incredible.
- What are you doing?
Teach a woman to read.
ls that not enough?
We have to do something.
You're incredible
creatures ever seen.
Nobody had ever seen.
But at least l know.
May l remind you about the time?
- What is wrong?
- There are women who need help.
Time to be a hero.
l'm not done with you.
l also.
Belle, l heard you had a problem
with the school principal.
May l give you a little advice?
- Do not ever trust him.
- What l want is to teach children to read.
The only children who should
you care about is yourself.
Yourself.
- l'm not ready to have children.
- Maybe you have not met the right guy.
No, Gaston. l've met them all.
Maybe you should
take another look.
- Some of us changed.
- Gaston, we will never be happy.
- Nobody can change that much.
- Oh, Belle.
You know what happens
when his father died?
They beg.
This is our world, Belle.
People like us are not
going to be better.
l may be a simple girl,
l'm not simple
l'm not going to marry Gaston.
Forgive me.
Can you imagine me to
be the man's wife bore
Mrs. Gaston
Can you see it?
his wife
No, sir! Not me!
l guarantee it
l want more out of life
l want adventure somewhere
l want it
And for once it might be great
Having someone who understands
l wanted it than they want
Very beautiful. l wish l
could have known you.
You know we are where?
Because l do not know.
All right, all right, Phillip.
We can pass here.
Come on. To the right.
There he is.
One road was closed,
others open.
OK.
Slowly.
Be careful slippery.
Come on.
Ay, Phillip!
Phillip!
Come on, kid!
Oh, Phillip you saved my life.
Nice.
They eat dinner elsewhere.
See.
Water. You're safe my friend.
l will honor...
as host.
lt may...
Hello. thanks.
thanks.
Hello.
l'm sorry to disturb travelers
seeking shelter from the storm.
Sorry to bother you.
There are people at home?
He must get lost in the woods.
Excuse me.
Beautiful.
Extraordinary.
- Humans today.
- He was talking about me.
Oops.
Wherever you're hiding
l just want to warm
themselves in the fireplace.
Much better.
thanks.
l should not be moved
because it was creepy.
Sorry.
lt is okay.
l can not thank you enough
for your generosity
l...
Come on. Go.
Wait! Wait.
You forget the roses.
Are here?
There is a rose.
This.
Where is Papa?
Take me to him.
See. Beautiful girl.
Yes, l could see the girl.
- Except for the hands and eyes.
- Maybe he can break the curse.
Who's talking?
Who is there?
Papa, is that you?
How did you find me?
Your hands are cold.
We need to go home.
He lives.
Now go before he found you!
Who?
Who is there?
Who are you?!
Who are you?
l came to pick up my father.
Your father is a thief.
Liar!
- He stole a rose.
- l asked her roses.
Law l'm not him.
No. That forever.
That's what happened here
when you pick flowers.
A life sentence for the roses?
l received the curse
of a lifetime.
- Now you still want to replace your father?
- Yes.
- Select - l will not let you do it. l
lost my mother is not with you, too.
Now go away.
All right, Dad, l'm gone.
l need more time with him.
You're so coldhearted. You
did not let me say goodbye.
Give it time.
lf it is closed, it
will not open again.
- l should be with. - No.
lt is okay.
Now go away.
Continue your life
and forget me.
Forget you? All
l've got for you.
l love you, Belle.
Do not be afraid.
l love you too, Dad.
l am not afraid.
And l'm going to run
away, l promise.
What? What?
You take his place.
- He's my father.
- He was stupid.
And you, too.
Belle.
Father! Do not hurt him!
- Dad! - Belle.
Belle! l will be back!
l promise!
Sorry l disturb, Miss.
But l have come to escort
you to your room a new one.
My room?
- But l thought...
- Oh, what? Words...
''Once the door is closed,
it will not open again.''
l know he's overrated.
Hello.
Oh, you're very strong.
lt's a good quality.
Creature are you?
- l Lumiere. -And...
- You can talk.
- Of course he can talk.
That's all he did.
Now, Lumiere. As head
of the furniture,
l ask you to immediately
prepare the food.
You want to be for the rest of your
life, Cogsworth? Humans, or hours?
Ready, Miss? Trust me.
- You do not be surprised.
- l was surprised.
- l'm talking to the candle.
- l sconce.
lt's French. Lumiere ready to
serve, the palace is now yours.
- So you can be anywhere.
- Except to the west wing.
And we did not have it.
Why? What was in the West Wing?
- Oh, nothing. - There is no.
- Warehouse. - Warehouse.
- That is all. - That is all.
Yes, that's it. Please pass
here to go to the east wing.
And l want to say,
only one wing.
Carefully step.
Welcome to your room a new one.
lt's simple, but comfortable.
lt's beautiful.
But of course, the hosts want you
to get the best room in the palace.
Gosh, we're waiting for guests.
Nice to meet you, Miss.
Do not worry, l'll clean
up this place quickly.
Dangerous plan.
l will risk all to kiss
you again, Plumette.
Do not love. l've
dikewakan by you.
- We have to be strong.
- How can l be strong,
when you made me very weak.
Everything here alive?
Hello. What is your name?
lt was only a hairbrush.
Do not be afraid.
lt's just a closet.
Meet, Madame Garderobe.
-A great singer.
- When he realized.
Good morning. My sleep soundly.
Stay with us, ma'am. We bring
someone to your makeup.
Finally, a woman.
Good eyes. The
face of the proud.
The perfect canvas. Nice!
l'll swatch you are
fit for a princess.
- Oh, not a princess.
- Nonsense.
Now, let's see what l
have in my drawer.
Embarrassing.
Froufrou, help the mother.
Good, l like it. Dah.
Froufrou, send my
love to the Maestro.
lmagine LeFou. Comfortable home.
Hurry last roasted in the fire.
Our children are running
around, while my wife...
Massaging my feet were tired.
Said Belle...
''l'll never marry you, Gaston.''
You know, there are other girls.
Great hunter does not spend
his time with the rabbits.
# Gosh, l was disturbed
to see you, Gaston #
# lt looks very sad #
#All the men here want
to be like you, Gaston! #
# Even to receive pukulanmu #
# There are no men in this
town are wonderful as you #
#You're like everyone #
# Everyone was amazed
and inspired by you #
#And it is not
difficult to know why #
# No one is as smart as Gaston #
# Nobody soon as gaston ## There's
nothing as strong neck Gaston #
# Nobody dashing in this city #
#A perfect example #
#You can ask Tom,
Dick, or Stanley #
#And they'll tell you they
prefer parties where #
#Who is playing... #
Archery as Gaston ###Who
played a heart like Gaston #
#Who is part of his
body like Gaston? #
#As a person, yes,
l'm intimidating! #
# Gaston great guy! #
# l need consolation... #
# Thanks LeFou ## Nothing
is embraced like #
- Exaggerating? - Yes.
# Nobody fights like Gaston #
# Turn off the wax like Gaston #
ln wrestling nobody
bites like Gaston #
#When l hunt l slipped
with my arrow #
#And all the animals fear #
# First, l shoot her ##
Then l shot from behind #
# lt is fair ## l do not care #
# Nobody hit like Gaston ##
Nothing is as smart as Gaston #
# ln a spitting match,
nobody spits like Gaston #
# l'm very good at spitting #
- # 10 points for Gaston! #
- Thank you.
#When l was young l
ate four dozen eggs #
# S3tiap morning to help large #
#And now that l'm big l
eat five dozen eggs #
# So l'm at the ship #
- #Who has a brain...
# - #As Gaston? #
- # Entertain... #
- #As Gaston? #
# Or make songs like Gaston? #
# l use antlers in
all dekorasiku #
# Tell me again #
#Who true man among men? #
#Who really successful? You do not know?
You can not guess? #
# Tanya fans and friends #
# Only one person in
town who can all #
#And the name G-A-S... T... #
# l'm sure there
is a ''T'' another #
# l just realized l
was illiterate #
#And actually l never
say it out loud before #
# Gaston! #
LeFou Oh, you're the best.
Why is not there a girl
who is close to you?
They told me that l was so dependent.
But l do not understand.
Please!
Komohon, anyone. Anyone.
- You have to help me. - Why?
You have to help me.
lt's about Belle.
lt's about Belle. He was jailed.
- Who is detained?
- Ugly creature.
Ugly horrible creatures great.
My daughter lives in danger,
why are you laughing?
This is not ajoke.
The palace was
hidden in the woods.
- There have been winter.
- Winter in June?
- Crazy old Maurice.
- Listen to me!
Ugly creature really exists.
You understand?
No one wants to help me?
l will help you, Maurice.
You want?
All.
Stop mocking this man.
Thank you, Captain.
Do not thank me, Maurice.
Show us the way to being ugly.
Come on.
- Mom, there's a girl in the palace.
- Yes, Chip.
- You already know.
- He likes what tea?
Herbal, oolong, camomile.
- l'm too excited. - Stop.
- lt will break your hand.
-Already, Ny. Potts.
- Lumiere!
- Calm down, let me do the talking.
- You make him dinner.
- We thought you wanted company.
Sir, l want to tell you,
if l had nothing to do in
prepare dinner.
Designing a dress for her, gave
him a room in the east wing.
- You gave him the room? - No.
- He gave him room. - Correct.
But this girl who can
break the spell,
and perhaps you could start by using
the dinner to make him fascinated.
- Good thinking, Cogsworth.
- What?
That's the most ridiculous
idea l've ever heard.
- Make fascinated prisoners.
- But you have to try, sir.
With each day that
passes, we are changing.
He's a thief.
- Do you think it has to what?
- You can not judge people
by their father, right?
You're going to have dinner with me.
lt was not a request.
Gently, sir. The
girl lost her father
and freedom in one day.
Yes, maybe now she was
frightened once inside.
Correct.
- Hold on. - See? There he is.
Now, remember. Gentle.
- Kind-hearted. - Enchanting.
-And sweet.
-And when he opened the door,
give him a smile.
Come on, show me that smile.
Forget it.
You want to have dinner with me?
You're holding me, and now you
want to have dinner with me?
- You are crazy? - He is angry.
Gosh.
- l told you to have dinner with me!
-And l say no!
Gosh, what time? What happened?
l'd better starve
than l eat with you.
Please! Up to you!
lf he does not eat with
me, so he did not eat!
Stupid!
He's gone?
l'm late? Unfortunately, this time
l'm really going to scold him.
- Sir, you're back. - What?
- You're so funny. - Gotcha.
Show me the girl.
- One more petals fall.
- Lumiere.
l grow three feathers again. And
l just pull it out yesterday.
l know, dear.
Every day l was
getting into metal.
Oh no. lt happened again.
- Sorry. - Everything is quiet.
We still have time.
Mother, what l'm going
to be a child again?
Yes, Chip. You will enjoy
a day in the sun again.
Leave it to me.
- l told you to go.
- Do not worry dear.
lt Ny. Potts.
Oh, you look beautiful.
Seanng once knew you.
Oh, this is a long journey.
Let me prepare you
before you left.
l knew if tired after
the trip could be lost
after a cup of tea.
Slowly, Chip.
Nice to meet you.
Want to see me do the trick?
Chip.
You did a very brave thing
for your father, dear.
Yes, so in our opinion.
l'm worried about him.
He was never alone.
Calm down, dear. Everything
will change in the end.
You'll feel much
better after dinner.
But he said, ''lf he does not want to
eat with me, then he should not eat.''
People talk carelessly
when angry.
lt is up to us to not listen.
You coming, dear?
They came. Semuanay
last inspection.
- Fast. - Come on.
lf the host know you
made the girl's food,
- She'll blame me.
- l'll make sure of it.
But what you see? l
tell this girl man.
They should fall in love that we
return to a human being again,
and how they can fall in love
if she stays in her room?
- Hey, you there is still dirt.
- Excuse me.
- You know that girl would not love him.
Hours broken right twice
a day, my friend.
But this is not the time.
Come on.
Now it's time to shine!
Hey, l could not feel,
but l know this is bad.
Move over, you're bothering me.
- Fast. - Come on.
- Slowly. - Of course.
But what is dinner
without music?
- Music?
- Maestro Cadenza, are you ready?
l have not been performed.
l do not even remember how.
- Cavities others.
- Maestro, teeth above.
lncreasingly difficult
to remain conscious.
He's relying on you to help
us to break this curse.
Then l'll play
despite a toothache.
Maestro, play some
soothing music.
Quiet music. Of course.
There are other requests that
you want of my artistic?
- No, that's all.
- There you are, dear.
Nona.
We welcome you with great pride and
pleasure to welcome you this evening.
And now, we invite you to relax.
Let us take a seat.
While the dining room
proudly presents...
Your dinner.
# Be our guest! #
# Be our guest! ##
Test the service our #
# Tie a napkin around
your neck, dear #
#And we'll arrange the rest #
# Soups, hot appetizers #
#We only want to serve #
# Try the gray, it was tasty #
# Do not believe me? ##
Ratings plate-plate #
# They can sing,
they can dance #
#After all, Miss,
this is France #
#And a dinner
here is the best #
# Come on, open menumu ## See
at a glance and you'll be #
# Be our guest, yes, our guests.
Be our guest #
# ''Beef ragout'',
''Cheese souffle'' #
# Pies and puddings
were all there #
#We will prepare
and serve well #
#A culinary cabaret! #
#You're alone and afraid ###
# But jamuannya ready #
# Nothing sad or complain ##While
entertaining dining furniture #
#We tell jokes! #
# l do the trick #
#With friends-my candle wax! #
#And everything with a sense of
perfect ##You can be sure #
# Come lift your glass #
#You've won a free ticket #
To be our guest ##
# lf you stress #
#We recommend a good dinner #
# Be our guest, be our
guest Be our guest ###
# Life is very debilitating #
# To the waiter who
did not serve #
# He's not himself
without a soul to wait #
#Ah, in moments of
fun where our handy #
True, Cogsworth?
# Suddenly an enjoyable
day was lost #
#We've rusted too long #
# Need more than to clean dust #
# Before the exercise, the opportunity
to use our capabilities #
# More often we lazing
in the palace #
# Flabby, fat and lazy #
#You're lazy to walk #
# There is a guest,
there is a guest #
# Gosh, we will be blessed #
#Wine has been poured,
and thank God #
# l have prepared a napkin #
#With dessert, she wants tea #
#And l do not mind, my dear #
#While the cups
clean themselves #
# l'll be bubbling, l'll cook #
# l will be Hangan, then heat #
# Gosh! That stain? #
# Clean up! We want
to impress guests! #
#We have much to do #
#You want one or two of sugar?
## For you, our guest! #
# He is our guest! #
# Be our guest! ## Our
command is your request #
# For a long time we did not
get a ##And we're obsessed #
###With your food with
your comfortability #
# That's right,
our aim airport #
#While the candle
is still burning #
# Let us help you, we will
continue to berinar #
# Eat for food #
# One by one #
# Until you shout,
''Enough, l'm full!'' #
# Then we'll sing till you
sleep while you're digesting #
# Tonight you lift your foot #
# But now let's eat #
# Be our guest! #
# Please, be our guests! #
Pudding?
Why are you nice to me?
Of course you're
trapped here like me.
You never want to go?
Tuan was not as bad as it looks.
Somewhere, in his soul,
he was a Pengeran.
Someone is waiting
to be unleashed.
Lumiere mentions something
about the west wing.
Forget it. Go to sleep, dear.
- Good night. - Good night.
Directly to the room.
What are you doing? What
did you do on a rose?
- There is no.
- You do not realize what can you do?
You can harm us all!
Go away from here!
Go!
- Checkmate. Again. - Wait.
- You cheated again.
- Miss, what are you doing?
- Go away from here. - Stop!
Do not, froufrou.
- Froufrou, stop him.
- Catch him!
Come on!
- Do not, froufrou.
- Do not get out.
- Do not! Dog silly.
- Naughty dog, bad dog!
Do not!
- Please do not go! That is dangerous!
- Yikes!
You have to help.
You have to stand.
l'm sure this is the way.
There are a lot of wolves.
That means we're getting
close to the palace.
Simply, we have to go back.
Stop! There he is!
There he is. That tree.
l am sure.
The time it collapsed
due to lightning.
But now the tree...
Stand back again because...
Magic, or the other.
Do you want to marry
into this family?
So it means, istanya toward...
No.
That is...
That way. Certainly.
lt's enough you play us.
Where is Belle?
- The ugly kidnapped her...
- The creature was not real.
Or cup speak. Or magic.
What was real was the wolves,
frostbite and starvation.
lnhale, Gaston.
Why do not we just go
back to the village?
l'm sure Belle was cooking
a delicious evening meal.
Why are you offering to help us?
Because he was not my
biological daughter!
Let us go home.
Belle was not at home.
He shared...
Say it again,
- Then l'll make you a wolf food!
- Gaston!
Stop!
Think about things that are fun.
Remember back during the war.
lmagine about the explosion...
-... The women widows. - Widow.
Correct. lmagine.
Correct.
Maurice.
Please forgive me.
That's no way to talk to the
prospective father-in-law, is not it?
Father-in-law?
You'll never marry my daughter.
l might have guessed it.
lf Maurice does not approve it,
it means he becomes penghalangku.
Once the wolf is finished with her,
Belle will not have anyone but me.
l know we're running
out of options,
but maybe you want to think
about how a little more...
-... Human? - You coming?
Sick.
lf you can be quiet, it
will not be too sore.
lf you did not run,
this will not happen.
lf you do not scare me,
l'm not going to run.
You should not go
to the East wing!
You're supposed to learn
to control his anger!
You should rest.
- Thank you.
- We are very grateful.
- Why are you so concerned about her?
- We have maintained for a long time.
He cursed you, even though
you are not doing anything.
You are right.
When Mr. losing his mother,
and when the father grabbed the
child a sweet and innocent,
change it to be like his father,
we can only dwell alone.
Let him sleep.
SONG: Days ln The Sun #
days when life begins #
# Not until my day ends #
#What l'm going to leave #
#What l will bow again ## By
the rhythm of the song dear #
#What you'll always be #
# Can not my flailing #
# The days that #
# l'm willing to give
anything to be back again #
Oh no.
# Changing everything
and restore shine #
# l sing about the pain
of a difficult day #
# Magic ensnare us ## l
sing for a miracle tonight #
# ln the midst of this sadness #
# Can love and hope to survive #
# For l was naive and unsure #
# But now l'm wiser
and wondered #
# Days ago ## l can not
go back to my childhood #
# Precious days it is not immortal #
#Yang realized because my father #
# l feel a change #
Hugging me tighter ### l
feel stronger but shackled #
#A sunny day will return ##We
have to believe Like the love #
#Wonderful days it
will come back #
What happens when the
last petals fall?
Tuan will be ugly forever.
-And we'll be... - antiques.
- Knick knacks.
- The furniture is rarely used.
Trash. We become garbage.
l want to help you.
There must be a way
to break the curse.
There is one way.
You do not have to
think about it.
We choose our options, and we
must bear the consequences.
Drink.
Termia love, Agathe.
Love can change a person's view.
Love looks way of thinking
is not the appearance.
And because it was the angel
of love blinded his eyes.
You know Shakespeare.
My education is quite high.
Romeo and Juliet is my favorite.
l'm not surprised.
- Sorry?
- She let her heart melt...
...and...
You'd better read another.
Like what?
You can start reading
all that is here.
You're going to do it?
Awesome.
Yes, l think so.
lf you really like it,
then all of it is yours.
Did you read all these books?
Not all.
Some of them speak Greek.
Are you kidding me?
Can you kidding me right now?
Maybe.
The air is so blue
and clear and cold.
Frozen in thin sheets.
Rolled stems and twigs
Each foliage in a blanket by...
...glass.
l feel like l've seen this.
What else?
But in the silence...
... He heard whispers
from all asleep.
Face. Look at me.
Come and wake me up.
Because l'll always be here.
SONG: SOMETHlNG THERE #
There is a sweet and good #
# But he was nasty and rude #
# Now he is changing
and unsure #
# l wonder why l did
not realize before #
# He glanced over
here l think l see #
#When the touch he does not
tremble viewed cakarku #
### Ku may not disregard it #
# But he had never seen
me like that before #
# New and makes me uneasy #
#Who would have thought
this could happen? #
# True, he is not a
handsome prince #
# But there was something about
him that l did not realize #
Who would have thought
### Bless my soul #
#Who would have thought #
#Who would have thought they
would unite with itself #
lt is strange ###We see #
#We pay attention
to a few days away #
# There may be something
that was not there #
there that was not there #
What, Mom?
# There may be something
there that was not there #
What is that? What is
going on over there?
l'll let you know
when you've grown.
OK. l've grown up.
Oh, Chip.
You're a grown-up.
- What are you reading?
- lt is nothing.
l guess ''Lancelot.''
Actually, ''King Arthur and the
Knights of the Roundtable.''
Nonetheless,
- The reading romance. - OK.
l have to thank you
for saving my life.
l have to thank you because it
has been rescued from the wolf.
- You know how to enjoy life.
- Yes.
When l walked into the
room and laughing.
l also.
The villagers told
me a strange girl.
l do not know they are
praising or insulting.
Sorry.
Your village does not seem good.
l felt lonely as does kastilmu.
Why do not we run away together?
lt was a gift from the witch.
Books that can help you escape.
Awesome.
This game is the most violent.
Almost like a curse.
This world has no place
for creatures like me.
But you can.
Think of a place
you want to visit.
Discover in mind.
Feel in your heart.
Where is this?
Paris.
Oh, l remember Paris.
What do you want to see first?
Rotterdam. Champs-Elysees.
No? Too many tourists?
Smaller than l imagined.
SONG: How Does a Moment Last Forever
# This is my childhood Paris #
Once this is my
life boundary ##
#At the top of a rickety
and dusty attic is #
#Where an artist
mencinitai wife #
# Easy to remember #
# Difficult to forget #
Knowing the Paris
of my childhood ##
# Has gone #
What happened to your mother?
He never told me.
l never dared to ask.
Mask doctor.
We have to go now.
- Drink this.
- lt would kill him, too.
Sorry to call your
father a thief.
Let us go home.
lt sucks.
At least we were not in the trees
and surrounded by a pack of wolves.
You know not too
late to go back.
Every time l close my eyes,
l imagined when l was stranded,
and when l opened my eyes...
Maurice.
Gaston. You're trying
to kill Maurice?
Maurice. Fortunately.
l've been looking for five days.
You're trying to kill me. You
left me with a herd of wolves.
Wolf?
l understand, if
you're imagining,
but not if you accusing me of
deliberately want to kill you.
Maurice, do you have proof?
- Tanya Agathe, he saved me.
-Agathe?
You accuse based on
statements from an old woman?
Sorry, Agathe.
Mr. LeFou. He was there.
She saw everything.
l? You are right.
Do not joke.
LeFou.
Dear friend of mine.
ls it me, the most loyal friend,
tried to kill the father of
a woman who l really love?
That question is
quite difficult.
But the answer is no.
He did not try to kill Maurice.
Basic you...
Maurice.
l hate to say this, but you'll endanger
yourself and the people around you.
That is why Belle run.
You need help.
A place to take a
load off your mind.
Everything will be alright.
l saw her in the
ballroom and said,
''l will make all look beautiful
and tonight we'll dance.''
l did not think he
would say ''yes.''
- What l think? - No, sir.
lt was perfect.
Petals roses are only four,
it means to be tonight.
You must tell your
feelings to her.
l feel stupid.
- He might not love me.
- Do not be discouraged.
He is.
Stop saying that.
- No way we are united.
- You care about him, is not it?
Then, with romantic
music and candles...
True, and when the
time is right...
How could l know?
Do not worry, sir.
You'll be fine.
Do not be too nervous and
say you feel about Belle.
Because if not, l swear you
will drink cold tea forever.
- ln the dark. - Full dust.
Dark and very dusty.
Starting from his
hair, comb his hair.
l'll take care of her nails.
l'll brush her teeth.
Rub her nails. Polishing horns.
Close your eyes.
And this is the last.
Voila!
OK. l can clean up this.
Oh, beautiful.
But something is missing.
Oh, right.
Last touch.
SONG: Beauty and the Beast
story of the ancient ##
#What is the real #
### But not friends
fall in love #
#Without the suspect #
# Only a few changes #
### Both Little change
slightly scared #
# Both were not ready #
# The beauty and the Beast #
Always the same ##
#Always surprising #
# Same as previous #
#Always confident #
#As the sun always rises #
# The story of the ancient #
# The music is old-fashioned #
# Fun painful and strange #
# Be aware you can change #
# Be aware that you're wrong #
#As Like the sun #
The rises in the East ###
The story of the ancient #
# Rhythms ancient song #
# The beauty and the Beast #
### The story is ancient
ancient rhythm of the song #
# The beauty and the Beast #
After all this time,
l almost forgot the taste.
This seems stupid.
For such a creature l hope...
... One day it will
get your attention.
- l do not know. - Really?
Do you think you
will be happy here?
Whether a person can be
happy without freedom?
My father taught
me how to dance.
l often stepped on his foot.
You must miss him.
Very.
You want to see him?
l want to see my father.
Father!
What did they do to him?
He is in danger!
Then you have to get there.
What are you saying?
You've got to save.
You need to hurry.
Bring it.
So you have a way to see me.
thanks.
Oh, my God.
Sir, l've figured everything
would run smoothly.
True love always wins.
l let it go.
What?
Sir, why did you do it?
l must.
- But why?
- Because he loves her.
- So why do we not change?
- Because Belle does not love him.
- Now it's too late.
- But he might come back.
No.
l released him.
l hope l can do the
same thing to you.
Go.
Our time is running out.
Go on, my love.
l who have myself.
l am the master of my faith.
l never needed
anybody in my life.
l learned today.
l'll never feel the pain.
l closed my eyes, but
he's still there.
More than me.
Now l know you never feel it.
Although he escaped.
He kept torturing me, coming to hurt
me, menggerakanku, come against me.
Waiting for my loneliness.
Waiting at the end
of the open door.
l feel myself to appear
in front of him.
And along with me forever more.
l'm ready to fight
a crazy court.
l hit the light is blurred.
He is already in reach.
He was never far outside.
And l knew he would
never see me.
Although he felt guilt.
He's still inside me. He
taught everything l do.
Waiting loneliness, waiting
at the end of the open door.
l walked right in front of him.
And it perbicaraan in
a very long night.
l think it could be waiting
here forever more...
Come on.
Exempt queen, please.
He was in the hospital.
Not in silence.
Do not you see? You deserve
to be in a mental hospital?
You would not last a week.
Submit your daughter to me,
and l'll set you free.
Will never.
Stop.
- Pa. - Oh, boy.
- l thought l lost you.
- Let her go.
Please release him.
We can not do that Miss Potts,
we'll take care of it properly.
My father was not crazy.
Gaston. Tell him.
You know how l am
loyal to your family,
but your father made
amazing claims.
That's right Bell.
He discusses about a
monster in the palace.
l just got out of the palace,
and there was a monster.
You can say anything to release,
words are difficult to prove.
You want proof?
Show me the monster that to me!
That's the proof.
lt's unbelievable.
See the monster.
Look at this.
Here.
Gosh. Do not be afraid.
She is gentle, and kind.
lt smelled like a monster.
lf l do not know right or bad.
He remains concerned him.
He was not a monster, Gaston!
You're the monster.
Monster was not going
to hurt anyone.
Hearts have been infected with dark
magic, l've never seen in my life.
This rift in our great justice.
Yes! Do something!
We're not going to run
to win from monsters.
Catch him also.
No!
- Get him! - No!
You're not going to get
away with this, Gaston.
Gaston.
Why fat? You want to be next?
That's what l said.
Alert, this village will be
damned if we do not stop it.
- Yes! - We kill that monster!
Kill the monster! Kill him!
lt's safe here until he
comes at night to scare us.
With sacrifice. l was not
appetizing at the monsters.
He will attack our village,
do not let him free.
lt is now time for
action, everything.
Now it's time to follow.
He disguised himself and came out of the
darkness, From the shadow of a nightmare.
And it was most encouraging.
Save them.
He would sneak into the palace, and
did something terrible inside.
He's a monster, he's got fangs.
Sharp.
Large claw, claw
killer for a party
Hear him roar, see the foam! But we
did not get home before he died!
Until he's dead!
Kill the monster!
Turn obormu, Saddle your horse.
Put your courage in place.
Call it war, call it a threat.
You can bet they will all
follow for at a time like this,
they will carry out my orders.
There's a monster.
Running clay, no question.
But l'm worried that the
wrong monster released.
Take ajourney! Calculate!
Hold your sword! Hold thine!
Praise the Lord
and here we come!
Show me the palace.
At least they finally
learn to love.
ln other words, they
do not have love.
lt's the first time for
me l was being rude.
you hear that? ls it painful?
ls he back?
l told you.
Lots of infidels.
We fight them.
This is it.
That is true love.
Prepare mortar, and step aside.
There is a place in the back,
we had to line up in battle.
and not afraid of the
dangers that come.
There were black in this song,
We will give this song.
We came to fight.
Come on, we need help.
- We must help the monster.
How did you get out of here?
He let me go.
He released me to see you.
l do not understand.
What are you?
He brought me there.
l know what happened
to my mother.
Then you know why l
have to keep it secret?
l had to protect you, l should
always protect my daughter.
Possible excessive.
l understand.
Will you help me now?
This is dangerous.
Yes.
l could try to damage the lock.
The key is to me, this.
Padlock.
You need something sharp.
Like that.
Perfect.
- l'm really sorry to bother
you, - she did not return.
No, they were behind the door.
lt is okay. Let them enter.
Kill the monster!
- lt did not work. - l know.
Kill that monster.
Do not you realize that
this house may be hunted?
Do not let yourself uneasy.
This place looks familiar. l
had never been here before.
Oh, hello. You
must teacup spoke.
And you must be his mother.
The mother of his best friends?
Attack!
Gaston!
Gaston.
- Please. - So devoted friend...
Yourself.
That helps you.
Sorry.
l'm sure it's yours?
He is so strong.
Do you have children?
Not until we get you.
Good son. Fool
intruders arrived.
No. Not now.
Go!
Those soldiers who called the
shots book, great warrior.
Time's up.
Quiet.
Come here little boy.
l moved here and there.
Young boys here.
Beautiful.
Go! They are free.
They are free.
go after him! Flush
with hot water.
Please dont.
Ma!
thanks.
Semprotanku.
Lost?
l was in the Gaston, We're in
a bad place at the moment.
You're too good for him.
Preparing to meet him.
- Humans are sweet.
- Destroy the piano.
l'm stronger.
Go! l'm coming, my love. This is it.
Miss fighter, singing.
Take this.
Watch your step.
Go! Go!
Why are you leaving?
- We're safe. - On the contrary.
l Gaston.
Belle sent me.
You fell in love with her?
Do you honestly think he wants?
No.
Where is he?
When we returned to the
village, you will marry me
And then he will die.
- Let her go.
You.
Run.
l tell you, monster.
No!
Back!
l tried to stop them.
Stay there. l come.
Drop him.
Gaston! No!
Remove.
Please, l'll do everything.
Release me, monster.
l'm not a monster.
Go!
Exit.
Do not! Too far.
Beast!
- You're back.
- Of course l'm back.
l'll never leave you again.
lt's time for me to go.
We're together now.
You'll be fine.
This is the last time
for me to see you.
Please dont.
Back.
We managed to Plumete.
Victory is ours.
Everything is ours.
Plumete.
Oh, my dear, Plumete.
- Oh.
- Maestro, you're very brave.
Goodbye my love.
Armole, no. Do not leave me.
Tea! Tea! You see Chip?
Enarnof.
Where is my little son?
Mama.
Mama!
- l can not talk.
- lt's okay hour box.
An hour, unable to move.
The honor is mine.
Come back.
Do not leave me.
l love you.
Gosh.
You are okay?
Come here. We beat the clock.
Can be.
Plumete.
Oh.
Say that again.
Boy, look at you. You
become a child again.
l could smell You smell, dear.
You smell very fragrant.
Gosh, here.
All turned to humans.
You are there.
Small piano.
You changed.
- Henry. - Henry?
- Henry? - Oh, l'm so lonely.
To become an hour.
Lumieas.
See.
Oh, prince.
- Hello, old friend.
- Nice to meet you.
- You look like a nanny?
- No, she was the queen.
She was the queen.
The oldest fairy tales.
The oldest song rhyme.
Bitter-sweet and strange.
Knowing you can change.
Studying're wrong, oh.
Papa.
Hunger turned into a party.
Nature shows the way.
Nothing could be delivered.
Beauty and the Monster.
- What is that?
- How are you feeling slightly grow?
l do not know.
Certain as the sun.
Rises in the east.
The oldest fairy tales,
poems are the oldest song.
Beauty and the Monster.
The oldest fairy tales.
The oldest song rhyme.
Beauty and the Monster.