Towels.
Lord Miraz?
You have a son.
The heavens have blessed us.
You know your orders.
General Glozelle?
Yes, my lord.
Five more minutes.
Won't be watching
the stars tonight, my prince.
Come. We must hurry.
- Professor, what's going on?
- Your aunt has given birth...
...to a son.
Come.
You must make for the woods.
- The woods?
- They won't follow you there.
It has taken me
many years to find this.
Do not use it except
at your greatest need.
Will I ever see you again?
I dearly hope so, my prince.
There is so much more
I meant to tell you.
Everything you know
is about to change.
Close the drawbridge!
Now, go.
- Halt!
A son! A son!
Lady Prunaprismia has this night
given Lord Miraz a son!
Which of you superstitious old women
wants to spend the night in a cell?
He's seen us.
Take care of him.
No!
- Mind yourself, love.
- I'm sorry.
Watch where you're going!
Wait for me!
You go to Saint Finbar's?
That's right.
I go to Hendon House.
Across the road.
I've seen you...
...sitting by yourself.
Yes, well, I prefer to be left alone.
Me, too.
What's your name?
- Phyllis.
- Susan!
You'd better come quickly.
Paper here!
Get your daily paper!
Edmund!
Go on! Kick him in the face!
Stop it. Break it up.
That's enough. Come on.
That's it. Get up.
Act your age!
- You're welcome.
- I had it sorted.
What was it this time?
- He bumped me.
- So you hit him?
No. After he bumped me,
they tried to make me apologize.
- That's when I hit him.
- Really?
- Is it that hard just to walk away?
- I shouldn't have to.
I mean, don't you ever get tired
of being treated like a kid?
We are kids.
Well, I wasn't always.
It's been a year.
How long does he expect us to wait?
I think it's time to accept
that we live here.
It's no use pretending any different.
Oh, no.
- Pretend you're talking to me.
- We are talking to you.
- Quiet, Lu.
- Something pinched me!
- Stop pulling!
- Not touching you.
Look, would all of you just...
What is that?
- It feels like magic.
- Everyone hold hands.
- I'm not holding your hand!
- Just...
Shame you're not as quick as me, Ed!
Last one in's a rotten egg.
Watch out!
Here it comes!
Wait a minute!
Come on, Susan. Hurry up!
Come on, it's lovely.
Edmund.
Ed? Ed!
- What is it?
- Where do you suppose we are?
Well, where do you think?
Well, I don't remember
any ruins in Narnia.
Wonder who lived here.
I think we did.
Hey, that's mine.
- From my chess set.
- Which chess set?
I didn't exactly have a solid gold
chess set in Finchley, did I?
Can't be.
- Don't you see?
- What?
Imagine walls.
And columns, there.
And a glass roof.
Cair Paravel.
Wait. Wait, my lord.
It is not what you think.
Then what is it?
We're not exactly sure.
Impossible.
I warned this council when it
put its trust in Lord Miraz...
...there would be consequences.
- No.
We can't accuse
the Lord Protector without proof.
How long are we going
to hide behind that excuse?
Until every chair
in this chamber is empty?
Lords of the council,
my apologies for being late.
I wasn't aware we were in session.
No doubt you were otherwise occupied.
My lord?
Ever since the death
of Caspian the ninth,
you've behaved
as if you were king.
Now it seems that from behind his walls
even Prince Caspian has gone missing.
My deepest condolences, Lord Miraz.
Imagine, losing your nephew,
the rightful heir to the throne,
on the very night your wife
has blessed you with a son.
Thank you, Lord Sopespian.
Your compassion is a boon
in this troubled time.
I trust you can tell us how such
a tragedy could have occurred.
That is the most
disturbing news of all.
Our beloved Caspian was abducted...
...by Narnians.
You go too far, Miraz.
Expect us to stand by while you blame
such a blatant crime on fairy tales?
What?
We forget, my lords,
Narnia was once a savage land.
Fierce creatures roamed free.
Much of our forefathers' blood was shed
to exterminate this vermin.
Or so we thought.
But while we've been bickering
amongst ourselves...
...they've been breeding
like cockroaches under a rock!
Growing stronger. Watching us.
Waiting to strike!
And you wonder why we don't like you.
Well, I intend to strike back.
Even if I have to cut down
the entire forest,
I assure you,
I will find Prince Caspian
and finish what our ancestors began.
- Catapults.
- What?
This didn't just happen.
Cair Paravel was attacked.
Don't suppose you have
any matches, do you?
No, but...
...would this help?
You might have mentioned that
a bit sooner.
I can't believe it.
It's all still here.
I was so tall.
Well, you were older then.
As opposed to hundreds of years
later... when you're younger.
- What is it?
- My horn.
I must've left it on my saddle
the day we went back.
When Aslan bares his teeth,
winter meets its death.
When he shakes his mane...
...we shall have spring again.
Everyone we knew...
Mr. Tumnus and the Beavers...
...they're all gone.
I think it's time we found out
what's going on.
He won't stop staring.
So don't look.
Here's far enough.
Drop him!
Crows and crockery!
"Drop him"!
That's the best
you can come up with?
A simple "thank you" would suffice.
They were doing fine
drowning me without your help.
Maybe we should have let them.
Why were they trying
to kill you, anyway?
They're Telmarines.
That's what they do.
Telmarines? In Narnia?
Where have you been
for the last few hundred years?
It's a bit of a long story.
Oh, you've got to be kidding me.
You're it?
You're the kings and queens of old?
High King Peter, the Magnificent.
You probably could've
left off the last bit.
Probably.
You might be surprised.
You don't want to do that, boy.
Not me. Him.
Edmund!
You all right?
Beards and bedsteads!
Maybe that horn worked after all.
What horn?
This bread is so stale.
I'll just get him some soup.
He should be coming around soon.
I don't think
I hit him hard enough.
Nikabrik, he's just a boy.
He's a Telmarine, not some lost puppy.
You said you were gonna get rid of him.
No. I said I'd take care of him.
We can't kill him now.
I just bandaged his head.
It would be like murdering a guest.
How do you think his friends
are treating their guest?
Trumpkin knew what he was doing.
It's not the boy's fault.
Stop! Stop!
Hold it. No, no!
I told you we should have killed him
when we had the chance.
- You know why we can't.
- If we're taking a vote, I'm with him.
We can't let him go. He's seen us.
That's enough, Nikabrik!
Or do I have to sit on your head again?
And you. Look what you made me do.
I spent half the morning on that soup.
What are you?
You know, it's funny
that you would ask that.
You think people would know
a badger when they saw one.
No. No, I mean...
...you're Narnians.
You're supposed to be extinct.
Sorry to disappoint you.
Here you go. Still hot.
Since when did we open a boarding house
for Telmarine soldiers?
I'm not a soldier.
I am Prince Caspian. The tenth.
What are you doing here?
Running away.
My uncle has always wanted my throne.
I suppose I have only lived this long
because he did not have
an heir of his own.
- Well, that changes things.
- Yeah.
Means we don't have
to kill you ourselves.
You're right.
- Where are you going?
- My uncle won't stop until I am dead.
But you can't leave.
You're meant to save us.
Don't you know what this is?
You have quite a library, doctor.
Is there anything particular
you seek, my lord?
I think I've already found
what I'm looking for...
...in one of my soldiers!
What do you know
of Queen Susan's horn?
It was said to be magic.
Magic?
The Narnians believed it could summon
their kings and queens of old.
At least, such was the superstition.
And what does Caspian
know of this superstition?
My lord, you forbade me
from mentioning the old tales.
So I did.
I will say this. If Caspian
does know of the Deep Magic,
my lord would have
good reason to be nervous.
First our prince...
...now his tutor.
If the members of Miraz's
own house are not safe,
- are any of us?
- Lord Sopespian!
Those are dangerous words,
Lord Sopespian.
But these are
dangerous times, general.
One should choose his words
as carefully as he chooses his friends.
How long until the bridge is finished?
- Construction continues on schedule.
- That's not good enough.
I need my army across that river now.
May I suggest you contribute
some of your own men?
I've only so many at my disposal.
A fact you'd be wise to remember.
Go to Beruna.
Take as many troops as you need.
We must get to Caspian before they do.
"They," my lord?
It's time you learned your history.
They're so still.
They're trees. What'd you expect?
They used to dance.
Wasn't long after you left
that the Telmarines invaded.
Those who survived
retreated to the woods.
And the trees,
they retreated so deep into themselves
that they haven't been heard from since.
I don't understand.
How could Aslan have let this happen?
Aslan?
Thought he abandoned us
when you lot did.
We didn't mean to leave, you know.
Makes no difference now, does it?
Get us to the Narnians...
...and it will.
Hello, there.
It's all right. We're friends.
Don't move, Your Majesty.
Stay away from her!
Shoot, Susan! Shoot!
- Why wouldn't he stop?
- I suspect he was hungry.
Thanks.
He was wild.
I don't think he could talk at all.
Get treated like
a dumb animal long enough,
that's what you become.
You may find Narnia a more savage place
than you remember.
I can hear you.
I just think we should wait
for the kings and queens.
Fine! Go then! See if the others
will be as understanding!
Or maybe I'll come with you.
I want to see you
explain things to the minotaurs.
Minotaurs?
They're real?
And very bad-tempered.
- Yeah, not to mention big.
- Huge.
What about centaurs?
Do they still exist?
Well, the centaurs will
probably fight on your side.
But there's no telling
what the others will do.
What about Aslan?
How do you know so much about us?
- Stories.
- Wait a minute.
Your father told you
stories about Narnia?
No, my professor, he...
Listen, I'm sorry.
These are not the kind of questions
you should be asking.
- What is it?
- Human.
- Him?
- No. Them.
- There they are!
- Run!
Now!
- Oh, no.
- Wait. I'll go.
Take it. Go!
It's more important than I am.
Get him out of here.
Where are you?
Choose your last words
carefully, Telmarine.
You are a mouse.
I was hoping for something
a little more original.
Pick up your sword.
No, thanks.
Pick it up! I will not fight
an unarmed man.
Which is why I might live longer
if I choose not to cross blades
with you, noble mouse.
I said I would not fight you.
I didn't say I'd let you live!
Reepicheep!
- Stay your blade!
- Trufflehunter?
I trust you have a very good reason
for this untimely interruption.
- He doesn't. Go ahead.
- He's the one who blew the horn.
- What?
- Then let him bring it forward.
This is the reason we have gathered.
I don't remember this way.
That's the problem with girls.
You can't carry a map in your heads.
That's because our heads
have something in them.
I wish he'd just listen
to the D.L.F. in the first place.
- D.L. F?
- Dear Little Friend.
Oh, that's not at all
patronizing, is it?
I'm not lost.
No.
You're just going the wrong way.
You last saw Caspian
at the Shuddering Woods,
and the quickest way there
is to cross at the river Rush.
But unless I'm mistaken,
there's no crossing in these parts.
That explains it, then.
You're mistaken.
You see, over time, water erodes
the earth's soil, carving deeper...
Oh, shut up.
- Is there a way down?
- Yeah, falling.
Well, we weren't lost.
There's a ford near Beruna.
How do you feel about swimming?
I'd rather that than walking.
Aslan?
It's Aslan!
It's Aslan over there!
Don't you see? He's right...
...there.
Do you see him now?
I'm not crazy.
He was there.
He wanted us to follow him.
I'm sure there are any number
of lions in this wood.
- Just like that bear.
- I think I know Aslan when I see him.
Look, I'm not about
to jump off a cliff
after someone who doesn't exist.
The last time I didn't believe Lucy
I ended up looking pretty stupid.
Why wouldn't I have seen him?
Maybe you weren't looking.
I'm sorry, Lu.
Kill him!
- Telmarine!
- Liar!
Murderer!
All this horn proves is they've stolen
yet another thing from us!
- I didn't steal anything.
- Didn't steal anything?
Shall we list the things
the Telmarines have taken?
- Our homes!
- Our land!
- Our freedom!
- Our lives!
You stole Narnia!
You would hold me accountable
for all the crimes of my people?
Accountable...
...and punishable.
That is rich coming from you, dwarf.
Have you forgotten it was your people
who fought alongside the White Witch?
And I'd gladly do it again,
if it would rid us of these barbarians.
Then it's lucky that it is not
in your power to bring her back.
Or are you suggesting that we ask
this boy to go against Aslan now?
Some of you may have forgotten,
but we badgers remember well,
that Narnia was never right
except when a Son of Adam was king.
He's a Telmarine!
Why would we want him as our king?
Because I can help you.
- It's a trick!
- At least hear him out!
Beyond these woods, I'm a prince.
The Telmarine throne
is rightfully mine!
Help me claim it,
and I can bring peace between us.
It is true. The time is ripe.
I watch the skies,
for it is mine to watch
as it is yours to remember, badger.
Tarva, the lord of victory,
and Alambil, the lady of peace,
have come together
in the high heavens.
And now here,
a Son of Adam has come forth...
...to offer us back our freedom.
Is this possible? Do you really
think there could be peace?
Do you? I mean, really?
Two days ago, I didn't believe
in the existence of talking animals...
...or dwarves... or centaurs.
Yet here you are
in strength and numbers
that we Telmarines
could never have imagined.
Whether this horn is magic or not,
it brought us together.
And together,
we have a chance
to take back what is ours.
If you will lead us,
then my sons and I...
...offer you our swords.
And we offer you our lives,
unreservedly.
Miraz's army will not
be far behind us, sire.
If we are to be ready for them, we need
to hurry to find soldiers and weapons.
I'm sure they will be here soon.
These ones!
And these ones!
Timber!
- Get back!
- Watch your back!
Look out!
- Steady, steady!
- Timber!
Perhaps this wasn't the best way
to come after all.
So where exactly
do you think you saw Aslan?
I wish you'd all stop trying
to sound like grown-ups.
I don't think I saw him,
I did see him.
I am a grown-up.
It was right over...
Lucy!
...here.
Lucy, are you awake?
Why do you think I didn't see Aslan?
You believe me?
Well, we got across the gorge.
I don't know.
Maybe you didn't really want to.
You always knew we'd be
coming back here, didn't you?
I hoped so.
I finally just got used
to the idea of being in England.
But you're happy
to be here, aren't you?
While it lasts.
Lucy.
Aslan!
I've missed you so much!
- You've grown.
- Every year you grow...
...so shall I.
Where have you been?
Why haven't you come to help us?
Things never happen
the same way twice, dear one.
Susan! Wake up!
Certainly, Lu.
Whatever you like.
Wake up.
Aslan?
No, stop!
Prince Caspian?
Yes? And who are you?
Peter!
- High King Peter.
- I believe you called.
Well, yes, but...
I thought you'd be older.
If you like, we could
come back in a few years...
No. No, that's all right.
You're just...
You're not exactly what I expected.
Neither are you.
A common enemy unites
even the oldest of foes.
We have anxiously awaited
your return, my liege.
Our hearts and swords
are at your service.
Oh, my gosh, he is so cute.
- Who said that?
- Sorry.
Your Majesty, with the greatest respect,
I do believe "courageous,"
"courteous," or "chivalrous"
might more befit a knight of Narnia.
Well, at least we know some of you
can handle a blade.
Yes, indeed. And I have
recently put it to good use,
securing weapons for your army, sire.
Good. Because we're going
to need every sword we can get.
Well, then, you will probably
be wanting yours back.
How much did they take?
Enough weapons and armor
for two regiments.
But... there's more.
"You were right to fear the woods."
- "X"?
- Caspian. The tenth.
I apologize, my lord.
The blame is mine.
I know.
Tell me, general...
...how many men did you lose?
- None, my lord.
- None?
They came like ghosts,
in the dead of night. We never saw them.
Then how do you explain your injuries?
I asked...
...how many men were killed
during this bloody Narnian attack?
Of which you were a fortunate survivor.
General...
...how many?
Three.
I apologize, Lord Sopespian.
Caspian is not a victim
of this savage uprising.
He is the instigator.
It seems Narnia is in need
of a new king.
Well, it's good you have troops,
but we need some fortifications.
Somewhere to train.
So? What are they like?
Malcontents, complainers,
stubborn as mules in the morning.
So you like them, then.
Well enough.
It may not be what you are used to,
but it is defensible.
Peter. You may want to see this.
It's us.
What is this place?
You don't know?
He must know what he's doing.
I think it's up to us now.
It's only a matter of time.
Miraz's men and war machines
are on their way.
That means those same men
aren't protecting his castle.
What do you propose we do,
Your Majesty?
- We need to get ready for it.
- To start planning for...
Our only hope is to strike them
before they strike us.
Crazy. No one has taken that castle.
- There's always a first time.
- We'll have the element of surprise.
- But we have the advantage here!
- If we dig in,
we could probably
hold them off indefinitely.
I, for one, feel safer underground.
Look. I appreciate
what you've done here,
but this isn't a fortress. It's a tomb.
Yes. And if they're smart,
the Telmarines will just wait
and starve us out.
- We could collect nuts!
- Yes! And throw them at the Telmarines.
Shut up!
I think you know where I stand, sire.
If I get your troops in,
can you handle the guards?
Or die trying, my liege.
- That's what I'm worried about.
- Sorry?
You're all acting like
there's only two options.
Dying here, or dying there.
- I'm not sure you've been listening.
- No, you're not listening.
Or have you forgotten who really
defeated the White Witch, Peter?
I think we've waited
for Aslan long enough.
Professor?
- I have to find him.
- You don't have time.
- You need to get the gate open.
- You wouldn't be here without him.
And neither would I.
You and I can deal with Miraz.
And I can still get
to the gate in time.
Yes, I'm a mouse.
We were expecting someone,
you know, taller.
- You're one to talk.
- Is that supposed to be irony?
Five more minutes?
What are you doing here?
I didn't help you escape
just so you could break back in.
You have to get out
before Miraz learns you're here.
He's going to learn soon enough.
We are giving him your cell.
Don't underestimate Miraz
as your father did.
What are you talking about?
I'm sorry.
Thank goodness you're safe.
Get up.
- Caspian?
- Stay where you are.
- What are you doing?
- I should think it's obvious, dear.
You know, some families might
consider this inappropriate behavior.
That doesn't seem to have stopped you!
But you are not like me, are you?
It's sad. The first time
you've shown any backbone...
...and it's such a waste.
Put the sword down, Caspian.
- I don't want to do this.
- We don't want you to either.
This used to be a private room.
What are you doing?
You're supposed to be in the gatehouse!
No!
Tonight for once, I want the truth.
Did you kill my father?
Now we get to it.
You said your brother died in his sleep.
That was more or less true.
Caspian, this won't
make things any better.
We Telmarines would have
nothing had we not taken it.
Your father knew that
as well as anyone.
How could you?
For the same reason
you will pull that trigger.
- For our son.
- Stop!
- Stay right there.
- You need to make a choice, dear.
Do you want our child to be king?
Or do you want him
to be like Caspian here?
- Fatherless!
- No!
Caspian!
What's that supposed to mean?
- We're under attack!
- Sound the alarm!
Men! Grab your bows!
- Peter!
- Our troops are just outside! Come on!
Now, Ed! Now!
- Signal the troops!
- I'm a bit busy, Pete!
Peter! It's too late.
We have to call it off while we can.
No, I can still do this!
Help me!
Exactly who are you
doing this for, Peter?
Come on!
Charge!
We're under attack!
Attack! Attack!
For Narnia!
Archers!
Pick a target!
Take aim!
Ed!
Get that gate closed.
Fall back!
We need to retreat! Now!
Go! Get her out of here!
Back to the gate! Go!
- Caspian!
- I'll find him!
Go! Get out! Go!
Get out! Retreat!
Follow me!
Give the order.
My men are still down there.
Draw back!
Get out! Retreat!
Now!
Fire!
Run for your life!
Save yourself!
Peter! The bridge!
Leave us! Go, brothers!
In the name of Aslan!
What happened?
Ask him.
- Peter.
- Me?
You could've called it off.
There was still time.
No, there wasn't, thanks to you.
If you kept to the plan,
those soldiers might be alive.
If you'd stayed here like I suggested,
they definitely would be!
- You called us, remember?
- My first mistake.
No. Your first mistake was thinking
you could lead these people.
I am not the one who abandoned Narnia.
You invaded Narnia. You have no more
right to lead it than Miraz does.
You, him, your father...
Narnia's better off
without the lot of you.
Stop it!
What are you all standing around for?
Telmarines will be here soon enough.
Thank you...
my dear little friend.
- Well done, lads.
- Move it faster, mate. Too slow!
Beruna pledges its troops.
Galma pledges its troops.
Tashbaan pledges its troops.
Ettinsmoor pledges its troops.
Long live the king!
Are you so glad
of that magic horn now, boy?
Your kings and queens have failed us.
Your army's half dead. And those
that aren't will be soon enough.
What do you want?
Congratulations?
You want your uncle's blood.
So do we.
You want his throne?
We can get it for you.
You tried one ancient power.
It failed.
But there is a power greater still.
One that kept even Aslan at bay
for near a hundred years.
Who's there?
I am hunger.
I am thirst.
I can fast a hundred years...
...and not die.
I can lie a hundred nights
on the ice...
...and not freeze.
I can drink a river of blood
and not burst.
Show me... your enemies!
What you hate, so will we.
No one hates better than us.
And you can...
guarantee Miraz's death?
And more.
Let the circle be drawn.
Wait.
This isn't what I wanted.
One drop of Adam's blood
and you free me.
Then I am yours, my king.
No!
Stop!
Come on! Come.
Get away from him!
Peter, dear.
I've missed you.
Come.
Just one drop.
You know you can't do this alone.
I know. You had it sorted.
Why did you never tell me
about my father?
My mother was a Black Dwarf
from the Northern Mountains.
I risked my life all these years
so that one day...
...you might be a better king
than those before you.
Then I have failed you.
Everything I told you,
everything I didn't,
it was only because I believe in you.
You have a chance to become the most
noble contradiction in history.
The Telmarine who saved Narnia.
You're lucky, you know.
What do you mean?
To have seen him.
I wish he'd just given me
some sort of proof.
Maybe we're the ones who need
to prove ourselves to him.
Pete. You'd better come quickly.
Cakes and kettledrums.
That's your next big plan?
Sending a little girl into the darkest
parts of the forest? Alone!
- It's our only chance.
- And she won't be alone.
Haven't enough of us died already?
Nikabrik was my friend too.
But he lost hope.
Queen Lucy hasn't.
And neither have I.
For Aslan.
For Aslan!
- Then I'm going with you.
- No. We need you here.
We have to hold them off
until Lucy and Susan get back.
If I may...
Miraz may be a tyrant
and a murderer...
...but as king, he is
subject to the traditions...
...and expectations of his people.
There is one in particular
that may buy us some time.
Perhaps they intend to surrender.
No.
They are much too noble for that.
"I, Peter, by the gift of Aslan,
by election and by conquest,
High King of Narnia, Lord of Cair
Paravel and emperor of the Lone Islands,
in order to prevent
the abominable effusion of blood,
do hereby challenge the usurper Miraz to
single combat upon the field of battle.
The fight shall be to the death.
The reward shall be total surrender."
- Tell me, Prince Edmund...
- King.
- Pardon me?
- It's King Edmund, actually.
Just "King," though.
Peter's the high king.
I know, it's confusing.
Why would we risk such a proposal
when our armies could
wipe you out by nightfall?
Haven't you already
underestimated our numbers?
I mean, only a week ago
Narnians were extinct.
And so you will be again.
Well, then you should have
little to fear.
This is not a question of bravery.
So you're bravely refusing
to fight a swordsman half your age?
I didn't say I refused.
You shall have our support,
Your Majesty.
Whatever your decision.
Sire, our military advantage alone
provides the perfect excuse to avoid
- what might otherwise be...
- I'm not avoiding anything!
I was merely pointing out
that my lord is well
within his rights to refuse.
His Majesty would never refuse.
He relishes the chance
to show the people
the courage of their new king.
You.
You should hope your brother's sword
is sharper than his pen.
Destrier has always served me well.
You are in good hands.
Or hooves.
- Good luck.
- Thanks.
Look.
Maybe it is time you had this back.
Why don't you hold on to it.
You might need to call me again.
- You might need to call me again?
- Oh, shut up.
If it should appear
to be going poorly...
Understood, Your Majesty.
I hope you won't be too disappointed
when I survive.
There is still time to surrender.
Well, feel free.
How many more must die for the throne?
Just one.
- Ride!
- They've seen us!
- Take the reins.
- What are you doing?
I'm sorry, Lucy. But it looks as if
you'll be going alone after all.
Are you sure you don't need that horn?
Does His Highness need a respite?
Five minutes?
Three!
Lucy?
She got through... with a little help.
- Thanks.
- Well, you were busy.
I assume you won't let things
get that close again!
You better get up there.
Just in case.
I don't expect the Telmarines
will keep their word.
- Sorry.
- It's all right.
Be careful.
Keep smiling.
How does he look to you?
Young.
But His Majesty's doing
extremely well... for his age.
I think it's dislocated.
What do you think happens
back home if you die here?
You know you've always been there,
and I never really...
Save it for later.
Respite!
Respite.
Now's not the time for chivalry, Peter!
Show no mercy!
Look out!
What's the matter, boy?
Too cowardly to take a life?
It's not mine to take.
Perhaps I was wrong.
Maybe you do have the makings
of a Telmarine king after all.
Not one like you.
Keep your life.
But I am giving the Narnians
back their kingdom.
My king.
I'll deal with you when this is over.
It is over.
Treachery! They shot him!
They murdered our king!
Be ready!
Peter!
Go!
To arms, Telmar!
To arms!
Loose!
Cavalry!
Attack!
Archers to the ready!
Narnians!
Charge!
One, two...
Three, four...
Five, six...
Take your aim!
Stay with them!
Eight, nine...
Get ready!
Now!
Stop! Back! Back!
Hold it now! Hold it!
Now!
Charge!
You're a mouse.
You people have no imagination.
Loose! Loose!
Lucy?
Back to the How!
Cut off their escape!
Loose!
Brace yourselves!
Back to the How!
Crush them all.
Aslan!
I knew it was you.
The whole time, I knew it.
But the others didn't believe me.
And why would that stop you
from coming to me?
I'm sorry. I was too scared
to come alone.
Why wouldn't you show yourself?
Why couldn't you come roaring in
and save us like last time?
Things never happen
the same way twice, dear one.
If I'd have come earlier, would everyone
who died... could I have stopped that?
We can never know
what would have happened, Lucy.
But what will happen
is another matter entirely.
- You mean you'll help?
- Of course.
- As will you.
- Oh, I wish I was braver.
If you were any braver,
you'd be a lioness.
Now, I think your friends
have slept long enough, don't you?
Come on!
Lucy.
For Aslan!
We can defeat them
if we draw them to the river.
We must regroup. To Beruna!
To the bridge!
Charge!
What is happening?
- The river!
- Retreat!
Back! Back!
Come on.
Assemble on that bank!
You will not be harmed!
Surrender your weapons!
Take off the armor!
Rise, kings and queens of Narnia.
All of you.
I do not think I am ready.
It's for that very reason
I know you are.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Thank you.
Hail, Aslan!
It is a great honor to be in...
I'm completely out of countenance.
I must crave your indulgence
for appearing in this unseemly fashion.
Perhaps a drop more?
- I don't think it does that.
- You could have a go.
It becomes you well, small one.
All the same, great king,
I regret that I must withdraw, for a
tail is the honor and glory of a mouse.
Perhaps you think too much
of your honor, friend.
Well, it's not just the honor.
It's also great for balance.
And climbing.
And grabbing things.
May it please Your High Majesty,
we will not bear the shame
of wearing an honor denied to our chief.
Not for the sake of your dignity,
but for the love of your people.
Look! Thank you, my liege.
I will treasure it always.
From this day forward it will serve
as a great reminder of my huge humility.
Now, where is this dear little friend
you've told me so much about?
Do you see him now?
Because you have snuck in...
I'm sorry, but their future
in that world shall be good.
Your Majesty?
We are ready.
Everyone has assembled.
Narnia belongs to the Narnians,
just as it does to man.
Any Telmarines who want to stay
and live in peace are welcome to.
But for any of you who wish,
Aslan will return you
to the home of our forefathers.
It's been generations
since we left Telmar.
We're not referring to Telmar.
Your ancestors were seafaring brigands.
Pirates run aground on an island.
There they found a cave, a rare chasm
that brought them here from their world.
The same world as our kings and queens.
It is to that island I can return you.
It is a good place for any
who wish to make a new start.
I will go.
I will accept the offer.
So will we.
Because you have spoken first,
your future in that world shall be good.
- Where did they go?
- They killed them.
How do we know he is not
leading us to our death?
Sire. If my example
can be of any service,
I will take 11 mice through
with no delay.
- We'll go.
- We will?
Come on. Our time's up.
After all...
...we're not really
needed here anymore.
I will look after it until you return.
I'm afraid that's just it.
We're not coming back.
We're not?
You two are.
At least, I think he means you two.
But why?
- Did they do something wrong?
- Quite the opposite, dear one.
But all things have their time.
Your brother and sister have learned
what they can from this world.
Now it's time for them
to live in their own.
It's all right, Lu.
It's not how I thought it would be...
...but it's all right.
One day you'll see, too.
Come on.
I'm glad I came back.
I wish we had more time together.
It would never have worked, anyway.
Why not?
I am 1,300 years older than you.
I'm sure when I'm older I'll understand.
I'm older and don't think
I want to understand.
Aren't you coming, Phyllis?
You don't think there's
any way we can get back?
I've left my
new torch in Narnia.
Subtitles by LeapinLar