Let's see what you got.
I need more runners. I can't
write the business fast enough.
You gotta see Granger.
8720. Yeah. Yeah.
Hold it a minute.
Beat it, Mottola! Mr. Granger?
Chicago's on the line.
Yeah.
This is Combs. Why haven't we
heard from you? Everybody else is in.
We had problems
with the law this morning.
The mayor promised
to get tough on the rackets...
so he shut everybody down for a
couple of hours to make it look good.
Nothing serious. It just
put us a little behind.
- Been making your payoffs?
- Hell, yes!
He does this every year. There's
nothing to worry about.
Finish your count and get it up here.
I don't want to be here all night.
The man's going to be real happy.
We cleared over ten grand this week.
We cleared 22 here.
What the hell! You got the
whole Chicago South Side.
How do you expect my eight
lousy spots to compete with that?
They did 14 grand in Evanston,
16.5 in Gary, and 20 in Cicero.
Looks like you're bringing
up the rear.
I just got the count. I'll
put the take on the 4:15.
We'll be waiting.
Mottola!
Take this up to Chicago on the 4:15.
They'll be waiting for
it at the clearinghouse.
And don't stop for any
entertainment. Get a cab over on 7th.
Cut it out!
8720.
Hey, you there! Stop! Hey,
you! Stop that man!
Stop him! He's got my
wallet! Stop him! Stop that man!
He's got all of my money!
Stop him! Stop him!
Goddamn nigger-lover!
I'm gonna get you someday
for this! Sucker egg!
Don't let him get away! He's got
my wallet! He's got all my money!
- My wallet! He's got my wallet!
- We got it!
What happened? Did he
get you with the knife?
- You need a doctor. I'll call a cop.
- No, no! No cops!
You wanted by the law or something?
No, it's okay.
Are you nuts, carrying a wad like
that in a neighborhood like this?
Thanks. I'm obliged to
you. I gotta get going.
You ain't going nowhere on this leg.
I gotta. Gotta run some
slots in West Bend for a mob here.
I got a little
behind in the payoffs.
They think I've been
holding out on 'em.
They gave me 'til 4:00 to
come up with the cash.
If they don't get it, I'm dead.
It don't look good,
Gramps. It's almost 4:00 now.
I'll give you and your friend a
hundred bucks to deliver it for me.
I don't know. That mug that hit
you is mad enough at me already.
What if he's around the
corner, waiting with some friends?
He won't know you're carrying
it. You've gotta help me.
I'm sorry, pal. I'm gonna maybe
help you get to a doctor...
but I ain't about to
walk into no knife for you.
How about you? All you gotta
do is put it in the door slot.
I'll give you the whole 100.
What makes you think you can
trust him? He didn't do shit.
Butt out!
I gave him back the
wallet. How far is this place?
1811 Mason. Put it in box
3- C. You won't have no trouble.
There's $5,000 there...
and here's a hundred bucks for you.
Okay, I'll make your drop for you.
And don't worry, you can trust me.
Hey. Hey!
If those goons search you, you ain't
gonna get far carrying it there.
- What'll we do?
- You got a bag or something?
- How about a handkerchief?
- Here's a handkerchief!
Give it to me. Give me the money.
Just hurry, will you?
You got any more? Better give it
all to me if you want to keep it.
They think I've been holding out.
My wife got sick, and
I had to pay the bill.
Stuff it down your pants
here, like that. Got it?
Hurry, will ya?
Ain't a tough guy in the
world that's gonna frisk you there.
- Thanks.
- Yeah.
Where to?
- Which way is Mason?
- Twenty blocks south.
- Go north, Joliet Station, fast!
- Right.
What's so funny?
I just made the
world's easiest five grand!
- Come on, Luther! Come on!
- Hold on, man! Okay!
Hustle!
In here!
Man, was that beautiful!
I thought for sure he was on to us.
No, you had him all
the way. All the way!
Wai...
Luther.
Good God! We're millionaires.
- Did you know he was that loaded?
- Hell, no!
I just cut into him.
I would've settled for
pawning one of them shoes.
Oh, God!
Do
you...
Come on. Let's get out of
here. We'll split it up tonight.
Heya, Marge!
- Hi, kid.
- Hi, Hooker. She's on stage.
Hi, Hooker. Gettin'
married or something?
Get used to it, Leonard. I'm going
to look this good from now on.
- Whaddaya say, Ed?
- Hi, Hooker.
I wanna
talk...
Hey, Hooker, you
gettin' married or somethin'?
For Christ's sake,
Ed, did you hear that?
Harry drops four beats in the
middle of my goddamn routine!
- How long do I gotta
put up with that?
Crystal! Leonard, you're on.
You wanna get outta here
tonight? I come into some dough.
I can't. I got a
10:00. I need the five bucks.
I'll spend 50 on you.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Okay.
.. opens up his pants, the
duck sticks his head out.
One lady says to the
other, "See what I see?"
She says, "So what? You've
seen one, you've seen 'em all."
She says, "Yes, but this
one's eating my popcorn."
You see that guy
Harry, he can't keep time.
Supposing there's some
Hollywood movie agent out there.
All those years of
training right down the drain.
Ain't seen you in
months. Thought you took a fall.
Just a little hard
times. Everything's jake now.
How about a ten spot on the line?
There's a lot of action
there on 28th Street. Pay you 35...
Three grand on the red.
- $3,000?
- Are you nuts?
No, I feel lucky.
Hooker, I can't accept
that. It's too big a bet.
- There's a house limit.
- Take it.
- But Hooker
here... - Take it!
Twenty-two, black.
Tough luck, kid.
Lucky for me it came up black.
A fella could get in trouble
here, losin' a bet like that.
Listen, Jimmy, can't
we do it again, huh?
Seven!
Don't worry about it. There's
always more where that came from.
Oh, don't worry about it, he
says. Three thousand dollars!
Thanks, Hooker.
Comes in here with $50 he's
going to spend on me!
- Thanks for the evening, Hooker.
- It's not over yet.
Next time you wanna spend
$50 on me, mail it.
Listen,
will ya...
They found Mottola, drunk in a dive
in Joliet. He never got on the train.
I don't wanna hear about his day,
Greer. What happened to the money?
He lost it to a couple of con
artists on his way out of the spot.
- How much?
- Eleven thousand.
Okay, I better get on
the phone to New York...
see what the big
mick wants to do about it.
I have a pretty good idea, though.
- Doyle, can I talk to you?
- I'm busy, Floyd.
It's important. We had a
little trouble in Chicago today.
One of our runners got
hit for 11 grand.
What makes you think he
just didn't pocket it?
We checked his story with a tipster.
He was cleaned by two grifters.
They working for anybody?
I don't know. Could be. We're
running that down now.
Have some local people take
care of them. Nothing fancy.
We've got to
discourage this kind of thing.
You follow?
Johnny Hooker!
- If you ain't a
sharper in them linens!
Evenin', Louise.
Hey, Ma!
If I didn't know you better,
I'd swear you had some class.
Johnny, Luther said you
was something to see today!
I don't know, Alva.
I gotta get faster
tyin' that bundle.
I still give 'em too
much time to think.
Bushwah! I used to make that switch
with slower hands than you got.
'Course, the Up and Down
Broadway was my best game.
Me and Luther didn't make much
on it, but it wasn't so touchy.
Them marks can beat you up bad when
they catch you makin' that switch.
Come on, Leroy. We'll
be late for church.
Ma, they were closin'
in on Machine Gun Kelly!
Who you rootin' for anyhow?
- Hey, Hooker!
- Can't help you, Leroy.
- You can't beat the house.
- Nuts!
Since when do you
go to church at night?
Since they started late bingo.
I'm gonna ask the Lord for some of
that cash while He's
still payin' off.
Luther, look in on the baby
from time to time, will you?
- You too, Louise? - Child, yeah,
got to go pray. See ya.
Hey, Erie.
- Gimme! Gimme, gimme!
- There's your cut.
Guy turned out to be an oil well.
Which way'd he go?
- Due north. He was
gonna take it all.
Ah, the bastard. He can
blow his nose all the way.
There you go, Luther. Six G's.
- You're late. Where you been?
- I had a couple of appointments.
How much did you lose?
All of it.
In one goddamn night?
What are you spraying
money around like that for?
You could've been nailed!
- I checked. There
were no dicks there.
But you're a con man, and
you blew it like a pimp!
- Didn't teach you to be no pimp.
- What's eatin' you?
- I've blown money before.
- No class grifter would've done it.
- You think my play is bad?
- I think you're the best.
I wouldn't be getting
out, otherwise.
What the hell are you talkin' about?
I'm getting too old for this racket.
You hang on too long and you
start embarrassing yourself.
We just took off on the
biggest score we've ever had.
It's nothing compared to what
you could be making on the big con.
But you played the big con.
You told me yourself it was some dumb
game for mama's boys and flakes.
Hell, I never played no big con.
I hung around and
picked up a few things.
Ain't no rich boys gonna trust a
hungry nigger enough to be conned.
But I'll tell you...
I've been looking for this
one all my life, Johnny.
Now I have a chance to
step out when I'm ahead.
Come on! What would
you do with yourself?
I have a brother in
K. C., runs a freight outlet.
I can go halfsies with him.
It ain't too
exciting, but it's mostly legal.
I got an old friend in
Chicago named Henry Gondorff.
I want you to look him up. There
ain't a better inside man alive.
- He'll teach you all you gotta know.
- To hell with that.
I want to work with you, Luther.
I'm out, Johnny.
Yeah, sure. If that's
the way you want it.
That's the way I want it.
How do you like that
Coleman? After five years.
- He knew he was holding you back.
- Yeah, but we were partners.
If it weren't for Luther, I'd still
be hustling pinball at Gianelli's.
I don't need more than what I got.
You ain't gonna have anything if you
don't lay off the games of chance.
There's a depression on.
- Yeah, there's
always a depression on.
If you saved a little, you
wouldn't have to grift so much.
- I like griftin'.
- You could buy yourself some things.
- What?
- New clothes, a car.
I got clothes, and I
don't know how to drive.
What else do you got to sell?
Hey, Hooker! Come
on, you son of a...
Hi there, Snyder.
What's the matter? Things a little
slow down at the bunco department?
Somebody lose the dominoes?
You scored blood money
today, and you need a friend.
Go find yourself a
shoplifter to roll.
You got the wrong guy, pal. I've
been home with the flu all day.
- Stake out my toilet if you want.
- Keep talkin'!
I'll tell you what
you did, smart boy.
You tied into a loaded mark
on 47th across from Maxie's.
You and Coleman
played the switch for
him and blew him
off to a cab on 49th.
If he hadn't been a
numbers runner for Doyle Lonnegan...
it would've been perfect.
You're crazy.
I ain't stupid enough to
play for no racket's money.
Not intentionally, maybe. That
don't cut no ice with Lonnegan.
- He'll swat you like
a fly. - Yeah, well...
I'll square it with the fixer.
Nobody can buy you a
prayer if I put the finger on you.
Now, I figure your end of the
score was at least three G's.
- I want two, no matter what it was.
- My take was only one.
Then you're gonna have to come
up with another grand somewhere.
All right.
You're a smart egg, Hooker.
No sense getting
dead over two grand.
Relax, Erie. I'll bill ya.
- I thought you blew all your money.
- I did.
The stuff I gave him is counterfeit.
They'll spot it the first
place he tries to spend it.
Are you crazy, giving
him counterfeit money?
Hey! Wait up! Where you goin'?
What the hell are you gonna do if
Snyder puts the finger on you?
- You're committin' suicide, kid.
- What difference does it make?
If Snyder knows, so does everybody
else. He never gets anything first.
Hey, listen to me. Don't go
back to your place tonight.
Don't go anyplace you
usually go. You hear me?
Damn! There's no answer at Luther's.
Look, you better get
out of town or something.
Hey, lady, lady, let go!
Ma'am! Ma'am! Hey!
I want my nickel
back for that telephone!
No, sir. Nobody here did.
1521 North Bryant.
- Is he dead? - I don't know.
There was a big fight.
I don't know. Somebody
must've pushed him.
- Jesus!
- Luther!
God! No! No! No!
Luther! Luther!
What happened? God, who would
do such a thing to you, Luther?
Come on. Come on! Let's
get out of here.
Come on! If Snyder catches
you here, you're dead!
- Get outta here!
- Outta the way.
Help me, help me, help me!
Excuse me.
I'm looking for a guy named
Henry Gondorff. You know him?
No.
You sure?
- Beat it.
- Luther Coleman sent me.
- Are you Hooker?
- Yeah.
Why didn't you say so?
We heard about Luther
last night. Come on.
I thought maybe you
were a cop or something.
It's the room in the back.
He wasn't expecting
you so soon, though.
Thanks.
The great Henry Gondorff.
Turn it off!
You sober?
Turn it off, will ya?
Glad to meet you, kid. You're
a real horse's ass.
Luther said I could
learn something from you.
I already know how to drink.
Sorry about Luther.
He was the best street
worker I ever saw.
He had you down as a
big-timer. What happened?
I conned a senator from
Florida on a stock deal.
A real lop-ear; thought he was
gonna take over General Electric.
Some chanteusie woke him,
though, and he put the feds on me.
You mean you blew it.
Luther didn't tell
me you had a big mouth.
He didn't tell me you
was a screw up either.
You played any big cons since then?
I lammed around a bunch of bohunk
towns, one kick ahead of the G-men.
Would be still, if Billie
hadn't set me up here.
Don't kid yourself,
friend. I still know how.
You gonna stay for breakfast, or
do you already know how to eat?
I picked something up along the way.
Is Lonnegan after you too?
I don't know. I ain't seen anybody.
You never do, kid.
Doyle?
Yeah.
We just talked to Chicago.
They got one of the
grifters last night... a nigger.
- How about the other one?
- They're still looking for him.
- Who did Combs put on it?
- He gave it to Riley and Cole.
They staked out the other guy's place
last night, but he never showed.
They figure maybe he skipped town.
You wanna keep after him?
You see that fella
in the red sweater?
His name's Danny McCoy.
Works a few of the
protection rackets...
when he's waiting for
something better.
Danny and I have known each
other since we were six.
Take a good look at
that face, Floyd.
Because if he ever finds out I
can be beat by one lousy grifter...
I'll have to kill
him and every other hood...
who wants to muscle in
on my Chicago operation.
- You follow?
- Yes, sir.
Good lad.
You feeling all
right this morning, Henry?
Yeah, fine.
You mind opening up the
round a little early today?
We got some business coming
in before hours.
- Sure.
- Check the main gearing, will ya?
Man O' War started rattling yesterday
and threw a kid on its head.
Great little countess, that Billie.
She runs a spiffy house up there too.
You plan to spend the
rest of your life here?
I could do a lot worse.
Listen, am I gonna learn to
play the big con or not?
What's your hurry?
- I wanna play for Lonnegan.
- You know anything about the guy?
Yeah, he croaked Luther. Anything
else I gotta know?
All right. He runs a numbers
racket on the South Side.
He owns a packing
house, a few banks...
Yeah, and half the
politicians in New York and Chicago.
Not a fix in this world is gonna
cool him out if he blows on you.
- I'll get him anyway.
- Why?
'Cause I don't know
enough about killing to kill him.
You can't do it alone, you know.
It takes a mob of guys and
money to make 'em look good.
- I know plenty of guys.
- It's not like playing winos.
- You can't outrun Lonnegan.
- I never played for no winos.
You gotta keep his con even
after you take his money.
- He can't know you took him.
- You're scared of him.
Right down to my socks, buster.
You're talking about a
guy who'd kill a grifter...
over a chunk of money wouldn't
support him for two days.
You're gonna go for him.
Just don't want a hothead
looking to get even,
coming back halfway through...
saying, "It ain't enough," 'cause
it's all we're gonna get.
Can you get a mob together?
After what happened to Luther,
I can't get more than 300 guys.
Luther said you learn
fast. I hope he's right.
Lonnegan gets most of his
income from the numbers...
even though he's been
putting more money
into his savings and loan business.
- Think he's moving out
of the racket? - No.
He owns most of the
stock, and it's traded.
My guess is he's just trying to
build himself a respectable image.
He came out of Five Points...
but he's been telling everybody
he was born in Forest Hills.
He knows the market, though.
I don't think we can
take him on a stocks deal.
Twist, what about the numbers?
It's run out of a packing
house on 14th by a guy named Combs.
Lonnegan comes out every three
weeks or so to check on it, but...
he stays away from the day-to-day
stuff in case it's raided.
These are two of Combs's favorite
torpedoes: Riley and Cole.
You ever seen 'em?
No.
They're the ones who hit Luther.
They also got the numbers runner
you conned: a guy named Mottola.
Found him in a quarry with
a knife in his eye.
Lonnegan's had seven or eight
people rubbed on his way up.
His pattern has been to get
close to a racket boss...
Learn the
operation, then move in on it.
He's done it to
Gorman, O'Donnell, Buchalman.
He took the numbers from Sharkey.
All four of these guys are
dead. He's vindictive as hell, Henry.
Kills for pride. Doesn't add up he'd
let Hooker get away from him.
You see anything,
kid, you let us know.
If they put you on the spot, we
gotta fold the con. You got that?
Yeah. You sure it's
gotta be one of these two guys?
Nope. They're just the
only ones we know of.
Time.
Set me up five more
beers, will you, Danny?
- You the owner here?
- That's right.
Lt. Snyder, Bunco.
That's a Joliet badge,
Snyder. Don't cut much up here.
Looking for a guy on the
lam from a counterfeiting rap.
- Thought he might've come here.
- Don't think so.
I know everyone in the place, and
I always bounce the lamsters.
All right if I look around in here?
No, but you're welcome to
a free beer before you go.
I don't really need your permission.
I don't know what
to do with this guy.
He's an Irishman who doesn't drink,
doesn't smoke and
doesn't chase dames.
He's a grand knight in
the Knights of Columbus...
and he only goes out to play faro.
Sometimes plays 15, 20 hours at a
time; just him against the house.
- Roulette, craps?
- He won't touch 'em.
The croupier at Gilman's says he
never plays anything he can't win.
Sports?
He likes to be seen with
fighters sometimes...
but he doesn't go to
the fights or bet on 'em.
Jesus. Does he do
anything where he's not alone?
Just poker.
And he cheats.
Pretty good at it too.
Where does he play?
The porters say he runs a braced
game on the Century Limited...
when he comes out
here from New York.
$100 minimum, straight poker.
A lot of high rollers ride
that train just to play him.
That sounds good, J. J.
Which way are the rooms?
- Who told you this guy was in here?
- Nobody.
I just know what kind
of woman he likes.
I'm gonna check all the
joy houses till I find him.
Maybe I could help you
if you tell me his name.
I doubt it. Which way are the rooms?
Right through there. But I wouldn't
go in there if I were you.
- What are you gonna do, call the
cops? - I don't have to.
You'd be busting in on the
chief of police just up the hall.
We'll play it out here. A
huge duke is too simple.
With no fix, we're gonna need
a con with a surefire blow-off.
I think we ought to play
this guy on the payoff.
It's the tightest game we got, and
it's not all over the papers yet.
Lonnegan is a fast egg.
He's not going to sit
still for a standard play.
What does that leave us? We
can't con the payoff to a banker.
We'll use the wire.
Haven't known a poker player
didn't wanna beat the ponies.
The wire's been out
of date for ten years.
That's why he won't know it.
I'm not sure I know it.
It'll take two of
us working the inside.
Any objections to
Hooker as second man?
All right.
We'll give Lonnegan the hook
on the train and play him here.
J. J., you think I can
get in that poker game?
Just show up with a lot of
money and look like a sucker.
I also gotta win.
By the way, any of you guys been
passing bad money lately?
If he comes in again, stall
him so I can get a look at him.
Fella by the name of Stenner had this
place 'til about six months ago...
but he had to give it up.
It doesn't look so good, but maybe
you can fix it up a little bit.
Watch your step when you come
in. There's a dip down to the left.
- How does it look, Eddie?
- It looks all right, Kid.
It's big enough, and
it's off the street.
It's kind of short notice. I'm not
sure we can get it done by Saturday.
Got to. Gondorff's riding the mark
down from New York on the Century.
We'll take it. That building at the
end of the alley, do you manage that?
For 15 years.
I'll need a corner
room facing this way.
- How much a week?
- Only rents by the month.
Two hundred and
fifty for the two of them.
Last time I expect to
see you down here.
Never heard of the place.
It's been a while since
I stocked the wire store.
Not many mobs playing that anymore.
All we'll need is the
bookie setup for now.
I'll rent you everything I got
in the warehouse for two grand.
That'll give you phones,
cages, blackboards and ticker gear.
If you want a counter and
bar, that's another grand.
- That's pretty steep, Benny.
- Gondorff's still a hot item.
- Where would I be if he gets hit?
- Just give us what you can.
We'll send a truck.
How do you want to work this?
Flat rate or percentage?
- Who's the mark?
- Doyle Lonnegan.
Flat rate.
The guy in the black
hat with the gimp.
He's not as tough as he thinks.
Neither are we.
- Mr. Shaw?
- Right.
You wanted to see me?
I hear there's a friendly
poker game on this train.
You know anything about it?
- Oh, a little.
- Thank you, sir.
- Can you get me in that game?
- Oh, I don't know.
There's usually a waiting list.
That'll get you first
alternate, sir.
I'll see what I can do.
Twist!
- Patty, me boy! How are you?
- How are you, Twist?
Champ, you're
lookin' like a million!
Good to see you!
Goldie, you old son of a gun.
I saw the Kid in Denver. He
says to say hello to you.
Joiner, are you still
workin' those shapes?
Any number you want, Twist!
- Good to see you again.
- Okay, Lacey. Good to see you.
- It's good to see you. Come on in!
- Dukey, how are you?
- When did you get back in town?
- A couple of days ago.
You heard about Luther
Coleman, didn't you?
Yeah. Some of the boys were passin'
the hat for Alva and the kids.
- I never seen the guys so worked up.
- Don't worry about it, Dukey.
We're gonna send a
little calling card of our own.
Gondorff is setting up a wire store.
I'm gonna need a
20-man boost right away.
I got plenty of talent out
there tonight. Take your pick. Lace!
This is a tough one. These
boys have got to be the quill.
Get me the sheet. Let's
see who's in town.
Patty, give me the sheet.
Sure.
Gondorff's
already on...
Twist, you know this guy?
No, I never saw him
before. He's a dick, though.
Hello, Snyder.
- What are you doin' up here?
- I'm on vacation.
You seen that
friend of yours lately?
No, no. He packed it in.
Enrolled in detective school.
If you see him...
you tell him he better
pay up before I get to him.
That son of a bitch.
Thanks, Lace.
Let's see what we got here.
Horse Face Lee, Slim Miller...
Suitcase Murphy and the Big
Alabama are in from New Orleans.
Cryin' Jonesy and the
Boone Kid from Denver.
Dippy Burke and Limehouse
Chappie from New York.
These and the guys outside should
give you 30 or more to choose from.
Good, Dukey.
Have them down at
Stenner's old pool hall before 6:00.
We're gonna run the route tonight.
Okay, Twist, but...
if this thing blows up, remember,
I can't do you no good downtown.
Gondorff is federal.
Dukey, if this thing blows up...
the feds will be the
least of our problems.
Yeah?
- You in?
- Yeah, I think so.
I gave the kayducer a
C- note. Did you find out the deck?
He usually plays with a
Tallyho Fan or a Tallyho Circle.
I got you one of each.
He likes to cold-deck
low, eights or nines.
That's nice work, J. J. Here.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- Don't mention it, ma'am.
- He'd like to join us.
- Yes, Clyde is a member of our firm.
She picked him
clean. He never missed it.
My God, it looks like he's
expecting a big night.
Must be 15, 20 grand here.
He's waiting for
you in the card room.
Let him wait.
Just worry about your end, kid.
If we ever get to it.
Excuse me.
You sure you checked this guy out?
He seemed like a pleasant
man; a lot of cash on him.
Two-hundred-dollar suit, expensive
luggage. I'll vouch for him.
Why isn't he here then?
Don't worry. He'll be here.
All right.
What're you doin'?
Always drink gin with a mark,
kid. He can't tell if you cut it.
Two thousand for you, Mr. Clayton?
Thank you.
All right, gentlemen. Should
we not wait for him?
Let's go.
I think that's a good idea.
Mr. Clemens, give me the cards.
Sorry I'm late,
guys. I was takin' a crap.
The name's Shaw.
Mr. Shaw, meet Mr.
Jameson from Chicago.
Mr. Lombard from Philadelphia.
- And Mr. Lonnegan from New York.
- Pleased to meet you.
Mr. Clayton, Pittsburgh.
Any of you guys want to make a little
book in Chicago, I'm the guy to see.
Game is straight poker...
$100 minimum, table stakes.
Mr. Shaw, this is
a gentleman's game.
We assume you're all
good for your debts.
- How much would you like, Mr. Shaw?
- I'll start with 5,000.
Mr. Shaw, we usually
require a tie at this table.
If you don't have
one, we can get you one.
Hey, that'd be real nice
of you, Mr. Lonneman.
Lonnegan.
Name's Curly Jackson. Worked
for Gad Bryan outta Baldwin.
Jackson?
Jackson, Jackson. Oh, yeah.
Ever play the wire, Curly?
Roped for it long ago. I can
shill, mark board, anything you want.
I don't run with riffraff, and
I only drink on weekends.
Me specialty's an Englishman.
We got a rack of suits over there.
Pick yourself a nice tweed one.
That's all right. I've
got all my own stuff.
Doyle?
One.
Bill?
I'll take one.
- Shaw?
- Three.
And the dealer will take one.
Bet 500.
I'll call.
Call and raise.
- Three hundred.
- I'm out.
Fold.
Your three...
and raise... 500.
That's eight to me.
Call.
Jacks on top.
Beats me.
Three tens.
Tough luck, Lonnihan.
But that's what you get for
playing with your head up your ass.
Couple more like that, we
can all go to bed early.
The name's Lonnegan. Doyle Lonnegan.
You're gonna remember that...
or you're gonna get
yourself another game.
You follow?
Bring it right up here!
Eddie, we brought you a
tap into Moe Anenberg's wire.
You'll get race
results, odds, scratches,
pole positions, everything.
And just as fast as
Western Union gets 'em.
- Does J. J. know how
to use that thing?
All he's gotta do is read.
The name is Joe Erie.
Joe Erie.
You played for any particular mobs?
No.
- You ever play the wire before,
Erie? - No.
I never played no
big con before, but...
Luther Coleman was a friend
of mine, and I thought maybe...
there'd be somethin' I could do.
You get that nose in
Duke Boudreau's tonight?
Yeah.
You got moxie,
Erie. Get yourself a suit.
Thanks.
I'll bet three.
Call and raise 200.
Call.
- No.
- I'm out.
Call.
Aces over.
Three cowboys.
All red, queen high.
- Well, that finishes me.
- Don't worry about it, pal.
They wouldn't have let you in
here if you weren't a chump!
Lombard'll be joining
you in a couple of minutes.
- Now, look here, Shaw... -
I've had enough of this game...
and quite enough of this company.
Check me out, Clemens.
I guess that just
leaves the three of us.
Yes, Mr. Shaw. That
just leaves us three.
Mr. Clayton, I think we
should take a break for five minutes.
Tempers seem to be
running a little high.
Ah, come on, Linneman, I
was just startin' to do good.
Stack me a cooler.
We'll be in the
station in another hour.
The other guys are the big
losers. You're still okay.
Fix me a deck... threes and nines.
I'll cut it in on Clayton's deal.
- What do you want Clayton to get?
- Nothin'.
I want him outta there early.
I'm gonna bust that
bastard bookie in one play.
Four hundred to you,
Mr. Jameson. You're even.
Well, it just wasn't my night.
Oh, I need it.
- You know what time we get in?
- No, I don't.
Hey, where's your ante?
Every time I had
anything, he stayed in front of me.
Five hundred.
Your five. One thousand.
I'll fold.
I'll play.
Cards?
Two.
Three.
Five hundred.
Your five hundred, and one thousand.
Your one thousand. I'll
raise you two thousand.
Your two thousand.
Mr. Clemens...
give me $10,000 more.
I'll call.
Four nines.
Four Jacks.
You owe me 15 grand, pal.
Must've left my wallet in my room.
Don't hand me any of that crap!
When you come to a game like
this, you bring your money!
How do I know you
won't take a powder?
I'll tell you what I'll do.
I'll send a boy around to
your room in five minutes.
You better have the money,
or it's gonna be all around
Chicago that you welched.
You won't be able to
get a game of jacks!
Cash me in for the
rest of these bums.
You're on, kid.
But I gotta tell you, it's
a hard act to follow.
- How'd it go?
- We got working money.
- Hey?
- Yeah?
- He's steamin'.
- Yeah.
Watch yourself.
Doyle, I know I
gave him four threes!
He had to make a switch!
We can't let him get away with that.
What was I supposed to do? Call
him for cheating better than me?
Name's Kelly. Shaw sent me.
Your boss is quite a
card player, Mr. Kelly.
- How does he do it?
- He cheats.
In that case, I'll keep my
money, and we'll have another game.
You don't have any to keep.
Here's your wallet. He hired
a dame to take it from you.
Shaw's been plannin' to
beat your game for months.
He's been waiting for you to
cheat him so he could clip you.
Who do you think you're talking
to, errand boy? Nobody sets me up!
Take him back to the baggage
room! Put one in his ear!
There were four
witnesses at that table!
Then get that other son of a bitch
and dump 'em in the first tunnel.
We're gonna be in the
station in a couple of minutes!
It ain't gonna look too good killing
a guy you owe money to.
There's better
ways of takin' him down.
What do you think Shaw would do if
he knew I was tellin' you this?
Okay.
Why the rat?
I wanna take over his operation, and
I need you to help me break him.
- Where's my money?
- Shaw's got it.
How the hell could I
ask him for it back?
We're pullin' in.
I'm givin' you a lift home.
- I was supposed to go with Shaw.
- Explain it to him somehow.
- But he's expecting me.
- I'm givin' you a lift home.
You follow?
Yeah, sure. Sure thing.
What makes you
think you can beat him?
I've been planning
this for two years.
I know his organization
backwards and forwards...
and I need somebody who's
respectable but not completely legit.
I'm a banker, Kelly. That's
legit in this state.
All you gotta do is put down
a bet for me at Shaw's place.
I'll do the rest. I'll supply the
money. I'll supply the information.
What about the
money you come to collect?
I'll tell him you paid it. I
keep his books. He trusts me.
If you help me, I'll pay back the
money he stole out of my own pocket.
- It's worth that much to you?
- Yeah.
Oh, yeah. Maybe a couple of million.
Where do you come from, Kelly?
From the east side of New
York. A place called Five Points.
- But I got out of there.
- Out and up, huh?
Hey, Floyd? I'm gonna have to
keep you away from this guy.
You're liable to get ideas.
I'll be at Klein's Drug Store...
660 South Marshall at
1:30, if you're interested.
If I'm not there by quarter
to 2:00, I'm not comin'.
Hey, Hooker, how'd it go?
Jake.
- Everything go okay?
- Yeah, sure. Hell, easy.
- No sign of trouble, huh?
- No.
- What about Lonnegan? - I gave him
the breakdown like you said.
- And? - He's good.
He threatened to kill me.
Hell, kid, if they don't do that,
you know you're not gettin' to 'em.
Hello, Doyle.
All right, Riley, what
the hell happened?
We missed him.
Whoever he is, he
made a fool out of you.
There was no way he
could've known we was in that room.
Somebody must've wised him up.
What does Cole say about that?
I don't know. He took it hard.
Get out of here, Riley.
Put Salino onto it.
Salino? Why waste our best
people on a small-time job?
This is a nickel-and-dime
grifter we're after, Doyle.
- They'll get him next time.
- They had their chance.
All they did was shoot up a
neighborhood, wake up a few cops.
I told you to put Salino onto it.
It may take a little more
time, but there won't be any holes.
Tell Cole I wanna see
him when he comes in.
He won't be comin' in; not to
get bounced off a job anyway.
This is Salino's job, Vince.
Cole wants to muscle
in, that's his business.
But he's breakin' the
rules and Salino won't like it.
Now, get me the books.
Those odds on the
third race are wrong.
Just a minute. I'll get 'em.
Don't worry so much. You're
gonna be all right.
Just stay to the back
the first time around.
Put a little of this on your nose.
Kelly?
You should always
look to the back, kid.
I was afraid you wasn't gonna
show. We haven't got much time.
Get on with it, then.
Sometime after 2:00...
a guy's gonna call on that phone
and give you the name of a horse.
All you gotta do is take
this two grand across the street...
to Shaw's place, and
bet it on that pony.
Don't take too much time.
We've only got four minutes
after you get the call.
You'll not break
him with a $2,000 bet.
This is just a test. The
big one comes later.
Be careful with
that. That's all I got.
You were gonna pay me
back out of your own pocket?
I am. After the race.
I gotta get back before
Shaw misses me. Good luck.
Yeah? Go ahead.
The horse is Blue Note to win.
- Fourth race at Narragansett.
- Got it.
Yeah?
Blue Note to win in the
fourth race at Narragansett.
Turning for home, it's
Lady Scout by a length.
Speed Queen a half, Lady
Trust and Miss Petrina.
Into the stretch, it's Lady
Scout ahead, Speed Queen a half.
And at the wire, it's
Speed Queen the winner!
Lady Scout placed and
Miss Petrina showed.
Post numbers two, five and one.
Taking off at 23.
Look at that.
He's got his apes with him.
Yeah, we're gonna have
to do something about that.
Bubblesome is 10, Beefsteak, 7...
Vote Boy, 6, Kerry Patch, 12.
Blue Note is 7 to 1.
This is your last call for the
third race at Lincoln Fields.
They're going to the post.
- You may still wager if you hurry.
- There he goes.
At Detroit, the winner,
Speed Queen, paid $7.20...
4.60 and 3.40.
Lady Scout, $7 and 4.20.
Miss Petrina paid four dollars.
Last flash at
Narragansett. Lady Higloss, 6 to 5.
I'd think you'd get
tired of losing, Harrigan.
Thank you, Mr. Williams.
Blue Note, $2,000 to win.
Fourth race, Narragansett.
Make sure you see the cash, Eddie.
He's got a name for bettin'
money he doesn't have.
We'll give you the
results on that one in a minute.
Ladies and
gentlemen, this is Arnold Rowe...
your caller for the fourth race.
The mile and one-sixteenth handicap
at Narragansett Park, Rhode Island.
Thirteen thousand dollars added
for three-year-olds and up.
The flag is up, and
they're off and running.
It's Bubblesome going to the
front, followed by Lady Higloss...
Vote Boy, Chancing, Beefsteak,
Kerry Patch...
and Blue Note trails the field.
Around the clubhouse
turn, it's Bubblesome ahead...
Chancing a half, Lady
Higloss by one...
followed by Vote Boy,
Beefsteak, Kerry Patch and Blue Note.
Into the second turn, it's
Chancing by a length.
Lady Higloss driving on
the rail and Vote Boy...
followed by Bubblesome,
Beefsteak, Kerry Patch and Blue Note.
Come on, Chancing!
Lady Higloss a
half, Vote Boy by one.
Lady Higloss is a hell of a finisher.
Chancing's gonna have to open up.
Know anything about a
horse named Blue Note?
He never done much. Probably in
there just to round out the field.
Chancing's where you want
to have your money.
Great tip you handed me, kid.
- Just give him time.
- Chancing by one.
And here comes Blue
Note driving on the outside!
- Nice work, Erie. He loves ya.
- He's third!
Chancing is shortening stride, and
now it's Lady Higloss and Blue Note.
They're head to head.
They're neck and neck.
It's Lady Higloss, Blue
Note; Lady Higloss, Blue Note.
And Blue Note wins it by a nose!
Lady Higloss is second by
three, and Chancing is third by one.
Who in the blazes is Blue Note?
The winner, Blue
Note, paid $16, 9.40 and $6.
So you want to have your
money on Chancing, huh?
Chancing paid 3.80.
Time for the mile and
1/16th: 1:44 and 1.
They're going to
the gate at Belmont.
And here are the late odds.
Those garbage men belong to you?
Get 'em out of here and don't bring
'em back. This is a class joint.
- Hey, you, Kelly!
- Yes, sir?
Run those bums out of here.
- Mr. Shaw, could l... - Don't
give me any of your lip, kid.
Now, run 'em out of here.
Time for the three-quarter
mile: 1:11 and 4.
The winner, Panic
Relief, paid 12.40, 8.20 and $5.
Barbara A., 6.20 and 4.
Wilder paid four dollars.
They're at the
post at Belmont at 38.
We're waiting on one.
I'll call Belmont next.
That's it, fellas!
- I wanna repeat
that... - All right, J. J.
What do you say, pal?
Yeah?
He's on his way.
Hi, Mutt.
Say, Jeff.
What'd I tell you?
- You got lucky once.
That's not enough.
Ah, lucky, hell. I
can do it every time.
- Why don't you then?
- It's better to do it all at once.
We're gonna put
down 400 grand next week.
At five-to-one
odds, that's two million.
- Twenty percent is yours.
- Got a system, Kelly?
No. You can still
lose with a system.
You're past-posting, aren't you?
Could be.
- How?
- You're gonna stay in?
Not 'til I get some answers.
I got a partner downtown.
He runs the central
office of the Western Union.
Race results from all
over the country...
come in and go across
his desk to the bookies.
All he does is hold 'em
up 'til he can call us,
get a bet down on the winner.
Then he releases the
results to the bookies.
We clean up on a race that's already
been run. You can't miss.
Unless the Western Union
dicks get a hold of it.
You got the 400 grand yet?
No, not
yet, but...
- There's only a grand here.
- Make another bet tomorrow.
Where's my money?
- I got 16 grand coming.
- You owe me 15 grand already.
If your setup's as good as you say
it is, there's plenty more to come.
I decide when to place the bets!
Not if you want me
to keep making 'em.
I gotta talk to my partner. We
can't afford to expose too much.
- I'll talk to him myself.
- No!
You've been waiting a long time for
this. Don't ruin it for yourself.
I'll pick you up
tomorrow at 3:00. You follow?
Twist, I told him the
tale, but he didn't go for it.
He wants to see my
partner tomorrow at 3:00.
- 3:00?
- Yeah.
We can't get a
telegraph store set up.
Any chance of talking him out of it?
None. I would've stalled him, but I
didn't have many friends in the room.
Yeah. All right, we'll
have to play him on the fly.
I'll get Eddie looking for a place.
- Let me know when you got something.
- Sure thing, tootsie.
All right, Hooker!
Stop him!
Hooker! Hooker!
I'll get you, you rat!
Why didn't you tell
me about Snyder before?
- I thought I'd lost him.
- You found him again.
We're gonna have to do
something about it.
- What else haven't you been
telling me? - Nothin'. That's all.
Hold still.
Why'd you move out of your room?
It was too noisy.
You can't play your
friends like marks, Hooker.
You know how easy it would be
for Lonnegan's guys to get you?
All we need is a couple of days...
and we can get the son
of a bitch and nail him.
You just won't learn, will ya?
I come in here, teach you stuff that
maybe five guys in the world know.
Stuff most grifters couldn't
do even if they knew it.
- All you wanna do
is run down a bullet.
I'm askin' a couple of days.
I can stay clear that long!
Christ, they'll
probably miss you and hit me.
- Hey.
- Hi.
What'll you have?
Give me the blue plate special.
One blue plate special.
- You're done?
- Yeah.
- Guess I should've
had the meat loaf.
It isn't any better.
- Hey, where's June?
- She quit.
I'm fillin' in for
her a couple of days...
until I can get a train out of here.
Yeah? Where are you going?
I don't know. Depends
on what train I get on.
- Keep it.
- Thanks.
Let's go.
Excuse me, ma'am, but
we're looking for Mr...
- Harmon.
- Mr. Harmon's office.
- Mr. Harmon?
- Yeah.
Got a work order for a painting job.
- For Mr. Harmon's office?
- That's right, ma'am.
Well, hold on. Just a second.
Hiya.
- Where to?
- 110 South Wabash.
110 South Wabash. Get going.
What happened to your face?
Ah, got into a fight with
a raggle down on 13th.
Cut me with her ring.
You oughta lay off the skirts.
You don't find any of my boys messin'
around with that kind of trash.
Brigham signed it, all right. I can't
understand why he didn't tell me.
Ah, he's like all them supervisors.
They think they're too
good for regular people.
He says he was in here a while
ago and the place was a mess.
We'll hurry so we don't
keep you out too long.
Why can't I work with you in here?
We gotta cover the
floor, the furniture,
everything so we
don't spill on nothin'.
If you want to sit in here
with a tarp over your head,
you're welcome to it.
- How long will you be?
- An hour or two at the most.
It's a small job.
We'll go in the side door here.
Hiya, Les.
Les, this is Doyle Lonnegan.
- Mr. Lonnegan, this is Les Harmon.
- How do you do?
What did you bring him here for?
I thought it would be a good
idea for him to see the operation.
I'm having the place
painted. We can't talk in here now.
We'll have to find someplace
else. Excuse me, Mr. Lonnegan.
Miss Barnes, I'm going
home a little early.
If there are any calls...
tell them they can reach
me here tomorrow morning.
Mr. Lonnegan?
I wanna see it one more time.
I can't do it. We got telegraph
inspectors all over the place.
One more time isn't
gonna make much difference.
We got 400 grand coming in
from the coast next week.
You gonna risk
that on a lousy 15 G's?
If it works again tomorrow,
I'll finance the whole thing.
Half a million
dollars. Sixty-forty, we split.
What are you talking... We've already
got a guy. He's gonna give us half.
- What am I supposed to say to him?
- Say to him what you want.
What I know about your
operation, if I were you...
I'd be worried about
making me happy.
Your guy says a week. How do
we know it won't be a month?
Lonnegan here's a banker.
He can get the money
without any questions asked.
We can't keep goin' into Shaw's
place and cleanin' up on long shots.
- He's bound to get wise.
- All right. We'll go for short odds.
You follow?
Are you Lieutenant William Snyder?
I don't know. What's up?
F. B. I.
Special Agent Polk would
like a few words with you.
You got a couple of minutes?
Yeah, sure.
No, no, no. It's got to
be south of the river.
Probably this section in here.
31st, 39th, Morgan and Halstead.
Now, that's this section here.
Now, let's break it into
two sections along 35th.
What the hell is
this? I got work to do.
Sit down and shut up, will ya?
Try not to live up to
all my expectations.
Take two men with you.
Work your way south from
31st to 35th, Morgan and Halstead.
Go into every place and
let me know what you find.
We've been told you know a
hustle artist named Johnny Hooker.
- You know him, or don't you?
- Yeah, but I don't know where he is.
Well, we do. He's chumming around
with a big C named Henry Gondorff.
Ring any bells?
Every bunco man in the
country knows Gondorff.
Well, there's word he's gonna
run a con on the South Side here.
We've got a year-old Florida
warrant on him, but it's a thin beef.
He can beat it in court
unless we catch him cold.
All we want you to do is
pick up Hooker for us.
Why don't you pick him up yourself?
If word gets out the
feds are in on it,
Gondorff will fold
up the whole thing.
Wouldn't that be too bad?
Then you'd have to move out of
this nice office you've got here.
Don't crack wise with me, flatfoot.
I spent too much time in dumps
like this eating Gondorff's dust...
while you guys in the bunco
squads get rich tipping him off!
That's not gonna happen this time.
We're not gonna tell
the police we're here.
You keep your mouth
shut and do a job,
there'll be reward
bucks in it for you.
And you better take it, 'cause I can
make you work for us without it.
What the hell good is Hooker to you?
He's gonna set up Gondorff for us.
- He'll never do it.
- I think he will.
He's there. Let's get on it.
What's the line on Exponent?
Five to one.
- How's it going?
- Nothing yet.
I had a good one on the lead at
Lincoln Fields, but he faded.
Best we had the last hour was
Love Potion at Rockingham...
and she was 5 to 1.
All the long shots coming in today.
Take 4 to 1 if you have to.
Okay.
You can forget the boodle, Eddie.
He could hit us for 15 grand
at 4 to 1. We can't handle that.
- Give him the shutout.
- Okay.
Okay, Billie, here we go.
At the wire, it's Wrecking
Crew, the winner by five.
Black Mischief,
second; Whichaway, third.
Wrecking Crew was...
3 to 1. That's our boy.
Henry?
Here we go, Henry. We got a 3
to 1 at Belmont... Wrecking Crew.
Yeah?
All right. Okay.
- Yeah?
- In the sixth race at Belmont.
Wrecking Crew to win; Black
Mischief to place;
Whichaway to show.
Wait here.
The winner, Time To Go,
paid seven dollars...
5.40 and 3.80.
Joy Flag, $6 and 4.20.
Readily paid 3.80 to show.
The weather's threatening,
but the track is fast there
in Salem, New Hampshire.
Here's a late jockey change there
in the fifth at Rockingham.
R. C. Stark will ride Itsie-Bitsie.
- Thank you, sir.
- That's R. C. Stark.
Five thousand on Black
Mischief, across the board.
Sixth at Belmont.
Would you hurry up there, please?
Wrecking Crew is 3 to
1; Vale Of Tears, four;
Black Mischief,
five; Whichaway, six;
Chief Yeoman, 12;
Peerless Pal is 20;
and Mariato is, uh, 40.
And here we go for
the sixth at Belmont.
It's five and a half
furlongs. They're at the post.
- Now.
- The flag is up.
- And they're off!
- Sixth race, Belmont, 15,000.
Excuse me, sir. We can't take any
bets once the race is started.
You can bet on another
race if you care to.
Going into the backstretch,
it's Wrecking Crew by two.
Whichaway a half, Black Mischief and
Vale Of Tears driving on the outside.
- Nothin', thank you.
- What happened?
I didn't get the bet down in time.
Jesus!
Heading for home, it's Wrecking
Crew all alone by six lengths...
Whichaway a
length, and Vale of Tears.
It's Wrecking Crew, Whichaway
and Black Mischief.
And at the wire, Wrecking
Crew wins it by six lengths.
Black Mischief is
second by a head...
Whichaway is third, followed
by Vale Of Tears.
You should've had your
money on Wrecking Crew.
It's raining and the track
is sloppy at Riverside Park.
There's a late scratch there.
Transmutate is scratched
in the fifth at Riverside.
At Belmont, the
winner, Wrecking Crew...
paid $6, 4.20 and 2.80.
Black Mischief, 4.60 and 3.20.
I'll have half a million here
by post time tomorrow.
Lay it on the first race where
the odds are 4 to 1 or better.
- Make sure I get to
the window on time.
How am I gonna do that?
I don't know. Figure it
out for yourself, Kelly.
Finished?
Yeah.
Meat loaf, apple
pie and a cup of coffee.
- Say, what time you get off work
here? - 2:00 a. m.
- Yeah? Doing anything tonight?
- Yeah. Sleepin'.
Eighty-five.
- You got a back door to this place?
- What's wrong with the front?
There's a guy out there I don't
need to see. Don't look around.
- What does he want?
- He'd like to kill me.
Do me a favor. Go into the bathroom,
open the window and wait there.
Do what I tell you, and
everything will be jake.
Please.
Thanks. Good night.
It's taken.
Thanks. See ya.
Shit.
Salino. Hey,
I wasn't...
Hey! Gotcha, Hooker!
Hey there, Snyder. Long time no see.
Get goin'!
Chuck...
get this off to the
department right away.
Yes, sir.
Hello, Hooker. Take them off.
Special Agent Polk, F. B. I.
Have a chair.
- You want a drink or something?
- No.
We want to talk to
you about Henry Gondorff.
Yeah? I don't think I know him.
Give yourself a couple of seconds.
You wouldn't want to lie to me.
Lt. Snyder here says you've done a
lot of confidence work in his town.
Oh, yeah? Lt. Snyder
doesn't know shit.
- You ain't got nothin' on me.
- Yeah?
How about counterfeiting?
We've got a tip that
Gondorff is gonna
run a con on the South Side here.
All you've gotta do is tell us
when he's gonna play his chump.
We come in at the
sting, make the pinch, and...
you walk out free as a bird.
No.
You wanna spend the next 20
years in a federal penitentiary...
starting tonight?
I'll make parole.
Like hell. You won't
even get a review.
I'll chance it.
Okay. If that's the way you want it.
We might even provide you with a
little company on
your way up the river.
That wife of Luther
Coleman's... what was her name?
- Alva.
That's it. Alva Coleman.
Pretty fair grifter in her time.
Snyder's given us quite
a folder on her.
Nothing major by itself, but...
put 'em all together, it
could add up to a lot of years.
- You stink, mister.
- Don't be a sap.
It's not her I want.
If you're too
dumb to save yourself...
there's no sense dragging
her down with ya.
It's over, Hooker.
You can save me a lot of trouble.
But I'm gonna get Henry Gondorff
whether you help me out or not.
- You'll wait till the chump
is played? - Hell, yes.
We don't care about the
mark. He deserves what he gets.
I mean completely played.
You come in before we beat
him, and I'll kill him.
All right, Hooker.
But you try to take it on the lam,
and we'll shoot you down on sight.
As long as I get to finish the play.
What is it, kid? You're
not saying much.
- Just got the jumps.
- Come in.
Things are a little slow. I wanna
open the round for the girls.
Sure.
Take it easy, kid. We're
not gonna lose him now.
We had him ten years ago when
he decided to be somebody.
Believe me, I've
seen enough to know. Ten.
- Twenty.
- Thirty.
- Go. -
Thirty-one.
How many guys you
conned in your life, Henry?
I don't know. Two, three hundred.
Sometimes we played two a
day when I was with O'Shea's mob.
Of course, Chicago
was a rigged town.
The fix was in. The dicks took
their end without a beef.
We had it down to a business.
And it really stunk, kid.
No sense in bein' a grifter if it's
the same thing as bein' a citizen.
I got packin' to do. I'm gonna be
a hot number again after tomorrow.
I wouldn't ask you to do this,
you know, if it weren't for Luther.
Nothin's gonna make up for
Luther. Revenge is for suckers.
I've been griftin' 30
years. I never got any.
Then why're you doin' it?
It seems worthwhile, doesn't it?
See ya.
Looks like he missed you.
Yeah, yeah. This time, anyway.
Good night, Mrs. Hillard.
I was wonderin' if you might
want to come out for a while...
maybe have a drink or something.
You move right along, don't you?
Hey, I don't mean nothin' by it.
I just don't know
many regular girls, is all.
And you expect me to
come out just like that?
If I expected somethin', I wouldn't
still be standin' here in the hall.
I don't even know you.
You know me. I'm just like you.
It's 2:00 in the
morning, and I don't know nobody.
Come on, Henry. Knock off.
You've done everything you can.
- Yeah? Polk.
- Polk, this is Hooker.
- Ready?
- Yeah, go ahead.
Everything's all set. There'll
be a guy or two at the door.
Nobody's carrying any heaters, so
you shouldn't have any trouble.
Okay. See you there.
She was gonna kill you,
kid. Her name's Loretta Salino.
Lonnegan's people set her
up in the diner. Come on.
Let's get out of here.
Come on!
She could have killed me last night.
Too many people could
have seen you go in her room.
She was a real professional. Used
to work in the Dutch Schultz mob.
Who are you?
Gondorff asked me to look after you.
Snyder, we just got a
tip that Gondorff's mark...
is some big New York wheel.
As soon as we're inside, you
get him out of there fast...
before the reporters show up.
I don't want any big shots
around to mess this up for me.
All right, let's go!
Let's go, guys!
The flag is up, kid.
- Anytime, J. J.
- I'm workin' on it.
We got one, Billie. Here we go.
- Yeah?
- Place it on Lucky Dan...
third race at Riverside Park.
1:11 and 3/5ths seconds.
They were off at 21.
Last call on the
third at Riverside Park.
They're at the post.
At Havre De Grace, the
winner, Light Chatter...
paid 5.40, 3.80...
and 2.40.
- Blacksod... -
$500,000 to win.
Lucky Dan, third race at Riverside.
- Post time for the third race...
- You heard me.
- is 2:27.
- Hold on, sir.
- There's a jockey change...
- I'll get the manager.
in the fourth at Belmont.
Jay Stout will ride Flying Cross.
See that guy over there? He just bet
a half million dollars on Lucky Dan.
The winner at Rockingham Park...
Enfin, paid 6.10...
4.30 and 2.50.
What's your problem?
I'm putting half a million
dollars on Lucky Dan to win...
third race at Riverside.
Can't lay that off in time. A
bet like that could break us.
Not only are you a cheat...
you're a gutless cheat as well.
- What are the odds?
- Four to one.
Take all of it.
Ladies and
gentlemen, this is Arnold Rowe...
calling the third race at Riverside.
This is a claiming race for
$1,500 for three-year-olds and up.
It's been raining, and
the track is muddy.
The flag is up, and
they're off and running.
Dr. Twink is going to the front...
followed by Lucky
Dan, Ima Dreamer, Orkin...
Josie G., Chi Chi and Little Star.
Around the clubhouse
turn, it's Lucky Dan ahead...
Dr. Twink a length, Orkin a half...
followed by Ima Dreamer, Josie
G., Chi Chi and Little Star.
Into the backstretch...
it's Lucky Dan a
length, Dr. Twink a half...
Orkin a head, Ima Dreamer by one.
Sorry, I couldn't wait. Everything
going all right?
You got nothing to worry about.
- Dr. Twink a length, Orkin a half.
- I put it all on Lucky Dan.
Half a million dollars to win.
- Into the turn Lucky Dan still a
length. - To win?
I said place! Place
it on Lucky...
That horse is gonna run second!
Ima Dreamer a half, Dr.
Twink a half and Orkin by two,
followed by Little Star.
It's a driving finish!
There's been a
mistake. Give me my money back!
I tell you there's been a mistake!
Give me my goddamn money back!
All right, everybody.
F. B. I.! Don't anybody try to leave.
Stand on your feet,
put your hands over your
head and move nice and slow.
Snyder!
Get 'em up against the wall. Make
sure they're not carrying anything.
Hello, Henry. It's been a long time.
But it's over.
Okay, kid, you can go.
All right, I said
hands up. Keep 'em up!
Come on. Move 'em back! Put 'em up!
Get him out. Get him out!
Come on! Gotta get you out of here!
- Come on!
- But my money's in there!
There's a couple of dead guys
too. You can't get mixed up in that.
You don't understand. There's a
half a million dollars in there!
He's gone.
Okay, Henry, all clear.
Can you believe
it? We pulled it off.
It's a nice con, Hickey.
I thought you were the feds
myself when you came in.
No trouble, Henry. Snyder
went for it all the way.
You should've seen the
rag he lit under Lonnegan!
Well, kid, you beat him.
You're right,
Henry. It's not enough.
But it's close.
Okay, guys, let's take
this place apart fast.
You can pick up your splits
from Eddie at Boudreau's tonight.
Nice goin', J. J.
You're not gonna stick around
for your share?
Nah. I'd only blow it.
One, two.
One, two, three.