*** Tristar Pictures 1993 Production ***
Subtitle: Forest Yee
Mommy got sick.
It happened just like that.
There was nothing anybody could do.
It isn't fair.
There's no reason.
But if we start asking why,
we'll go crazy.
Five minutes in the microwave. Any one
of them. They're done. Ready to eat.
Do you know how to make juice?
Microwave. Five minutes.
Here.
My shrink. Call him.
"Loss of Spouse Support Group.
Chicago Cancer Family Network.
Parents Without Partners.
Partners Without Parents.
Hug Yourself. Hug a Friend.
Hug a Shrink. "
Or work. Work hard.
Work will save you. Work is the only
thing that will see you through this.
Don't mind him. He's just a guy
who's lost his wife.
What I think we really
need is a change.
Good idea. Take a couple of weeks off.
Get some sun. Take Jonah fishing.
No, a real change.
A new city.
Someplace where every time I go around
a corner I don't think of Maggie.
Where you gonna go?
I was thinking about Seattle.
Eventually, in a few months,
you'll start seeing women.
- You'll meet someone.
- Right.
Move on. Right.
That's what I'm gonna do.
And then in a few months, boom, I'll
be fine. I'll just grow a new heart.
- Sam, I'm sorry.
- She didn't mean that.
I know. Look,
it just doesn't happen twice.
You must remember this
A kiss is still a kiss
A sigh is just a sigh
The fundamental things apply
As time goes by
And when two lovers woo
They still say, I love you
On that you can rely
No matter what the future brings
As time goes by
Moonlight and love songs
Never out of date
Hearts full of passion
Jealousy and hate
Woman needs man
And man must have his mate
That no one can deny
It's still the same old story
A fight for love and glory
A case of do or die
The world will
always welcome lovers
As time
Goes by
The tall one with red hair
is your cousin Irene.
You'll recognize her by
the disappointed look on her face.
Who was married to Harold
who ran off with his secretary.
But came back because Irene threatened
to put the dog to sleep if he didn't.
Your brother Dennis
is a professor at Johns Hopkins.
He's married to Betsy.
The most competitive woman
in the world.
I don't see how
I'm gonna remember all this.
Oh, well, Walter, you will.
Your Uncle Milton
lost all of his money-
- And some other people's.
- In a pyramid scheme.
Don't mention the IRS
or the federal prison system.
Your mother's Barbara.
Your father's Cliff.
- My father has electric trains.
- Really?
Am I what they had in mind?
Oh, Walter,
they're gonna love you.
Everybody.
Annie has an announcement.
Walter and I are engaged.
Thank you. Thank you.
Dad, Mom knew.
- I don't see a ring, Annie.
- I don't have a ring yet.
Congratulations.
Bless you. Bless you.
- Oh, my goodness.
- Are you all right?
- It's nothing.
- Maybe it's the flowers.
- We'll move them.
- No! Don't touch them!
I feel terrible,
sneezing at a time like this.
This is a very
important moment for me.
He's allergic to everything.
Don't worry about it.
Bees. I'm allergic to bees.
Harold is allergic
to every type of bee.
We always have to carry a hypodermic
of adrenaline wherever we go.
If he eats even
one tiny piece of a nut-
My head swells up like
a watermelon, and I drop dead.
It's the same
with Harold and bees.
Your mother and I had salmon at our
wedding. A wedding without cold salmon-
- I'm not allergic to salmon.
- Oh, he's not allergic to salmon.
I don't think,
but you never know.
- You never know.
- Harold wasn't always allergic to bees.
Honey, what a shame. We had
some champagne. What did we use it for?
- Uncle Milton's parole.
- And it was delicious.
It was, wasn't it, Milton?
When are you getting married?
- In early June, in the garden.
- Does it have to be in the garden?
- What a great idea.
- What about Harold and bees?
- I'm allergic to bees.
- We'll spray you.
Cold salmon, a lovely
cucumber salad, strawberries.
I'm afraid I am allergic
to strawberries.
Allergic to strawberries.
Is this all right
with you, Walter?
Today I consider myself
the luckiest...
m- m-man on the f-f-face
of the E-E-Earth.
The Lou Gehrig line.
Remember? Remember, Dad?
- The Lou Gehrig line from-
- Pride of the Yankees.
- Pride of the Yankees!
- It's baseball.
- A historical reference.
I would like to propose a toast
to my kid sister.
To Walter and my baby.
To Walter and Annie.
Everyone, please eat
before it gets cold.
Here it is.
The historical society wanted this,
and I never would give it to them.
Oh, Mom!
I noticed these things
are back in fashion.
- Grandmother's dress.
- Oh, honey.
He's a lovely man, Annie.
I know. He is wonderful, isn't he?
And he's such a wonderful athlete.
- Are his folks nice?
- You'll love them.
We're going down to D.C. Tonight
to be with them Christmas morning.
- How did it happen?
- Well, it's silly, really.
I'd seen him at the office.
Obviously, I'd seen him.
He's the associate publisher.
One day we both ordered sandwiches
from the same place.
He got my lettuce and tomato on wheat,
which, of course, he was allergic to.
And I got his lettuce
and tomato on white.
- How amazing.
- It is, isn't it?
You make a million decisions
that mean nothing.
Then one day you order takeout,
and it changes your life.
Destiny takes a hand.
Mom, destiny is
something we've invented...
because we can't stand the fact that
everything that happens is accidental.
How do you explain that you both ordered
the same sandwich except for the bread?
How many people in this world
like lettuce and tomato...
without something else like tuna?
Well, it wasn't a sign.
It was a coincidence.
I was in Atlantic City with my family.
Cliff was a waiter.
He wasn't even supposed to work
that night, and suppose he hadn't?
He asked me to take a midnight walk
on the Steel Pier.
I've probably told you this
a million times, but I don't care.
Then he held my hand.
At one point I looked down
and I couldn't tell...
which fingers were his
and which were mine.
And I knew.
- What?
- You know.
- Magic.
It was magic.
Magic?
I knew we'd be together forever and
that everything would be wonderful...
just the way you feel about Walter.
Walter? It's quite
a formal name, isn't it?
One of the things I truly knew
was that your father and I...
were going to have
a wonderful time in-
- The sack, I believe you call it.
- Mom!
Of course, it took
several years before everything...
worked like clockwork
in that department.
So don't be worried
if it takes a while.
- Well, we already-
- Fine. Fine. Fiddle-de-dee.
- How's it working?
- Like clockwork.
Oh, honey.
- It's a sign.
- You don't believe in signs.
They loved you! I told you they
would love you, and they loved you!
- I love you.
- I love you, Walter.
Did anyone ever call you
anything other than Walter?
Nope.
Not even when you were young?
Nope, not even when I was young.
You sure you don't
want to drive with me?
How will I get back
to Baltimore on Friday?
I forgot the present. I left your
stepmother's present inside by accident.
When we're old and gray, you're gonna
have to remind me to put my teeth in.
I'll be walking all over town, smacking
my gums together and not even noticing.
- I'll wait.
- You'll wait? Oh! Right.
Don't wait. It's silly.
Go ahead. We're late anyway.
I'll be ten minutes behind you.
Sleigh bells jing-a-ling
Ring-ting-ting-a-ling too
Horses, horses, horses
It's lovely weather
for a sleigh ride together with you
Giddyap, giddyap, giddyap
The snow is falling
and friends are calling, Yoo-hoo
Friends are calling, Yoo-hoo
Ding-a-ling-a-ling
Horses, horses, horses
Jingle bells, jingle bells
Jingle all the way
Oh, what fun it is to ride
in a one-horse open sleigh
Jingle bells
- Horses, horses, horses
- Welcome to "You and Your Emotions. "
- Laughing all the way
- I'm Dr. Marcia Fieldstone...
broadcasting live across America from
the top of the Sears Tower in Chicago.
Tonight we're talking
about wishes and dreams.
- What's your wish this Christmas Eve?
- What's your wish?
- Maybe the best gift you can give your-
- My wish is to turn the radio station.
Subject of this evening's medical update
is "You and Your Spleen. "
- Your host is-
- Not on your life.
Coming up, "Jingle Bells" backwards,
sung by the New Jersey-
- Seattle, go ahead.
- Hello, this is Jonah-
No last names, Jonah.
You sound younger than
our usual callers. How old are you?
- I'm eight.
- Eight. How come you're up so late?
- It's not that late in Seattle.
- Of course. You're absolutely right.
What's your Christmas wish, Jonah?
It's not for me. It's for my dad.
I think he needs a new wife.
- You don't like the one he has now?
- He doesn't have one now.
That's the problem.
- Where's your mom?
- She died.
- I'm so sorry to hear that.
- Well, who can believe this?
I've been pretty sad,
but I think my dad's worse.
Have you talked
to your dad about this?
- No.
- Why not?
- It's like it makes him sadder.
- I can understand that.
- Jonah, is your dad home right now?
- Yeah.
- What's he doing? Is he busy?
- Not really. He's out on the deck.
I'm sure that I can help, but I'm
going to need you to help me help him.
- Wretched woman!
- Bring your dad to the phone.
- Hang up, Jonah! Don't listen to her.
- No way. He'd kill me.
Trust me, Jonah.
He won't be angry...
when he realizes
how concerned you are about him.
Wanna bet?
If I get yelled at, I'm never
going to listen to your show again.
Fair enough.
- Dad?
- Yeah?
There's someone
on the phone for you.
- His name's Sam.
- Sam.
If you've just tuned in,
this is Dr. Marcia Fieldstone.
Tonight's topic is
"Your Wishes and Dreams. "
- I got it.
- We're on the line with Seattle.
- Hello?
- Hello, Sam.
This is Dr. Marcia Fieldstone
on Network America.
What are you selling tonight?
Micro hibachis or Ginza knives?
I'm not selling anything.
I just want to help.
I want you to know
that your son called...
and he asked me for advice
on how you might find a new wife.
- Who is this?
- Dr. Fieldstone of Network America.
- You are on the air.
- You called a radio station?
- Sam? Sam? Sam, are you with me?
- Yeah. Yes.
Your son feels that since your wife's
death you've been very, very unhappy.
He's genuinely worried about you.
Oh, hey, get out here.
Get out here.
I'm not gonna
go through this alone.
I think it's very hard for him
to talk to you about all this.
I thought maybe you and I could talk.
It would make Jonah feel better.
- Sam?
- Talk to her, Dad. She's a doctor.
Of what?
Her first name could be Doctor.
- Please?
- Sam?
Sam, it's his Christmas wish.
- Okay.
- Okay, good.
I know this is difficult.
But how long ago
did your wife die?
About a year and a half ago.
Have you had
any relationships since?
- Nope.
- No?
Why not?
Marcia- Or should
I call you Dr. Fieldstone?
- Dr. Marcia.
- I don't mean to be rude.
- I don't want to invade your privacy.
- Oh, sure you do.
- Sure you do.
Go on, Sam.
I'm listening.
Sam?
We had a pretty
tough time there at first.
But we're dealing with it.
And Jonah and I will
get along just fine again...
as soon as I break his radio.
I have no doubt that
you're a wonderful father.
- You can tell a lot from a voice.
- You certainly can.
But something must be missing if
Jonah still feels you're under a cloud.
Just a few questions.
Are you sleeping at night?
- He doesn't sleep at all.
- How do you know that?
I live here.
Look, it's Christmas.
Maggie, my wife-
She really did it.
I mean, she loved-
She made everything beautiful.
And it's just tough
this time of year.
Any kid needs a mother.
Could it be that you need someone
just as much as Jonah does?
Yes.
Don't answer that. Let's get into that
right after these messages.
Sam, Jonah, don't go away.
If you've just tuned in,
we're talking to Sleepless in Seattle.
We'll be right back after this break
with your listener response.
What's she talking about?
This is when other people get to call in
and dump on what you said.
Oh, oh. This is really fun,
and helpful.
I'll bet he's tall
with a cute butt.
Bet he hasn't bathed in weeks
and he stinks.
Harriet, shut up.
Hi. Can I help you?
Tea with the bag out.
Maybe I'll hustle myself out to Seattle.
Give him a gift for New Year's Eve.
You go on out there if you want to,
but don't open his refrigerator.
They don't cover anything
when they put it in the fridge.
They just stick it in there and
leave it till it walks out by itself.
What I'm saying is, I wouldn't kick this
guy out of my bed for eating crackers.
You know what I'm saying?
Sixty-five cents.
Let's take a call
before we get back to Sleepless.
Knoxville, Tennessee,
you're on the air. Talk to me.
Yes, I would just like to know
where I could get this man's address.
- Honey, get in line.
- We don't give that information.
Next caller, go ahead.
If there was one question
I was allowed to ask-
Oh, go ahead.
People who truly loved once
are far more likely to love again.
Do you think there's someone out there
you could love as much as your wife?
Well, Dr. Marcia Fieldstone,
that's hard to imagine.
What are you going to do?
Well, I'm going to get
out of bed every morning...
breathe in and out all day long.
Then after a while
I won't have to remind myself...
to get out of bed in the morning
and breathe in and out.
And then after a while
I won't have to think about how...
I had it great and perfect
for a while.
Sam, tell me what was
so special about your wife?
Well, how long is your program?
Oh, well, it was a-
It was a million
tiny little things.
When you added them all up, it just
meant we were supposed to be together.
And I knew it. I knew it
the very first time I touched her.
It was like coming home...
only to no home I'd ever known.
I was just taking her hand...
to help her out of a car...
and I knew it.
It was like-
- Magic.
Well, folks,
it's time to wrap it up.
I'm Dr. Marcia Fieldstone
in Chicago.
And to all my listeners,
a magical and merry Christmas.
And to you, Sleepless in Seattle,
we hope you'll call again soon.
- Let us know how it's going.
- Oh, you can count on it.
When you find me
I know somewhere
Over the rainbow
The bluebirds glide
Birds fly
Over the rainbow
Why, then, oh, why
Can't I
This man sells the greatest soup
you've ever eaten...
and he is the meanest man
in America.
I feel very strongly about this, Becky.
It's not just about the soup.
- Do it. What else?
- New Year's Eve.
- Please don't make me write it.
- Listen to this.
"Phone service in the greater Chicago
area was tied up for two hours...
Christmas Eve when some kid
calls a phone-in radio show...
and says that his dad
needs a new wife.
Two thousand women called the station
asking for the guy's number. "
I heard it. This kid calls up
and says, "My dad needs a wife. "
This shrink forces the guy to the phone
and says, "You want to talk about it?"
He says, "No,
as a matter of fact, I don't. "
Suddenly, for no reason at all, he talks
about how much he loved his wife...
and how he just
fell in love with her...
like he was one
of those cows in Michigan.
- What cows in Michigan?
- It was on 60 Minutes.
There were those cows
that got zapped by stray voltage.
No one knows why.
Maybe it was Wisconsin.
But anyway, I was listening to him
talk about how much he loved his wife...
and suddenly I was crying.
It's like what happens when
I watch those phone company ads.
I don't have to see the whole thing,
just the part where...
the daughter gives the mother the
refrigerator with the big red bow on it.
The Polaroid commercial. Two 5-year-olds
at their grandfather's birthday party.
- They're making the album.
- With the glue.
That kills me.
You should write
something about this.
- About what?
- Whatever it is.
I'll tell you. Two thousand women
calling a radio station for a husband.
There are a lot of desperate women
out there lookin' for love.
Especially over a certain age.
It's easier to be killed by a terrorist
than get married over the age of 40.
That is not true.
That statistic is not true.
That's right. It's not true.
But it feels true.
It feels true
because it is true.
There's practically a whole book
about how that's not true.
- Calm down. You brought it up.
- I did not, Wyatt.
- Did you even read that book?
- Did anyone read it all the way through?
Are you two finished?
Fine. Now where were we?
If someone is a widower,
why do they say that he was widowed?
Why don't they say
he was widowered?
I was just wondering.
What was that about up there?
- What was what?
- What's with you?
- Nothing's with me.
- Something's with you.
- What are you saying?
- Whatever it is, you can tell me.
Sleepless in Seattle?
That's what she called him on the show
because he can't sleep.
And now 2,000 women
want his number.
The guy could be a crackhead,
a transvestite...
a flasher, a junkie,
a chain-saw murderer...
or someone really sick,
someone like my Rick.
- Actually, he sounded nice.
- Oh?
Oh, really?
Now we're getting down to it.
Please. Becky,
I'm madly in love with Walter.
He did the craziest thing
the other night. What was that?
Oh, it was so funny.
We were hysterical. What was that?
You know, I've got to go to Boston
for the convention, right?
Then I got to visit Winston-Hughes
about switching over our computers.
But why don't we meet in New York
for Valentine's Day weekend?
Walter, I'd love to!
We can stay at the Plaza.
Ice-stake in Central Park.
Register.
Register?
You know, for dishes,
glasses, silver, everything.
How about it?
I'll take you to Chinatown
for dim sum.
- Does it have wheat in it?
- I don't think so.
Dim sum, dim sum
Ten, nine, eight, seven, six...
five, four, three, two, one!
Hey, Jonah. Wake up. Wake up, man.
The ball's droppin'.
Happy new year!
Okay, pal. I got ya.
It's okay.
There we go.
Happy new year.
Kiss Howard.
Good night, Howard.
Sometimes I wonder
Why I spend
The lonely night
Dreaming of a song
The melody
Haunts my reverie
And I am once again with you
When our love was new
And each kiss an inspiration
But that was long ago
Now my consolation
Is in the stardust of a song
Beside the garden wall
When stars are bright
You are in my arms
The nightingale
Tells his fairy tale
Of paradise where roses bloom
Can I have half your beer?
Sure. Go ahead.
What did I used to say?
"Here's looking at you"?
"Here's mud in your eye"?
"Here's to us. "
You used to say, "Here's to us. "
Oh, babe.
I miss you so much it hurts.
- What do you want to do?
- We'll tell him when he gets here.
You want to tell him.
I don't mind telling him.
- She's here.
- She's back. She has another idea.
I don't need-
Claire, how are you?
I'm so glad you're here.
I heard you on the radio.
- I told everyone about it.
- We already knew.
- How did you-
- Grace.
The dispatcher?
All of Seattle knows.
I was brushing my teeth
and suddenly there you were.
I couldn't believe my ears.
I called my mother in Las Vegas.
I said, "Mother, turn on the radio.
That's my architect. "
It is so nice...
when a man
can express his feelings.
- It's wonderful.
- I wish I could express my feelings.
- So, Claire, is there a problem?
- I was tossing and turning last night.
I realized I'm never going to fit my
platters in the refrigerator we ordered.
When I give parties,
I always put in platters.
So I thought I would get the Sub-Zero
refrigerator instead. The only problem-
We have to redo all the cabinets.
- We'll be into this wall.
- That's a bearing wall.
That's a delay, Claire, of-
- Two, three-
- Five, six-
- Twelve weeks.
- I don't mind.
The important thing
is to get it right.
- Absolutely.
- Your words.
I've got to rush.
La d¨¦corateur calls.
- Bye!
- Bye-bye.
Well, this is fate.
She's divorced.
We don't want to redo the cabinets,
and you need a wife.
What do they call that
when everything intersects?
The Bermuda Triangle.
And here's another one.
You got room for one more here?
There you go.
You all right there?
- Look at this, Dad. They're all for you.
- Yes, sir. There you go.
"Sleepless in Seattle.
In care of Dr. Marcia Fieldstone"?
If you have trouble sleeping, drink
a glass of water from the other side.
- I thought that was for hiccups.
- Does it work for hiccups?
For hiccups, take a spoonful of sugar
and hold it in your mouth for a minute.
- Really?
- Thank you.
What possessed you
to give them our address?
They called and asked for it.
"Dear Sleepless in Seattle...
You're the most attractive man
I ever laid ears on. "
Wait, wait, wait. They called?
How did they get our number?
Let me guess.
You gave it to them.
You have to give them your phone number,
or they won't let you on the air.
"Dear Sleepless in Seattle,
I live in Tulsa. "
- Where's that?
- It's in Oklahoma.
- Do you know where Oklahoma is?
- Somewhere in the middle.
I'm not even gonna think about
what they're not teaching you in school.
Yeah, it's somewhere
in the middle.
Generally speaking, we should rule out
anyone that doesn't live near here.
She's willing to fly anywhere.
She looks like my third grade teacher.
I hated my third grade teacher.
Wait a minute.
She is my third grade teacher!
- Aren't you gonna read any of these?
- This is not how it's done.
I'd much rather
just see somebody I like...
and get a feeling about them...
and ask them
if they want to have a drink.
- Or a slice of pizza?
- Not dinner.
Not necessarily on the first date.
Halfway through dinner you could be
really sorry you asked them to dinner.
Whereas, if it's just a drink...
if you like them,
you could always ask them to dinner.
But if not, you can just say,
"Well, that was great. "
And then you go home.
See what I mean?
I wonder if
it still works this way.
- It doesn't. They ask you.
- I'm starting to notice that.
If you get a new wife, I guess
you'll have sex with her, huh?
I certainly hope so.
- Will she scratch up your back?
- What?
In movies, women are always scratching
up the man's back and screaming.
- How do you know this?
- Jed's got cable.
Oh, Jed's got cable.
Hand me that towel
behind you, please.
- Thank you.
- I need it too.
Here. Let me get you.
Jed's got cable.
Another bride
Another groom
Another sunny honeymoon
Another season
And that's the reason
for makin' whoopee
When the sun is high
in the afternoon sky
You can always
find something to do
But from dusk till dawn
as the clock ticks on
Something happens to you
In the wee small hours
Of the morning
While the whole wide world
Is fast asleep
You lie awake
And think about the boy
And never ever think
Of counting sheep
Welcome back to
the "Best of Dr. Marcia Fieldstone"...
clinical psychologist
and the friend you never had.
- Remember Marooned in Miami?
- He says he doesn't love me anymore.
Why would you want to be
with someone who doesn't love you?
Disappointed in Denver.
Every time I come close to orgasm,
he goes to make himself a sandwich.
Why don't you make him
a sandwich beforehand?
Sleepless in Seattle.
Well, I'm going to get
out of bed every morning...
and breathe in and out all day long.
Then after a while
I won't have to remind myself...
to get out of bed in the morning
and breathe in and out.
And then after a while
I won't have to think about how...
I had it great and perfect
for a while.
Sam, tell me what was
so special about your wife?
Well, how long is your program?
Oh, well, it was a-
It was a million
tiny little things.
When you added them all up, it just
meant we were supposed to be together.
And I knew it. I knew it
the very first time I touched her.
It was like coming home...
only to no home I'd ever known.
I was just taking her hand...
to help her out of a car...
and I knew it.
It was like...
magic.
I think I'm going crazy, Dennis.
Are you happily married?
- What?
- I mean, why did you get married?
Was it all trumpets
and fireworks?
I got married because Betsy said
we had to break up or get married...
so we got married.
But when you first met her...
did you believe
she was the only person for you?
That in some mystical,
cosmic way it was fated?
Annie, when you're
attracted to someone...
it just means that your subconscious
is attracted to their subconscious...
subconsciously.
What we think of as fate is two neuroses
knowing they're a perfect match.
I don't even know him.
I am having all of these fantasies
about some man I have never even met...
who lives in Seattle!
It rains nine months
of the year in Seattle.
I know! I know!
I do not want to move to Seattle.
But what I really don't want
to do is end up always wondering...
what might have happened
and knowing I could have done something.
What do you think?
It's just cold feet, isn't it?
Everybody panics before
they get married. Didn't you?
- I did.
- You did.
Thank you very much, Dennis. I feel so
much better just having blown this off.
Anytime.
Sandy has a girlfriend, Glenda.
She's a weight lifter.
It's not like her neck
is bigger than her head.
I'm not asking you to set me up.
I don't need your help with that.
I just want to know
what it's like out there.
That's what I'm trying to tell you,
what women are lookin' for.
Pecs and a cute butt.
- Like, "He has the cutest butt"?
- Yeah.
- Where did I hear that recently?
- Everywhere.
You can't even turn on the news
nowadays without hearing about...
how some babe thought
some guy's butt was cute.
Who the first woman to say this was,
I don't know. But it caught on.
So how's my butt?
- Not bad.
- Really?
- Is it cute though?
- I don't know.
Are we grading on a curve?
When's the last time
you were out there?
Jimmy Carter, 1978.
Things are
a little different now.
First you have to be friends.
You have to like each other.
Then you neck.
This could go on for years.
Then you have tests.
Then you get to do it with a condom.
The good news is,
you split the check.
I don't think I could
let a woman pay for dinner.
Great. They'll throw
a parade in your honor.
You'll be man of the year
in Seattle magazine.
Tiramisu.
- What is tiramisu?
- You'll find out.
- What is it?
- You'll see.
Some woman will want me to do it to her.
I'm not going to know what it is.
You'll love it.
This is going to be tough.
Tough, tough.
This is going to be much tougher
than I thought it was going to be.
How about that decorator
on the Bennett job?
- Victoria?
- Yeah, she's perk.
- No, I don't-
- Come on!
I'm far away from that.
- I'm just assembling notes.
- Notes.
- How would I do that?
- What do you mean? Call her up.
You say, "Let's get together.
We'll look at swatches. "
Call her on the phone?
Say, "Let's look at swatches"?
- Color schemes.
- She's not gonna see through that?
You don't do it like I do it.
You do it in your own suave way.
Think Cary Grant.
Cary Grant would say,
"Come look at my swatches"?
Maybe he did. I know
he didn't do it in the movies.
Gunga Din?
Gunga Din is not
a swatch kind of movie.
Who knows what
he did in real life?
But he did that
with Dyan Cannon?
"Hello, Dyan.
Take a look at these swatches. "
Jonah, I'm home.
Hey, Jonah!
Hi, Dad. This is Jessica.
Well, it's nice
to meet you, Jessica.
Dad, this is amazing. If you play this
backwards, it says, "Paul is dead. "
Yeah, I know.
How do you know?
Dad, could you shut the door?
Sure. Sure.
H and G.
Hi and good-bye.
I'm back in the saddle again
Out where a friend is a friend
Where the longhorn cattle feed
on the lowly jimsonweed
Back in the saddle again
Ridin' the range once more
Totin' my old. 44
Where you sleep out every night
Hello, Victoria?
This is Sam Baldwin.
I don't know if you remember me, but-
Oh, great. Hi.
I was wondering if-
if you would like
to have a drink with me?
Dinner?
Dinner would be even better.
Friday would be great.
Yeah. How-
I hear that's a good place.
How- 7:30 would be fine.
And I'Il-
Okay, I'll meet you there. Okay.
So it's Friday...
at 7:30 for dinner.
Great.
Me too. Bye.
Back in the saddle again
Are you in love with him?
I'm not now.
Now those were the days
when people knew how to be in love.
- You're a basket case.
- They knew it.
Time, distance, nothing could separate
them, because they knew it was right.
- It was real. It was-
- A movie.
That's your problem.
You don't want to be in love.
You want to be
in love in a movie.
Read it to me.
"Dear Sleepless and Son, I have never
written a letter like this in my life. "
That's what everyone writes at
the beginning of letters to strangers.
I know that.
You think I don't know that?
What about Walter?
Walter. Oh, I would
give anything to marry Walter.
He's so unexpected.
You think you can tell what he's like
by just looking at him, but you can't.
I should write something
in this about magic.
- What?
- Something.
What if I never meet him? What if this
man is my destiny and I never meet him?
Your destiny can be your doom.
Look at me and Rick.
"I want to meet you-"
- The top of the Empire State Building?
- The top of the Empire State Building.
That's perfect.
Sunset, Valentine's Day.
I'll be in New York with Walter.
I can squeeze it in.
Do you want to
hear about destiny?
If I hadn't married Martin, I wouldn't
have had the house with the dead tree.
On account of which,
I got divorced.
On account of which, I hit a car
and met Rick while buying a neck brace.
Wait. You never told me you got
a divorce because of a dead tree.
The tree man.
You fell in love
with the tree man?
I did not say "love. "
Did I say "love"?
This is my favorite part.
It's now or never.
"Never" is a frightening word.
We'd be fools
to let happiness pass us by.
Winter must be cold
for those with no warm memories.
We've already missed the spring.
Men never get this movie.
I know.
Mommy! Mommy!
It's okay. I'm here.
- Dad!
- I'm comin'.
It's all right. It's okay.
What was that about?
- It was sinking.
- What was?
Our house. There was water
coming in all the windows.
Well, it's okay now.
It's all right.
So what should we do?
Your mother used to...
sing to you
when you had bad dreams.
"Bye-Bye, Blackbird. "
I miss her.
What do you think happens
to someone after they die?
- I don't know.
- Like, do you believe in heaven?
I never did.
Or the whole idea of an afterlife,
but now I don't know.
'Cause I have
these dreams about-
about your mom.
And we have long talks...
about you,
how you're doin'.
Which she sort of knows,
but I tell her anyway.
So what is that?
It's sort of an afterlife,
isn't it?
I'm starting to forget her.
She could peel an apple...
in one long...
curly strip.
The whole apple.
Pack up all my cares and woes
Feelin' low
Here I go
I say bye-bye
I love you, Jonah.
I love you, Dad.
See you tomorrow.
Sugar's sweet
So is she
I say bye
Bye
Blackbird
No one seems to love
Or understand me now
Oh, and hard luck stories
They keep handin' me, yeah
Where somebody shines a light
I'm comin' on home tonight now
Oh, Lord
Yeah, darlin'
I wanna say
Bye-bye, blackbird
Lord have mercy
Somebody love me now
Laurie?
Hi, it's Annie.
Fine. I'm fine.
Listen. I'm doing an article
on call-in radio shows.
Do you know anyone who works for
someone named Dr. Marcia Fieldstone?
I'm a writer for the Baltimore Sun
and a friend of Laurie Johnson's.
I'm doing a piece on how
people handle bereavement...
and I understand you had a caller
the other night, some guy from Seattle.
This is Jonah Baldwin. We're not in
right now, but you can leave-
Architect.
Okay, Clarise, I'm gonna be back
either by midnight...
or 8:30, if disaster strikes.
Here's one for both of us.
- "Sleepless and Son, Baltimore. "
- I left the restaurant's phone number.
If there's a problem, the pediatrician's
number is right above the phone.
Here's a bottle of ipecac if anybody
drinks poison. By the juice glasses.
- Fine.
- How do I look?
- Great.
- Do I look okay?
Do I look all right? I look stupid.
I look like I'm tryin' too hard.
I was gonna get a haircut,
but then I'd look like I got one.
- This is a good letter, Dad.
- The heels on these shoes are grotesque.
Looks like
I'm tryin' to be tall.
Her name is Annie.
Annie Reed.
- Bye.
- Read this!
Read this!
"Dear Sleepless and Son,
I've never written-" Blah, blah.
"I've been an excellent third baseman
for as long as I remember...
and while we're on the subject,
let's just say that...
Brooks Robinson
was the best third baseman ever.
It's important you agree with me,
because I'm from Baltimore. "
She thinks Brooks Robinson's
the greatest. So do you.
- Everyone thinks he's the greatest.
- It's a sign.
Come here.
I'll show you a sign.
Here's a sign.
All right.
Where is Seattle?
Right.
Where is Baltimore?
It's right there! Look!
One, two, three, four- There's like
26 states between here and there.
Now that's a sign.
I'm outta here.
Good-bye. Good night.
I love you.
Clarise, did you move your car?
- Thank you, Derrick.
- You're welcome.
- I'll have-
- White wine?
- And you, sir?
- I'm fine, thank you.
- You look good.
- You look good yourself.
- I thought you were never gonna call me.
- You did?
But I really wanted you to,
and I thought you were never going to.
- Excuse me, Mr. Baldwin?
- Yes?
There's a phone call for you.
Thank you.
Hello?
Dad, can we go to New York City
for Valentine's Day?
What?
Annie Reed from Baltimore
wants to meet us...
at the top of the Empire State Building
on Valentine's Day.
- Jonah.
- What?
Have you fallen down?
Are you bleeding?
Is Clarise there?
Has she been strangled?
So this is the only reason
for this phone call?
If we book now,
we can get an excursion fare.
Jessica's parents are travel agents,
and Jessica says-
I'm not going to have
this conversation now.
We will talk about it
at a later time.
I can't believe this conversation
has lasted this long. You go to bed.
Everything all right?
Oh, yeah.
Do you have kids?
- No.
- Want mine?
I will have an Absolut
straight up, please.
Sure.
Put that down! Stop it!
There she is.
- Why is she bringing those groceries?
- She's cooking for us, so be prepared.
Hi, Sam. Thanks.
Thanks.
And let me guess.
You must be Jonah.
- This it?
- Yeah.
- The car's down this way.
- Great.
She's on her sixth painter...
and we're never
gonna finish this job.
Now she wants
the fireplace re-bricked.
I know her pretty well.
I could give her a call.
I've got it solved. I'm just gonna hit
her with one of those fireplace bricks.
Oh, that is so funny.
You are so funny.
Whenever she wants anything done,
she does this song and dance about...
"I don't know. I'm stupid.
You tell me.
You know better than I,
but couldn't we flip the house...
so everything on one side is now on the
other, and the back becomes the front?
Could the whole house
open up on a hinge?
That way I could just get in
with the garage door opener. "
I just say, "Yeah, we can do that.
We're just gonna have to-"
"Move the kitchen cabinets. "
Jonah, bring that stuff.
Do you like baseball?
Yes, I do.
My firm has box seats to the Mariners.
Why don't we all go sometime?
- What about camping?
- What about it?
- Do you like camping?
- I went camping once.
You know what?
We oughta start camping more often.
You're right. Camping is good.
Time for bed.
- It's only 10:00.
- Yeah, 10:00.
Time for bed.
Good night.
Don't you wanna thank Victoria
for this delicious dinner?
Thanks for dinner. I never saw
anybody cook potatoes that way.
I'm glad you liked it.
Good night, Jonah.
Yeah, we don't see
a lot of potatoes around here.
We're rice men.
I'm sorry, Walter.
I'm sorry.
- Hello?
- Turn on your radio.
- What?
- The kid is on.
You've got me
listening to this garbage.
Who is it?
It's Becky. She's-
She's having trouble with Rick again.
I'll go downstairs, Becky.
I'll call you back.
I'm sorry, Walter.
Are you bleeding?
- He's kissing her right this minute!
- Oh, really?
Jonah, tell the truth.
Are you spying on your father?
- Who's he kissing right this minute?
- Listen to this.
I have to make them stop.
- How am I gonna explain this to Walter?
- She came over and cooked dinner.
She brought two bags of groceries,
like she was staying for a year.
Jonah, it's good
that your father's dating.
It's just hard on you.
It's something you think you want.
- Then when it happens, it scares you.
- That's not true.
Think. Shouldn't your father
be the judge...
of whether someone is right
or wrong for him?
He's not sane enough
to judge anything.
Now he's kissing her on the lips.
She's a 'ho!
My dad's been captured by a 'ho!
What am I going to do?
Calm down, Jonah.
Tomorrow morning when you're
having breakfast with your dad...
tell him how you feel.
It's not good to keep
your feelings inside you.
Miss Scarlet. In the broom closet.
With the radio.
You scared me.
Don't ever do that again.
- I thought I saw a black widow.
- You scared me to death!
- You scared Victoria to death.
- It was right over there.
The next time you think you see a
black widow spider, I want you to say...
"Dad, excuse me, but I believe
a poisonous insect is in the house"...
and I will calmly come
and take care of it.
Scream again, I'll kill you.
Becky heard this guy on the radio she
was sure was Rick. She was hysterical.
And then it turned out
the guy lived in Duluth.
- Where is Duluth?
- That doesn't make any sense.
I know, Walter.
It doesn't make any sense at all.
Thank God my life is in place.
Duluth? That's in North Dakota.
I love this letter.
You have to write to her.
- You think so?
- It's Y.O.H.
Yeah. What's that?
Your only hope.
I thought I would look into
doing a story on those radio shows.
You'd probably have to go somewhere
to really look into it.
Definitely.
Couldn't you do
a phone interview?
Not for the kind of piece I wanna do.
I won't be in Chicago that long.
When you get back, I'll be gone.
And then I'll see you in New York.
I'll get it.
This is Captain Browning.
We're at our cruising altitude
of approximately 35,000 feet.
The weather is clear to the west, and we
expect to arrive in Seattle on schedule.
- Don't you hate flying?
- Yes, I do.
And I just told the most terrible one
to the man I'm about to marry.
Do you feel that
any lie is a betrayal?
I said "flying. "
Thanks for bringing me out here.
Well, he likes the planes.
Can I bring something back for you?
A souvenir? Does he like snow globes?
You shake them up
and then the snow floats down.
Sure. I'd really like that.
Thank you so much.
- He's eight.
- He's good at it.
I read an article about this.
All children are hideous at age eight.
It's quite normal.
Well, maybe when I come back...
the two of us oughta spend
some time together on our own.
What do you think?
Bye.
Bye, Jonah.
Listen to me.
You don't know Victoria.
I hardly know her myself.
She is, in fact,
a mystery to me.
She tosses her hair a lot.
Why does she do this?
I have no idea. Is it a twitch?
Does she need a haircut?
Should she use a barrette
to keep her hair out of her face?
These are things I'm willing
to get to the bottom of.
And that is why I am dating her.
That's all I'm doing.
I'm not living with her.
I'm not marrying her.
Can you appreciate
the difference?
This is what single people do.
They try other people on
and see how they fit.
But everybody's an adjustment.
Nobody's perfect.
There's no such thing
as a perfect-
Come on.
Dad, I was talking to Jessica
about reincarnation.
She says you knew Annie
in another life.
- Who's Annie?
- The one who wrote us.
But Jessica says you and Annie
never got together in that life.
So your hearts are like puzzles
with missing pieces.
And when you get together,
the puzzle's complete.
Goddamn it.
The reason I know this and you don't
is because I'm younger and purer...
so I'm more in touch
with cosmic forces.
- Who told you this stuff?
- Jessica.
I sincerely hope
you're not marrying Jessica.
I remember the days
of just keepin' time
Of hangin' around
in sleepy towns
Forever
Back roads empty for miles
Well, you can't have a dream
and cut it to fit
But when I saw you
I knew
We'd go together
Like a wink and a smile
Leave your old jalopy
By the railroad track
We'll get a hip
double-dip, tip-toppy
Two-seat Pontiac
So you can rev her up
Don't go slow
It's only green lights
and all rights
Let's go together
With a wink and a smile
Give me a wink and a smile
We go together
Like a wink and a smile
Now my heart hears music
Such a simple song
Sing it again
The notes never end
This is where I belong
Just the sound of your voice
The light in your eyes
We're so far away
from yesterday
Together
With a wink and a smile
We go together
Like a wink and a smile
- I watched him play with his son.
- Did you talk to him?
I couldn't do it.
- How did I get here?
- You told a lie and got on a plane.
That's not what I mean.
I'm going back over there tomorrow
and talk to him. I am.
Okay. Good.
Good-bye.
- Beck?
- What?
- Is this crazy?
- No.
That's the weirdest part about it.
Thank you.
I love you.
- I love you too.
- Good night.
Oh, it's so good to see you.
Where's Greg?
Hello.
- So then what happened?
- So then I left, obviously.
You were standing
in the middle of the street?
You know that dream when you're on the
street naked and everyone is looking?
I love that dream.
That was nothing compared
to this humiliation. Nothing.
- But he saw you, right?
- He saw me.
- You were face-to-face?
- He said hello.
- He said hello, and what did you say?
- All I could say was hello.
Oh, my God!
And all I could say was hello.
It's a sign.
It's a sign that I have watched
this movie too many times.
So stupid.
Since I listened to that stupid program
on the radio, I've been a complete jerk.
- You are not a jerk.
- Thank you.
- Idiot.
- You don't know who she was.
I saw her. I have a picture of her.
I'll show you a picture of her.
That detective in Seattle
sent me a picture of her.
Here. See?
That's exactly
what she looks like.
This is a picture
of someone's back.
Well, it's her
and he was crazy about her.
What's this?
This is from Seattle.
So I mailed your letter.
"Dear Annie,
thanks for your letter.
It was great.
You sound neat.
We're very excited about meeting you
in New York on Valentine's Day...
and seeing if we are...
M.F.E.O.
See you soon.
Sleepless in Seattle. "
M.F. E.O.?
Made for each other.
It's cute.
It's like a little clue.
So he can't write. Big deal.
Verbal ability is a highly
overrated thing in a guy...
and our pathetic need for it
is what gets us into trouble.
I will be running back to Walter's arms,
if he'll still have me.
- What about the letter?
- It means nothing.
It was written before
I went out there, before the 'ho.
The only thing is,
she didn't look like a 'ho.
She looked like somebody
we would've been friends with.
- You saw her in the airport, then here?
- I tried to talk to her.
It was like I knew her.
It was weird.
Like a d¨¦j¨¤ vu thing?
It was a very French
d¨¦j¨¤ vu-ish kind of thing. Oui.
At least you're out there
seeing people again. That's terrific.
Well, there's really just the one.
Victoria.
- You don't like Victoria?
- She laughs like a hyena.
Is this true?
Sort of, a little bit.
Tell them what you did.
Tell 'em about the radio show.
They wanna hear it.
Tell 'em. Christmas Eve, he phones in
one of those radio call-in shows.
Tells them I need a new wife.
Oh, you're kidding.
That's so sweet.
- He's obsessed with a lady who wrote me.
- You serious?
She wants to meet me at the top
of the Empire State Building.
On Valentine's Day.
- It's like that movie.
- What movie?
An Affair To Remember.
Did you ever see it?
Oh, God.
Cary Grant and Deborah Kerr.
Is it "car" or "cur"?
- Cur.
- Car.
She's gonna meet him at the top
of the Empire State Building...
only she got hit by a taxi.
And he waited and waited.
And it was raining, I think.
And then...
she's too proud to tell him...
that she's, uh...
crippled.
And he's too proud to find out
why she doesn't come.
But he comes to see her anyway.
I forget why, but, oh-
Oh, it's so amazing
when he comes to see her because...
he doesn't even notice that
she doesn't get up to say hello.
And he's very bitter.
And you think that he's just gonna
walk out the door...
and never know why she's just
lying there, you know, on the couch...
with this blanket
over her shriveled little legs.
- Are you all right?
- She's fine.
Suddenly he goes,
"I already sold the painting. "
And he like
goes to the bedroom...
and he looks and he comes out and
he looks at her and he kind of just-
They know and then they hug.
And it's so-
- That's a chick's movie.
- I would say so.
What kind of a person would write
to someone they heard on the radio?
I got hundreds of letters
from women all over the country.
Desperate women.
Just because someone is looking for
a nice guy doesn't make them desperate.
How about rapacious
and love-starved?
It is easier to be killed by a terrorist
than to find a husband after the age-
That is absolutely untrue.
Right, honey. Right.
I'm not lookin' for
a mail-order bride.
I just want somebody that I can have a
decent conversation with over dinner...
without it fallin' down
into weepy tears over some movie.
She's very emotional.
- But I cried at The Dirty Dozen.
- Who didn't?
Jim Brown is throwin' these
hand grenades down these air shafts...
and Richard Jaeckel and Lee Marvin
were sittin' on top of this...
armored personnel carrier,
dressed up like Nazis.
They're waiting.
Trini L¨®pez-
He busted his neck when they were
parachuting down behind the Nazi lines.
Stop it.
Richard Jaeckel had on this shiny helmet
'cause he was the M.P.
No more.
Oh, God, I love that movie.
This is the best movie
I've ever seen in my life.
What's so great about it?
You have to find her.
You have to go to her.
Do you know how much money it costs
to go to New York?
Nobody knows.
It changes practically every day.
How much money do you have?
Eighty dollars.
I have 42. That would
probably cover taxicabs.
How would I get there?
Honey, I have to run
these tickets over to someone.
Can you keep an eye on things?
Sure, Mom.
- Do you want a window seat or an aisle?
- Window.
- Do you want a fruit plate?
- I don't know. Do I?
I'd rather die
than eat airplane food.
I'm telling them you're 12
so you can fly unaccompanied...
and the stewardess
won't carry you around.
Are you crazy?
Who'd believe I'm 12?
If it's in the computer,
they believe anything.
Are you sure?
Do you want me to say that
you're really short for your age...
and that they shouldn't say anything
'cause it would hurt your feelings?
Yeah, that's a great idea.
Sometimes it's hard to be
A woman
Givin' all your love
To just one man
Walter.
- You're gonna miss the train.
- No, I'm not.
I'm so happy, Becky.
Finally I feel happy.
This is right. This is real.
Everything else is what happens
when you watch too many movies...
and you completely
lose sight of what counts.
Please, don't tell anybody
what happened.
I would be so absolutely mortified
if anyone knew...
I did anything even
remotely close to what I've done.
- Thank you. Do you promise?
- I promise.
Sleepless in Seattle
is history.
He's hard to understand
And if you love him
Oh, be proud of him
'Cause after all
He's just a man
Stand by your man
I was-
- Go ahead.
- You go.
Okay. Well,
I was just gonna say...
that ever since Christmas,
you've been different...
kind of distracted, distant.
But now...
it feels as if you're coming back
from wherever you were.
I am.
I was just, uh-
I just got-
I think I got nervous.
But that's normal, right?
I mean, don't you ever
feel nervous about-
You know?
What?
Forever.
I did, and you know what I think?
I think I thought
it was too perfect, you know?
I started to wonder
if we were the human equivalent...
of two rights making a wrong.
You know what it was?
It was like kismet, but not,
if you see what I mean.
You have to grow up.
You just can't keep having
all these adolescent fantasies...
about how exciting
your life is gonna be.
Don't hate me,
but I love this pattern.
- You couldn't.
- I do.
This is just like
my grandmother's china.
How many place settings
should I put down?
Ten.
Exactly. Eight is too few.
Twelve is too many.
It was my mother's.
I had them size it down.
She had really fat fingers.
It's so beautiful.
It's exactly what I would
pick out if I had...
every ring in the whole world
to choose from.
You see what I mean?
There are people who would like
a relationship to be full of surprises.
But I am not one of those people.
No, sirree.
Surprises are highly overrated.
I'm leavin' first thing in the morning,
but I'm only gonna be gone one night.
Clarise is gonna be here,
so you'll be able to see...
plenty of Geraldo
and Nightmare On Elm Street 12.
- I will never know.
- Are you going with her?
I'm going with Victoria, yes.
And don't try anything tricky.
Understand?
Don't go rollin' in poison ivy
as soon as I leave the house...
or lock yourself in a closet or do
anything that makes you need stitches.
If your finger falls off,
it's stayin' off.
No one's gonna pack it on ice
and take you to the hospital...
so you can be
a breakthrough in laser surgery.
- Is this about that woman in Baltimore?
- Annie.
- I don't care what you do!
- Good! Fine!
I'll tell you what I'm doin'
this weekend. I'm getting laid.
1990s and nobody is getting laid.
I'm the only man in America
who is getting laid this weekend.
I haven't been laid that much.
Six girls in college, maybe seven.
- How long you been standin' there?
- Forever.
- What did you hear me just say?
- "Six girls in college, maybe seven. "
Seven.
Eight! Mary Kelly.
This is the one I like.
Jonah, the fact is...
you're not gonna like any woman
because it isn't your mother.
How do you know?
- What's wrong with Annie?
- Oh, Jonah, shut up!
Shut up?
Mom never said "shut up" to me.
Mom never yelled at me.
- The conversation is finished.
- Why can't we go to New York?
There is no way
that we are going on a plane...
to meet some woman
who could be a crazy, sick lunatic.
- Didn't you see Fatal Attraction?
- You wouldn't let me.
Well, I saw it!
And it scared the shit outta me.
It scared the shit
outta every man in America!
I'm not leaving till you say yes.
- I hate you!
- That's good!
You'll have to tell Oprah.
How your dad destroyed your life
'cause he had to go off...
for a weekend special
at the Holiday Inn!
Jonah, Clarise is here
and I gotta go.
Hey, Jonah.
All right.
Jonah, listen.
I gotta go, and I'm-
Jessica, honey,
you have to tell us where he is.
Jonah's daddy is very upset.
This is your father.
Tell us where he is, right this minute.
N.Y.
- What is that?
- No way.
That's N.W.
New York.
He's on his way to New York.
- What?
- How?
- United 597.
- Jessica.
- When does it leave?
- 7:30.
Here you go. Here's a nice pen
for you for flying with us.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Can I take this for you?
- No.
- Where to, kid?
- Empire State Building.
Hold on.
Empire State Building.
Get a little further away
from the curb next time, mac.
There it is.
What you gonna do
when you get up there?
- Spit off the top?
- No.
I'm going to meet my new mother.
Excuse me. I'm Jonah.
Are you Annie?
No. I'm Cynthia.
Excuse me.
Are you Annie?
Great table. Thanks.
Something wrong?
- Can I get you a drink?
- Some champagne?
Fine.
Can we have a bottle...
of Dom DeLuise?
- Just kidding.
- It was a joke.
- He meant Dom P¨¦rignon.
- I got it.
Beautiful view, isn't it?
Walter, there's something
I have to tell you.
Hey, I'm sorry.
I have an emergency.
Look! Money!
All right?
- Get right in.
- Wait a minute.
Taxi!
So, he could be on top
of the Empire State Building now.
I guess he could be.
It's not him, Walter.
It's me.
I can't do this.
Look, Annie...
I love you,
but let's leave that outta this.
I don't wanna be someone
that you're settling for.
that anyone settles for.
Marriage is hard enough...
without bringing such
low expectations into it.
Isn't it?
Walter, I don't deserve you.
I wouldn't put it that way.
But, okay.
You okay?
Yeah.
- What?
- Look.
- It's a sign.
- Who needed a sign?
I have to go.
What if something had happened to you?
What if I couldn't get to you?
I'm sorry.
What would I have done?
You are my family.
You're all I've got.
I thought she'd be here.
I thought she'd come.
We're doin' okay, aren't we?
Aren't we all right?
- Have I done anything really stupid?
- No.
- Have I screwed it up for both of us?
- Observation deck?
- Sorry, ma'am, but it's too late.
Please. I really need
to get up there.
We're closing up.
No more runs tonight.
Listen.
Can I just take a look?
There's someone I was supposed to meet.
He's probably not there,
but if I don't at least look...
I'll always wonder about it.
Cary Grant, right?
You know that movie?
One of my wife's favorites.
Maybe when we get home
we'll get a dog.
- Okay.
- What do you mean "okay"?
- Wouldn't you like to have a dog?
- Sure.
I'm sorry, ma'am. Empty.
Can I take a minute?
Go ahead.
I left it by the telescopes.
- It's you.
- It's me.
- I saw you in the street.
- Are you Annie?
Yes.
You're Annie?
This must be yours.
I'm Jonah.
This is my dad.
- His name's Sam.
- Hi, Jonah.
- And who's this?
- Howard.
Oh, Howard.
Hello, Howard.
We better go.
Shall we?
It's so important
to make someone happy
Make just one someone happy
Make just one heart
the heart you
- You sing to
- Sam.
It's nice to meet you.
One face that lights
when it nears you
One girl you're
You're everything to
Fame
If you win it
Comes and goes in a minute
Where's the real stuff in life
To cling to
Love is the answer
Someone to love is the answer
Once you've found her
Build your world around her
Make someone happy
Make just one someone happy
And you will be happy too